

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">j.ctt45kc24</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Communication Studies</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Screen Genealogies</book-title>
         <subtitle>From Optical Device to Environmental Medium</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <role content-type="editor">Edited by</role>
         <contrib contrib-type="editor" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Buckley</surname>
               <given-names>Craig</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="editor" id="contrib2">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Campe</surname>
               <given-names>Rüdiger</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="editor" id="contrib3">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Casetti</surname>
               <given-names>Francesco</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>11</day>
         <month>11</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9789048543953</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Amsterdam University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Amsterdam</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>All authors / Amsterdam University Press B.V.</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvs32t6s"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>Against the grain of the growing literature on screens, *Screen Genealogies* argues that the present excess of screens cannot be understood as an expansion and multiplication of the movie screen nor of the video display. Rather, screens continually exceed the optical histories in which they are most commonly inscribed. As contemporary screens become increasingly decomposed into a distributed field of technologically interconnected surfaces and interfaces, we more readily recognize the deeper spatial and environmental interventions that have long been a property of screens. For most of its history, a screen was a filter, a divide, a shelter, or a camouflage. A genealogy stressing transformation and descent rather than origins and roots emphasizes a deeper set of intersecting and competing definitions of the screen, enabling new thinking about what the screen might yet become.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="320"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Buckley</surname>
                           <given-names>Craig</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Campe</surname>
                           <given-names>Rüdiger</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib3" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Casetti</surname>
                           <given-names>Francesco</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>A flourishing of screens increasingly defines our contemporary lifeworld. Screens have become more numerous and more protean, changing in size, position, and dimension as well as thickness, shape, and material. But with this increase in number and variety, the screen’s functions have also mutated. No longer solely surfaces for the display of representations, they are central to mobile, multi-directional communication. They are surfaces for writing and aggregating messages; they also serve as interfaces for the storage, sharing, and filtering of information. As their uses expand, screens also reshape the most public as well as the most intimate of experiences, obliterating</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1.</label>
                     <title>Primal Screens</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Casetti</surname>
                           <given-names>Francesco</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>27</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Media studies often falls prey to a strange fascination. The more frantic the transformations of the media landscape, the more theorists feel the need to cast a retrospective look at the media past. This historical view is expected to capture not only the story of a single medium but also its place in a longer lineage: its origins and previous instantiations. Hence the current boom of media archaeology, whose tasks and methods have been voiced especially by Erkki Huhtamo and Jussi Parikka—and in a more critical mode, by Thomas Elsaesser.¹ Beyond offering readers the pleasure of its historical reconstructions,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2.</label>
                     <title>‘Schutz und Schirm’:</title>
                     <subtitle>Screening in German During Early Modern Times</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Campe</surname>
                           <given-names>Rüdiger</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>51</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Ever since the advent of electronic and digital projection, looking at screens or displays in German amounts to gazing at <italic>Schirme</italic>: screens or displays. More precisely, in German you look at <italic>Bildschirme</italic>: screens intended for the display of images. By contrast, the projection surface in a movie theatre never came to be known as a <italic>Bildschirm</italic> but instead as a <italic>Filmleinwand</italic>, or ‘movie canvas’, in a nod to the semantic regime of painting. Only radar, TV, computer displays, and other devices whose projection techniques do not reproduce images analogically acquired the status of <italic>Bildschirm</italic>, or screen, rather than <italic>Leinwand</italic>, or</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3.</label>
                     <title>Face and Screen:</title>
                     <subtitle>Toward a Genealogy of the Media Façade</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Buckley</surname>
                           <given-names>Craig</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>One no longer need travel very far to encounter façades that pulse and move like electronic screens. Media façades have spread far beyond the dense commercial nodes with which they were once synonymous—New York’s Times Square, London’s Piccadilly Circus, Berlin’s Alexanderplatz, or Tokyo’s Shibuya. Some of the most ambitious media façades are today realized in places such as Birmingham, Graz, Tallinn, and Jeddah; Abu Dhabi, Tripoli, Montreal, and San Jose; Lima, Melbourne, Seoul, and Ningbo. Within the darkness of a global night this emerging network of cities registers itself through a call and response of ever-changing luminous façades designed</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4.</label>
                     <title>Sensing Screens:</title>
                     <subtitle>From Surface to Situation</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Verhoeff</surname>
                           <given-names>Nanna</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>115</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The recent public art installation <italic>In the Air Tonight</italic> uses light and architectural surface for data visualization. (Figures 4.1 and 4.2) The project, by Toronto-based artists Patricio Davilla and Dave Colangelo of Public Visualization Studios, makes use of a LED façade of the Ryerson Image Center in Toronto. It is a temporary but recurring installation for a pre-existing and fixed architecture. It was on display for one month in 2014, and again in 2015 and 2016, with the aim of raising awareness of homelessness in the city. Throughout the cold winter evenings, a blue wave on the façade displayed fluctuating</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5.</label>
                     <title>‘Taking the Plunge’:</title>
                     <subtitle>The New Immersive Screens</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Rogers</surname>
                           <given-names>Ariel</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>135</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>A cover story in <italic>Variety</italic> on 22 March 2016 marked a perceived turning point in the emergence of virtual reality (VR), just as the Oculus Rift and HTC Vive headsets were about to be made available to the public. Titled ‘Taking the Plunge’, the article featured an illustration depicting three virtual reality users, each wearing opaque goggles and walking blindly toward the edge of a high dive, about to fall into a pixelated abyss (Figure 5.1). The would-be cybernauts, improbably dressed in vintage business attire, are equipped with only old-fashioned inflatable lifesavers to buoy them, and one of these has</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6.</label>
                     <title>The Atmospheric Screen:</title>
                     <subtitle>Turner, Hazlitt, Ruskin</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Somaini</surname>
                           <given-names>Antonio</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>159</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In his ‘Notes on a Genealogy of the Excessive Screen’—the text that introduced Yale’s Mellon Sawyer Seminar, <italic>Genealogies of the Excessive Screen</italic>, from which the essays in this volume originate—Francesco Casetti presents the history of screens and of the very term ‘screen’ as the intertwining of two different traditions. On the one hand there is a tradition, beginning in the early nineteenth century, that considers the screen to be first and foremost an optical device: a material surface onto which an image is projected or from which an image emanates. On the other hand, there is an older</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7.</label>
                     <title>The Fog Medium:</title>
                     <subtitle>Visualizing and Engineering the Atmosphere</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Furuhata</surname>
                           <given-names>Yuriko</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>187</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Fogs, as Japanese artist Nakaya Fujiko once noted, are clouds that descend on earth.² Recently, clouds have become a much-debated and researched topic in film and media studies. Terms such as ‘atmospheric media’ and ‘elemental media’ have gained popularity, alongside the metaphor of the cloud in cloud computing. Scholars as diverse as Weihong Bao, Mark Hansen, Tung-Hui Hu, John Durham Peters, Nicole Starosielski, and Antonio Somaini have prompted us to look at the affinity between media and atmospheric environment in a new light.³ To put it schematically, the old framework of media ecology represented by the Toronto School of communication</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>8.</label>
                     <title>The Charge of a Light Barricade:</title>
                     <subtitle>Optics and Ballistics in the Ambiguous Being of Screens</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Peters</surname>
                           <given-names>John Durham</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>215</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>When we see, do we see the world or images of the world? Do our eyes give us direct access to reality, or do they construct pictures by means of which we navigate it? The long history of disputes about the theory of vision could be boiled down to the question of whether sight is immediate or mediated. Certainly in everyday practice, almost everyone votes for the former view. We trust intuitively that our eyes deliver the world to us. The trees, houses, windows, books, and people I see feel like they are simply there and not like neurologically processed</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>9.</label>
                     <title>Flat Bayreuth:</title>
                     <subtitle>A Genealogy of Opera as Screened</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Kreuzer</surname>
                           <given-names>Gundula</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>237</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Over the last several decades, music scholars have developed a keen interest in opera’s relationship to the screen. A substantial number of essays and monographs have addressed such aspects of ‘opera on screen’ as studio productions of opera, TV relays or videos of live performances, television opera, opera films, or the diegetic use of opera in feature films.² In this discourse, ‘ screen’ often serves as a shorthand for all manner of cinematic media, which are contrasted to the seemingly independent phenomenon of opera: the screen tends to stand as the ‘other’ to live operatic performance.</p>
                     <p>This ontological opposition has</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>10.</label>
                     <title>Imaginary Screens:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Hypnotic Gesture and Early Film</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Eugeni</surname>
                           <given-names>Ruggero</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>269</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Between the 1910s and 1920s, the iconography of hypnosis in film was changing. The hypnotist no longer pointed his fingers at the subject, hitting him with a shot of magnetic fluid; instead, subjects now fell into hypnosis as a consequence of the hypnotist waving his hand in slow and repeated gestures in front of their eyes. Occasionally, other hypnotic procedures were also shown, such as the gaze of the hypnotist or the movement of shining objects. But the waving gesture of the hypnotist’s hand appears to have held primary interest, for even as it remained marginal in the extra-cinematic practice</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>11.</label>
                     <title>Material. Human. Divine. Notes on the Vertical Screen</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Elcott</surname>
                           <given-names>Noam M.</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>293</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>
                        <italic>Screens For Looking at Abstraction</italic> (2011-), a multi-part installation by Josiah McElheny, encapsulates the whole history of abstract cinema. Selections from the canon and margins of abstract film—projected upside-down, backwards, and in reverse—are refracted horizontally, vertically, or prismatically across a series of mirrors and screens to form new kaleidoscopic configurations. (Figure 11.1) These visual symphonies immediately conjure the iridescent images produced on Sir David Brewster’s kaleidoscope (patented in 1817), A. Wallace Rimington’s Colour Organ (patented in 1895), Alexander B. Hector’s Apparatus for Creating Colour Music (patented in 1921), the lumia of Thomas Wilfred (to which I will return),</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgments</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>321</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvs32t6s.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>323</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
