

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvthhdtc</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">PN4784.W43 C47 2020</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Web usage mining in journalism</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">United States</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Web usage mining in journalism</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">France</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Journalism</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Technological innovations</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">United States</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Journalism</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Technological innovations</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">France</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Communication Studies</subject>
         <subject>Language &amp; Literature</subject>
         <subject>Sociology</subject>
         <subject>Anthropology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Metrics at Work</book-title>
         <subtitle>Journalism and the Contested Meaning of Algorithms</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Christin</surname>
               <given-names>Angèle</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>30</day>
         <month>06</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691175232</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780691200002</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0691200009</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Princeton University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvthhdtc"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> The starkly different ways that American and French online news companies respond to audience analytics and what this means for the future of news When the news moved online, journalists suddenly learned what their audiences actually liked, through algorithmic technologies that scrutinize web traffic and activity. Has this advent of audience metrics changed journalists' work practices and professional identities? In Metrics at Work, Angèle Christin documents the ways that journalists grapple with audience data in the form of clicks, and analyzes how new forms of clickbait journalism travel across national borders. Drawing on four years of fieldwork in web newsrooms in the United States and France, including more than one hundred interviews with journalists, Christin reveals many similarities among the media groups examined-their editorial goals, technological tools, and even office furniture. Yet she uncovers crucial and paradoxical differences in how American and French journalists understand audience analytics and how these affect the news produced in each country. American journalists routinely disregard traffic numbers and primarily rely on the opinion of their peers to define journalistic quality. Meanwhile, French journalists fixate on internet traffic and view these numbers as a sign of their resonance in the public sphere. Christin offers cultural and historical explanations for these disparities, arguing that distinct journalistic traditions structure how journalists make sense of digital measurements in the two countries. Contrary to the popular belief that analytics and algorithms are globally homogenizing forces, Metrics at Work shows that computational technologies can have surprisingly divergent ramifications for work and organizations worldwide.</p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>v</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PROLOGUE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>xi</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The shape of a city changes more quickly than the mortal heart, wrote Baudelaire. The northeast of Paris is certainly no exception. In the rapidly gentrifying neighborhood of Belleville, North African delis and old-fashioned sports bars are being replaced by pour-over coffee shops, pop-up restaurants, and municipally sponsored tech incubators like the white building where the <italic>LaPlace</italic> office was located.</p>
                     <p>Three journalists were having a cigarette and a cup of coffee downstairs, making snarky comments about the latest press announcement of then-President Nicolas Sarkozy and discussing where they would have lunch later that day. After a couple of jokes, someone</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We live in a world of data. Our work, as well as how we stay informed and interact with others, increasingly takes place online. Our activities on the internet generate a tremendous amount of information about our social networks, financial records, shopping preferences, and geographical movements, all of which are recorded, stored, and analyzed by the very websites we spend time on. Our data is valuable. In what is sometimes compared to a new “oil rush,” companies gather and mine this information to determine algorithmically what we see when we browse the web. Think of Google, which personalizes its results</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1</label>
                     <title>From Circulation Numbers to Web Analytics:</title>
                     <subtitle>Journalists and Their Readers in the United States and France</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>I first encountered the software program Chartbeat during one of my early days at <italic>LaPlace</italic>. It was a tense period for the news website, which had just been acquired by a larger media company; the journalists were cautious. During their many cigarette breaks, they devised complex strategies to get what they wanted from “the bosses” (<italic>les chefs</italic>). I was not invited to join them during these breaks. In fact, I was not told much at that point. When I asked the journalists who were storming in and out of the newsroom questions about the sale, most responded to me with</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2</label>
                     <title>Utopian Beginnings:</title>
                     <subtitle>A Tale of Two Websites</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>36</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The internet may have a short history, but it is already full of surprising twists. From the early days of the cyberpunk movement and the techno-utopianism of <italic>Wired</italic> to the global empires of Google, Facebook, Amazon, and Apple, the digital landscape has witnessed major evolutions over the past twenty years.¹ Online news is an important part of this story. In the 1990s, many of the journalists who started writing online considered the internet a new frontier—a place where they could fix what they found problematic in traditional media. They thought that they had found uncharted territory where they could</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3</label>
                     <title>Entering the Chase for Clicks:</title>
                     <subtitle>Transatlantic Convergences</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>54</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Markets and industries are sometimes dramatically reconfigured around new measurements of value and success.¹ This is what happened in online news around 2008 when, during the Great Recession, news websites entered the chase for traffic. Faced with strong pressures to make a profit, editors and staff writers in New York and Paris searched desperately for techniques that would magically attract more readers to their webpages. They began surveilling and imitating their competitors. Eventually, they adopted the same strategies to stay afloat financially: publishing more, faster, and paying closer attention to the technical underpinnings of traffic maximization, all of which laid</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4</label>
                     <title>The Multiple Meanings of Clicks:</title>
                     <subtitle>Journalists and Their Algorithmic Publics</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>75</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>When web journalists talk about the kind of articles that attract a lot of clicks, they often use the word “trash,” in English and in French. In fact, some of them go further, deploying the metaphor of prostitution. For instance, Philippe, <italic>LaPlace</italic>’s editor-in-chief, told me how the editorial team had come up with the term “the whore’s spot” (<italic>la place de la pute</italic>) to describe a specific location on the website’s homepage where they often posted popular articles:</p>
                     <p>We’re always trying to find a balance between serious and light articles, short and long papers. … The second article on the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5</label>
                     <title>The Fast and the Slow:</title>
                     <subtitle>Producing Online News in Real Time</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>102</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>News organizations are characterized by an intrinsic tension, as sociologist Gaye Tuchman first pointed out: news is by definition unpredictable because it depends on each day’s events, but media companies need to put together a highly standardized product regardless—be it a newspaper or a television show—at the same time, day after day. Thus, news organizations need to find ways to “routinize the unexpected” and streamline the production of information.¹</p>
                     <p>Traditionally, print newsrooms achieved this by relying on hierarchical and compartmentalized structures. As Herbert Gans argued in the 1970s, the journalistic distinction between “hard” and “soft” news, together with</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6</label>
                     <title>Between Exposure and Unpaid Work:</title>
                     <subtitle>Compensation and Freelance Careers</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>125</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>On March 4, 2013, the veteran journalist Nate Thayer, well known for his coverage of military zones in Cambodia and North Korea, published a post on his blog entitled “A Day in the Life of a Freelance Journalist, 2013.”¹ Thayer simply copied and pasted an email exchange he had with a web editor of the <italic>Atlantic Monthly</italic>. The editor was interested in publishing a version of an article that Thayer had posted that day on NKNews.org. When Thayer expressed his interest and asked for more information about the format and fees, the <italic>Atlantic</italic> editor wrote:</p>
                     <p>Thanks for responding. Maybe by</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Conclusion</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>152</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Things change rapidly in the world of online news. When I started my fieldwork in 2011, <italic>TheNotebook</italic> and <italic>LaPlace</italic> were both prospering. There was always a difference in scale between them—<italic>TheNotebook</italic> had a team of about forty journalists and attracted more than 4.5 million unique visitors per month, whereas <italic>LaPlace</italic> had fifteen journalists and attracted 2 million visitors per month. Over time, however, the two websites took different trajectories. Already, towards the end of my fieldwork in 2014, <italic>TheNotebook</italic> was growing, attracting about 30 million unique visitors, whereas <italic>LaPlace</italic> had declined to 1.5 million. In 2018, the fortunes of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX:</title>
                     <subtitle>A Fly on the Screen? Behind the Scenes in the (Digital) Field</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>163</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>179</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>221</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvthhdtc.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>247</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
