

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">j.ctt7mjcq</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.5749/j.ctv64h79h</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">QA76.625 .M3825 2018</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Internet programming</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Science &amp; Technology Studies</subject>
         <subject>History of Science &amp; Technology</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Internet Daemons</book-title>
         <subtitle>Digital Communications Possessed</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>McKELVEY</surname>
               <given-names>FENWICK</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>30</day>
         <month>10</month>
         <year>2018</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781517901547</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781452957562</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">1452957568</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>University of Minnesota Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Minneapolis; London</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Regents of the University of Minnesota</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5749/j.ctv64h79h"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> A complete history and theory of internet daemons brings these little-known-but very consequential-programs into the spotlight We're used to talking about how tech giants like Google, Facebook, and Amazon rule the internet, but what about daemons? Ubiquitous programs that have colonized the Net's infrastructure-as well as the devices we use to access it-daemons are little known. Fenwick McKelvey weaves together history, theory, and policy to give a full account of where daemons come from and how they influence our lives-including their role in hot-button issues like network neutrality. Going back to Victorian times and the popular thought experiment Maxwell's Demon, McKelvey charts how daemons evolved from concept to reality, eventually blossoming into the pandaemonium of code-based creatures that today orchestrates our internet. Digging into real-life examples like sluggish connection speeds, Comcast's efforts to control peer-to-peer networking, and Pirate Bay's attempts to elude daemonic control (and skirt copyright), McKelvey shows how daemons have been central to the internet, greatly influencing everyday users. Internet Daemons asks important questions about how much control is being handed over to these automated, autonomous programs, and the consequences for transparency and oversight.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="336"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>v</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABBREVIATIONS AND TECHNICAL TERMS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Users having trouble with eMule, a Peer-to-Peer (P2P) file-sharing application popular in the 2000s, often sought help on its online message board. Frustrations with slow downloads, confusion about internet connections, and worries about uploading echo throughout the hundreds of posts. On July 23, 2006, one user named thelug wondered why “uploaders in the queue keep disappearing”-a problem, since eMule used a credit system to reward users for uploading files.¹ Other users responded to the thread, reporting the same mysterious problem with uploading. Later, thelug posted again with an account of a call to his or her internet service provider (ISP),</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>THE DEVIL WE KNOW:</title>
                     <subtitle>Maxwell’s Demon, Cyborg Sciences, and Flow Control</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>23</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>“Maxwell’s demon,” the celebrated thought experiment by physicist James Maxwell, occupies a strange space, at once both abstract and real. Perhaps the demon is abstract enough to explore the realities of control and communication. What started out as a pure thought experiment inspired decades of speculation about its possible existence and then attempts to build an artificial demon. Maxwell’s demon inspired the crucial breakdowns that Donna Haraway identifies as part of postwar computer research, or what has been called the “cyborg sciences.” Two breakdowns in particular relate to my interest in networks, infrastructures, and control: between humans and machines and</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>POSSESSING INFRASTRUCTURE:</title>
                     <subtitle>Nonsynchronous Communication, IMPs, and Optimization</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>45</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Daemons helped inspire what we now call packet switching. Donald Davies, a researcher at the prestigious National Physical Laboratory (NPL) in the United Kingdom and one of the inventors of packet switching, discovered daemons, the same ones mentioned in the previous chapter, when he visited Project MAC (Man And Computer) at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT). On a research trip in May 1965, he observed the Compatible Time-Sharing System (CTSS) and noted that a “central part of the system” was a “scheduling algorithm” that allowed users to share time on an IBM 7094 computer. While Davies did not mention it</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>IMPs, OLIVERs, AND GATEWAYS:</title>
                     <subtitle>Internetworking before the Internet</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>71</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Before the first Interface Message Processor (IMP) had been delivered, former directors of the Information Processing Techniques Office (IPTO) J. C. R. Licklider and Robert Taylor were imagining a world filled with daemons and digital communications (to everyone’s benefit, of course). Their optimism abounded in a lighthearted article entitled “The Computer as a Communication Device” for the business magazine <italic>Science &amp; Technology for the Technical Men in Management.</italic> Published in 1968, the article filled in a vision for the Advanced Research Projects Agency’s ARPANET that was absent from the IMP Request for Quotations (RFQ) discussed in the previous chapter. The pair</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4</label>
                     <title>PANDAEMONIUM:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Internet as Daemons</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>93</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The Cisco Service Control Engine (SCE) 8000 debuted in 2008. Designed as carrier-grade equipment, the forty-two kilogram metal box requires only five rack units within the tall metal cages of an internet service provider’s (ISP) infrastructure. When running, it can manage a million concurrent internet users. The processing power of the SCE 8000 enables “stateful awareness” of packet flows, which means it is able to look into the contents of a sequence of packets and contextualize this data within the overall state of the infrastructure. The SCE’s built-in packet inspection detects six hundred known protocols and has adaptive recognition for</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>SUFFERING FROM BUFFERING?</title>
                     <subtitle>Affects of Flow Control</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>135</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We sit in front of our computers waiting for media to load. We stare at the familiar turning circle when a video buffers on YouTube. Buffering postpones the satisfaction of watching another cat play or learning how to assemble a new piece of furniture. At other times, bad connections cause our conversations to stutter into incomprehensible fragments. Distant friends and family cut out or suddenly speed up as the connection resynchronizes. Avatars perish in virtual worlds because of lag: a sudden pause, and we find ourselves staring up from the ground or floating above our digital corpses. Our communications online</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>THE DISOPTIMIZED:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Ambiguous Tactics of The Pirate Bay</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>161</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>On January 31, 2008, Swedish authorities filed charges against the three administrators of the infamous site “The Pirate Bay” (TPB): Fredrik Neij, Gottfrid Svartholm Warg, and Peter Sunde. The trial of the site’s administrators was one front in a long battle to remove TPB from the internet. The website had served as the homepage for internet piracy since its launch in 2003 and belonged to a broader propiracy, anticopyright movement in Sweden.¹ This informal movement included political parties and think tanks, while the TPB team coordinated an easy-to-find and politically vocal website that facilitated mass piracy. The website acted mostly</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7</label>
                     <title>A CRESCENDO OF ONLINE INTERACTIVE DEBUGGING?</title>
                     <subtitle>Gamers, Publics, and Daemons</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>185</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>René Descartes and computer gamers faced a similar problem. A mischievous creature haunted both of them. Symptoms varied. Descartes worried that some malicious demon was manipulating him, generating illusions that meant he could not trust his hands, eyes, flesh, and blood. Everything his senses detected might be one of these illusions caused by an evil demon (or evil genius in other interpretations).¹ Canadian gamers had less existential woes. Beginning in 2010, gamers who subscribed to Rogers Internet experienced trouble enjoying online games like <italic>World of Warcraft</italic> and <italic>Call of Duty.</italic> The <italic>ouroboros</italic> symbol of lag haunted their games until, suddenly,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>CONCLUSION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>209</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This journey through Pandaemonium now ends. Through the book, I have explored the history of internet daemons, their present work, and the conflicts between them and against them. Though contested, they are a constant presence online. Daemons run on the switches, routers, gateways, and other middleboxes that the internet’s infrastructure comprises. Networking happens through their constant work. Daemons inspect, queue, route, and coordinate the sending of packets across the internet. Their distributive agency enacts what I have called “flow control.” Through this control, daemons realize the conditions of transmission that govern networks online, enacting a certain optimization.</p>
                     <p>Internet daemons have</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>229</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX:</title>
                     <subtitle>Internet Measurement and Mediators</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>233</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>239</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>267</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>309</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv64h79h.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Back Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>321</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
