

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">j.ctvcmxp9b</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvpbnq9j</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Sociology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Art &amp; Art History</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Minor Platforms in Videogame History</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Nicoll</surname>
               <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>09</day>
         <month>09</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9789048540303</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Amsterdam University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Amsterdam</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>B. Nicoll</copyright-holder>
         <copyright-holder>Amsterdam University Press B.V.</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvpbnq9j"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>Videogame history is not just a history of one successful technology replacing the next. It is also a history of platforms and communities that never quite made it; that struggled to make their voices heard; that aggravated against the conventions of the day; and that never enjoyed the commercial success or recognition of their major counterparts. In Minor Platforms in Videogame History, Benjamin Nicoll argues that 'minor' game histories are anything but insignificant. Through an analysis of transitional, decolonial, imaginary, residual, and minor videogame platforms, Nicoll seeks out moments of difference and discontinuity in game history. From the domestication of vector graphics in the early years of videogame consoles to the proliferation of videogame piracy in South Korea in the 1980s, this book explores case studies that challenge taken-for-granted approaches to videogames, platforms, and their histories.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="224"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>List of Tables and Figures</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgements</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Introduction:</title>
                     <subtitle>Failed, forgotten, or overlooked? Methods for historicizing minor platforms</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>11</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Over three days in April 2014, a team of self-described ‘punk archaeologists’ (Caraher et al., 2014)—researchers, historians, and filmmakers—excavated a videogame trash dump in Alamogordo, New Mexico. The site of their dig was videogame history’s most infamous e-waste deposit: the ‘Atari landfill’. This is a site where Atari had, in the midst of its financial collapse in September of 1983, buried thousands of unsold videogame cartridges, consoles, and computers. The three-day excavation yielded 1300 of approximately 700,000 buried videogames, barely scratching the surface of the 30-foot deep landfill. Many of the unearthed videogames remained surprisingly intact, despite sustaining</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1.</label>
                     <title>Ways of seeing videogame history:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Vectrex as a transitional platform</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>45</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Videogames inherit many of their aesthetic qualities from a deep lineage of representational media and visual techniques. Alexander Galloway (2006: 40) notes that early first-person shooter videogames, for example, built on a direct legacy of photographic and cinematic techniques for structuring embodied vision.¹ In a similar vein, Angela Ndalianis (2004: 102) suggests that videogames such as <italic>Doom</italic> (id Software, 1993) possess a labyrinthine logic similar to that which proliferated in baroque art and culture in sixteenthcentury Europe. David Surman (2009: 165) argues that <italic>Pokémon’</italic>s visual style draws influence from a long history of Japanese art and design, namely the ‘recurring</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2.</label>
                     <title>Articulations of videogame piracy:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Zemmix as a decolonial platform</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It is often argued that videogames became a ‘global’ commodity in the 1980s, precipitated by the collapse of the North American videogame industry and its subsequent revival by Nintendo. This argument can, however, be critiqued for its implicit focus on the North American and Japanese home console markets and, by extension, for overlooking the many ‘microcomputer’ industries that spearheaded the emergence of videogame development scenes in Europe, South America, and Australasia during this period. Such a critique takes its cue from cultural theory, which has long recognized that narratives of neocolonialism and hegemonic expansion do not adequately account for the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3.</label>
                     <title>Domesticating the arcade:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Neo Geo as an imaginary platform</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>105</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In <italic>The Arcades Project</italic>, Walter Benjamin (1999) chronicles various discourses, objects, and texts from the era in which the Paris arcades of the 1820s thrived. He presents these historical sources as constellated fragments that can be used to reconstruct the ruins of early modernity and identify the wellsprings of consumer capitalism. The arcades are treated as a relic of the moment when technologically propelled modes of industrial engineering fused with new forms of urban planning and architecture to create these burgeoning consumer environments. A key element of Benjamin’s project is to reawaken the media ‘imaginary’ of the 19th century in</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4.</label>
                     <title>A dialectic of obsolescence?</title>
                     <subtitle>The Sega Saturn as a residual platform</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>133</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the introduction to this book, I discussed media archaeology as an approach to historical description that, broadly defined, rejects teleology in favour of a ‘non-linear’ conception of media history. Media archaeology is, however, often shot through with a contradictory desire to make both a ‘poetics’ and ‘fetish’ of obsolesced technologies (cf. Elsaessser, 2016: 47). That is, media archaeology is motivated on the one hand by something of a ‘disinterested’ aesthetic impulse to liberate outmoded technologies from the grip of planned obsolescence (Elsaesser, 2016: 335). Practitioners of media archaeology—be they researchers or artists¹—often seek to ascribe aesthetic value</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5.</label>
                     <title>‘How history arrives’:</title>
                     <subtitle>Twine as a minor platform</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>157</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The question of ‘what counts’ in videogame history should not simply be answered by taking a shovel to the past and digging up marginalized subjects and objects. As Laine Nooney (2013: n.p.) argues, the question of what counts in videogame history should also involve an interrogation of ‘how history arrives’ in the present; how the dominant construction of videogame history gives shape to certain subject positions and ways of knowing or feeling. Nooney (2013: n.p.) asks, ‘[h]ow do spaces, bodies, and objects entangle to produce a historical subject—and why do we presume that this subject is a “gamer”?’. Asking</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Conclusion:</title>
                     <subtitle>‘Something new in the old’</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>191</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In 2015, fourteen years after declaring ‘year one’ for game studies as a specialized area of scholarly research, Espen Aarseth (2015: n.p.) made an equally bold declaration in an editorial for the open-access web journal <italic>Game Studies</italic>: ‘game studies is a success. We did it’. For Aarseth (2015: n.p.), the proof of game studies’ success is in the proverbial pudding: there are, now, numerous international conferences, research centres, and publication venues dedicated to the study of videogames. Furthermore, claims Aarseth, videogames are now ‘accepted’ as a viable area of research in disciplines where they were previously shunned. Meanwhile, orthodox game</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpbnq9j.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>201</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
