

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Law</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>EU GDPR &amp; EU-U.S. Privacy Shield</book-title>
         <subtitle>A pocket guide, second edition</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>CALDER</surname>
               <given-names>ALAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>15</day>
         <month>10</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787780729</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787780736</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <edition>2</edition>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Alan Calder</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvq4c0ft"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;Get a clear understanding of the EU GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) and the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield with this essential pocket guide, which explains:  &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The terms and definitions used within the GDPR and the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield &lt;li&gt;The key requirements of the GDPR &lt;li&gt;How to comply with the Regulation  &lt;p&gt;The GDPR unifies data protection across the EU. It applies to every organization in the world that does business with EU residents.  &lt;p&gt;U.S. organizations can self-certify to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield (the successor to the Safe Harbor framework), which permits international data transfers of EU data to U.S. organizations.  &lt;p&gt;<italic>EU GDPR &amp; EU-U.S. Privacy Shield - A pocket guide, second edition</italic> provides an accessible overview of the Regulation, and sets out the compliance obligations for U.S. organizations when handling EU residents' data, including guidance on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield.  &lt;p&gt;<bold>New for the second edition</bold>:  &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;A more detailed explanation of which organizations are within the scope of the GDPR, who the authorities are, and the possible repercussions for non-compliance &lt;li&gt;Additional requirements for controllers that are subject to lower-tier fines for non-compliance &lt;li&gt;An expanded chapter on the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield  &lt;p&gt;<bold>Buy this pocket guide to get a better understanding of:</bold>  &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The GDPR's origins and scope, and who the key authorities are &lt;li&gt;The key requirements for both controllers and processors &lt;li&gt;What steps to take to achieve GDPR compliance &lt;li&gt;How data can be transferred outside the EU, and the role of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield &lt;li&gt;The principles of the Privacy Shield, and how to register to the framework  &lt;p&gt;<bold>This pocket guide is the ideal resource for anyone wanting a clear, concise primer on the GDPR and EU-U.S. Privacy Shield. Buy your copy today.</bold>  &lt;p&gt;<bold>About the author</bold>  &lt;p&gt;Alan Calder is a leading author on IT governance and information security issues. He is the CEO of GRC International Group plc, the AIM-listed company that owns IT Governance Ltd.  &lt;p&gt;Alan is an acknowledged international cyber security guru. He has been involved in the development of a wide range of information security management training courses that have been accredited by the International Board for IT Governance Qualifications (IBITGQ).  &lt;p&gt;He is a frequent media commentator on information security and IT governance issues, and has contributed articles and expert comment to a wide range of trade, national and online news outlets.  </p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="76"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>2</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>6</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>8</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Over the last decade, cybersecurity has become an increasingly important issue across the European Union (EU) and further afield. While cyber threats cover a wide spectrum of targets, from critical national infrastructure to intellectual property, from trade secrets to financial information, a key area of interest for cyber criminals continues to be personal data (sometimes referred to as personally identifiable information, or PII).</p>
                     <p>Personal data – names, addresses, payment card information, social security or tax identifiers – is valuable because it can open routes to a wide range of crimes, including economic theft and identity crime.</p>
                     <p>The dramatic migration of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>A BRIEF HISTORY OF DATA PROTECTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>10</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The (now) common concept of data protection is actually a very modern notion. When we think of digitally stored databases and records, we understand the importance of protecting them: Digital records do not physically take up space, can be mislaid or stolen without removing the original, and such a loss could represent an enormous amount of information. However, this was not always the case.</p>
                     <p>Possibly the earliest forms of data and privacy protection come from the professions rather than legislation itself. Attorney-client confidentiality (or ‘legal professional privilege’, as the British call it), for instance, is believed to have begun as</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>TERMS AND DEFINITIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Before getting into the meat of the GDPR and how you can comply with it, it is useful to have a set of definitions for common and useful terms. Where the Regulation provides a definition, this is included, as well as any additional commentary where helpful.</p>
                     <p>personal data protection policies which are adhered to by a controller or processor established on the territory of a Member State for transfers or a set of transfers of personal data to a controller or processor in one or more third countries within a group of undertakings, or group of enterprises engaged in a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>APPLICABILITY, AUTHORITIES, AND REPERCUSSIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>24</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Before discussing the GDPR’s specific requirements in greater depth, this chapter will clarify exactly which organizations are within the scope of the Regulation, who the authorities are, and what the repercussions for non-compliance can be.</p>
                     <p>The GDPR applies to organizations within the EU, as well as to any external organizations doing business within the EU. Specifically, it applies to non-EU organizations that:</p>
                     <p>Offer products and/or services to individuals based in the EU</p>
                     <p>Monitor EU residents’ behavior</p>
                     <p>Process EU residents’ personal data</p>
                     <p>This includes organizations potentially everywhere in the world. This extensive reach is likely, however, to keep European organizations from</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>KEY GDPR REQUIREMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>31</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The GDPR is a long document that sets out requirements for organizations and for Member States, and makes provision for the EDPB. This chapter provides an overview of the three key requirements to comply with:</p>
                     <p>1. Adhere to the six data processing principles (Article 5(1) of the GDPR)</p>
                     <p>2. Be able to facilitate data subjects exercising any or all of their rights (Chapter III of the GDPR)</p>
                     <p>3. Put provisions in place for data transfers outside the EU (Chapter V of the GDPR)</p>
                     <p>Article 5 of the GDPR outlines the six principles that should be applied to any activity that involves processing personal</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>EU-U.S. PRIVACY SHIELD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>43</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>As discussed in the previous chapter, the European Commission cannot grant the U.S. an adequacy decision due to its lack of a federal data privacy law, so EU organizations are unable to freely transfer personal data to the U.S. under the GDPR.</p>
                     <p>The EU-U.S. Privacy Shield is a data transfer mechanism that was adopted by the European Commission in July 2016 and became available on August 1, 2016. U.S. organizations attesting that they adhere to the framework’s seven Principles provide sufficient assurances that any EU personal data transferred to them is secure. This qualifies them for certification and trouble-free access</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>OTHER POINTS FOR CONTROLLERS TO CONSIDER</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>51</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Chapter 4 discussed the GDPR’s key requirements – the processing principles, data subjects’ rights, and international transfers – which are all subject to the higher tier of fines. There are, however, more requirements and points that controllers in particular need to consider, which are discussed in this chapter.</p>
                     <p>Where a controller contracts with a data processor, that processor must be able to provide “sufficient guarantees to implement appropriate technical and organisational measures”<sup>40</sup> that personal data processing will comply with the GDPR and ensure data subjects’ rights are protected.</p>
                     <p>This requirement flows down the supply chain, so a processor cannot engage</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7:</label>
                     <title>COMPLYING WITH THE REGULATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>61</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>There are clearly multiple key points to observe in your approach to complying with the GDPR. Some of them will be resolved simply and quickly, usually at the prompting of a third party or your DPO. Others, however, will require a great deal of work or specific expertise. This chapter will discuss those things that are critical to observe and offer advice for staying on the right side of the law.</p>
                     <p>The GDPR deals with existing personal data as well as with how that data is to be processed, transmitted, and stored in future. The first step towards compliance for</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 8:</label>
                     <title>INDEX OF THE GDPR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>66</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX 1:</title>
                     <subtitle>NATIONAL DATA PROTECTION AUTHORITIES</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>71</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX 2:</title>
                     <subtitle>EU GDPR RESOURCES</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>72</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvq4c0ft.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>74</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
