

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.7591/j.ctvqc6k17</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">HG101 .P656 2020</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Efficient market theory</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Economics</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Sociological aspects</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Knowledge, Sociology of</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Finance</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Sociology</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>The Ascent of Market Efficiency</book-title>
         <subtitle>Finance That Cannot Be Proven</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Polillo</surname>
               <given-names>Simone</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>15</day>
         <month>08</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781501750380</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781501750397</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">1501750399</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Cornell University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>ITHACA; LONDON</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Cornell University</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.7591/j.ctvqc6k17"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> The Ascent of Market Efficiency weaves together historical narrative and quantitative bibliometric data to detail the path financial economists took in order to form one of the central theories of financial economics-the influential efficient-market hypothesis-which states that the behavior of financial markets is unpredictable. As the notorious quip goes, a blindfolded monkey would do better than a group of experts in selecting a portfolio of securities, simply by throwing darts at the financial pages of a newspaper. How did such a hypothesis come to be so influential in the field of financial economics? How did financial economists turn a lack of evidence about systematic patterns in the behavior of financial markets into a foundational approach to the study of finance? Each chapter in Simone Polillo's fascinating meld of economics, science, and sociology focuses on these questions, as well as on collaborative academic networks, and on the values and affects that kept the networks together as they struggled to define what the new field of financial economics should be about. In doing so, he introduces a new dimension-data analysis-to our understanding of the ways knowledge advances. There are patterns in the ways knowledge is produced, and The Ascent of Market Efficiency helps us make sense of these patterns by providing a general framework that can be applied equally to other social and human sciences.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="204"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>v</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Data-Method-Theory Triad, or Why Finance Cannot Be Proven</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Over the past half century, in the United States and many other countries, finance has become deeply enmeshed in, and consequential for, everyday life. Virtually ubiquitous and all-powerful, financial markets now play a fundamental role in determining the life chances of individuals, serving as indispensable sources of funding both for everyday necessities, as testified by the expansion of credit card–fueled expenses, and for lifelong savings strategies—witness the proliferation of long-term, heftier investments, from retirement portfolios to car loans and home mortgages.</p>
                     <p>There are many complex reasons behind the rise of financial markets, ranging from the emergence of institutional</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>THE RHETORIC OF MARKET EFFICIENCY:</title>
                     <subtitle>How Data Analysis Became Legitimate</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>29</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In 1977, a professor of finance at the Anderson School (UCLA’s business school), trained at Chicago under the “father of modern finance” Eugene Fama, and himself on his way to becoming a central figure in financial economics, wrote and published a paper that would quickly become a classic. His name was Richard Roll, and the main topic of the paper was asset-pricing theory, a burgeoning research program that strives to develop objective methods to determine how much an asset is worth. He began the paper with a decidedly nontechnical quote: “If the horn honks and the mechanic concludes that the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>COLLABORATIONS AND MARKET EFFICIENCY:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Network of Financial Economics</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>60</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>As Eugene Fama and Stephen Ross—two central figures in financial economics—recalled their first encounter with the new technologies and datasets that would soon become central to the “basic structure of orthodox modern finance theory,” they painted a picture of thrilling excitement and buoyant expectation. To Fama, it felt like being “a kid in a candy store,” an analogy that hints at both the joyful abundance of data now awaiting him (“nuggets of gold,” as Stephen Ross called them) and his own newness to the discipline. Although he possessed unique technical skills for operating the computers, skills that others</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4</label>
                     <title>WINNERS AND LOSERS IN FINANCIAL ECONOMICS, OR FAMA VERSUS BLACK:</title>
                     <subtitle>How Markets Became Efficient and Equilibrium Was Defeated</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>90</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In a 1985 critique of the seemingly unbridgeable chasm between research on finance in <italic>economics</italic> and research on finance in <italic>financial</italic> economics, Larry Summers likened the study of finance to the systematic study of ketchup. In a thought experiment, he invited his readers to imagine a new field, “ketchup economics.” This field would have two groups of researchers: general economists, working in economics departments, and “ketchup economists,” “located in Department of Ketchup where they receive much higher salaries than do general economists.” (As a sociologist, I do not feel much empathy toward the plight of the latter.) He continued: “Each</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>HOW FINANCIAL ECONOMICS GOT ITS SCIENCE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>119</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the beginning, praising the methodological advances achieved by the field seemed like a good idea. Surely, if there was a way forward, it would involve reliance on new techniques, new data, and new analytical approaches—or so argued Fred Weston, then editor of the <italic>Journal of Finance</italic>, the top journal of the field.</p>
                     <p>The emerging problems and issues of finance make it unsatisfactory for us to expect that we can contribute to the improvement of economic and business decisions solely by generalization and judgment. We now have at our command improved techniques for formulating models; we have developed improved</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>CONCLUSION:</title>
                     <subtitle>A Network Sociology of Scholarly Affects</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>143</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Financial economists described markets as efficient on the basis of the alleged unpredictability of price changes over time. They could not test efficiency directly without making further assumptions about how markets work—without a joint hypothesis, that is. How, then, did they come to accept efficiency as a valid representation of market processes when tests of market efficiency inevitably were tests of other processes as well? And more specifically, how did they go about reinventing finance as a science in the process of testing this elusive notion of market efficiency?</p>
                     <p>As we investigated these questions, we met some of the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgments</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>165</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Appendix A</title>
                     <subtitle>APPENDIX TO CHAPTER 2</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>167</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Appendix B</title>
                     <subtitle>METHODOLOGICAL APPENDIX TO CHAPTER 3</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>171</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Notes</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>175</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>References</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>179</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvqc6k17.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>189</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
