

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Mathematics</subject>
         <subject>Sociology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Games for Your Mind</book-title>
         <subtitle>The History and Future of Logic Puzzles</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>ROSENHOUSE</surname>
               <given-names>JASON</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>24</day>
         <month>11</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691174075</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780691200347</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0691200343</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Princeton University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv11hprm2"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lively and engaging look at logic puzzles and their
role in recreation, mathematics, and philosophy&lt;/strong&gt; Logic
puzzles were first introduced to the public by Lewis Carroll in the
late nineteenth century and have been popular ever since. Games
like Sudoku and Mastermind are fun and engrossing recreational
activities, but they also share deep foundations in mathematical
logic and are worthy of serious intellectual inquiry. &lt;em&gt;Games for
Your Mind&lt;/em&gt; explores the history and future of logic puzzles
while enabling you to test your skill against a variety of puzzles
yourself. In this informative and entertaining book, Jason
Rosenhouse begins by introducing readers to logic and logic puzzles
and goes on to reveal the rich history of these puzzles. He shows
how Carroll's puzzles presented Aristotelian logic as a game for
children, yet also informed his scholarly work on logic. He reveals
how another pioneer of logic puzzles, Raymond Smullyan, drew on
classic puzzles about liars and truthtellers to illustrate Kurt
Gödel's theorems and illuminate profound questions in mathematical
logic. Rosenhouse then presents a new vision for the future of
logic puzzles based on nonclassical logic, which is used today in
computer science and automated reasoning to manipulate large and
sometimes contradictory sets of data. Featuring a wealth of sample
puzzles ranging from simple to extremely challenging, this lively
and engaging book brings together many of the most ingenious
puzzles ever devised, including the "Hardest Logic Puzzle Ever,"
metapuzzles, paradoxes, and the logic puzzles in detective
stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>xi</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1</label>
                     <title>Is Logic Boring and Pointless?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>3</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Logic is easy in specific cases, but difficult in general.</p>
                     <p>If I tell you that all cats are mammals and that allmammals are animals, then you conclude that all cats are animals. If another time I tell you that my cat is always asleep at 4 o’clock in the afternoon, and you then notice that it <italic>is</italic> 4 o’clock, then you conclude that my cat is asleep. If instead you see my cat walking around and plainly not asleep, then you conclude that it is not 4 o’clock.</p>
                     <p>That is logic.</p>
                     <p>This is simple. These conclusions are <italic>obvious</italic>. Suppose, though,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2</label>
                     <title>Logic Just for Fun</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>If you ask the average person what he thinks of mathematics, there is a good chance his reply will not be printable. People not only claim to dislike mathematics, they typically do so with pride and gusto. Often, though, the issue is really one of presentation. If you ask someone to find all solutions in positive whole numbers to the system of equations</p>
                     <p>you are in danger of dredging up unpleasant memories from high school algebra class. Instead, suppose you tell him that you have 120 treats to divide among a collection of 50 kittens and puppies, and that each</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3</label>
                     <title>Aristotle’s Syllogistic</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>31</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Lewis Carroll pioneered the field of recreational logic by publishing, in 1886, a short book called <italic>The Game of Logic</italic>. Noticing that logic could be pursued just for fun was no small accomplishment, given the scholarly climate at the time he was writing. The logic of his day was still dominated by the traditional logic of Aristotle and his followers, and this was primarily what was taught to university students. We cannot appreciate Carroll’s work until we have a solid grounding in Aristotelian logic.</p>
                     <p>Aristotle wrote six works related to logic. Today these works are known collectively as the <italic>Organon</italic>.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4</label>
                     <title>The Empuzzlement of Aristotelian Logic</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>50</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We need a word for the process through which flaccid and boring textbook discussions of difficult material are transformed into fun and engaging puzzles. I suggest “empuzzlement” for that purpose. If ever there was a subject in need of empuzzlement, it is Aristotelian logic.</p>
                     <p>As I mentioned at the start of Chapter 3, Lewis Carroll (1832–1898) published a short book called <italic>The Game of Logic</italic> in 1886. In this work, he used Aristotelian logic to devise puzzles intended for young people. Where Aristotle saw a complete and systematic account of the entirety of human reasoning, Carroll saw a game</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5</label>
                     <title>Sorites Puzzles</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>68</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Carroll followed up <italic>The Game of Logic</italic>with a longer work titled <italic>Symbolic Logic</italic>, published in 1896. The contents of this work were heavily influenced by John Venn’s characterization of the <italic>elimination problem</italic> in logic. Venn wrote:</p>
                     <p>[T] he general problem . . . may be stated thus:—‘Given any number of propositions, of any kind, categorical, disjunctive, or otherwise, and involving any number of terms, find the mutual relation to one another, in respect of their a extension, of any selection from amongst all these terms to any other such selection.’ Again, the syllogism is a case of <italic>Elimination</italic> as</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6</label>
                     <title>Carroll’s Contributions to <italic>Mind</italic>
                     </title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>93</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Carroll made two further contributions to logic, in the form of two short papers published in the academic journal <italic>Mind</italic>. This is the sort of journal where scholars publish work addressed to one another, typically assuming considerable background knowledge in their readers. It is telling that even here Carroll published his logical work under his pseudonym, best known from the <italic>Alice</italic> books, which were directed at children. Even as he wanted to make a mark among professional logicians, he also strove for his work to be engaging and accessible.</p>
                     <p>In a discussion of Carroll’s work on logic as a whole,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7</label>
                     <title>Liars and Truthtellers</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>115</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Lewis Carroll empuzzled the central principles of Aristotelian logic, thereby making them accessible to an audience that would find the textbook treatments unintelligible. In so doing, he achieved something of great importance, independent of any debates regarding his contributions to scholarship.</p>
                     <p>Raymond Smullyan achieved something similar for propositional logic, the central principles of which are explained in Section 7.1. His preferred mode of empuzzlement was to imagine an island on which every inhabitant is either a knight or a knave. Knights always tell the truth, while knaves always lie. The two tribes are visually indistinguishable, meaning that the only way</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 8</label>
                     <title>From Aristotle to Russell</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>137</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter, the plot of our story changes dramatically. A major part of Smullyan’s output in recreational logic involved the empuzzlement of central principles in mathematical logic. I would like to tell you about that output, but doing so requires first that we discusswhat mathematical logic actually is. This will be the work of several chapters.</p>
                     <p>You see, Aristotle worked out the basic principles of his logical system in the long-ago of ancient history, roughly the 300s BCE. The principles of propositional logic were worked out not long after that, by Stoic logicians working around 3 BCE (Bonevac and</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 9</label>
                     <title>Formal Systems in Life and Math</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>154</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The brief history of logic in Chapter 8 culminated with Russell and others striving to reduce all of mathematics to a small number of axioms from which everything else could be derived. That this is flatly impossible was shown by Kurt Gödel in 1931. The theorems showing this are nowadays referred to as his first and second incompleteness theorems.</p>
                     <p>Raymond Smullyan was a great authority on the subtleties of Gödel’s theorems, and he devoted much of his popular writings to presenting the underlying ideas in the form of logic puzzles. Some of these puzzles employed his usual device of knights</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 10</label>
                     <title>The Empuzzlement of Gödel’s Theorems</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>164</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Lewis Carroll empuzzled the central principles of Aristotelian logic, thereby making them accessible to an audience that would find the textbook treatments unintelligible. In so doing, he achieved something of great importance, independent of any debates regarding his contributions to scholarly treatments of logic.</p>
                     <p>Raymond Smullyan achieved a similar feat by empuzzling the two great incompleteness theorems of Kurt Gödel. The first theorem states, roughly, that in any formal system that is capable of expressing the basic arithmetic of natural numbers, there must be sentences that are true but unprovable. Gödel proved this in 1931, and it came as a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 11</label>
                     <title>Question Puzzles</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>184</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In his doctoral thesis of 1867, mathematician Georg Cantor wrote: “In mathematics, the art of asking questions is more valuable than solving problems.” In this chapter, we show that in logic, at least sometimes, this maxim remains true. We will consider knight/knave puzzles in which the goal is the formulation of questions so clever that the answers are informative, even if you do not know the types of the people to whom you are speaking. Along the way, we shall develop some general principles for handling such puzzles.</p>
                     <p>Throughout this chapter, we will continue to refer to knights and knaves.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 12</label>
                     <title>Should “Logics” Be a Word?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>201</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Such was Aristotle’s dominance over logic for most of its history that it was hard not to notice a certain triumphalism among his followers. Immanuel Kant expressed a common view when he wrote, in 1787 (comparing the development of logic to the “sure path” traveled by successful sciences):</p>
                     <p>That logic has already, from the earliest times, proceeded upon this sure path is evidenced by the fact that since Aristotle it has not [been] required to retrace a single step. . . . It is remarkable also that to the present day this logic has not been able to advance a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 13</label>
                     <title>Many-Valued Knights and Knaves</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>212</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Nonclassical logic certainly takes some getting used to. As noted in Chapter 12, one of the selling points of classical logic is its naturalness, in the sense that it captures many of our intuitive notions of how logic is supposed to be. Certainly if you go looking for trouble, you can find it in the form of the paradoxes of material implication or the principle of explosion, but those are things only philosophers worry about. The simple fact is that there is no scenario in your daily routine where you will go wrong by applying classical logic, which makes the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 14</label>
                     <title>The Saga of the Hardest Logic Puzzle Ever</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>239</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>TheHardest Logic Puzzle Ever (HLPE) was introduced by George Boolos, then a philosophy professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, in a 1996 paper. The paper was titled “The Hardest Logic Puzzle Ever.” Since then, the puzzle has attracted an impressive academic literature, which we shall survey in this chapter. When we are done, I am sure you will agree that the term “saga” is appropriate.</p>
                     <p>The HLPE is an especially fiendish version of a question puzzle, which we discussed in Chapter 11. Some of the techniques developed in that chapter are about to reappear.</p>
                     <p>Here is George Boolos’s statement</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 15</label>
                     <title>Metapuzzles</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>266</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Logic puzzles are all about determining the deductive consequences of given information. In Lewis Carroll’s puzzles, the given information was presented in the form of humorous categorical propositions. Raymond Smullyan countenanced the more general sorts of propositions uttered by knights and knaves.</p>
                     <p>We could imagine another sort of puzzle, however, in which the given information comes in the form of statements made about what other people were able to infer from information <italic>they</italic> had received. Smullyan referred to such puzzles as “metapuzzles,” by which he meant puzzles that could only be solved by knowing about other puzzles that could or</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.19</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 16</label>
                     <title>Paradoxes</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>274</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>My introduction to paradox came when I was 5 years old. My father asked me, “If you are standing on the Earth, and you want to see the Moon, what do you do?” I replied that you should look up. “Very good,” my father said. “Now, if you are standing on the Moon and you want to see the Earth, what do you do?” Of course, I replied that you should look down. Then my father sprang his trap. He said, “But Jason, if you look down, you will see your feet.”</p>
                     <p>I am older now, and I have the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.20</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 17</label>
                     <title>A Guide to Some Literary Logic Puzzles</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>292</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We have encountered many great logicians to get to this point, but we have somehow omitted the greatest of them all. Of course, I am referring to Mr. Spock.</p>
                     <p>Spock, as he was usually called, was a fictional character on the 1960s science fiction television series <italic>Star Trek</italic>. He hailed from the planet Vulcan, whose residents are trained from a young age to suppress their emotions entirely. For them, only pure logic is important. Vulcans speak in amonotone, never smile or laugh, and calmly assess any situation without fear or anger clouding their judgment.</p>
                     <p>Spock was a capable officer, a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.21</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>GLOSSARY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>311</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.22</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>REFERENCES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>319</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hprm2.23</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>327</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
