

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">j.ctt4zbrx</collection-id>
      <volume>385</volume>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvss3wsw</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Mathematics</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>A Hierarchy of Turing Degrees</book-title>
         <subtitle>A Transfinite Hierarchy of Lowness Notions in the Computably Enumerable Degrees, Unifying Classes, and Natural Definability (AMS-206)</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Downey</surname>
               <given-names>Rod</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Greenberg</surname>
               <given-names>Noam</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>16</day>
         <month>06</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691199665</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780691200217</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0691200211</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Princeton University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvss3wsw"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> Computability theory is a branch of mathematical logic and computer science that has become increasingly relevant in recent years. The field has developed growing connections in diverse areas of mathematics, with applications in topology, group theory, and other subfields. In A Hierarchy of Turing Degrees, Rod Downey and Noam Greenberg introduce a new hierarchy that allows them to classify the combinatorics of constructions from many areas of computability theory, including algorithmic randomness, Turing degrees, effectively closed sets, and effective structure theory. This unifying hierarchy gives rise to new natural definability results for Turing degree classes, demonstrating how dynamic constructions become reflected in definability. Downey and Greenberg present numerous construction techniques involving high-level nonuniform arguments, and their self-contained work is appropriate for graduate students and researchers. Blending traditional and modern research results in computability theory, A Hierarchy of Turing Degrees establishes novel directions in the field.</p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgments</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter One</label>
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>What does it take to perform a certain construction? In computability theory, this question is the basis of a long-term programme which seeks to understand the relationship between dynamic properties of sets and their algorithmic complexity. Our main thesis in this monograph is that where the computably enumerable (c.e.) Turing degrees are concerned, <italic>a degree can compute complicated objects if and only if some functions in the degree are difficult to approximate</italic>. Computability-theoretic tools allow us to quantify precisely what we mean by “difficult to approximate.” More specifically, we use a classification of <tex-math>$\Delta _{2}^{0}$</tex-math> functions defined by Ershov in [39</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter Two</label>
                     <title>α–c.a. functions</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>23</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Ershov ([40], see also [4]) extended the hierarchy of differences of c.e. sets into the transfinite, based on Kleene’s notations for computable ordinals. Unfortunately, the levels of this hierarchy depend heavily on the choice of notation. To get around this problem, based on ideas from [15], we focus on lower levels of the hierarchy, using canonical well-orderings.We then, extending [3], relate these lower, canonical levels, to iterations of a jump in the weak truth-table degrees.</p>
                     <p>We remark that Kleene’s notations suffice for the purposes they were designed for. For example, Spector’s theorem states that the iteration of the Turing jump</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter Three</label>
                     <title>The hierarchy of totally α-c.a. degrees</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>55</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The following is the central definition of this work. For <italic>α</italic> = <italic>ω</italic>, this definition was originally made by J. S. Miller (unpublished), and first investigated in detail in [25].</p>
                     <p>Definition. Let <italic>α</italic> ≤ ε<sub>0</sub>. A Turing degree d is <italic>totally α-c.a</italic>. if every function <italic>f</italic> ∈ d is <italic>α</italic>-c.a.</p>
                     <p>Basic properties of totally <italic>α</italic>-c.a. degrees are shared among totally <italic>R</italic>-c.a. degrees, even when <italic>R</italic> is not canonical. For any computable well-ordering <italic>R</italic>, we say that a Turing degree d is <italic>totally R-c.a</italic>. if every function <italic>f</italic> ∈ d is <italic>R</italic>-c.a. We note the following:</p>
                     <p>Lemma 3.1. <italic>Let R be</italic>
                     </p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter Four</label>
                     <title>Maximal totally α-c.a. degrees</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>84</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>For a collection <italic>F</italic> of c.e. degrees, we say that a degree a ∈ <italic>F</italic> is maximal in <italic>F</italic> if it is maximal as an element of the partial ordering induced on <italic>F</italic> by the ordering on the Turing degrees. In other words, if there is no degree b &gt; a in <italic>F</italic>.</p>
                     <p>Classes of c.e. degrees which contain maximal elements are rare; they are mostly prevented by density considerations. For example, no jump classes contain maximal elements, and there are no maximal cappable degrees. A notable exception is the example of the <italic>contiguous</italic> degrees—those degrees all of whose c.e.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter Five</label>
                     <title>Presentations of left-c.e. reals</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>106</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter we prove Theorem 1.4:</p>
                     <p>(1) If a c.e. degree d is not totally <italic>ω</italic>-c.a. then there is a left-c.e. real <italic>ϱ</italic>C ≤ <sub>T</sub> d and a c.e. set <italic>B</italic> &lt; <sub>T</sub> 
                        <italic>ϱ</italic> such that every presentation of <italic>ϱ</italic>C is <italic>B</italic>-computable.</p>
                     <p>(2) If a left-c.e. real <italic>ϱ</italic>C has a totally <italic>ω</italic>-c.a. degree then there is a presentation of <italic>ϱ</italic>C which is Turing equivalent to C<italic>ϱ</italic>.</p>
                     <p>One of the main ideas of this book is unifying the combinatorics of constructions in various subareas of computability theory. In this chapter we will look at one such subarea: <italic>algorithmic randomness</italic> [27, 69, 74]. Algorithmic</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter Six</label>
                     <title>m-topped degrees</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>134</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It was Post [78] who first pointed out that many reducibilities occurring in practice were stronger than Turing reducibility; indeed most codings of the halting problem into a concrete undecidable problem like the word problem for groups were <italic>m</italic>-reducibilities. For example, for the word problem, for each instance <italic>e</italic>, we could compute a word <italic>w(e)</italic> such that <italic>e</italic> ∈ Øʹ ⇔ <italic>w(e)</italic> = 1<sub>
                           <italic>G</italic>
                        </sub>. The thrust of Post’s problem was whether all instances of undecidable c.e. problems were simply the halting problem in disguise. Myhill characterised the c.e. sets as those that are <italic>m</italic>-reducible to Øʹ. Thus interactions of Turing</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter Seven</label>
                     <title>Embeddings of the 1-3-1 lattice</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>149</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>One of the central and longstanding areas of classical computability theory concerns the structure of the degrees of unsolvability, and particularly the computably enumerable degrees. In the same way that studying symmetries in nature and solutions to equations leads to group theory, studies of the computational content of mathematics lead naturally to the structure of sets of integers under reducibilities. Understanding these structures should lead to insights into relative computability.</p>
                     <p>Notable in these studies is the question of embeddability into the c.e. degrees. We know that the c.e. degrees form an upper semilattice. Sacks [82] showed that this structure is</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter Eight</label>
                     <title>Prompt permissions</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>188</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter we consider prompt versions of the permitting notions we investigated in this monograph. These prompt notions of permission allow us to perform constructions that are closer to the original construction we considered, rather than their variations when adopted for permitting. For example, in the usual embedding of the 1-3-1 lattice one gets the bottom element to be 0. When we then added permitting, we showed that the 1-3-1 lattice can be embedded below any not totally &lt; ω<sup>ω</sup>-c.a. degree, but we did not get an embedding with bottom 0; this seems necessary. However, below any degree which is</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvss3wsw.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Bibliography</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>215</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
