

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv1f8xc7v</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Law</subject>
         <subject>Criminology &amp; Criminal Justice</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>The Ransomware Threat Landscape</book-title>
         <subtitle>Prepare for, recognise and survive ransomware attacks</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>CALDER</surname>
               <given-names>ALAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>18</day>
         <month>02</month>
         <year>2021</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787782785</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787782792</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2021</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Alan Calder</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv1f8xc7v"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fastest-growing malware in the world&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core functionality of ransomware is two-fold: to encrypt
data and deliver the ransom message. This encryption can be
relatively basic or maddeningly complex, and it might affect only a
single device or a whole network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is the fastest-growing malware in the world. In 2015,
it cost companies around the world $325 million, which rose to $5
billion by 2017 and is set to hit $20 billion in 2021. The threat
of ransomware is not going to disappear, and while the number of
ransomware attacks remains steady, the damage they cause is
significantly increasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the duty of all business leaders to protect their
organisations and the data they rely on by doing whatever is
reasonably possible to mitigate the risk posed by ransomware. To do
that, though, they first need to understand the threats they are
facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ransomware Threat Landscape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book sets out clearly how ransomware works, to help
business leaders better understand the strategic risks, and
explores measures that can be put in place to protect the
organisation. These measures are structured so that any
organisation can approach them. Those with more resources and more
complex environments can build them into a comprehensive system to
minimise risks, while smaller organisations can secure their
profiles with simpler, more straightforward implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suitable for senior directors, compliance managers, privacy
managers, privacy officers, IT staff, security analysts and admin
staff - in fact, all staff who use their organisation's
network/online systems to perform their role - &lt;em&gt;The Ransomware
Threat Landscape: Prepare for, recognise and survive ransomware
attacks&lt;/em&gt; will help readers understand the ransomware threat
they face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From basic cyber hygiene to more advanced controls, the book
gives practical guidance on individual activities, introduces
implementation steps organisations can take to increase their cyber
resilience, and explores why cyber security is imperative. Topics
covered include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;About ransomware 

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;An anti-ransomware 

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The control framework&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Risk management&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Controls&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Maturity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Basic controls&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Additional controls for larger organiations&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Advanced controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't delay - start protecting your organis&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ation from ransomware and buy this book today!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the author&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Calder is the Group CEO of GRC International Group plc, the
AIM-listed company that owns IT Governance Ltd. Alan is an
acknowledged international cyber security guru, and a
leading author on information security and IT governance issues. He
has been involved in the development of a wide range of information
security management training courses that have been accredited by
IBITGQ (International Board for IT Governance Qualifications).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan has consulted for clients across the globe and is a regular
media commentator and speaker. &lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="85"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>6</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In May 2017, someone in the UK’s National Health Service clicked a link in an email. Within hours, hospitals, surgeries and offices across the country were being shut out of their own systems, causing delays to critical healthcare. For several days, the NHS was paradoxically in a state of both paralysis and upheaval: crucial health information couldn’t be accessed, appointments couldn’t be made or checked, and patients were left waiting; meanwhile, IT teams scrambled to contain the outbreak and searched for a solution.</p>
                     <p>WannaCry, the ransomware to blame, went far beyond the NHS: it affected around a quarter of a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>ABOUT RANSOMWARE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In general, there are three types of ransomware:</p>
                     <p>1. Scareware</p>
                     <p>2. Screen lockers</p>
                     <p>3. Encrypting ransomware</p>
                     <p>Before we go further, I should note that this book is primarily interested in ‘encrypting ransomware’.</p>
                     <p>Scareware is typically little more than malicious advertising. The user might see a pop-up advising that malware has been detected and instructing them to visit a website or make a payment to have the malware removed. This can be served on a website (in which case it’s likely you’re not infected at all and it’s just an obnoxious pop-up) or from a malware infection on your device. In most cases, this</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>BASIC MEASURES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>27</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>While this book sets out a programme that any organisation can implement to help protect itself from ransomware, there’s a lot of crossover with the sort of measures you might put in place to protect yourself from cyber threats more generally. These should be in place in any organisation and form a strong foundation that can later be developed into something more comprehensive and mature.</p>
                     <p>The following measures will be built on in later chapters, so any organisation interested in an incremental approach can work up from first principles in an organic way.</p>
                     <p>Cyber hygiene is about securing the organisation</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>AN ANTI-RANSOMWARE PROGRAMME</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>37</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The first step beyond having simple measures in place should be to make your efforts systematic. The programme we describe in this book is fundamentally a set of controls to reduce the risks posed by ransomware, but it should be implemented as part of a larger structure to ensure that these controls are subject to review and revision on an ongoing basis.</p>
                     <p>The first part of this will be to ensure there is a single person responsible for the project who has direct access to the top of the organisation. As the programme needs to cover potentially a great deal</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>BASIC CONTROLS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>53</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>These controls have been selected as suitable for SMEs and can be implemented in every organisation at relatively little cost or effort. While they may not all be necessary for every SME, they can protect an organisation as it grows and should be considered best practice.</p>
                     <p>Larger organisations likely already have many of these in place, but should verify that they are and that they are appropriate to the organisation’s size and operations.</p>
                     <p>Because phishing is one of the most common ways for malware to enter the organisation, all staff should be trained to identify it and understand what they</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>ADDITIONAL CONTROLS FOR LARGER ORGANISATIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>65</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The following controls are suited to larger organisations as additional measures on top of those set out in the previous chapter. In many cases, they build on capabilities that should already exist or are developed in the earlier controls.</p>
                     <p>Phishing training is all well and good, but if you decide that the measure of success is that the organisation has staved off ransomware attacks, you’re running the very real risk that the training hasn’t been effective. It’s also worth remembering that a ransomware attack may only need one person to slip up.</p>
                     <p>A low-risk way of assessing the effectiveness of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>ADVANCED CONTROLS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The following controls extend those set out previously to provide a more advanced, mature anti-ransomware capability. They can be selected on the basis of need, to develop stronger defences or to protect particularly vulnerable or valuable systems and information.</p>
                     <p>Incident response is critical for any organisation under attack, but developing the skills relevant for dealing with ransomware can be difficult or prohibitively expensive for smaller organisations. In many cases, this role is best filled by third parties, the cost of which might be covered by insurance.</p>
                     <p>In addition to the basics of response that should be delivered in staff training</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1f8xc7v.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>83</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
