

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvdtphcs</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">QA268. N54 2009</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Coding theory</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Cryptography</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Geometry, Algebraic</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Mathematics</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Algebraic Geometry in Coding Theory and Cryptography</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>NIEDERREITER</surname>
               <given-names>HARALD</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>XING</surname>
               <given-names>CHAOPING</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>21</day>
         <month>09</month>
         <year>2009</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691102887</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781400831302</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">140083130X</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2009</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Princeton University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvdtphcs"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;This textbook equips graduate students and advanced undergraduates with the necessary theoretical tools for applying algebraic geometry to information theory, and it covers primary applications in coding theory and cryptography. Harald Niederreiter and Chaoping Xing provide the first detailed discussion of the interplay between nonsingular projective curves and algebraic function fields over finite fields. This interplay is fundamental to research in the field today, yet until now no other textbook has featured complete proofs of it. Niederreiter and Xing cover classical applications like algebraic-geometry codes and elliptic-curve cryptosystems as well as material not treated by other books, including function-field codes, digital nets, code-based public-key cryptosystems, and frameproof codes. Combining a systematic development of theory with a broad selection of real-world applications, this is the most comprehensive yet accessible introduction to the field available.  &lt;p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Introduces graduate students and advanced undergraduates to the foundations of algebraic geometry for applications to information theory &lt;li&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Provides the first detailed discussion of the interplay between projective curves and algebraic function fields over finite fields &lt;li&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Includes applications to coding theory and cryptography &lt;li&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Covers the latest advances in algebraic-geometry codes &lt;li&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Features applications to cryptography not treated in other books &lt;li&gt;        </p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Preface</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Niederreiter</surname>
                           <given-names>Harald</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Xing</surname>
                           <given-names>Chaoping</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>Finite Fields and Function Fields</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the first part of this chapter, we describe the basic results on finite fields, which are our ground fields in the later chapters on applications. The second part is devoted to the study of function fields.</p>
                     <p>Section 1.1 presents some fundamental results on finite fields, such as the existence and uniqueness of finite fields and the fact that the multiplicative group of a finite field is cyclic. The algebraic closure of a finite field and its Galois group are discussed in Section 1.2. In Section 1.3, we study conjugates of an element and roots of irreducible polynomials and determine</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>Algebraic Varieties</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>30</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter is devoted to the fundamentals of algebraic geometry. After some preliminaries in Sections 2.1 and 2.2, we introduce in Section 2.3 the basic concept of an algebraic variety. According to a rough definition, an algebraic variety (or a variety in short) consists of the solutions of a system of (in general multivariate) polynomial equations over an algebraically closed field, and in addition a variety must satisfy a certain indecomposability condition. There are affine and projective varieties, depending on whether we work in an affine or a projective space. The discussion of function fields of varieties in Section 2.4</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>Algebraic Curves</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>68</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Algebraic curves, that is, algebraic varieties of dimension 1, are crucial for the applications that will be discussed in Chapters 5 and 6. In the present chapter, we emphasize the interplay between algebraic curves and function fields, which has become a powerful tool in both the theory and the applications.</p>
                     <p>The important family of nonsingular or smooth curves is introduced in Section 3.1. For nonsingular projective curves we establish a link between points of the curve and valuations of the corresponding function field. This link is strengthened in Section 3.2 where it is shown that nonsingular projective curves and algebraic</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4</label>
                     <title>Rational Places</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>105</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Many applications of algebraic curves over a finite field Fq utilize the Fq -rational points of these curves. Thus, it is of great interest to study these points. Since we are adopting the equivalent viewpoint of global function fields, we consider instead rational places of global function fields, that is, places of degree 1. A major result on rational places is the Hasse-Weil bound on the number of rational places of a global function field. This bound is derived in Section 4.2 from the equally important Hasse-Weil theorem on zeta functions of global function fields. Preliminaries on zeta functions and</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>Applications to Coding Theory</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>147</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>A code is a scheme for detecting and correcting transmission errors that can occur in noisy communication channels. A code operates by adding redundant information to messages. One of the main aims of coding theory is the construction of efficient codes, that is, of codes that achieve a prescribed error-correction capability with a minimum amount of redundancy. Algebraic curves over finite fields, or equivalently global function fields, play an important role in coding theory, as we will demonstrate in this chapter.</p>
                     <p>We start this chapter by recalling some basic facts from coding theory in Section 5.1. A core part of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>Applications to Cryptography</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>206</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Cryptography is concerned with the design of schemes that aim to resolve security issues such as the confidentiality, authenticity, and integrity of sensitive data. Cryptography has become a major research area, which is driven by the demands of modern information and communication technology. This chapter is not meant to survey this large area, but presents instead a sample of cryptographic constructions in which algebraic curves over finite fields, or equivalently global function fields, are involved. For systematic treatments of cryptography, we refer to the encyclopedic handbook by Menezes, van Oorschot, and Vanstone [80] and to the textbooks of Buchmann [12],</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>A</label>
                     <title>Appendix</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>241</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Bibliography</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>249</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvdtphcs.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>257</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
