

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv17f12nv</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Law</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>EU GDPR – An international guide to compliance</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>CALDER</surname>
               <given-names>ALAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>15</day>
         <month>10</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787782525</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787782532</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Alan Calder</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv17f12nv"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;strong&gt;A clear, concise primer on the GDPR&lt;/strong&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The GDPR aims to unify data protection and ease the flow of
personal data across the EU. It applies to every organisation in
the world that handles EU residents' personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the GDPR is not law in countries outside the EU, it is
effectively part of the legislative environment for organisations
that do business with the EU. This is enforced through a
combination of international trade law and business pressure -
after all, a partner in the EU is unlikely to want to risk engaging
with a company in the US, Australia or Singapore (or anywhere else)
that will put them at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EU GDPR - An international guide to compliance&lt;/em&gt; is the
ideal resource for anyone wanting a clear primer on the principles
of data protection and their obligations under the GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A concise pocket guide, it will help you understand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The terms and definitions used in the GDPR, including
explanations;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The key requirements of the GDPR, including:&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which fines apply to which Articles;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The principles that should be applied to any collection and
processing of personal data;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Regulation's applicability;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Data subjects' rights;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Data protection impact assessments;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The data protection officer role and whether you need one;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Data breaches, and notifying supervisory authorities and data
subjects; and&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Obligations for international data transfers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to comply with the Regulation, including:&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding your data, and where and how it is used (e.g.
Cloud suppliers, physical records);&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The documentation you must maintain (such as statements of the
information you collect and process, records of data subject
consent, processes for protecting personal data); and&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The "appropriate technical and organisational measures" you
need to take to ensure compliance with the Regulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A full index of the Regulation, enabling you to find relevant
Articles quickly and easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplemental material&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most of the EU GDPR's requirements are broadly unchanged
in the UK GDPR, the context is quite different and will have
knock-on effects. You may need to update contracts regarding EU-UK
data transfers, incorporate standard contractual clauses into
existing agreements, and update your policies, processes and
procedural documentation as a result of these changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have published a s upplement that sets out specific extra or
amended information for this pocket guide. Click here to download
the supplement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;About the author&lt;/strong&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Alan Calder is the Group CEO of GRC International Group plc, the
AIM-listed company that owns IT Governance Ltd. He is an
internationally acknowledged cyber security expert, and a leading
author on information security and IT governance issues. He
co-wrote the definitive compliance guide &lt;em&gt;IT Governance: An
International Guide to Data Security and ISO27001/ISO27002&lt;/em&gt;,
which is the basis for the Open University's postgraduate course on
information security, and has been involved in the development of a
wide range of information security management training courses that
have been accredited by IBITGQ (International Board for IT
Governance Qualifications). Alan has consulted on data security for
numerous clients in the UK and abroad, and is a regular media
commentator and speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="77"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>2</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>6</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Few companies are in favour of further regulation, but it is generally recognised that it has a role to play in keeping industries honest and protecting the populace at large. There is also a lot of opposition to particularly strong regulation, so more heavy-handed laws are often developed incrementally, which conveniently reduces the outcry at any given stage. It’s quite rare for a particularly strong regulation to come about all at once: the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is one such beast, however.</p>
                     <p>It’s not that the GDPR is unnecessary, nor that any individual requirement is particularly egregious;</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>A BRIEF HISTORY OF DATA PROTECTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The common conception of data protection is a very modern notion. We think of digitally stored databases and records, and we understand the importance of protecting them. It’s obvious: digital records have no physical weight and can be mislaid or stolen without removing the original, and it’s easy to comprehend that such a loss could represent an enormous amount of information. This isn’t the way it’s always been, though, and even today information in other formats needs to be protected.</p>
                     <p>Possibly the earliest forms of data and privacy protection come from the professions rather than legislation itself. For instance, lawyer-client</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>TERMS AND DEFINITIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Before getting into the meat of the Regulation and how you can comply with it, it’s useful to have a set of definitions for common and useful terms. Where the Regulation provides a definition, this is included, and any additional commentary has been added where useful. Terms are presented in alphabetical order.</p>
                     <p>personal data protection policies which are adhered to by a controller or processor established on the territory of a Member State for transfers or a set of transfers of personal data to a controller or processor in one or more third countries within a group of undertakings, or</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>THE REGULATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>26</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The GDPR was adopted by the EU Council and Parliament in April 2016, and took effect in every EU Member State in May 2018. The GDPR is a long document, setting out requirements for organisations and for Member States, and making provision for an EU Data Protection Board. This chapter aims to provide a quick overview of the key points you need to be aware of to comply.</p>
                     <p>The full text of the GDPR can be found on the EUR-Lex database (https://eur-lex.europa.eu/) in every language of the European Union.<sup>23</sup>
                     </p>
                     <p>Organisations based outside the EU should also look for guidance on</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>COMPLYING WITH THE REGULATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>58</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>There are clearly a number of key points to observe in your approach to complying with the GDPR. Plenty of them will be resolved fairly simply and quickly, if only at the prompting of a third party or a DPO. Some, however, will require a great deal of work or specific expertise. This section of the book will discuss those things that are critical to observe and offer advice for staying on the right side of the law.</p>
                     <p>It’s been mentioned several times already, but it’s worth reiterating that the GDPR can levy considerable fines. For certain breaches of the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>INDEX OF THE REGULATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>67</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>EU GDPR RESOURCES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12nv.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>76</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
