

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv17f12mb</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>The Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification (CMMC) – A pocket guide</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>GAMBLE</surname>
               <given-names>WILLIAM</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>10</day>
         <month>11</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787782440</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787782457</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>William Gamble</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv17f12mb"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;p&gt;The United States DoD (Department of Defense) is one of the
largest employers in the world, with about 2.87 million employees.
It spends more than a year among more than 350,000 contractors and
subcontractors throughout its supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information in the DoD network is shared digitally across the
contractor and subcontractor supply chain, offering an irresistible
target for nation-states and cyber criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protecting the DoD supply chain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CMMC was developed to step up measures for protecting the
DoD supply chain. Its objectives are to standardize cybersecurity
controls and ensure that effective measures are in place to protect
CUI (Controlled Unclassified Information) on contractor systems and
networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All companies doing business with the DoD, including
subcontractors, must become certified by an independent third-party
commercial certification organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your essential guide to understanding the
CMMC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you get to grips with the CMMC, this essential pocket
guide covers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What the CMMC is and why it has been introduced&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Who needs to comply with the CMMC&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The implementation process&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The road to certification&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;CMMC implications for firms doing business with the US
government&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suitable for senior management and the C-suite, general or legal
counsel, IT executives, IT organizations, and IT and security
students, this pocket guide will give you a solid introduction to
the CMMC and its requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the author&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William Gamble is an international cybersecurity and privacy
compliance expert. He is one of the few lawyers to hold advanced
cybersecurity professional qualifications, and has an in-depth
understanding of the design, management, and deployment of
technology within the ISO 27001 framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more than 30 years' experience of international regulatory
practice in the U.S., EU, China, and other countries, William has
had hundreds of articles published globally, written three books,
and appeared on numerous radio and television programs around the
world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William is a member of the Florida Bar and several federal
courts. His qualifications include Juris Doctor (JD), Master of
Laws (LLM), CompTIA® A+, Network+, Security+, CASP (Advanced
Security Practitioner), ISO 27001 Lead Auditor and Lead
Implementer, and GDPR Practitioner (GDPR P).&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="75"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>2</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>6</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>AN INTRODUCTION TO THE US DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE DIGITAL SUPPLY CHAIN</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The US Department of Defense (DoD) is one of the largest employers in the world. It employs about 2.87 million people,¹ and has a base budget of $671 billion, and a $69 billion budget for overseas contingency operations for the 2021 fiscal year.² It also engages about 350,000 contractors.</p>
                     <p>These contractors represent the Department’s supply chain. They also present a security risk – a problem familiar to many businesses. Supply chains need to be managed to be efficient, economical and effective. One objective is to avoid single points of failure, because like a regular chain, a supply chain is only</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>TERMS AND DEFINITIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>14</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The following highlighted terms and definitions are cited from resources provided in the footnotes. Not all of them are discussed in this pocket guide, but you may come across any or all of these terms when dealing with the DoD, therefore this chapter serves as a guide to navigate some of the most common acronyms you may encounter on your CMMC implementation journey.</p>
                     <p>The CMMC Accreditation Body is authorized by the US Department of Defense to be the sole authoritative source for the operationalization of CMMC Assessments and Training with the DOD contractor community, or other communities that may adopt</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>WHO NEEDS TO COMPLY WITH THE CMMC?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>19</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The CMMC was developed for all government contractors (herein after Organizations Seeking Certification or OSCs) that process federal contract information (FCI) and CUI. It applies to both primary contractors and subcontractors, who will have until the US 2026 fiscal year to demonstrate CMMC compliance.</p>
                     <p>The first ten Requests for Information (RFIs) that include CMMC requirements were scheduled to appear at the end of July/early August 2020. The Requests for Proposals (RFPs) will follow in early 2021 and the first contract awards are expected to follow shortly after.<sup>23</sup> The program will eventually expand to all DoD procurement and it is expected</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>CMMC IMPLEMENTATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>26</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The whole point of the CMMC process goes back to the original requirement of DFARS 52.204-7012 – to provide ‘adequate security’.</p>
                     <p>But what is adequate security? In the past the legislation would have created a set of controls as adequate security. This has changed. This test of adequate security is now known as the risk-based standard and is in line with most modern cybersecurity legislation around the world. It is similar to the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Article 32, which requires anyone who processes the information of EU residents to “implement appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>THE ROAD TO CERTIFICATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>65</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Even the most cursory perusal of the 17 domains makes it obvious that implementing the controls is a long, involved process. Therefore, while the implementation of a NIST framework to protect CUI will undoubtedly increase cybersecurity manyfold for any organization, it should only be undertaken as a business decision. If the organization can exist and prosper only by fulfilling DoD contracts, then it should start the implementation process. It should be noted that this framework may be expanded to all government contracts that concern CUI. Since there are 70 CUI categories, the number of contracts where the implementation of these</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>CMMC IMPLICATIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>72</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv17f12mb.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
