

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">QA76.9.I52 S393 2021</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Information visualization</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Visual analytics</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Cultural Studies</subject>
         <subject>Business</subject>
         <subject>Library Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Better Data Visualizations</book-title>
         <subtitle>A Guide for Scholars, Researchers, and Wonks</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Schwabish</surname>
               <given-names>Jonathan</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>09</day>
         <month>02</month>
         <year>2021</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780231193108</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780231550154</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0231550154</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Columbia University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>NEW YORK</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2021</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Columbia University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.7312/schw19310"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>Now more than ever, content must be visual if it is to travel far. Readers everywhere are overwhelmed with a flow of data, news, and text. Visuals can cut through the noise and make it easier for readers to recognize and recall information. Yet many researchers were never taught how to present their work visually. This book details essential strategies to create more effective data visualizations. Jonathan Schwabish walks readers through the steps of creating better graphs and how to move beyond simple line, bar, and pie charts. Through more than five hundred examples, he demonstrates the do's and don'ts of data visualization, the principles of visual perception, and how to make subjective style decisions around a chart's design. Schwabish surveys more than eighty visualization types, from histograms to horizon charts, ridgeline plots to choropleth maps, and explains how each has its place in the visual toolkit. It might seem intimidating, but everyone can learn how to create compelling, effective data visualizations. This book will guide you as you define your audience and goals, choose the graph that best fits for your data, and clearly communicate your message.</p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Raise your hand if your approach to creating a graph goes something like this: You analyze some data. Write up the results. Make a graph and drop it into the report, surrounded by text. Label it something benign like “Figure 1. Average Earnings, 1990–2020.” Save it as a PDF. Post it to the world.</p>
                     <p>It might have taken you months or even years to compile and analyze the data and write the report. For many, it takes far less time to design the graphs that showcase that data. You might open a program like Microsoft Excel, paste in the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>VISUAL PROCESSING AND PERCEPTUAL RANKINGS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>13</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Before we start creating our charts and graphs, we need to cover some basic theory of how the brain perceives visual stimuli. This will guide you as you decide what chart type is most appropriate to visualize your data.</p>
                     <p>When we consider how to visualize our data, we must ask ourselves how accurately the reader can perceive the data values. Are some graphs better equipped to guide the reader to the specific difference between, say, 2 percent and 2.3 percent? If so, how should we think about those differences as we create our visualizations?</p>
                     <p>There’s a thread of research in</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>FIVE GUIDELINES FOR BETTER DATA VISUALIZATIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>29</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Whenever I create a data visualization, whether it’s static, interactive, or part of a report or blog post or even a tweet, I follow five primary guidelines.</p>
                     <p>1. Show the data</p>
                     <p>2. Reduce the clutter</p>
                     <p>3. Integrate the graphics and text</p>
                     <p>4. Avoid the spaghetti chart</p>
                     <p>5. Start with gray</p>
                     <p>Showing the data and reducing the clutter means reducing extraneous gridlines, markers, and shades that obscure the actual data. Active titles, better labels, and helpful annotations will integrate your chart with the text around it. When charts are dense with many data series, you can use color strategically to highlight series of interest or break</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>FORM AND FUNCTION:</title>
                     <subtitle>LET YOUR AUDIENCE’S NEEDS DRIVE YOUR DATA VISUALIZATION CHOICES</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>53</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The primary focus of this book is on static data visualizations. That is, those visualizations that are not interactive and do not move. But interactive and animated visualizations are becoming more common even in academic fields, and the tools to make interactive visuals are, year by year, becoming easier to use, cheaper (even free), and more powerful.</p>
                     <p>Aside from the standard design decisions about color, layout, and font that apply to static visualizations, there is another set for interactive visualizations. Where will the button go? What will it look like? How will the user be guided to different parts of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4</label>
                     <title>COMPARING CATEGORIES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>67</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The graphs in this chapter are intended to help our readers compare values across categories. Bars, lines, and dots can all let our readers compare within and between groups. In some cases, we want our reader to see both levels <italic>and</italic> change, or some other variable combination; in other cases, we want to focus their attention on one comparison or another.</p>
                     <p>The challenge when comparing categorical data is deciding what we want the chart to convey. Is there a primary argument or story? Is there something you can identify as the most important comparison you want the reader to make?</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>TIME</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>133</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The graphs in this chapter show changes over time. Your readers will most likely be familiar with visuals like line, area, and stacked area charts. But others, like connected scatterplots and cycle charts, may need more labeling and annotation for the reader to navigate them successfully.</p>
                     <p>Many of the visuals in this chapter are variations on the line or area chart. Some let us include more data on the page than usual, while others allow us to combine changes over time with some other view of the data. With horizon charts and streamgraphs, for example, we can include more data</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>DISTRIBUTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>179</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter covers visualizations of data distributions and statistical uncertainties. These may be inherently difficult for many readers because they may not be as familiar with the statistical terminology or the graphs themselves, which may look quite different from the standard graphs they are used to seeing.</p>
                     <p>Charts like the fan chart and the box-and-whisker plot show statistical measures like confidence intervals and percentiles. Violin plots, which depict entire distributions, may look so foreign that your reader will need detailed explanations to understand them. This doesn’t mean that these charts are inherently <italic>bad</italic> at visualizing data—proper labeling and design</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7</label>
                     <title>GEOSPATIAL</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>217</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>There is an obvious advantage to plotting geographic data on a map—people can find themselves in the data. They can literally <italic>see</italic> themselves in the data, a connection with the subject matter that other visualizations cannot muster. Plotting geographic data may mean adding color to geographic areas likes states or countries, or adding circles, squares, lines, or other shapes on top of a geographic map.</p>
                     <p>Data-driven maps are not new. In 1922, the “Maps and Sales Visualization” on the next page shows the reader thirty-six different ways to place data on a map. The author writes:</p>
                     <p>The use of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>8</label>
                     <title>RELATIONSHIP</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>249</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The charts in this chapter show relationships and correlations between two or more variables. Perhaps the most familiar chart type in this class is the scatterplot, a chart in which the data are encoded to a single horizontal and vertical axis. Other shapes and objects can also be used to visualize the relationship between two or more variables—a parallel coordinates plot uses lines, while a chord diagram uses arcs within a circle. These charts can show the reader correlations and even causal relationships.</p>
                     <p>For this chapter, I use the color palette and font from a famous bubble chart created</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>9</label>
                     <title>PART-TO-WHOLE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>289</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This class of charts shows how the shares of some amount relate to the total. The most popular and familiar graph in this class is the pie chart, which introduces a variety of perceptual challenges, as we’ll see. Other charts in this class like the treemap and sunburst have different perceptual issues and, as always, we must ask ourselves whether we must show <italic>all</italic> of the components and how they sum to the total. Graphs in this chapter can also be used to visualize hierarchical data—data that can be grouped into layers where natural groups exist—which we have</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>10</label>
                     <title>QUALITATIVE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>311</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Until now, we’ve explored charts that mostly communicate quantitative data. But there are also graphs that communicate <italic>qualitative</italic> data, non-numerical information collected through means of observations, interviews, focus groups, surveys, and other methods. The charts in this chapter primarily communicate words and phrases.</p>
                     <p>We can build narratives and tell stories around qualitative results in ways that can be more difficult with quantitative data. Downloading a big data set, running regressions, and creating tables may provide more generalizable results, but readers don’t connect to them the way they connect to a story. Qualitative data can help tell those stories.</p>
                     <p>As with</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>11</label>
                     <title>TABLES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>327</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Yes, tables are a form of data visualization. If you want to show the exact amount of every value in your data, a table might be your best solution. They are not the best solution if you want to show a lot of data or if you want to show the data in a compact space—but still, a well-designed table can help your reader find specific numbers and discover patterns and outliers.</p>
                     <p>As we’ve seen with other graphs, gridlines, tick marks, and other clutter can crowd a visualization and obscure takeaways. Tables are especially susceptible to clutter. The same</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>12</label>
                     <title>DEVELOPING A DATA VISUALIZATION STYLE GUIDE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>349</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>A data visualization style guide does for graphs what the <italic>Chicago Manual of Style</italic> does for English grammar. It defines the components of a graph and their proper, consistent use. Like a writing style guide, a comprehensive data visualization style guide breaks down the parts of graphs, charts, and tables to demonstrate best practices and strategies to design and style your charts. Elements like font and color, the widths of lines and style gridlines, and the use of tick marks are all choices that determine whether a graph is clear, engaging, and consistent—or whether it isn’t.</p>
                     <p>The difference between</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>13</label>
                     <title>REDESIGNS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>369</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>By this chapter, your data visualization toolbox contains much more than it did when you began this book. We’ve seen dozens of graphs, many of which may have been new to you. As you develop your own eye for data visualization, you’ll find places where these new graph types may be especially useful.</p>
                     <p>In this chapter, we’ll cover a handful of data visualization redesigns. The graphs I choose to redesign here are not all especially <italic>bad</italic> graphs. Some are simply chosen because I believe there are more effective ways to plot the data. My goal is not to criticize these</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>CONCLUSION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>391</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Now, at the end of this book, your data visualization toolbox has expanded considerably. Instead of using whatever the default graphs are available in your favorite software tool, you can now draw upon more examples to visualize your data in the ways that best serve your reader, user, and audience.</p>
                     <p>The graphs presented in these chapters have been tested over and over again. Analysts, researchers, reporters, and scholars have used them with different data sets and layers of text, annotation, color, font, purpose, and platform. But the set of graphs available to you is infinite. The bar chart did not</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX 1:</title>
                     <subtitle>DATA VISUALIZATION TOOLS</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>397</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.19</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX 2:</title>
                     <subtitle>FURTHER READING AND RESOURCES</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>403</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.20</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>409</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.21</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>REFERENCES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>413</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/schw19310.22</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>431</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
