

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Law</subject>
         <subject>Criminology &amp; Criminal Justice</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>The Cyber Security Handbook</book-title>
         <subtitle>Prepare for, respond to and recover from cyber attacks with the IT Governance Cyber Resilience Framework (CRF)</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>CALDER</surname>
               <given-names>ALAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>10</day>
         <month>12</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787782600</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787782617</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Alan Calder</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv19shhms"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;p&gt;In the world as we know it, you can be attacked both physically
and virtually. For today's organisations, which rely so heavily on
technology - particularly the Internet - to do business, the latter
is the far more threatening of the two. The cyber threat landscape
is complex and constantly changing. For every vulnerability fixed,
another pops up, ripe for exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is a comprehensive cyber security implementation
manual which gives practical guidance on the individual activities
identified in the IT Governance Cyber Resilience Framework (CRF)
that can help organisations become cyber resilient and combat the
cyber threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suitable for senior directors (CEO, CISO, CIO), compliance
managers, privacy managers, IT managers, security analysts and
others, the book is divided into six parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1: Introduction.&lt;/strong&gt; The world of cyber
security and the approach taken in this book. &lt;strong&gt;Part
2:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Threats and vulnerabilities.&lt;/strong&gt; A
discussion of a range of threats organisations face, organised by
threat category, to help you understand what you are defending
yourself against before you start thinking about your actual
defences. &lt;strong&gt;Part 3:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The CRF
processes.&lt;/strong&gt; Detailed discussions of each of the 24 CRF
processes, explaining a wide range of security areas by process
category and offering guidance on how to implement each.
&lt;strong&gt;Part 4: Eight steps to implementing cyber
security.&lt;/strong&gt; Our eight-step approach to implementing the
cyber security processes you need and maintaining them.
&lt;strong&gt;Part 5:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Reference frameworks.&lt;/strong&gt; An
explanation of how standards and frameworks work, along with their
benefits. It also presents ten framework options, introducing you
to some of the best-known standards and giving you an idea of the
range available. &lt;strong&gt;Part 6:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Conclusion and
appendices.&lt;/strong&gt; The appendices include a glossary of all the
acronyms and abbreviations used in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are just starting out on the road to cyber security
or looking to enhance and improve your existing cyber resilience
programme, it should be clear that cyber security is no longer
optional in today's information age; it is an essential component
of business success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you understand the threats and vulnerabilities
your organisation faces and how the Cyber Resilience Framework can
help you tackle them. Start your journey to cyber security now -
buy this book today!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="361"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>2</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>6</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>THE THREAT LANDSCAPE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>11</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We live in a world where technology and vast quantities of data play a considerable role in everyday life, personal and professional. For the foreseeable future (and perhaps beyond), their growth and prominence are showing no signs of slowing down, even if the technology in question will likely change in ways perhaps unimaginable today. Naturally, all this innovation brings huge opportunities and benefits to companies and individuals alike. However, these come at more than just a financial cost.</p>
                     <p>In the world as we know it, you can be attacked both physically and virtually. For today’s organisations, which rely so heavily</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>INFORMATION AND CYBER SECURITY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The terms ‘information security’ and ‘cyber security’ are often used interchangeably, when in fact they refer to different (albeit related) things.</p>
                     <p>To start with the similarities, both information and cyber security are concerned with security on three fronts:</p>
                     <p>1. Confidentiality:</p>
                     <p>Information assets and systems should only be accessible to those who need access.</p>
                     <p>2. Integrity:</p>
                     <p>Information assets and systems should be protected from unauthorised modification, destruction and loss.</p>
                     <p>3. Availability:</p>
                     <p>Information assets and systems should be accessible to authorised persons as and when necessary.</p>
                     <p>Considering all three aspects of security (also referred to as ‘CIA’) means that you will not make the common</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>CYBER RESILIENCE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>17</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Unfortunately, even the most secure organisation can still fall victim to a cyber attack. To a large extent, it is simply a case of having the odds stacked against you: although you need to protect <italic>all</italic> your assets from <italic>all</italic> types of threat, an attacker requires only <italic>one</italic> weakness to get into your systems. On top of that, any security measure you put in place is only designed to stop a handful of threats – at most. That means that it is likely to be inherently ineffective against other kinds of threat.</p>
                     <p>It is important both to recognise these challenges</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>REGULATORY AND CONTRACTUAL REQUIREMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>19</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>If the fact that your organisation needs to wade through a complex cyber threat landscape in order to compete in today’s digital world is in itself not a strong enough case to invest in cyber security and resilience, the added pressure from a global regulatory system that is beginning to catch up might be.</p>
                     <p>The introduction of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in 2016 – which was enforced two years later – marked a major milestone for data protection and privacy laws across the world. Most of us remember the flood of ‘we need your consent’ emails that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>IMPLEMENTING CYBER SECURITY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>23</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Although chapter 1 mentioned that cyber security need not be expensive, and that your implementation does not need to take a long time, it can still be difficult to know where to start.</p>
                     <p>In truth, there are many different and valid ways of implementing cyber security. The correct one for your organisation depends on your goals and requirements, so a good place to start is by clearly defining what they are. Our eight-step approach to implementing cyber security, laid out in part 4 of this book, will discuss in more detail how you might do this. For now, think about</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>THE ANATOMY OF THREATS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>34</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>As we have seen, for all the benefits of the cyber world, it also brings significant risk. Much like any other type of risk, cyber security risk derives from a combination of threats and vulnerabilities – vulnerabilities are exploited by threats to achieve certain goals, such as accessing a secure network or installing malware. This does not mean that cyber security risk is limited to deliberate actions by malicious actors, however – a leaky roof in a server room (vulnerability), for instance, can be ‘exploited’ by a rainstorm (threat) with potentially catastrophic results. Developing an understanding of what threats you</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7:</label>
                     <title>TECHNICAL THREATS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>37</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Most of the time, when people think about cyber security, they think of technical threats first. The media regularly features stories of vast data breaches that are eventually traced to some hardware or software vulnerability, both obscure and otherwise. In 2011–2020, malware increased by a staggering 1,634%.⁹ In less than two months, one million phishing emails were reported to the UK’s National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) alone.<sup>10</sup>
                     </p>
                     <p>Although the NCSC successfully blocked or took down thousands of malicious websites, undoubtedly many more new ones have since appeared in their place. Unfortunately, attackers often have the upper hand, having to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 8:</label>
                     <title>HUMAN THREATS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>48</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Some of the biggest threats to cyber security come not from technology, but from the people who use it. 68% of organisations have observed a rise in insider attacks and, as mentioned in chapter 6, 70% actually experienced at least one insider attack in 2019.<sup>18</sup>
                     </p>
                     <p>When you think about it, this should make sense – for all the different types of malware that are out there, they still need to find a way of getting into an organisation’s systems. Getting an insider to inadvertently introduce it into your network by, for example, opening a malicious attachment from an email that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 9:</label>
                     <title>PHYSICAL THREATS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>59</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Physical threats are an often-neglected aspect of cyber security, yet they can affect organisations every bit as much as technological threats. Cyber and information security must incorporate physical security to be truly effective – it is no good protecting sensitive data with an array of technological controls if someone can simply walk in the building and take it. An attacker might also want to gain physical access to your offices to, for example, install a keylogger or another type of hardware.</p>
                     <p>A common way for attackers to gain entry is tailgating. Tailgating is a social engineering technique used to gain</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 10:</label>
                     <title>THIRD-PARTY THREATS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>65</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>An increasingly interconnected world requires increasingly interconnected organisations. No matter the field your organisation operates in, there is a good chance you rely on components or even whole products produced by third parties. No doubt you also share data – via email perhaps, or through a dedicated vendor portal. This connectivity brings great business benefits, but it also exposes you to new risks. The risks that directly relate to your organisation are completely within your control, but your suppliers’ measures are a different matter.</p>
                     <p>The modern supply chain stretches across the globe and encompasses thousands of organisations. More data is</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 11:</label>
                     <title>AN OVERVIEW OF THE CRF PROCESSES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Part 3 – by far the longest part of this book – goes into a wide range of security processes (all taken from the CRF) you might need to implement. For ease of reference, this chapter offers a short description for each of the 24 processes within our CRF, giving you a better idea of which ones you should look at further.</p>
                     <p>To break the Framework down, there are four process categories, with each process falling within one of them. Each category describes how its processes fit within the overall Framework. The four categories are:</p>
                     <p>1. Manage and protect:</p>
                     <p>Deploy risk-appropriate</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 12:</label>
                     <title>MANAGE AND PROTECT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>85</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>‘Manage and protect’, the first and largest process category of the CRF, consists of activities that are central to managing cyber security and protecting the organisation from threats. Of course, in order for your defensive measures to be effective, you need to know what those threats are. By this we do not mean in a generic way, as discussed in part 2 of this book, but specifically those that apply to you. You need to understand who might attack you and how, and what their motivations are.</p>
                     <p>What line of business are you in? Is it likely, for instance, that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 13:</label>
                     <title>IDENTIFY AND DETECT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>204</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Effective security is about managing your risks, monitoring them to make sure they are acceptable and taking appropriate action if not. Importantly, it is not about eliminating all risk and achieving absolute security, as the trade-offs that approach would require – not having an online presence, for instance – are simply too great. However, an acceptable risk is still a risk. Even with a preventive measure in place, that measure might fail, or that measure may have been implemented to only reduce the impact and not necessarily to prevent the risk from materialising. Furthermore, the attacker might be able to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 14:</label>
                     <title>RESPOND AND RECOVER</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>226</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We have already discussed that incidents happen no matter how strong your security, and how detection works where prevention fails. That said, even very reliable detection will not do much good if there is no response. Having an effective prevention–detection–response system in place also improves your cyber resilience and is a form of defence in depth (see 12.12.8) – even if one measure fails, other measures will stop the attack from being successful or minimise its impact. You may also find yourself observing sequences such as in the following examples:</p>
                     <p>1. Preventive measure: password protection.</p>
                     <p>2. Detective measure: access logs</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 15:</label>
                     <title>GOVERN AND ASSURE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>250</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The final CRF control category, ‘govern and assure’, comprises activities that ensure and demonstrate an ongoing and organisation-wide commitment to security. Governance is about ensuring the project is suitably overseen, and assurance is about providing evidence to the oversight authority (both internal and external, where necessary) so they can make sensible, reasoned decisions about it. More concretely, that might mean making your chosen cyber security processes part of a larger structure, with clear governance lines (see 15.4) and visible board-level support (see 15.3), in a formal security programme (see 15.1).</p>
                     <p>The governance lines should make cyber security responsibilities and accountability</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.19</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 16:</label>
                     <title>MATURITY LEVELS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>282</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The CRF has a further layer beyond the roster of control activities: maturity. As you are probably aware, maturity describes how well developed and integrated an activity (or framework) is. In the context of security, this is a valuable way of understanding both how well you are protecting your organisation and how much further you may need to go in order to meet your organisation’s requirements for cyber security and resilience.</p>
                     <p>The CRF maturity levels, which can be used to measure individual processes as well as the overall framework, are:</p>
                     <p>1. Non-existent:</p>
                     <p>The framework/process does not exist, or is not consistent</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.20</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 17:</label>
                     <title>INTRODUCING THE IT GOVERNANCE EIGHT-STEP APPROACH</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>286</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.21</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 18:</label>
                     <title>STEP 1 – START THE PROJECT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>287</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It may be something of a cliché but, for cyber security implementation projects, it is certainly true to say that ‘well begun is half done’. The person charged with leading the project has to reduce something that looks potentially complex, difficult and expensive in terms of time and resources, to something that everyone believes can be achieved in the time frame allocated and with the resources allowed. And then you have to make sure that it is actually delivered!</p>
                     <p>What this means in practice is that the project leader has to set up the project in such a way that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.22</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 19:</label>
                     <title>STEP 2 – DETERMINE REQUIREMENTS AND OBJECTIVES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>294</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>There may have been a specific requirement that prompted your organisation to embark on a cyber security project, and for you to read this book. Now that you are embarking on a full cyber security programme, however, it is important to move beyond the catalyst and look at the bigger picture.</p>
                     <p>What other legal and/or contractual requirements must you meet? Are there sector-specific requirements you need to consider? What are your competitors and partners doing? What do customers expect? What key products and services must be available to ensure you can do business? For a truly effective and sustainable programme,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.23</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 20:</label>
                     <title>STEP 3 – DETERMINE THE SCOPE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>296</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Project scoping is fundamental. You need to know the boundaries of what you are planning to implement, which you can derive from the objectives you established in step 2 (chapter 19).</p>
                     <p>Scope determination is harder for larger, more complex organisations than it is for smaller ones. However, scoping is essential whatever your size: you have to decide which information and IT assets you are going to protect and which ones you are not, before you can decide on appropriate protection. To avoid trying to draw the boundaries too narrowly, make sure that you can justify any exclusions. It is also</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.24</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 21:</label>
                     <title>STEP 4 – DEFINE CURRENT AND IDEAL TARGET STATES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>298</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Most organisations already have some cyber security measures in place – these may not be sufficient or as effective as they should be, but the point is that you are almost certainly not starting from scratch. It is therefore important to understand how far your current practices are from where you want to be.</p>
                     <p>Before you can do that, you have to define both your current and ideal target states in a way that they can easily be compared against one another. The CRF can make this task easier.</p>
                     <p>The most pertinent parts of the CRF for this process are</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.25</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 22:</label>
                     <title>STEP 5 – ESTABLISH A CONTINUAL IMPROVEMENT MODEL</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>301</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Whatever continual improvement method or model you use, and wherever your inputs come from, it is critical that it is cyclical to ensure you keep your improvements both regular and manageable. Some example methods are discussed in more depth in 15.2.3 and 15.2.4.</p>
                     <p>Continual improvement is not just something you do at the end of a project, however. Particularly for a more complex project, as cyber security may well be, it can be a useful way of taking an incremental, step-by-step approach to implementation, with brief reviews between each step to make sure that you are heading in the right</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.26</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 23:</label>
                     <title>STEP 6 – CONDUCT A RISK ASSESSMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>303</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Risk assessment has already been discussed in detail in 12.12, so will not be discussed in much more depth here. However, it is worth looking at a condensed version of security guru Bruce Schneier’s five steps (or questions) that are intended as a mechanism for judging whether a certain security trade-off is worth making.<sup>97</sup> The five questions are:</p>
                     <p>1. What assets are you trying to protect?</p>
                     <p>2. What are the risks to those assets?</p>
                     <p>3. How well does the security solution mitigate the risk?</p>
                     <p>4. What other risks does the security solution cause?</p>
                     <p>5. What trade-offs does the security solution require?</p>
                     <p>It is a straightforward</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.27</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 24:</label>
                     <title>STEP 7 – SELECT AND IMPLEMENT CONTROLS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>305</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.28</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 25:</label>
                     <title>STEP 8 – MEASURE AND REVIEW PERFORMANCE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>306</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Your cyber security programme will only be useful – and sustainable – if you can show that your cyber security and project objectives are being met. For this, measurement of the logs and outputs of the controls implemented in step 7 (see chapter 24) is essential. These measurements should be designed so that you can compare the information you gain now to measurements you take in the future. (Measurement was briefly covered in 15.1.2.)</p>
                     <p>For the best results and a consistent approach from the start, you should plan the measurement as you plan the implementation of the control. It could</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.29</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 26:</label>
                     <title>WHY YOU SHOULD CONSIDER REFERENCE FRAMEWORKS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>311</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It is perfectly possible to develop a robust cyber security system without using internationally recognised standards or frameworks. Indeed, if you purely viewed part 3 of this book as a reference, rather than the building blocks of our resilience framework, and just implemented the most basic and relevant controls discussed, you are already off to a great start. As your cyber security posture evolves, however, you may find that standards or frameworks can benefit your organisation in several ways.<sup>98</sup>
                     </p>
                     <p>Standards and frameworks offer a tried, tested and comprehensive approach to cyber security developed by experts in the field. By adopting</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.30</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 27:</label>
                     <title>CORE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>315</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>One way to approach standards and frameworks, especially if you are not sure whether they are right for your organisation, is to start small and work your way up. The more basic frameworks can also be a good way of generally getting started with cyber security, as they tend to be affordable and relatively straightforward to implement.</p>
                     <p>Cyber Essentials is a UK government scheme supported by the NCSC, and is intended to help organisations of any size demonstrate their commitment to cyber security, while keeping the approach simple and the costs low.</p>
                     <p>The scheme focuses on five key cyber security</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.31</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 28:</label>
                     <title>BASELINE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>321</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>If Cyber Essentials does not go far enough, or if you are looking for something recognised outside the UK, then your next stop will almost certainly be the NIST CSF (see 28.1) or ISO 27001 (see 28.2). Both form a good baseline for starting to develop a solid cyber security framework.</p>
                     <p>The NIST CSF offers a straightforward yet flexible framework. The Framework can help organisations establish a new cyber security programme or improve existing practices, and can be implemented alongside other frameworks such as ISO 27001 (see 28.2). Combining a standard you can certify against with the NIST CSF can</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.32</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 29:</label>
                     <title>EXTENDED</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>328</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Your baseline framework can be extended with more specialised standards and frameworks – focusing on areas such as business continuity (see 29.1), incident response (see 29.2), Cloud and supply chain security (see 29.3) and privacy management (see 29.4) – to help you build a more comprehensive cyber resilience stance.</p>
                     <p>International standard ISO 22301 provides the specification for an effective business continuity management system (BCMS), and can be an excellent addition to ISO 27001 if you are considering an integrated management system – the ISO 27001 and ISO 22301 combination covers the two most fundamental aspects of cyber resilience: information security</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.33</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 30:</label>
                     <title>EMBEDDED</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>337</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>At this stage, you should have developed your base framework and extended it as your specific needs demand, drawing on best-practice standards and frameworks where appropriate. Now, you should think about how you can align your cyber resilience objectives and activities with your wider business objectives, maximising the effectiveness and sustainability of your security programme.</p>
                     <p>IT governance – an element of corporate governance aimed at improving the overall management of IT and deriving improved value from investment in information and technology – plays a vital role in aligning your cyber security and resilience activities with your wider business objectives. IT</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.34</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 31:</label>
                     <title>CONCLUSION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>344</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.35</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX 1:</title>
                     <subtitle>IT AND INFORMATION ASSET CHECKLIST</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>345</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.36</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX 2:</title>
                     <subtitle>TEMPLATE OUTLINE PROJECT PLAN</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>347</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.37</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX 3:</title>
                     <subtitle>GLOSSARY OF ACRONYMS AND ABBREVIATIONS</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>351</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv19shhms.38</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>GRC INTERNATIONAL GROUP RESOURCES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>354</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
