

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv14t45v5</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Development Studies</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>A Matter of Trust</book-title>
         <subtitle>Building Integrity into Data, Statistics and Records to Support the Achievement of the Sustainable Development Goals</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="editor" id="contrib1">
            <role>edited by</role>
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Thurston</surname>
               <given-names>Anne</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>01</day>
         <month>12</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781912250349</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781912250356</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>University of London Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>contributors</copyright-holder>
         <copyright-holder>contributors and copyright holders named in captions</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv14t45v5"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Sustainable Development Goals initiative has
the potential to set the direction for a future world that works
for everyone. Approved by 193 United Nations member countries in
September 2016 to help guide global and national development
policies in the period to 2030, the 17 goals build on the successes
of the Millennium Development Goals, but also include new priority
areas, such as climate change, economic inequality, innovation,
sustainable consumption, peace and justice. Assessed against common
agreed targets and indicators, the goals should facilitate
inter-governmental cooperation and the development of regional and
even global development strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, each goal presents considerable challenges in terms of
collecting and analysing relevant data and producing the statistics
needed to measure progress. Most governments in lower resourced
countries simply do not yet have the systems and controls in place
to produce high quality, reliable data and statistics, and it is
questionable whether the quality and integrity of the available
information is adequate to support meaningful decisions and set
direction for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are substantial implications: where progress cannot be
measured accurately because of inadequate or flawed statistics, the
result can be misguided decisions, doubts about achievement of the
goals and significant wasted resources. Getting statistics 'right'
depends upon the quality and integrity of the data used to produce
them and on the quality of the processes for collecting,
manipulating and analysing the data. Without a documentary records
as evidence of how the data were gathered and analysed or how
statistics were produced and disseminated, it is not possible to
confirm that the statistics are complete, accurate and
relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various global organisations do recognise the importance of high
quality data and statistics for measuring the SDG indicators
reliably, but there has been little attention to the role of
records in providing the evidence needed to trust the data and
statistics. There is, moreover, a lack of awareness that digital
information simply will not survive without policies and procedures
to manage and preserve it through time. As a result, digital data,
statistics and records are being lost regularly on a large scale,
particularly in lower resource countries, where the structures
needed to protect and preserve them are not yet in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book explores, through a series of case studies, the
substantial challenges for assembling reliable data and statistics
to address pressing development challenges, particularly in Africa.
Hopefully, by highlighting the enormous potential value of creating
and using high quality data, statistics and records as an
interconnected resource and describing how this can be achieved,
the book will contribute to defining meaningful and realistic
global and national development policies in the critical period to
2030.&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <funding-group>
         <award-group>
            <funding-source>AHRC, Knowledge Unlatched Select 2020: HSS Frontlist</funding-source>
         </award-group>
      </funding-group>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="300"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>v</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgements</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="editor" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Thurston</surname>
                           <given-names>Anne</given-names>
                        </name>
                        <role>Editor</role>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Notes on contributors</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) initiative has the potential to set the direction for a future world that works for everyone. The SDGs were approved by 193 United Nations member countries in September 2016 to help guide global and national development policies in the period to 2030. The 17 goals build on the successes of the Millennium Development Goals, while also including new priority areas such as climate change, economic inequality, innovation, sustainable consumption, peace and justice. Each of the 17 SDGs is to be assessed against agreed targets and indicators.¹ One hundred and sixty nine targets set out quantitative</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1.</label>
                     <title>Records as evidence for measuring sustainable development in Africa</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Thurston</surname>
                           <given-names>Anne</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The expectation that the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) will provide a basis for addressing global economic, social and environmental crises assumes the availability of trustworthy, accessible evidence of measurable progress. The lack of policies and systems for managing this information reliably inevitably means that there are gaps in the information and that often its reliability cannot be demonstrated, in Africa or elsewhere. It is important to understand how this situation came about and the impact it has on development.</p>
                     <p>The SDG approach to measuring progress does not yet take account of the challenges for managing records. Addressing the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2.</label>
                     <title>The state of data and statistics in sub-Saharan Africa in the context of the Sustainable Development Goals</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Komba</surname>
                           <given-names>Paul</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Kandala</surname>
                           <given-names>Ngianga-Bakwin</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>19</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) were set up to support sustainable health, tackle poverty and enhance peace and prosperity for present and future generations, at all levels, locally to globally.¹ The implication is that the SDGs can be achieved through governmental and nongovernmental interventions, supported by data and statistics to ensure that they are on course to deliver those goals and targets. The rise of an evidencebased policy paradigm and the idea of managing by results has led aid agencies and international policy-makers to place statistical measurement at the heart of monitoring and evaluation of official development assistance.²</p>
                     <p>Statistical development</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3.</label>
                     <title>Data, information and records:</title>
                     <subtitle>exploring definitions and relationships</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Yeo</surname>
                           <given-names>Geoffrey</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2" xlink:type="simple">
                        <role>interviewed by</role>
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Lowry</surname>
                           <given-names>James</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>49</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The achievement and measurement of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) depend on the availability of trustworthy data from a variety of sources. Records, especially records created by government agencies, are often identified as one of the most important sources from which such data can be derived. Over centuries, the records and archives management profession has developed approaches to maintaining, controlling and contextualising records, which can help users assess the trustworthiness of the records and perhaps also the quality of the information that can be gained from them. With so much vested in the SDGs, it has become increasingly important to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4.</label>
                     <title>The potential – constructive and destructive – of information technology for records management:</title>
                     <subtitle>case studies from India</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Manor</surname>
                           <given-names>James</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>67</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Twenty years ago, it was sometimes difficult to explain the importance of improving records management. Sceptics wondered whether it was worthwhile sorting through floor-to-ceiling stacks of old government files in musty Asian or African offices. They had to be persuaded that orderly sets of records could restore the memories of governments. However, effective records management facilitates government driven by precedent and not by the whims of politicians and bureaucrats. It promotes the rule of law. It prepares the ground for greater government transparency and accountability and for efforts to curb corruption. It enables governments - and citizens - to see</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5.</label>
                     <title>Statistical accuracy and reliable records:</title>
                     <subtitle>a case study of mortality statistics in The Gambia</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Griffin</surname>
                           <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>83</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter examines the relationship between data, statistics and records in the context of mortality statistics in The Gambia. The aim is to illustrate the complexities and practical challenges in acquiring reliable information as a basis for national development planning, as well as for measuring the achievement of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), especially in low resource environments. The first section provides a brief overview of The Gambia’s economic challenges. The second deals with the complexities of birth and mortality data, how they are estimated and discrepancies between different data sources. It argues that, ultimately, accurate statistics can only be</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6.</label>
                     <title>Mainstreaming records and data management in sustainable development:</title>
                     <subtitle>lessons from the public and private sectors in Kenya</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Wamukoya</surname>
                           <given-names>Justus</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Ambira</surname>
                           <given-names>Cleophas</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>97</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>K enya is one of more than 190 countries supporting the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) initiative, also known as the Global Goals for Sustainable Development. Successful implementation of the SDGs will complement Kenya’s socio-economic development blueprint for the period to 2030. All 17 SDGs address global challenges and social issues, including those related to poverty, climate change, environmental degradation, prosperity, peace and justice. Moreover, they are intended to bolster government efforts to implement national development plans and to revitalise the global partnership for sustainable development.</p>
                     <p>In Kenya, as in most other countries, implementing the goals successfully depends on</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7.</label>
                     <title>Open data and records management – activating public engagement to improve information:</title>
                     <subtitle>case studies from Sierra Leone and Cambodia</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Townsend</surname>
                           <given-names>Katherine</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Lamin</surname>
                           <given-names>Tamba</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib3" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Massally</surname>
                           <given-names>Amadu</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib4" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Chung</surname>
                           <given-names>Pyrou</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>109</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Open data initiatives support transparency, innovation, the promotion of a knowledge-based society and the advancement of democratic principles. Data in the hands of citizens can facilitate empowerment and support improved government efficiency and accountability. Open data promotes transparency by enabling citizens to reanalyse data underpinning government decisions and to monitor the impact of government policies. Citizens with access to the same government data used by policy-makers are more informed and better able to participate in and contribute to policy-making. Through their access to the administrative data generated by government, they are also able to identify incidents of corruption. For instance,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>8.</label>
                     <title>Assuring authenticity in public sector data:</title>
                     <subtitle>a case study of the Kenya Open Data Initiative</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Lowry</surname>
                           <given-names>James</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>121</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Measuring the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), and ultimately the success of the whole SDG initiative, will depend on the availability of authentic public sector data. By the time it reaches policy-makers, either as baseline data or as comparative data indicating progress, it will have been assembled through one or more methods from sources as varied as paper or digital records, management information systems, people and scientific instruments. After collection, it will be curated, cleaned, analysed, augmented and remixed. It will be subjected to formulas in spreadsheets, algorithms in apps and the intervention of people in various roles with various priorities</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>9.</label>
                     <title>Preserving the digital evidence base for measuring the Sustainable Development Goals</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Brown</surname>
                           <given-names>Adrian</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>135</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The role of good recordkeeping in providing evidence for measuring the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) has been discussed in depth in Chapter 1 of this volume, ‘Records as evidence for measuring sustainable development in Africa’, as has the fact that data, documents and other forms of recorded information are increasingly digital in form. The need for digital preservation will only continue to grow, an issue that cannot be avoided if SDGs are to be met. Furthermore, the SDG agenda requires that these records remain accessible to 2030 and beyond, which, in the digital world, can only be achieved through continuous</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>10.</label>
                     <title>Preserving and using digitally encoded information as a foundation for achieving the Sustainable Development Goals</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Giaretta</surname>
                           <given-names>David</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>153</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The health, wealth and happiness of a great many people worldwide, now and in the future, will depend upon the accuracy, intercomparability and preservation of the Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) measurements, information that is of global significance. This chapter offers a view on how to manage the complexity of gathering comparative data to monitor progress towards the SDGs in the years leading to 2030 from the perspective of collecting, using and preserving digitally encoded information, in particular scientific data. The aim is to help improve the way that information relevant to the SDGs is collected and used, so that the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>11.</label>
                     <title>Transparency in the 21st century:</title>
                     <subtitle>the role of records in achieving public access to information, protecting fundamental freedoms and monitoring sustainable development</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Lemieux</surname>
                           <given-names>Victoria</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>173</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>A reliable and accessible evidence base is vital for all aspects of transparent and open government, particularly in an age of propagation of fake news and misinformation. Now more than ever, we need reliable facts about government decisions and actions for public accountability and economic and social development. Unless digital data and documents are created in the first instance, and then managed and protected as reliable evidence, they cannot serve the ends of transparency, openness and accountability, nor can they be used to track progress on goals for sustainable development.¹</p>
                     <p>This chapter primarily draws upon a programme of research² on</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>12.</label>
                     <title>Information management for international development:</title>
                     <subtitle>roles, responsibilities and competencies</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Shepherd</surname>
                           <given-names>Elizabeth</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>McLeod</surname>
                           <given-names>Julie</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>189</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter addresses the roles, responsibilities and competencies needed to manage information for international development, particularly in connection with measuring the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) reliably. We specifically focus on the management of records, which are information carriers and can contain or be used to create data and statistics. However, our approach can equally be applied to the management of data, statistics and information more generally.</p>
                     <p>An important theme running through the chapters in this volume is the role of records as evidence for accountability and transparency in civil society and for organisational decision- making. Information, data and records are</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>13.</label>
                     <title>The quality of data, statistics and records used to measure progress towards achieving the SDGs:</title>
                     <subtitle>a fictional situation analysis</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>McDonald</surname>
                           <given-names>John</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>211</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This is a fictional situation report from the fictional nation of Patria that aims to illustrate the issues associated with managing the data, statistics and records used to measure the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in lower- and middle-income countries. This approach should make it possible to present key issues without identifying individual countries and it should allow them to assess the extent to which the fictional situation matches their own realities. A close match will suggest greater relevance. It is hoped that this will increase awareness and understanding of issues and their consequences, leading to concrete action.</p>
                     <p>Patria is one</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.19</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>243</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv14t45v5.20</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Back Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>249</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
