

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvrnfqsx</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>How Cyber Security Can Protect Your Business</book-title>
         <subtitle>A guide for all stakeholders</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>WRIGHT</surname>
               <given-names>CHRISTOPHER</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>26</day>
         <month>11</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787781955</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787781962</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Christopher Wright</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvrnfqsx"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;<bold>Summary</bold>  &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Explains in easy-to-understand terms what executives and senior managers need to know and do about the ever-changing cyber threat landscape. &lt;li&gt;Gives strategic, business-focused guidance and advice relevant to C-suite executives. &lt;li&gt;Provides an effective and efficient framework for managing cyber governance, risk and compliance. &lt;li&gt;Explains what is required to implement an effective cyber security strategy.  &lt;p&gt;<bold>Description</bold>  &lt;p&gt;With high-profile cyber attacks, data breaches and fines for GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) non-compliance hitting the headlines daily, businesses must protect themselves and their reputations, while reassuring stakeholders they take cyber security seriously.  &lt;p&gt;Cyber attacks are becoming more sophisticated and prevalent, and the cost of data breaches is soaring. In addition, new regulations and reporting requirements make cyber security a critical business issue.  &lt;p&gt;Board members and senior management must understand the threat landscape and the strategies they can employ to establish, implement and maintain effective cyber resilience throughout their organisation.  &lt;p&gt;<italic>How Cyber Security Can Protect your Business - A guide for all stakeholders</italic> provides an effective and efficient framework for managing cyber governance, risk and compliance, which organisations can adapt to meet their own risk appetite and synchronise with their people, processes and technology. It explains what is meant by governance, risk and compliance, how it applies to cyber security and what is required to implement an effective cyber security strategy.  &lt;p&gt;The pocket guide:  &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Gives readers a greater understanding of cyber governance, risk and compliance; &lt;li&gt;Explains what executives, senior managers and their advisors need to know and do about the ever-changing cyber threat landscape; &lt;li&gt;Provides context as to why stakeholders need to be aware of and in control of their organisation's cyber risk management and cyber incident response; &lt;li&gt;Gives guidance on building an appropriate and efficient governance framework that enables organisations to demonstrate their cyber approach in a non-technical, strategic, business-focused way; &lt;li&gt;Details an overview process to enable risk assessment, assess existing defence mitigations and provide a framework for developing suitable controls; and &lt;li&gt;Includes a checklist to help readers focus on their higher-priority cyber areas.  &lt;p&gt;Suitable for all managers and executives, this pocket guide will be of interest to non-cyber specialists, including non-executive directors, who may be required to review cyber arrangements. For cyber specialists, it provides an approach for explaining cyber issues in non-jargonistic, business-based language.  &lt;p&gt;<bold>Kick-start your journey to becoming cyber secure - buy this pocket guide today!</bold>  
         </p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="68"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FOREWORD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Akingbehin</surname>
                           <given-names>Yinka</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>I was in the audience at an ISACA® conference in Manchester when Chris delivered a lecture on information security audits. It was pretty clear that, with almost four decades’ experience, he had mastery of the subject. Despite the fact the room was full of seasoned audit professionals, he delivered his lecture in simple language that you did not have to be an information security audit professional to understand. At the end, he spoke about his new book <italic>How Cyber Security Can Protect Your Business – A guide for all stakeholders</italic> and how he wanted to demystify cyber.</p>
                     <p>When he approached</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>11</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>12</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION TO CYBER SECURITY GRC</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>14</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Governance. Risk. Compliance (or ‘Control’). Simple words – but they encompass so much. They cover the steps taken by organisations to ensure they act ethically, legally and with integrity, and can effectively and efficiently handle risks (or other uncertainties) in achieving their business goals or other objectives.</p>
                     <p>GRC was first defined by Scott Mitchell, OCEG, in 2007 as:</p>
                     <p>the integrated collection of capabilities that enable an organization to reliably achieve objectives, address uncertainty and act with integrity.²</p>
                     <p>Governance is the ability to ensure that the organisation achieves its goals and objectives. It includes policies and processes led by senior management</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>CYBER SECURITY GOVERNANCE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>21</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Good control requires good corporate governance from the top (directors and executive management). Top management should ensure that the organisation is well structured and managed with strong policies and a strong ethos. Governance forms the foundation on which other controls and risk mitigations can be built. For example, controls will only be effective if there is the culture to ensure that they are adhered to and that anyone breaking these rules will be held to account and treated accordingly. Ultimately, those who hold governance accountability will be held responsible for all failures regardless of where they occur.</p>
                     <p>These corporate governance</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>CYBER SECURITY RISK MANAGEMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>30</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We all take risks every day. Life is a risky business. But without risk there is no progress. The same applies to organisations in the cyber world: there are risks of hacking, fraud, state interference and identity theft. But these have to be matched against risks of not doing business via cyber (e.g. failure to win new customers or reduce costs). The risks are great but so are the potential rewards: competitive advantage, reduction in costs, increased awareness of your products and services via social media, to name but a few. These risks can be managed in the same way</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>CYBER RISKS AND CONTROLS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>36</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The process described in the previous chapter can be used to manage any risk management process, including cyber. Where cyber differs is in the specific nature of the risks faced by organisations and the controls used to mitigate them. Cyber risks can be categorised, like other IT security risks, using CIA.</p>
                     <p>Confidentiality – relates to organisations’ duty of care, and legal responsibility (under the GDPR or other relevant data privacy legislation): they must act as the guardian of the personal and sensitive data they hold on behalf of customers, employees, suppliers, etc. Organisations should also have a means to classify</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>RESPONDING TO AN ATTACK</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>50</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Even the best controlled organisations are attacked. All organisations must be ready for such an eventuality by planning accordingly and developing processes to detect and respond to an attack.</p>
                     <p>A key part of preparation is to:</p>
                     <p>1. Assess which electronic information is vital for the operation of the organisation (sales and staff contact details, key customer details), and ascertain where and how this is stored and can be recovered. Ensure that backup copies of these files are maintained securely and are retrievable (some ransomware attacks seek to destroy backup data before the threat is revealed).</p>
                     <p>2. Prioritise processes and systems so those</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>CYBER COMPLIANCE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>55</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the context of cyber we are seeking to comply with our organisation’s policies, procedures and processes as well as with legislation. Compliance should not be an annual tick-box exercise, but an opportunity to ensure that controls continue to operate effectively and that the risks of financial penalties and loss of reputation are minimised. It provides assurance that the organisation is taking cyber threats seriously and has controls in place that are designed, implemented and operating effectively. Cyber GRC is not a one–off project, to be completed and then forgotten about. It needs to be embedded as the organisation’s</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>BOOKS BY THE SAME AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>65</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfqsx.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>66</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
