

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">Q334.7 .K38 2020</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Artificial intelligence</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Moral and ethical aspects</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Artificial intelligence</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Political aspects</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Male domination (Social structure)</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">White supremacy movements</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Philosophy</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Imperialism and science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Logic</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Political aspects</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Sociology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Public Policy &amp; Administration</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Artificial Whiteness</book-title>
         <subtitle>Politics and Ideology in Artificial Intelligence</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>KATZ</surname>
               <given-names>YARDEN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>17</day>
         <month>11</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780231194907</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780231551076</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">023155107X</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Columbia University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Yarden Katz</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.7312/katz19490"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
Dramatic statements about the promise and peril of artificial
intelligence for humanity abound, as an industry of experts claims
that AI is poised to reshape nearly every sphere of life. Who
profits from the idea that the age of AI has arrived? Why do ideas
of AI's transformative potential keep reappearing in social and
political discourse, and how are they linked to broader political
agendas? Yarden Katz reveals the ideology embedded in the concept
of artificial intelligence, contending that it both serves and
mimics the logic of white supremacy. He demonstrates that
understandings of AI, as a field and a technology, have shifted
dramatically over time based on the needs of its funders and the
professional class that formed around it. From its origins in the
Cold War military-industrial complex through its present-day
Silicon Valley proselytizers and eager policy analysts, AI has
never been simply a technical project enabled by larger data and
better computing. Drawing on intimate familiarity with the field
and its practices, Katz instead asks us to see how AI reinforces
models of knowledge that assume white male superiority and an
imperialist worldview. Only by seeing the connection between
artificial intelligence and whiteness can we prioritize
alternatives to the conception of AI as an all-encompassing
technological force. Bringing together theories of whiteness and
race in the humanities and social sciences with a deep
understanding of the history and practice of science and computing,
&lt;em&gt;Artificial Whiteness&lt;/em&gt; is an incisive, urgent critique of
the uses of AI as a political tool to uphold social hierarchies.
</p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is capturing many minds. The famed physicist Stephen Hawking said the creation of “effective AI” may be “the biggest event in the history of our civilization, or the worst.”¹ Vladimir Putin declared, “Whoever leads in AI will rule the world.”² The United States, Britain, France, Russia, and China (among many governments) have drafted national plans on AI. Museums, too, have begun exploring the nature of art and creativity in what is widely, and nonchalantly, described as “the age of AI.”³ The fashion industry is asking how AI will “reprogram” clothing lines, and even human rights organizations are</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>IN THE SERVICE OF EMPIRE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>19</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In Herman Melville’s <italic>Moby-Dick</italic>, Ishmael surveys the formidable scientific efforts to capture the essence of the whale. As Ishmael shows, however, these efforts proved futile. The science of cetology remains confused and incomplete, forever befuddled by conundrums such as whether a whale is a fish. The diversity of whales simply defies physiological and anatomical taxonomies; one cannot classify “the constituents of a chaos.”¹ The whale that Melville’s Ahab was after could not be reduced to its innards because the animal’s significance lies elsewhere. This chapter explores the origins and scope of another messy arena, that of “Artificial Intelligence,” which I</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>IN THE SERVICE OF CAPITAL</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>65</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the 2010s AI forcefully reemerged in the mainstream, rolling off the tongues of politicians, academics, policy experts, and journalists. Money flowed into a range of academic, corporate, and state-military initiatives on AI. How did it become so central again, and who stood to gain from this development?</p>
                     <p>I will argue that in this period, AI was rebranded to support a variety of capitalist visions and projects. AI’s sudden reappearance temporarily diverted attention from systems of mass surveillance enabled by companies such as Google and Microsoft. The “AI” label refreshed these companies’ neoliberal vision of world governance, which rests on</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>EPISTEMIC FORGERIES AND GHOSTS IN THE MACHINE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>93</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In his book <italic>Forgeries of Memory and Meaning</italic>, Cedric Robinson examined how the representations of black people in Western culture helped construct whiteness. These representations and the myths accompanying them became, in Robinson’s words, “Inventions of the Negro” and were always changing to suit imperial interests and meet antiracist challenges.¹ They were constructed with diverse instruments: from theater, film, fiction, painting, and even cooking to racial science.² This last pillar, racial science, played an important role because, according to Robinson, it forged a “scientific” basis for relations of power between whites and nonwhites—categories that racial science attempts to ground.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4</label>
                     <title>ADAPTATION, NOT ABOLITION:</title>
                     <subtitle>Critical AI Experts and Carceral-Positive Logic</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>127</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Systems of white supremacy do not sit still; they change in the face of resistance. After the dismantling of chattel slavery in the United States, white supremacy was reinforced by the convict lease system and Jim Crow laws. Following gains made by social movements in the 1960s, white supremacy was reinstated by institutions and policies affecting housing, banking, health, education, and more, as well as through a growing system of mass incarceration. These developments were accompanied by discourses of equal rights, colorblindness, and multiculturalism.¹ Such progressive veneers helped mask the reconfigured rule of white supremacy.</p>
                     <p>AI doesn’t sit still, either.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>ARTIFICIAL WHITENESS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>153</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>I want to return to the question posed in the first chapter: What is Artificial Intelligence? This question requires us to account for AI’s reappearances and shifts, and its place in imperial and capitalist projects. The question also calls for an explanation of AI’s flexibility: its ability to move from the world of Pentagon technocrats to that of self-styled “progressive” activists. This question also calls for an accounting of AI’s models of the self.</p>
                     <p>This chapter sketches the beginnings of an answer by exploring “Artificial Intelligence”—as a concept, field, and set of practices—through the ideology of whiteness, as</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>DISSENTING VISIONS:</title>
                     <subtitle>From Autopoietic Love to Embodied War</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>185</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In previous chapters we saw that although AI’s boundaries were contested and its computational engines always changing, the endeavor has consistently advanced imperial and capitalist visions. I have argued that AI is a technology of power that serves white supremacy and even reproduces the ideological form of whiteness. AI is nebulous and dynamic, with its reconfigurations steered by imperial and capitalist projects. AI practitioners have steadily produced racial, gendered, and classed models of the self that both reflect and recharge these projects.</p>
                     <p>This raises the question: Can something like what AI purports to be—an attempt to understand ourselves, our</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7</label>
                     <title>A GENERATIVE REFUSAL</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>225</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>I have argued in this book that artificial intelligence is a technology of whiteness: malleable, contested, and continually remade to serve imperial and capitalist aims. Whiteness is artificial, and so perhaps it is natural that AI has mirrored it so well.</p>
                     <p>While the endeavor’s offerings were always a moving target, AI’s recurring “revolutions” were staged with remarkable consistency. And when this nebulous technology broke down, raising questions about its utility to invested powers, practitioners would help connect the dots for their patrons by formulating their work around imperial and capitalist visions and offering new computational engines. But new computational engines</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>235</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>237</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>303</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.7312/katz19490.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>325</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
