

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11hpr8w</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">TK7882.B56 G75 2020</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Biometric identification</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Social aspects</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>General Science</subject>
         <subject>Science &amp; Technology Studies</subject>
         <subject>Communication Studies</subject>
         <subject>History of Science &amp; Technology</subject>
         <subject>Health Sciences</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>The Social Life of Biometrics</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>GRINNELL</surname>
               <given-names>GEORGE C.</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>15</day>
         <month>05</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781978809079</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781978809109</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Rutgers University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>New Brunswick, Camden; Newark, New Jersey; London</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>George C. Grinnell</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv11hpr8w"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> In The Social Life of Biometrics, biometrics is loosely defined as a discrete technology of identification that associates physical features with a legal identity. Author George Grinnell considers the social and cultural life of biometrics by examining what it is asked to do, imagined to do, and its intended and unintended effects. As a human-focused account of technology, the book contends that biometrics needs to be understood as a mode of thought that informs how we live and understand one another; it is not simply a neutral technology of identification. Placing our biometric present in historical and cultural perspective, The Social Life of Biometrics examines a range of human experiences of biometrics. It features individual stories from locations as diverse as Turkey, Canada, Qatar, Six Nations territory in New York State, Iraq, the skies above New York City, a university campus and Nairobi to give cultural accounts of identification and look at the ongoing legacies of our biometric ambitions. It ends by considering the ethics surrounding biometrics and human identity, migration, movement, strangers, borders, and the nature of the body and its coherence. How has biometric thought structured ideas about borders, race, covered faces, migration, territory, citizenship, and international responsibility? What might happen if identity was less defined by the question of "who's there?" and much more by the question "how do you live?"</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="244"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It is not easy to form an idea of the ground and what it knows. Consider the strip of land between Greece and Macedonia and the stories it has been told by the footfalls of mi grants who fled war and insecurity in Syria following government repression of peaceful uprisings associated with the Arab Spring in 2011 and the subsequent conflict that displaced more than ten million people. What does this ground know of the aches, joy, and tears of those who walked upon it in search of a life that is livable? What does it know of the many</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>BIOMETRIC ENCOUNTERS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>26</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>A commonsense concern with biometric technology is that it is invasive and violates a person’s right to privacy or that it might do so if data is stored improperly or stolen. I have little quarrel with this legitimate concern except to say that this should not be the primary or only concern one has with biometrics. The idea that biometrics may compromise an individual actually conceals a very different insight: many of the most powerful effects of biometric measures are social rather individual. As a practice of verifying identity, biometrics depends upon a set of assumptions that frame and produce</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>THE SOCIAL LIFE OF BIOMETRICS OF BIOMETRICS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>51</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the novel Preparations for the Next Life, Atticus Lish tells the story of two mi grants who make a life together and try to understand what it means to live as foreigners in New York City. Zou Lei arrived as an undocumented mi grant from China, while Brad Skinner is an American citizen who has returned from war in Iraq. Neither one finds it easy to be at home in oneself, and neither knows exactly how to live in this foreign city. The novel reminds readers that identity depends so much on those around us, who make it possible</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>THE DOMAINS OF BIOMETRIC THOUGHT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>If one has ever felt anxiety at a moment of inspection, perhaps at a border, it can invoke an odd sort of trepidation when realizing the impossibility of acting in a manner consonant with whatever the official record of identity might suggest or in a way that seems utterly “normal.” The ritual of identification can be like getting thrust on stage without a script, wondering how to perform a calmer, more lively, upstanding, relaxed, happy, serious, obsequious, or assertive version of oneself. It is as if the official record, itself a fiction of identity that has reduced the individual to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>A GENEALOGY OF BIOMETRICS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>127</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In his study of techniques of identification, historian Edward Higgs suggests that our pre sent era is distinguished by the disappearance of an identity one can assert on one’s own terms. One must “claim it from institutions” and from “official registries and databases” (205). The idea that identity is something outside of oneself is not new, however, at least if we recall Hegel’s fundamental insight that existence depends upon being recognized by others. And while this might sound benign when addressed to bureaucracy, we can recall Kiese Laymon’s experiences of the ordinary violence of racism that is likewise part of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>THINKING IN THE WAKE OF BIOMETRIC THOUGHT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>155</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In 2014, the graffiti artist Banksy added a stenciled image to Clactonon-Sea in Britain: a colorful African songbird juxtaposed against the ugly desires of inhospitable colorless birds carrying placards and banners that read “Migrants not welcome,” “Go back to Africa,” and “Keep off our worms.” Banksy’s artwork is known for drawing attention to how social matters are framed, and in this case the image encourages viewers to rethink how they understand migration. While the image did not last long before being covered up, it references a set of hostilities toward immigrants that has remained volatile in the United Kingdom and</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>173</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>WORKS CITED</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>175</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>181</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv11hpr8w.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Back Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>189</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
