

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctt183pbtr</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Political Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>@ is for Activism</book-title>
         <subtitle>Dissent, Resistance and Rebellion in a Digital Culture</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Hands</surname>
               <given-names>Joss</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>20</day>
         <month>11</month>
         <year>2015</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780745327006</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781849645393</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Pluto Books</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>London; New York</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2011</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Joss Hands</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt183pbtr"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>@ is For Activism examines the transformation of politics through digital media, including digital television, online social networking and mobile computing. Joss Hands maps out how political relationships have been reconfigured and new modes of cooperation, deliberation and representation have emerged. This analysis is applied to the organisation and practice of alternative politics, showing how they have developed and embraced the new political and technological environment. Hands offers a comprehensive critical survey of existing literature, as well as an original perspective on networks and political change. He includes many case studies including the anti-war and global justice movements, peer production, user created TV and 'Twitter' activism. @ is For Activism is essential for activists and students of politics and media.</p>
      </abstract>
      <funding-group>
         <award-group>
            <funding-source>Knowledge Unlatched Select 2020: HSS Backlist</funding-source>
         </award-group>
      </funding-group>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="224"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>v</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgements</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>On Monday 15 June 2009, the ‘Twitter Blog’ announced that it would be postponing a planned maintenance shutdown, given the recognition of ‘the role Twitter is currently playing as an important communication tool in Iran’ (Twitter, 2009).¹ On the same day as Twitter’s postponed maintenance, the <italic>New York Times</italic> reported that ‘Iranians are blogging, posting to Facebook and most visibly coordinating their protests on Twitter, the messaging service’ (Stone &amp; Cohen, 2009).</p>
                     <p>This was a response to the widespread unrest in Iran in the aftermath of the perceived fixing of the presidential election. Reports of unrest, street protests and images of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>Activism and Technology</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>23</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The history of technology is the history of human development. It is no accident that we define epochs by the substance of their dominant technologies. It is through technology that our material, social, cultural, political and economic life is constructed. The process of making sense of the organisation of the human world thus depends on how we understand the role of technology in society, and so in the first instance demands a consideration of the nature of technology itself.</p>
                     <p>While the computer on which I write these words is readily defined as a product of technology, what does it have</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>The Digital Author as Producer</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>48</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Mass communications, for most of the latter half of the twentieth century, were dominated by the technology of analogue broadcast media. Critics such as Herbert Marcuse defined this technology, including television, radio, cinema, and newspaper publishing, as fully intertwined with capitalist domination (Marcuse, 1964). From a technical point of view, it is clear why this should be: a central point of broadcast with millions of points of reception, from the few to the many, is the structure of such networks. The technology necessary to undertake production and distribution also requires large amounts of capital investment; the institutions and technical systems</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>Protocol, Norm, Imperative:</title>
                     <subtitle>Networks as Moral Machines</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>77</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The potential for digital technology to allow its users to be ‘mobile active subjects’ and ‘surprising as guerrillas’ (Enzensberger, 1982: p. 47) might look somewhat limited in the context of digital broadcast television, but the technology of the Internet has long been held to contain such liberatory potential.</p>
                     <p>Governments of the industrial world, you weary giants of flesh and steel, I come from cyberspace, the new home of the mind. On behalf of the future, I ask you of the past to leave us alone … I declare the global social space we are building to be naturally independent of</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4</label>
                     <title>Power-Law Democracy</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>99</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Digital networks are now thoroughly interwoven with the culture, politics and economy of society as a whole at all levels, from the local to the global. Thus the aim of maximising participation, openness and recognition in these networks is profoundly important in enabling democracy in its widest sense, including dissent, resistance and rebellion. One obvious route for this is using the connective power of digital networks to create influence in actually existing democracies. Such an approach represents one direction of digital activism that is most certainly taking place, the logic being that, by leveraging the power of the network towards</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>Mobil(e)isation</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>124</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The difference between mass demonstration and direct action is not always clear, but it can be usefully compared to that between dissent and resistance. Where dissent focuses on challenging dominant views, expressing opposition and relying on the force of argument alone, resistance, and indeed rebellion, entail some form of intervention or disruption, and thus direct action against power-over. As with dissent, these actions are born of the ‘scream’, in that out of the negation of its negation comes the mutual recognition of a shared ‘No!’, and thus solidarity. And so these actions are built through anti-power: dignity, respect, and mutual</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>@ is also for Alter-Globalisation</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>142</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The alter-globalisation, or global justice, movement – also more pejoratively referred to as the anti-globalisation movement – is the first great movement of the Internet age. It is the first to have a significant impact on a global scale – an impact defined by its networked characteristics and its use of digital network communications.</p>
                     <p>The widely understood characteristics of globalisation, against which this movement has reacted, are primarily the combination of global networks of communication with deregulated neoliberal economics. This has entailed the shifting of manufacturing from the centres of capital to the developing world, where low-wage, unprotected workers can</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7</label>
                     <title>Constructing the Common:</title>
                     <subtitle>Cooperation and Multitude</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>162</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the previous chapters I have focused on the quasi-autonomous recognition network, civil society and the political. But of vital importance to any activism is of course the aim of challenging the hegemony of neoliberal capitalism at its core: the capacity to exploit labour and expropriate the wealth it creates. This final chapter will accordingly address the role of labour, production and alternative models of social reproduction – and here the notion of the common is pivotal.</p>
                     <p>‘The common’ has emerged as one of the driving concepts of anti-capitalism. It offers a concept both to motivate action and to describe</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Notes</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>191</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>References</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>195</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt183pbtr.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Notes</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="editor" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <role>Compiled by</role>
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Carlton</surname>
                           <given-names>Sue</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>203</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
