

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvsn3pnr</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Law</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>ISO/IEC 27701:2019: An introduction to privacy information management</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>SHIPMAN</surname>
               <given-names>ALAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>WATKINS</surname>
               <given-names>STEVE</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>31</day>
         <month>01</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787781993</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787782006</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Alan Shipman</copyright-holder>
         <copyright-holder>Steve Watkins</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvsn3pnr"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>An ideal primer for anyone implementing a PIMS based on ISO/IEC 27701 &lt;p&gt;ISO/IEC 27701:2019 is a privacy extension to the international information security management standard, ISO/IEC 27001. It has been designed to integrate with ISO 27001 to extend an existing ISMS (information security management system) with additional requirements, enabling an organisation to establish, implement, maintain and continually improve its PIMS. &lt;p&gt;ISO 27701 provides guidance on the protection of privacy, including how organisations should manage personal information, and helps demonstrate compliance with privacy regulations around the world, such as the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation). &lt;p&gt;<italic>ISO/IEC 27701:2019: An introduction to privacy information management</italic> offers a concise introduction to the Standard, aiding those organisations looking to improve their privacy information management regime, particularly where ISO/IEC 27701:2019 is involved. It is intended for: &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Individuals looking for general information about privacy information management; and</p>
         <p> &lt;li&gt;Organisations implementing, or considering improving, a PIMS, particularly where the use of ISO/IEC 27701:2019 is being considered.</p>
         <p> &lt;p&gt;It will enable you to understand the basics of privacy information management, including: &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;What privacy information management means;  &lt;li&gt;How to manage privacy information successfully using a PIMS aligned to ISO/IEC 27701; &lt;li&gt;Key areas of investment for a business-focused PIMS; and &lt;li&gt;How your organisation can demonstrate the degree of assurance it offers with regard to privacy information management. This guide will prove useful throughout a number of stages in any privacy information management project - buy your copy today!</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="50"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHORS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>8</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This pocket guide is a companion to <italic>An Introduction to Information Security and ISO 27001:2013: A Pocket Guide</italic>, written by Steve Watkins. One of the major requirements for the management of personal information is that the information is processed in a secure manner. Hence, information security is one of the major elements that needs consideration when developing or improving a privacy information management system (PIMS).</p>
                     <p>This pocket guide provides a concise introduction to such considerations, aiding those organisations looking to improve their privacy information management regime, particularly where ISO/IEC 27701:2019 is involved.</p>
                     <p>This pocket guide is intended for:</p>
                     <p>Individuals looking</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>WHAT IS PRIVACY INFORMATION MANAGEMENT?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>10</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>‘Privacy’ is a term that is being increasingly used in life – but its meaning is not well understood. Wikipedia¹ describes it as “the ability of an individual or group to seclude themselves, or information about themselves, and thereby express themselves selectively”.</p>
                     <p>This guide to ISO/IEC 27701 focuses on the ‘information’ aspects of privacy. Hence, a privacy information management system (PIMS) deals with the processing of personal information – typically by organisations that an individual deals with.</p>
                     <p>How you and the organisations that you deal with look after your personal information and allow others to use it without adversely affecting</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>WHAT NEEDS TO BE CONSIDERED?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>16</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>So, how can an effective privacy information management system (PIMS) address the needs of an organisation? What needs to be addressed? Does this include issues relating to clients and customers, staff at all levels, suppliers and cultural issues? What must also be considered is that privacy information management is a topic that goes well beyond the remit of information technology, as personal information contained in any medium (such as paper) needs to be included in the organisation’s PIMS. The organisation would also benefit if the PIMS covers the whole of the organisation and its sub-contractors.</p>
                     <p>Having identified what privacy information</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>ISO/IEC 27701 AND THE PRIVACY INFORMATION MANAGEMENT SYSTEM REQUIREMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>20</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>ISO/IEC 27701:2019 is the international standard for privacy information management.⁴</p>
                     <p>It is structured in the same way as ISO/IEC 27001 – hence from the establishment of the privacy information management system (PIMS) through to its review and adaptation. There are also sections on performance evaluation and improvement. Addressing the requirements in this order, though, is not a requirement in itself.</p>
                     <p>One of the challenges of the International Standard is the variation of the definition of privacy information processing around the world. Indeed, the definition of personal information differs internationally. The ISO/IEC committee that develops privacy-related standards (ISO/IEC JTC1/SC27/WG5) has decided</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>LEGAL, REGULATORY AND CONTRACTUAL REQUIREMENTS AND BUSINESS RISK</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>24</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>As noted above, the processing of personal information is covered in most countries by legislation and/or regulations. Hence, any processing needs to be carried out within the local rules. Further, where the organisation is acting as a data processor, contractual requirements will be in place that dictate how the organisation is to act to ensure that the local rules are not compromised.</p>
                     <p>Thus, the specific requirements of a privacy information management system (PIMS) need to be determined in light of the appropriate local rules and contractual requirements. These requirements will need to be devised by the organisation, using whatever resources</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>PRIVACY INFORMATION MANAGEMENT CONTROLS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>30</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Having now gained an appreciation of the methodical approach to the selection of privacy information management controls and other ways of addressing risks, it is time to examine the controls defined in ISO/IEC 27701.</p>
                     <p>There are 31 controls in Annex A and 18 controls in Annex B of the International Standard, each split into 4 identical categories:</p>
                     <p>1. Conditions for collection and processing.</p>
                     <p>2. Obligations to PII principles.</p>
                     <p>3. Privacy by design and by default.</p>
                     <p>4. PII sharing, transfer and disclosure.</p>
                     <p>These are of course in addition to the controls included in Annex A of ISO/IEC 27001. These four categories are not themselves significant</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>CERTIFICATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>39</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The first point to clarify is that certification to ISO/IEC 27701 will not be accredited in accordance with ISO/IEC 17065 and hence is not an ‘EU GDPR certification’ as referenced to in Articles 42 and 43 of the Regulation. This is because ISO/IEC 17065 sets out the requirements for organisations certifying products and services. As ISO/IEC 27701 is an ISO management system standard (MSS), the appropriate accreditation standard is ISO/IEC 17021. Certification to ISO/IEC 27701 will provide an assurance that management processes are in place to protect privacy, with some important caveats as described in this chapter. The assurance that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7:</label>
                     <title>TERMS AND DEFINITIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>43</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>For access to a comprehensive set of all things relating to privacy information management, see:</p>
                     <p>www.itgovernance.co.uk/iso-27701.</p>
                     <p>For general advice that is as applicable to the home as the office, take a look at www.getsafeonline.org.</p>
                     <p>Definitions that have been taken from ISO/IEC 27000:2018 are identified thus: *</p>
                     <p>Accreditation: the scheme through which an authoritative body formally recognises a person’s or organisation’s competence to carry out specified tasks. Not to be confused with certification. Third-party certification (auditing) bodies become accredited and those they audit, subject to a successful outcome, become certificated.</p>
                     <p>Asset: anything that has value to the organisation. Information assets are</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvsn3pnr.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>47</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
