

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.7591/j.ctvh1dn1r</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">HD9993.E452 B86 2020</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Video games industry</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Employees</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">Job satisfaction</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject content-type="lcsh">Middle West</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Video game designers</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Job satisfaction</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">Middle West</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Video games industry</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Social aspects</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">Middle West</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Ethnology</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Middle West</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Labor &amp; Employment Relations</subject>
         <subject>Sociology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>A Precarious Game</book-title>
         <subtitle>The Illusion of Dream Jobs in the Video Game Industry</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Bulut</surname>
               <given-names>Ergin</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>15</day>
         <month>03</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781501746550</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781501746543</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">1501746545</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Cornell University Press</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Cornell University</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.7591/j.ctvh1dn1r"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;<italic>A Precarious Game</italic> is an ethnographic examination of video game production. The developers that Ergin Bulut researched for almost three years in a medium-sized studio in the U.S. loved making video games that millions play. Only some, however, can enjoy this dream job, which can be precarious and alienating for many others. That is, the passion of a predominantly white-male labor force relies on material inequalities involving the sacrificial labor of their families, unacknowledged work of precarious testers, and thousands of racialized and gendered workers in the Global South.  &lt;p&gt;<italic>A Precarious Game</italic> explores the politics of doing what one loves. In the context of work, passion and love imply freedom, participation, and choice, but in fact they accelerate self-exploitation and can impose emotional toxicity on other workers by forcing them to work endless hours. Bulut argues that such ludic discourses in the game industry disguise the racialized and gendered inequalities on which a profitable transnational industry thrives.  &lt;p&gt;Within capitalism, work is not just an economic matter, and the political nature of employment and love can still be undemocratic even when based on mutual consent. As Bulut demonstrates, rather than considering work simply as a matter of economics based on trade-offs in the workplace, we should consider the question of work and love as one of democracy rooted in politics.  </p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="222"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Preface</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgments</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>xi</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Introduction:</title>
                     <subtitle>FOR WHOM THE LOVE WORKS IN VIDEO GAME PRODUCTION?</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>One of the competing titles I considered early on for this book was “The Deluxe Suite on the <italic>Titanic</italic>: Precarious Playbor in the Digital Game Industry.” Clunky, without a doubt, but James Cameron’s historical drama has a lot in common with labor practices in the video game industry. The idea of using the <italic>Titanic</italic> as a metaphor for precarious labor in the video game industry goes back to a team meeting at Studio Desire, the ethnographic setting for this book.</p>
                     <p>Almost all Desire employees attended this meeting, which was held just a couple of months after the studio’s major franchise</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>THE UNEQUAL LUDOPOLITICAL REGIME OF GAME PRODUCTION:</title>
                     <subtitle>Who Can Play, Who Has to Work?</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>30</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>I am in a college library. Desire’s employees are about to meet with students aspiring to become game developers. The room is packed, full of ludic energy. It is decorated with posters of blockbuster games, including those Desire makes. Some of the developers are proudly wearing the T-shirts of their franchise. The meeting starts, and the vibrancy in the room transforms into laughter and serious conversations about having a future in the industry.</p>
                     <p>Attending some of these recruitment meetings alerted me to two issues about the conception of video game production as a glamorous profession. First, college students had no</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>THE END OF THE GARAGE STUDIO AS A TECHNOMASCULINE SPACE:</title>
                     <subtitle>Financial Security, Streamlined Creativity, and Signs of Friction</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>54</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>When Desire was still an independent studio, it had to constantly struggle to find financial resources for their games. This anxious rush to secure funding came to an end when the publicly traded Digital Creatives decided to acquire Desire in the 2000s. This was a moment of relief and validation, as Desire’s games were successful enough to draw the attention of one of the largest game publishers in the market.</p>
                     <p>This acquisition, however, brought its own problems. Digital Creatives’ coming to the scene meant “a contradictory drama of expropriation” (Huws 2014, 111) in that the laboring capacities of Desire’s developers</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>GAMING THE CITY:</title>
                     <subtitle>How a Game Studio Revitalized a Downtown Space in the Silicon Prairie</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>73</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The preceding chapter revealed the tensions between creativity and commerce as Desire transitioned from being an independent studio to a corporate one. A rationalized and streamlined creative labor process brought organizational shifts to the studio. Acquisition by a major player in the industry relieved the workers from the mandate to produce demos again and again, but this freedom also unleashed antagonisms and inequalities derived from Digital Creatives’ imperative to rationalize production along its own financialized logics.</p>
                     <p>Although space is fundamental to understanding how people and companies work on an everyday basis, media studies scholars, with a few notable exceptions (de</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4</label>
                     <title>THE PRODUCTION OF COMMUNICATIVE DEVELOPERS IN THE AFFECTIVE GAME STUDIO</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>89</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>
                        <italic>Titanic</italic> was only one metaphor among others that game developers used in describing their work. For instance, roller coaster, as a metaphor, came up in a conversation I had with Theodor, one of Desire’s art directors. Theodor was a big fan of superheroes and a very calm and kind man. Before becoming an art director, he had gone to school in the region and studied civil engineering. Then, he studied fine arts, focusing on painting, which led ultimately to a BFA. Following college, he was involved in sales and graphic design before he started his job at Desire. Before being</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5</label>
                     <title>REPRODUCING TECHNOMASCULINITY:</title>
                     <subtitle>Spouses’ Classed Femininities and Domestic Labor</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>105</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Right before the Christmas break in 2012, I was at Desire to interview Dan. It was a calm day. One could feel the holiday joy at the studio. Workers looked relaxed as they were enjoying snacks and beverages scattered around the studio. A white man in his early forties, Dan had started his career as a 3-D modeler in 1995. Around 2000, he joined a start-up where they had the budget for only three artists, which forced him to learn the roles of multiple positions. This ultimately turned Dan into a technical artist, his current role at Desire.</p>
                     <p>Dan was</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6</label>
                     <title>GAME TESTERS AS PRECARIOUS SECOND-CLASS CITIZENS:</title>
                     <subtitle>Degradation of Fun, Instrumentalization of Play</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>122</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Nathan Peters (2013), a former video game tester (quality assurance, or QA), once wrote an article for the gaming site Kotaku. Entitled “Don’t Sign That Contract,” this piece received about a thousand replies, and due to its impact, it was also featured on the prominent Gamasutra site. In his article, Peters gave aspiring video game testers and developers some sobering advice: “Never accept a job as a contractor.” Peters’s story is informative in terms of highlighting the hierarchies, pains, and pleasures of video game testing.</p>
                     <p>First, perhaps even more than core development, video game testing perfectly fits the “do what</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7</label>
                     <title>PRODUCTION ERROR:</title>
                     <subtitle>Layoffs Hit the Core Creatives</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>141</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The well-being of Desire’s developers and the success of Desire as a workplace structured by the unequal regime of ludopolitics depended on a few immediate factors and some external ones, which earlier chapters have foregrounded. The immediate factors included management’s re-organization of the labor process to streamline and better regulate creativity and the construction of a flexible and playful workplace to ensure productivity. Another essential factor was whether a developer was able to draw on the emotional infrastructure of a domestic partner. The level of occupational skills also was crucial to determine a worker’s status in the workplace hierarchy. Some</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>CONCLUSION:</title>
                     <subtitle>Reimagining Labor and Love in and beyond Game Production</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>159</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this book, I documented the inequalities surrounding video game production as a precarious labor of love. I told Desire’s story as it transitioned from being an independent studio to the flagship of Digital Creatives, only to be sold again after the parent company declared bankruptcy. A major lesson Desire’s story reveals is that failure and precarity are endemic to game production as innovative and creative work. Dream jobs in the video game industry are surrounded with illusions.</p>
                     <p>This book illustrates how a decidedly unequal regime of ludopolitics structures game production. At different levels and from varying angles, love anchors</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Notes</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>175</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>References</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>181</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvh1dn1r.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>197</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
