

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvc775sx</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Mathematics</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Infinity and the Mind</book-title>
         <subtitle>The Science and Philosophy of the Infinite</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>RUCKER</surname>
               <given-names>RUDY</given-names>
            </name>
            <role>FEATURING A NEW PREFACE BY THE AUTHOR</role>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>23</day>
         <month>07</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691191386</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780691191256</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0691191255</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>1995</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Princeton University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvc775sx"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;<bold>A dynamic exploration of infinity</bold>  &lt;p&gt;In <italic>Infinity and the Mind</italic>, Rudy Rucker leads an excursion to that stretch of the universe he calls the "Mindscape," where he explores infinity in all its forms: potential and actual, mathematical and physical, theological and mundane. Using cartoons, puzzles, and quotations to enliven his text, Rucker acquaints us with staggeringly advanced levels of infinity, delves into the depths beneath daily awareness, and explains Kurt Gödel's belief in the possibility of robot consciousness. In the realm of infinity, mathematics, science, and logic merge with the fantastic. By closely examining the paradoxes that arise, we gain profound insights into the human mind, its powers, and its limitations. This Princeton Science Library edition includes a new preface by the author.  </p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>v</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE TO THE 2019 EDITION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Rucker</surname>
                           <given-names>Rudy</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE TO THE 2005 EDITION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Rucker</surname>
                           <given-names>Rudy</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>xv</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE TO THE 1995 PAPERBACK EDITION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Rucker</surname>
                           <given-names>Rudy</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>xxiii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE TO THE FIRST EDITION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <string-name>R.v.B.R.</string-name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>xxv</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER ONE</label>
                     <title>INFINITY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The symbol for infinity that one sees most often is the lazy eight curve, technically called the lemniscate. This symbol was first used in a seventeenth century treatise on conic sections.¹ It caught on quickly and was soon used to symbolize infinity or eternity in a variety of contexts. For instance, in the 1700s the infinity symbol began appearing on the Tarot card known as the Juggler or the Magus. It is an interesting coincidence that the Qabbalistic symbol associated with this particular Tarot card is the Hebrew letter א, (pronounced alef), for Georg Cantor, the founder of the modern</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER TWO</label>
                     <title>ALL THE NUMBERS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>53</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter we will begin by tracing the development of the familiar real number system with its infinity of irrational numbers. Once one has accepted irrational numbers, there is really no reason not to accept infinitely large or transfinite numbers. So the second section of the chapter will be devoted to the transfinite ordinals and cardinals. The ordinals form a gappy number sequence somewhat like the natural numbers. It is a natural move to fill in these gaps as densely as possible, just as one fills in the space between, for instance, two and three with rational and real</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER THREE</label>
                     <title>THE UNNAMEABLE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>93</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter discusses three famous logical paradoxes: the Berry paradox, Richard’s paradox, and the paradox of the Liar. It is my contention that each of these paradoxes points to the existence of mental concepts that defy any exact formalization. Insofar as the human mind understands these paradoxes, it is in some sense infinite.</p>
                     <p>The first section deals with the Berry paradox—a paradox having to do with the impossibility of ever explaining exactly how we use language. This paradox has certain implications about the limitations of man-made “thinking machines.”</p>
                     <p>The second section discusses a number of topics relating to Richard’s</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER FOUR</label>
                     <title>ROBOTS AND SOULS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>157</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Are people just complicated robots … or do we have souls? On the one hand, being conscious certainly <italic>feels</italic> like something more than the mechanical working out of a computer program. But on the other hand, what could a soul possibly be? How could it act on matter? Might a machine have a soul?</p>
                     <p>A theorem of mathematical logic, Gödel’s Incompleteness Theorem, is widely thought to have a bearing on this constellation of problems. In this chapter we will begin by investigating Gödel’s famous theorem and end by making some speculations about mechanical intelligence and the nature of consciousness.</p>
                     <p>The</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER FIVE</label>
                     <title>THE ONE AND THE MANY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>189</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Think of Everything-the whole physical universe past and present, all the other possible universes, all the possible thoughts, all the mathematical sets—or <italic>can</italic> one think about it? The classical One-Many problem is this question: Can Everything be regarded as a unity, as a single definite thing? Is the world a One or a Many?</p>
                     <p>The first section of this chapter contains a brief account of some aspects of the classical One/Many problem. The problem allows itself to be stated in terms of set theory, so the following section, “What Is a Set?,” introduces the general notion of set, and</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>EXCURSION I</label>
                     <title>THE TRANSFINITE CARDINALS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>221</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this excursion into mathematics we make a detailed tour of the transfinite cardinals. The first section describes the way in which one argues from (i) the existence of the Absolute Infinite, and (ii) the Reflection Principle, to get (iii) the existence of the infinite numbers we need. The second section describes exactly how one works with these infinite numbers.</p>
                     <p>In the “Continuum” section we examine a number of sets having the cardinality <italic>c</italic> of the set of points on a mathematical line; then we discuss the difficult question of where <italic>c</italic> lies in the hierarchy of alefs.</p>
                     <p>The “Large</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>EXCURSION II</label>
                     <title>GÖDEL’S INCOMPLETENESS THEOREMS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>267</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this excursion we will examine a semiformal proof of Gödel’s Incompleteness Theorems. Even at this modest level of precision, the proof takes on a somewhat technical appearance, but this is unavoidable if we are to understand some of the finer points of Gödel’s proof.</p>
                     <p>In the “Formal Systems” section a number of preliminary notions are discussed: the idea of a formal system, the distinction between syntax and semantics, and the notions of consistency and completeness. This is all done with reference to the description of a particular formal system: Peano Arithmetic.</p>
                     <p>In the “Self-Reference” section we see how to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ANSWERS TO THE PUZZLE S AND PARADOXES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>295</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>307</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>329</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvc775sx.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>339</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
