

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv1fnkv02</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>ITIL® 4 Direct, Plan and Improve (DPI)</book-title>
         <subtitle>Your companion to the ITIL 4 Managing Professional and Strategic Leader DPI certification</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>AGUTTER</surname>
               <given-names>CLAIRE</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>25</day>
         <month>02</month>
         <year>2021</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787782822</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787782839</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2021</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Claire Agutter</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv1fnkv02"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ITIL® 4 Direct, Plan and Improve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you've achieved your ITIL® 4 Foundation certificate, you're
probably planning the next stage in your ITIL journey and which
qualification to work towards. DPI provides essential knowledge and
capabilities for service management professionals, supporting those
involved in directing or planning based on strategy and continual
improvement - a must-have skillset practitioners should seek beyond
Foundation level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DPI is the only one of the ITIL 4 advanced level courses that
leads to both Managing Professional (MP) and Strategic Leader (SL)
status. The module is aimed at managers and aspiring managers at
all levels, providing them with the practical skills needed to
improve themselves and their organisation by way of effective
strategic direction and delivering continual improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An excellent supplement to any training
course&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ITIL&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;® 4 Direct, Plan and Improve (DPI) - Your
companion to the ITIL 4 Managing Professional and Strategic Leader
DPI certification&lt;/em&gt; is a study guide designed to help students
pass the ITIL® 4 Direct, Plan and Improve module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of this book is based on the AXELOS &lt;em&gt;ITIL® 4:
Direct, Plan and Improve&lt;/em&gt; publication and the associated DPI
Strategist syllabus. It provides students with the information they
need to pass the DPI exam, and help them become a successful
practitioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suitable for existing ITIL v3 experts, ITIL 4 Managing
Professional (MP) students, ITIL 4 Strategic Leader (SL) students,
ITSM (IT service management) practitioners who are adopting ITIL 4,
approved training organisations, IT service managers, IT managers
and those in IT support roles, the book covers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key concepts;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Scope, key principles and methods;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The role of governance, risk and compliance;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Continual improvement;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Organisational change management;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Measurement and reporting;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Value streams and practices; and&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Exam preparation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A useful tool throughout your career&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to being an essential study aid, the author - a
seasoned ITSM professional - also provides additional guidance
throughout the book which you can lean on once your training and
exam are over. The book includes her own practical experience from
which she gives advice and points to think about along the way so
that you can refer back to this book for years to come - long after
you've passed your exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The essential link between your ITIL qualification and
the real world - buy this book today!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ITIL® is a registered trade mark of AXELOS Limited. All rights
reserved. This book is an official AXELOS licensed product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the author&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claire Agutter is a service management trainer, consultant and
author. In 2020, she was one of Computer Weekly's Top 50 Most
Influential Women in Tech. In 2018 and 2019 she was recognised as
an HDI Top 25 Thought Leader and was part of the team that won
itSMF UK's 2017 Thought Leadership Award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claire provides regular, free content to the ITSM community as
the host of the popular ITSM Crowd hangouts, and is the chief
architect for VeriSM™, the service management approach for the
digital age. She is the director of ITSM Zone, which provides
online ITSM training, and Scopism, a content and consulting
organisation and the publisher of the SIAM Body of Knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="194"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>2</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FOREWORD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Ford</surname>
                           <given-names>Rob</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Congratulations on purchasing <italic>ITIL® 4 Direct, Plan and Improve (DPI) – Your companion to the ITIL 4 Managing Professional and Strategic Leader DPI certification</italic>. In my opinion, the title perfectly describes the real value and purpose of the book. It is an invaluable source of guidance when preparing for the Direct, Plan and Improve certification, but perhaps more importantly, it serves as a critical companion for all professionals tasked with “setting strategy”.</p>
                     <p>Having read numerous service management guides and strategy books over the years, this one stands apart from the others as it combines the necessary revision support with a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>8</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>12</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The majority of this book is based on the <italic>ITIL® 4 Strategist – Direct, Plan &amp; Improve (DPI)</italic> publication and the associated DPI Strategist syllabus. DPI is the only one of the ITIL 4 advanced level courses that contributes to both Managing Professional (MP) and Strategic Leader (SL) status.</p>
                     <p>In addition to helping you prepare for your certification, I also want to give you some advice and guidance that will lead to you using this book once your training and exam are over. I’ve added some of my own practical experience to this book and given you advice and some points</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>DIRECT, PLAN AND IMPROVE KEY CONCEPTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter introduces the DPI key concepts that underpin the rest of the DPI content. These include:</p>
                     <p>DPI key terms;</p>
                     <p>Differentiating between key concepts, including:</p>
                     <p>Vision and mission;</p>
                     <p>Strategy, tactics, operations;</p>
                     <p>Governance, compliance, management; and</p>
                     <p>Policies, controls, guidelines.</p>
                     <p>Value, outcomes, costs and risks in a DPI context.</p>
                     <p>The ITIL 4 DPI manual is intended to support practitioners at all levels:</p>
                     <p>
                        <italic>“Regardless of organizational role, everyone has authority, even if it is limited to personal direction. Everyone should plan. And everyone should be contributing to, if not leading, improvement. The publication explores and explains principles, methods, and techniques that can be</italic>
                     </p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>DPI SCOPE, KEY PRINCIPLES AND METHODS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>33</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter studies the scope of control in more depth, including:</p>
                     <p>How to cascade objectives and requirements;</p>
                     <p>How to define effective policies, controls and guidelines; and</p>
                     <p>How to place decision-making authority at the correct level.</p>
                     <p>The dictionary definition of objective is “a thing aimed at or sought; a goal.”</p>
                     <p>Once the organisation’s mission and strategy are defined, they can be used to create and cascade objectives. Objectives are used to translate the strategy through the organisational levels, ensuring they stay aligned. Organisations create feedback loops by reporting on the achievement of objectives.</p>
                     <p>Figure 2 shows an example of an objectives</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>THE ROLE OF GOVERNANCE, RISK AND COMPLIANCE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>41</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Risk management is an important part of direction, planning and improvement. No organisation is immune to risk. Risks need to be managed to increase the chance of an organisation meeting its objectives. Direction must consider risk; plans must address risk; improvements need to consider risk.</p>
                     <p>Is someone responsible for risk management in your organisation? Are you aware of a risk register for your team, your product or the organisation as a whole? How would you report a risk that you became aware of? If you can’t answer these questions, that is a risk in its own right!</p>
                     <p>Risk is <italic>“a</italic>
                     </p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>FOCUS ON IMPROVEMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>52</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The DPI syllabus looks at all aspects of continual improvement and the use of the ITIL 4 continual improvement model. The topics covered in this chapter include:</p>
                     <p>How to use the continual improvement model in relation to the service value system (SVS);</p>
                     <p>How to identify assessment objectives, outputs, requirements and criteria;</p>
                     <p>How to select an appropriate assessment method;</p>
                     <p>How to define and prioritise improvement outcomes;</p>
                     <p>How to build, justify and advocate for a business case;</p>
                     <p>How to conduct improvement reviews and analyse lessons learned; and</p>
                     <p>How to embed continual improvement in the SVS.</p>
                     <p>Improvements are changes and can affect an</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>FOCUS ON ORGANISATIONAL CHANGE MANAGEMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>95</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Organisational change management (OCM) enables many direction, planning and improvement activities. The DPI syllabus requires you to understand topics including:</p>
                     <p>The nature, scope, and potential benefits of OCM;</p>
                     <p>Using OCM key principles and methods to:</p>
                     <p>Identify and manage different types of stakeholders;</p>
                     <p>Effectively communicate with and influence others;</p>
                     <p>Establish effective feedback channels; and</p>
                     <p>Establish effective interfaces across the service value chain.</p>
                     <p>Take a moment to think about any significant changes you have been affected by, for example a merger or acquisition, an office move, or organisation rebrand. How did you feel? Did you have all the information you needed? What</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>DPI, MEASUREMENT AND REPORTING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>136</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Measurement and continual improvement are embedded in every element of IT and IT service management. Without measurement and analysis, we cannot make good decisions. Choosing what to improve, directing activities and validating success all rely on effective measurement and reporting.</p>
                     <p>It can be tempting to think of measurement as dull, administrative, routine work. It’s anything but. Measuring the right things gives you a health check of your organisation, products, services, technology…and early warning when things are going wrong.</p>
                     <p>Measurement and reporting have moved beyond glossy monthly management packs. Try reading up on concepts like observability and how they relate to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7:</label>
                     <title>DPI, VALUE STREAMS AND PRACTICES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>158</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>An important part of building your own capabilities to direct, plan and improve is understanding how to direct, plan and improve value streams and practices, including:</p>
                     <p>The differences between value streams and practices, and how those differences affect DPI; and</p>
                     <p>How to select and use appropriate methods and practices:</p>
                     <p>Addressing the four dimensions.</p>
                     <p>Applying the guiding principles.</p>
                     <p>Value stream mapping.</p>
                     <p>Optimisation of workflow.</p>
                     <p>Elimination of waste.</p>
                     <p>Ensuring and utilising feedback.</p>
                     <p>Service management workflows can be visualised, organised and improved by using value streams. Organisations need to identify and map value streams, to allow them to analyse their current state. Value</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 8:</label>
                     <title>EXAM PREPARATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>183</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Here are the key facts about the ITIL 4 DPI exam:</p>
                     <p>The exam is 90 minutes. Extra time is allowable if English is not your native language and a translated paper isn’t available.</p>
                     <p>The exam is closed book – it’s just you and your knowledge.</p>
                     <p>It has 40 multiple-choice questions, and you must get 28 correct, or 70%, to pass.</p>
                     <p>There is no negative marking (so you don’t lose a mark if you get a question wrong).</p>
                     <p>There are 13 questions at Bloom’s Level 2 and 27 at Bloom’s Level 3.</p>
                     <p>Remember that this is a Strategist course, and is</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX:</title>
                     <subtitle>BANKSBEST CASE STUDY</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>186</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv1fnkv02.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>192</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
