

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv15r588t</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">N8600 .G735 2021</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Art</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Economic aspects</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">History</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject content-type="lcsh">19th century</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Art, Modern</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">19th century</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Art and society</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">History</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">19th century</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Art</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Historiography</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">Methodology</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Economic history</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Methodology</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Art &amp; Art History</subject>
         <subject>Economics</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Painting by Numbers</book-title>
         <subtitle>Data-Driven Histories of Nineteenth-Century Art</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>GREENWALD</surname>
               <given-names>DIANA SEAVE</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>16</day>
         <month>02</month>
         <year>2021</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691192451</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780691214948</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0691214948</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2021</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Princeton University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv15r588t"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A pathbreaking history of art that uses digital research
and economic tools to reveal enduring inequities in the formation
of the art historical canon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Painting by Numbers&lt;/em&gt;
presents a groundbreaking blend of art historical and social
scientific methods to chart, for the first time, the sheer scale of
nineteenth-century artistic production. With new quantitative
evidence for more than five hundred thousand works of art, Diana
Seave Greenwald provides fresh insights into the nineteenth
century, and the extent to which art historians have focused on a
limited-and potentially biased-sample of artwork from that time.
She addresses long-standing questions about the effects of
industrialization, gender, and empire on the art world, and she
models more expansive approaches for studying art history in the
age of the digital humanities. Examining art in France, the United
States, and the United Kingdom, Greenwald features datasets created
from indices and exhibition catalogs that-to date-have been used
primarily as finding aids. From this body of information, she
reveals the importance of access to the countryside for painters
showing images of nature at the Paris Salon, the ways in which
time-consuming domestic responsibilities pushed women artists in
the United States to work in lower-prestige genres, and how images
of empire were largely absent from the walls of London's Royal
Academy at the height of British imperial power. Ultimately,
Greenwald considers how many works may have been excluded from art
historical inquiry and shows how data can help reintegrate them
into the history of art, even after such pieces have disappeared or
faded into obscurity. Upending traditional perspectives on the art
historical canon, &lt;em&gt;Painting by Numbers&lt;/em&gt; offers an innovative
look at the nineteenth-century art world and its legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>[i]</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>[vii]</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1</label>
                     <title>What Is a Data-Driven History of Art?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the mid 1960s, the art historian Jules Prown was jeered. He was presenting new research at the annual meeting of the College Art Association, the principal professional art historical organization. Prown’s first slide—which showed an IBM punch card, then representative of cutting-edge computing technology—prompted some colleagues to boo.¹ In his essay “The Art Historian and the Computer,” Prown describes how he arrived at that presentation. He used a mainframe in the Yale University computer lab to examine the link between the socioeconomic backgrounds of American painter John Singleton Copley’s sitters and their preferences in portraiture. Recounting this</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2</label>
                     <title>The Historical Data of the Art World</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>23</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Artists and art historians have—often inadvertently—created valuable datasets for decades. Exhibition checklists, catalogues raisonnés, finding aids to archival sources, and collections information generated by museums are all rich sources of data. However, art historians do not generally conceive of them as such. Instead, we are trained to treat these resources as simple lists of information. This book repurposes, digitizes, and reconceives of many of these kinds of common art historical sources to create novel datasets. Of the wide range of sources deployed in this book, information about historical exhibitions provides the largest datasets; these data are graphed in</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3</label>
                     <title>Between City and Country:</title>
                     <subtitle>Industrialization and Images of Nature at the Paris Salon</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>52</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Reflecting on his arrival in the French capital from Normandy, Jean-François Millet supposedly wrote: “Paris, black, muddy, smoky … made the most painful and discouraging impression upon me. … The immense crowd of horses and carriages crossing and pushing each other, the narrow streets, the air and smell of Paris seemed to choke my head and heart, and almost suffocated me.”¹ The juxtaposition of this dark urban imagery with Millet’s preferred choice of subject matter—peasants like those in <italic>The Sower</italic> (fig. 2.5) and <italic>The Gleaners</italic> (fig. 2.16)—is evocative. It implies that Millet’s choice to depict rural subjects represents</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4</label>
                     <title>Why Have There Been No Great Women Artists?</title>
                     <subtitle>Artistic Labor and Time-Constraint in Nineteenth-Century America</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>85</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The Guerrilla Girls, an anonymous feminist artist collective founded in 1985, call attention to systematic gender and race discrimination in the art world by creating posters and handbills that feature a mix of dark humor, politics, and statistics.¹ One of their best-known posters (fig. 4.1) features a send-up of French artist Jean-Auguste-Dominique Ingres’s <italic>Odalisque</italic> (1814). In it, the Guerrilla Girls, who had collected data on the representation of women in major museum collections, posed a clear question: Do women have to be naked to get into the Metropolitan Museum of Art? The answer appeared to be “yes”—the collective concluded</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5</label>
                     <title>Implied But Not Shown:</title>
                     <subtitle>Empire at the Royal Academy</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>115</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In 1913, the total population of the British Empire was 412 million people—ten times the population of Britain itself.¹ The British controlled roughly one-quarter of the world’s land surface and served as global gatekeepers of the oceans.² Considering the sheer scale of the imperial enterprise, the introduction to the popular history book <italic>The Rise and Fall of the British Empire</italic> (1994) boldly states: “Possession of an empire profoundly influenced the ways in which the British thought of themselves and the rest of the world.”³ Though Lawrence James’s bestselling work is not academic, this statement succinctly summarizes an assumption that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6</label>
                     <title>Conclusion</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>153</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Having presented these constituent case studies focused on specific geographies, themes, and research questions, this conclusion turns to some general takeaways from a data-driven history of art and its place in the discipline of art history. To do this, it takes a brief detour into philosophy. From Plato to Kant and Adorno, many scholars have taken on the field of aesthetics. They have proposed standards and tests by which one can define art and judge its quality.¹ Of these efforts, the most useful for the purposes of this book is David Hume’s 1757 essay “Of the Standard of Taste.” The</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX A</title>
                     <subtitle>Further Information about Compilation of and Access to Data Sources</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>157</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX B</title>
                     <subtitle>A Brief Historiography of the Study of Jean-François Millet and the Relationship between City and Country in Nineteenth-Century French Rural Genre Painting</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>159</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX C</title>
                     <subtitle>Subject Headings in the Whiteley Index Identified as Rural, Industrial, Religious, and Family Tags</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>165</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX D</title>
                     <subtitle>Full Regression Tables, How to Read Regression Tables, and Further Discussion of Results</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>167</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX E</title>
                     <subtitle>French Transcription of Letters Written by Jean-François Millet</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>175</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX F</title>
                     <subtitle>Still Life Keywords Identified in Titles of Works Exhibited at the National Academy of Design, 1826–1900</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>177</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX G</title>
                     <subtitle>Further Information about Geographic Classifications of Royal Academy Data and Imperial Keywords</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>178</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgments</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>180</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Notes</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>184</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Bibliography</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>215</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctv15r588t.19</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>235</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
