

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Library Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>The Universal Service Desk (USD)</book-title>
         <subtitle>Implementing, controlling and improving service delivery</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>JOHNSON</surname>
               <given-names>BRIAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>DE ROUW</surname>
               <given-names>LÉON-PAUL</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>28</day>
         <month>05</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787781481</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787781498</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Brian Johnson</copyright-holder>
         <copyright-holder>Léon-Paul De Rouw</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv10crcf1"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> A universal service desk (USD) is the central point of contact between a service provider and users for everyday activities, and within an organisation for all requests for and enquiries about the services provided to customers, both internal and external. The USD is a concept of service delivery and resolution through different channels (Internet, post, intranet, phone, email, physical counter). It also covers account management and its focus on customer relationships at different levels in the organisation. The Universal Service Desk (USD) - Implementing, controlling and improving service delivery defines what a USD is, why it is valuable to an organisation and how to build and implement one. This practical guide gives advice about: The use of software tools; Service sites; Self-service; Call centre functionality; Account management; Processes between the USD and back office; Quality management; Competence management; Capabilities; and The service catalogue. It also discusses the evolution of the USD as part of integrated workplace management. This book is ideal for those working in service management and the service desk industry, from managers to employees, and can also be used by students to understand all the components that relate to a USD. Understand the essentials of any USD - buy this book today!</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="244"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>2</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHORS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>6</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>13</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The USD directs the bundling/combining and delivery of user or customer calls and by default, is the front office intermediary between customer and delivery organisation, or ‘back office’. The USD can be found anywhere, internal service organisation (IT, facilities, HR etc.), as a customer service centre (call centre, help centre etc.) for any enterprise, or as a temporary single point of contact for events, incidents, requests or large scale interventions. Depending on whom you consult, the USD has its own language, approach and good practice.</p>
                     <p>For example, if you mentioned the USD to someone in IT, they will refer to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>16</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>THE USD IN THE ENTERPRISE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>17</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In general, enterprises require that all service processes relating to customers are handled in line with the perspective of the customer. This does not happen when the favourite framework of the IT organisation or department becomes the goal, rather than the tool. Focusing on the customer’s perspective usually means that all services offered through the USD should be streamlined for efficiency and channelled for ease of access.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will become acquainted with the subject of the USD and concepts of service delivery. Readers will understand how this book is structured. It is intended as a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>THE USD AS A CONCEPT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>23</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The USD as a concept constitutes a coherent aggregate of intranet, phone, email and digital document handling, desk and account management. The demand process is structured according to the front office/back office principle. After reading this chapter the reader will be aware of the definition and meaning of the USD for the enterprise, which tasks belong to a USD and how the USD can be considered in such a way that it is applicable as concept in all enterprises.</p>
                     <p>The USD is the central point of contact for the service organisation. It accepts all customer enquiries, calls and tickets; qualifies</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>DELIVERING PRODUCTS AND SERVICES THROUGH THE USD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>30</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Products and services that are offered by the USD depend on their attributes, on the choices made in relation to service quality and on the nature of the enterprise (whether the preference is the ‘all in one USD’ or a ‘hub-and-spoke’ distributed set).</p>
                     <p>A smart classification of products and services, and the way they can be requested, helps to efficiently organise demand and delivery. In this way, it is possible to bring about an effective balance in matching specific customer demand and generic standardised service delivery.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader should understand the attributes of the USD (or</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>THE USD CUSTOMERS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>41</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Users of the USD should be considered customers for internal services. External users would be very surprised if they were not. Customers can be categorised in customer groups/ segments. One of which will inevitably be ‘awkward…’. Each segment has its own attributes. The added value of the USD is that it can act as a central portal to any question on service products and services.</p>
                     <p>After reading this you will understand the implications of being a customer of the USD, what the added value of the USD is, and how customer groups can be segmented. With luck, you will also</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>FROM DESIGN TO REALITY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>54</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter explains the concept of the USD as an integral front office for the service organisation. We also discuss the design and development of improvements to the USD, for example the hiring and training of staff.</p>
                     <p>Five phases are posited, each with a number of steps. We begin with ambition and the necessary tasks, and end with an operating USD. After reading this chapter, the reader should understand the approach to creating, developing and improving a USD.</p>
                     <p>An action plan structures thinking and development. You can compare this with building a house. Not the USD, for sure we cannot</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>THE SERVICE DESK OF BREDA UNIVERSITY OF APPLIED SCIENCES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>63</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>At Breda University of Applied Sciences (BUAS), the central service desk provides services to all students, visitors and employees. The service desk accepts calls for several disciplines in the organisation (IT, housing, facilities, and cleaning) and also provides specific services for the academies.</p>
                     <p>BUAS provides Bachelor’s and Master’s programmes in the following areas:</p>
                     <p>Tourism;</p>
                     <p>Facility;</p>
                     <p>Hotel;</p>
                     <p>Built environment;</p>
                     <p>Games;</p>
                     <p>Leisure and events; and</p>
                     <p>Logistics and media.</p>
                     <p>In addition, it conducts applied research, supports emerging entrepreneurs, develops knowledge under license, and provides courses and training for professionals.</p>
                     <p>BUAS is the new name of NHTV Breda and has approximately 8,000 students and</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>SUMMARY OF PART 1</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>74</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>SECTION FOR YOUR NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>75</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>77</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7:</label>
                     <title>SERVICE MANAGEMENT SOFTWARE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>78</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In addition to the commitment and competence of employees, the use of ICT in the provision of information now largely determines the efficiency and professionalism of a USD. Service management software (SMS) in facilities is called integrated workplace management system (IWMS) or facilities management information system (FMIS), and in IT it is called IT service management (ITSM) tools. A SMS is the ‘beating ICT heart’ of the USD and offers ample functionality for the support of a USD.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will be aware of the scope of SMS and what function this service has within the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 8:</label>
                     <title>THE VIRTUAL USD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>90</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The virtual USD is the first level of service within the USD. Often, it is an intranet service portal combined with the specific applications of the SMS. The major advantage of a virtual USD is that users can use self-service as part of their workplace support (reservations, notifications, complaints, etc.) independent of time. An important advantage for the service organisation (or company), is that these reports can generally be processed easily and directly.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will better understand how services are organised via the Internet or intranet, and how this allows users to access and request</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 9:</label>
                     <title>CALL CENTRE FUNCTIONALITY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>100</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The second level of service is called the call centre functionality of the USD. The characteristic feature of this level is that there is no physical customer contact, and this functionality does not have to be located at the same location where the service page is offered, or where the desk is located. Contact, for example, takes place via telephone, email or chat.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will gain insight into what is necessary for the design of the call centre functionality, the second level of service in the USD.</p>
                     <p>The call centre functionality of the USD is</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.19</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 10:</label>
                     <title>THE SERVICE COUNTER</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>106</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The development of the USD is the result of the physical translation of the one-stop-shop concept. The starting point is that the customer can go to one central physical location within the building for all questions about internal products and services. The design and construction of the physical USD, however, needs some thought. This concerns not only the non-tangible aspects, (organisation, function and philosophy), but also the very tangible aspects, such as materials, colour, location and space.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will have insight into the subjects that are related to the construction of the physical USD counter.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.20</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 11:</label>
                     <title>ACCOUNT MANAGEMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>111</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Not everything can be automated or standardised. In some cases, interaction with the customer will be needed to find out exactly what they require. In general, we see this task arising in two ways, initially via the service request, via an interview with an employee at the desk or over the telephone. In some cases the level of knowledge of the interviewer or the mandate is insufficient. In these instances, it is easier and more effective to enter into a personal conversation with the customer bringing account management into contact.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will have insight into</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.21</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 12:</label>
                     <title>EXPERT USD STAFF</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>117</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>No USD will function without employees (hold back the tears); they determine the success of the USD. So, to operate professionally, the USD must have expert staff who like to help and serve customers.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will have insight into the importance of well-trained employees with the right competencies for a well-functioning USD.</p>
                     <p>With a professional USD, a service organisation strives for a customer-oriented attitude. In order to be able to make this happen, the right expertise and the right behaviour must be fulfilled for employees, and the USD must also have the power to oversee</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.22</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 13:</label>
                     <title>THE USD AND BACK OFFICE DEPENDENCIES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>129</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Proper handling of customer questions requires a demarcation between USD and back office processes. The USD exists only because of a back office, and a successful USD depends on the working of the processes between the USD and back office. The processes within and between the USD and the back office should be recorded and often secured in contracts (external customers) and/or agreements. These contracts/agreements in turn should be based on the way in which requests are to be handled.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader should better understand how processes between request and delivery come into being, the relationship</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.23</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 14:</label>
                     <title>BUSINESS INFORMATION FOR THE USD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>142</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The USD can only function properly if it has the right information. Information should be both timely and accurate, so the USD must be well connected to various business processes served by the service and facilities organisation.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will better understand what information the USD needs and how service management can ensure that the USD is connected to this information. A practical graphical diagram (‘metro map’, based on the London Underground concept by Harry Beck), is also described and with which these processes can be made visible in relation to the USD.</p>
                     <p>As discussed in</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.24</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 15:</label>
                     <title>USD MANAGEMENT AND ORGANISATION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>150</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The USD can be set up within the enterprise when all of the following elements of the USD structure are in place:</p>
                     <p>Mission</p>
                     <p>Vision</p>
                     <p>Products and services to be delivered</p>
                     <p>Focus</p>
                     <p>Insight into customer needs</p>
                     <p>Processes between USD and back office</p>
                     <p>Relationship with IT</p>
                     <p>The required skills of the employees</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will better understand how the USD can be organised and positioned within the enterprise. It is clear, that the final design will differ for every enterprise.</p>
                     <p>The USD vision, mission and objectives are derived from the enterprise and are dictated by the environment (market</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.25</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 16:</label>
                     <title>IT AND THE SERVICE HELP DESK – REFLECTIONS BY A PROVIDER OF MANAGED SERVICES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>167</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The manager and a small team of analysts employed by a provider of managed services (outsourced service desk capabilities), were interviewed to discuss USD concepts such as their specific application to their ‘ITIL compliant’ service desk (which was one of their advertised capabilities), and the differences they observed when customers focused on IT services or wider managed services, including facilities management issues.</p>
                     <p>We wish to express our thanks to the interviewees for their time and patience.</p>
                     <p>The enterprise is international, though this interview was restricted to a single facility in the UK where the outsourcer employs over 300 people in</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.26</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>SUMMARY OF PART 2</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>171</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The design and construction of the USD are described in fifteen steps divided over five phases. Some steps are sequential while others can be executed in parallel. The different parts of the USD, which have to be developed and set up in different steps, are explained separately in part 2. There we cover the service or facility management information system (FMIS, SMS or ITSM Tool), the virtual USD, the call centre functionality, the account management, the interest of expert employees, the way in which the processes between the USD and the back office are designed and secured, and the structure</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.27</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>SECTION FOR YOUR NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>173</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.28</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>175</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.29</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 17:</label>
                     <title>THE USD AS A KEY TO MANAGEMENT AND CONTROL</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>176</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The answer to that question provides the basis for a mission statement and it requires the creation of a strategy to fulfil that mission. The service management strategy should not be limited to IT or facilities; it must identify the means to fulfil the whole enterprise’s needs. The first step is to understand and influence the enterprise’s functioning. The second step would be to take responsibility to steer overall service management, and therefore this concerns controlling service and facilities functions in their entirety. The decision to embrace both internal customer service and external customers is one of the key strategic</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.30</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 18:</label>
                     <title>CONTRACT MANAGEMENT AND THE USD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>186</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Enterprises purchase many types of movable goods, including deliveries of everything from flowers for the boardroom, to building materials and services. This will also cover office furniture, cleaning and catering, management, maintenance and the hiring of external personnel, organisational advice, and ICT services or accountancy services. Contract management plays the leading role, though the USD has an operational role in contract management.</p>
                     <p>Every enterprise arranges purchasing differently. In large enterprises, there are separate purchasing departments. For example, one enterprise may have multiple ‘category’ managers with substantive knowledge of their particular market and the needs of their own enterprise. Small enterprises</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.31</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 19:</label>
                     <title>SUCCESS CRITERIA</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>194</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The structure and functioning of the USD determine the extent to which success factors can be met. Factors for a successful USD are related to good accessibility, accurate information, effective and efficient operation and the conviction among customers that they have been effectively helped.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader can identify factors that describe a successful USD.</p>
                     <p>The impact of a USD service depends in part on its interaction with customers. Often customers will actively participate in the service process and their experiences are in part determined by the interaction with those who provide services. The result is that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.32</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 20:</label>
                     <title>QUALITY IMPROVEMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>198</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In order to guarantee the quality of service, you need to understand the activities and their consequences and this insight helps an organisation make the right decisions. But what does this mean and how do you organise this?</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will better understand the need for quality management in the USD. Examples will provide insights on how to deal with criteria and standards, and how these can be translated into a USD staffing occupation requirement.</p>
                     <p>In order to safeguard or realise the goals of a successful USD, the assurance and improvement of quality is required. According</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.33</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 21:</label>
                     <title>IMPLEMENTATION AND FURTHER DEVELOPMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>208</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Successful implementation and further development of an existing USD will only be achieved if the consequences of the adjustments, and therefore of the improvements have been carefully considered beforehand. This means that the project team responsible for the design and final construction of the USD must first take into account the environment in which the USD operates, and the parties involved. This requires management involvement and a strategic approach.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will have insight into the way in which the implementation of a new USD, and further improvement of it can be tackled systematically. Attention must</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.34</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 22:</label>
                     <title>IMPROVEMENT POSSIBILITIES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>214</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the previous chapters, many ideas and examples have been given regarding how new ambitions may lead to adapted designs and, therefore, to structural changes. However, this is not always possible and sometimes quick and dirty improvements and solutions are required. In this chapter, thirty different ideas are offered and suggestions are presented; these are divided into four themes:</p>
                     <p>1. Quality</p>
                     <p>2. Employees</p>
                     <p>3. Delivery</p>
                     <p>4. Orchestration and policy</p>
                     <p>We do not aim to provide an exhaustive list because every situation is different. Use these ideas as a source of inspiration and as starting points for your own USD. Be well aware of the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.35</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 23:</label>
                     <title>THE USD OF THINGS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>221</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The classic boundaries of enterprises are fading under the influence of technological innovations, cultural changes and globalisation. As a result, in some enterprises the support services will change substantially in the coming years, and with them the role of the USD.</p>
                     <p>After reading this chapter, the reader will better understand how new ideas will change the USD, perhaps as an ‘intelligent hub’.</p>
                     <p>In the previous chapters, the USD position within the enterprise’s management was established based on sound principles and the concept of building blocks. The USD was positioned as part of the service management concept of the enterprise, more</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.36</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 24:</label>
                     <title>A CASE STUDY FROM THE UK GOVERNMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>229</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>One of the key reforms in government was to brigade a number of government agencies (departments that were staffed and run by public servants, but were not funded by the public purse and were expected to charge other government departments for their services), under one commercial structure.</p>
                     <p>The purpose of the new organisation was to support the procurement and acquisition process of public sector organisations in the UK through policy and process guidance, and the negotiation of overarching service and provision frameworks. This was intended to improve value for money for the taxpayer, optimising the level of taxpayer’s equity directed</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.37</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>SUMMARY OF PART 3</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>235</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.38</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>SECTION FOR YOUR NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>236</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.39</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 25:</label>
                     <title>FINALLY … FOR THE CUSTOMER:</title>
                     <subtitle>THE USD AS AN INTERFACE</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>237</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>If you have read right through this book, you have discovered that behind something as simple as a USD is a complex world of pain… This book is not an instruction manual but a book about the different ingredients required and how these ingredients interact. It is up to you to assess which parts apply to your own situation. There are examples, tips and practical advice, but in the end you need to decide for yourself what will or will not work in your own environment.</p>
                     <p>An important feature of enterprises is their interaction with customers. This interaction has become</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.40</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>240</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv10crcf1.41</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>243</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
