

<book xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctt19qgf1f</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Application security in the ISO27001:2013 Environment</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>VASUDEVAN</surname>
               <given-names>VINOD</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib2">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>MANGLA</surname>
               <given-names>ANOOP</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib3">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>UMMER</surname>
               <given-names>FIROSH</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib4">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>SHETTY</surname>
               <given-names>SACHIN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib5">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>PAKALA</surname>
               <given-names>SANGITA</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib6">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>ANBALAHAN</surname>
               <given-names>SIDDHARTH</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>15</day>
         <month>10</month>
         <year>2015</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781849287685</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <edition>2</edition>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Vinod Vasudevan et al</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt19qgf1f"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>
Web application security as part of an ISO 27001-compliant
information security management system

&lt;p&gt;Web application vulnerabilities are a common point of intrusion
for cyber criminals. As cyber security threats proliferate and
attacks escalate, and as applications play an increasingly critical
role in business, organisations urgently need to focus on web
application security to protect their customers, their interests
and their assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although awareness of the need for web application security is
increasing, security levels are nowhere near enough: according to
the 2015 Trustwave Global Security Report, 98% of tested web
applications were vulnerable to attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SMEs in particular should be very concerned about web
application security: many use common, off-the-shelf applications
and plugins - such as Internet Explorer, Java, Silverlight, and
Adobe Reader and Flash Player - which often contain exploitable
vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Application Security in the ISO 27001:2013 Environment&lt;/em&gt;
explains how organisations can implement and maintain effective
security practices to protect their web applications - and the
servers on which they reside - as part of a wider information
security management system by following the guidance set out in the
international standard for information security management, ISO
27001.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book describes the methods used by criminal hackers to
attack organisations via their web applications and provides a
detailed explanation of how you can combat such attacks by
employing the guidance and controls set out in ISO 27001.&lt;/p&gt;

Product overview

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second edition, updated to reflect ISO 27001:2013 as well as
best practices relating to cryptography, including the PCI SSC's
denigration of SSL in favour of TLS.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Provides a full introduction to ISO 27001 and information
security management systems, including implementation
guidance.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Describes risk assessment, management and treatment
approaches.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Examines common types of web app security attack, including
injection attacks, cross-site scripting, and attacks on
authentication and session management, explaining how each can
compromise ISO 27001 control objectives and showing how to test for
each attack type.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Discusses the ISO 27001 controls relevant to application
security.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lists useful web app security metrics and their relevance to
ISO 27001 controls.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Provides a four-step approach to threat profiling, and
describes application security review and testing approaches.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sets out guidelines and the ISO 27001 controls relevant to
them, covering: 

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;input validation&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;authentication&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;authorisation&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;sensitive data handling and the use of TLS rather than SSL&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;session management&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;error handling and logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Describes the importance of security as part of the web app
development process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

About the authors

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vinod Vasudevan&lt;/strong&gt;, CISSP, is the chief technology
officer (CTO) at Paladion. Before co-founding Paladion, Vinod
worked with Microsoft. He wrote the chapter 'Application Security
and ISO27001'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anoop Mangla&lt;/strong&gt; is a risk specialist in banking
and finance, and an expert on the effectiveness of security
technologies in organisations' security. He wrote the chapter
'Introduction to Application Security Threats'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firosh Ummer&lt;/strong&gt;, CISA, ISO27001 LA, CBCP, BS15000
LA, is co-founder of Paladion and head of the ISO 27001 consulting
practice. Firosh wrote the chapter 'Threat Profiling and Security
Testing'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sachin Shetty&lt;/strong&gt;, CISSP, is a senior application
security engineer with Paladion. He wrote the chapter 'Attacks on
Applications'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sangita Pakala&lt;/strong&gt;, GCIH, is Head of Application
Security Projects at Paladion. She wrote the chapter 'Secure
Development Lifecycle'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Siddharth Anbalahan&lt;/strong&gt; is a senior application
security engineer. He has developed anti-phishing toolkits to
enable banks to detect phishing attacks in real time. Siddharth
wrote the chapter 'Secure Coding Guidelines'.&lt;/p&gt;
</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="254"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHORS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Vasudevan</surname>
                           <given-names>Vinod</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>10</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION TO THE INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION SECURITY STANDARDS ISO27001 AND ISO27002</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>11</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It is a truism to say that information is the currency of the information age. Information is, in many cases, the most valuable asset possessed by an organisation, even if that information has not been subject to a formal and comprehensive valuation.</p>
                     <p>IT governance is the discipline that deals with the structures, standards and processes that boards and management teams apply to effectively manage, protect and exploit their organisations’ information assets.</p>
                     <p>Information security management is the subset of IT governance that focuses on protecting and securing an organisation’s information assets. The international standard ISO27000 defines information security as the “preservation</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>THE ISO27001 IMPLEMENTATION PROJECT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>22</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The successful design, development and implementation of an ISMS in line with the requirements of ISO27001 is a significant project. There are a number of important aspects to such a project, all of which are developed in detail in <italic>IT Governance: An International Guide to ISO27001/ISO27002</italic>. A project team will need to be set up and it will need the full support of management.</p>
                     <p>Previously, ISO27001 mandated the use of the Plan-Do-Check-Act (PDCA) model to create a compliant ISMS. The 2013 update, however, allows for the use of either PDCA or comparable continual improvement management methods such as ITIL<sup>®</sup> or</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>RISK ASSESSMENT</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>34</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Any organisation pursuing ISO27001 certification for its information security management system will need an approach to risk assessment that meets the requirements of ISO/IEC27001:2013. Clause 6.1.2 of ISO27001 requires the organisation to take an explicitly risk-based approach to the selection and operation of information security controls.<sup>10</sup> The approach to risk in ISO2001:2013 can be described as scenario-based rather than asset-based; each risk is treated across the entire organisation rather than on an asset-by-asset basis.</p>
                     <p>Risk management is a discipline for dealing with non-speculative risks - those risks from which only a loss can occur. In other words, speculative risks can</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION TO APPLICATION SECURITY THEATS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>45</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>All businesses today use software automation to streamline their core functions - selling, procuring, production and customer relationship management.</p>
                     <p>People performing these functions make use of data to perform their work. For example, employees working in a bank use customers’ account balances to clear issued cheques, to create account statements or to calculate interest paid. The data - the customers’ account balances in this case - is fundamental for this function of the bank. Any loss or inaccuracy of customers’ account balances will jeopardise the bank’s functioning. Similarly, since customers’ account balances are important data, a bank wants only authorised</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>APPLICATION SECURITY AND ISO27001</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>51</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>As the threats to applications increase, we need a structured approach for managing the security of our applications. ISO27001 is the international standard for information security management best practice, and is the most comprehensive standard for information security. It provides a framework to manage the security of our applications.</p>
                     <p>ISO27001 defines controls for the acquisition, development, customisation, maintenance and operation of applications. The controls are process-centric and technology-independent, thus making the Standard strong. The Standard does not specify the technical details for the controls. It is expected that organisations will draw on the more detailed technical guidance available from specific</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>ATTACKS ON APPLICATIONS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>99</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter we will look at some of the common attacks on applications and their effects. The object of this chapter is to show you how easy many application layer attacks are.</p>
                     <p>Application-specific attacks can be targeted at a specific user or at a large mass of users at one time. These attacks are, increasingly, the preserve of automated ‘bots’<sup>18</sup> that scan as many systems on or linked to the Internet as possible with an eye to exploiting flawed or vulnerable applications. The financial implications of these exploits, the loss of reputation, the resultant downtime and lost productivity can</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7:</label>
                     <title>SECURE DEVELOPMENT LIFECYCLE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>145</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Now that we have seen some of the more common attacks on applications, let’s take a look at the vital task of securing software. All of us usually focus on the functionality of our software first. We overlook security when software is first built. Security often only comes into the picture after the application has been developed and deployed.</p>
                     <p>But research shows that the cost and effort of fixing security weaknesses after deployment is much higher than building security into the application in the first place.</p>
                     <p>Having said that, please note that security is not a one-time activity. If security</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 8:</label>
                     <title>THREAT PROFILING AND SECURITY TESTING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>178</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In Chapter 7 we discussed the approach of integrating security requirement analysis, design, implementation and testing into the software development lifecycle stages. In this chapter we will discuss the process of identifying threats to the application and using them in different security testing methods.</p>
                     <p>Studying the motivations and methods of an adversary is the first step in designing a secure application. The goals and motivations of an adversary are treated as the <italic>threats</italic> to the application. The structured process of identifying and documenting all possible security threats is called <italic>threat profiling</italic>. The justification for implementing an application security feature is</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 9:</label>
                     <title>SECURE CODING GUIDELINES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>206</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In Chapter 7 we discussed the role of secure coding guidelines in ensuring that applications are secure. In this chapter we look at some of the most important guidelines developers should follow; for a comprehensive look at the topic, the OWASP Secure Coding Practices Guide is recommended.<sup>50</sup> Since many of these are low-level code writing requirements, we illustrate the guidelines with code snippets. As the coding guidelines are platform-agnostic and apply to all popular platforms, we show code snippets only for one platform, .NET. The examples we show with .NET can be ported to J2EE, PHP, Perl and other platforms,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctt19qgf1f.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ITG RESOURCES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>251</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
