

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvrnfpwx</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Philosophy</subject>
         <subject>Religion</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>AI and IA</book-title>
         <subtitle>Utopia or Extinction?</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="editor" id="contrib1">
            <role>Edited by</role>
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Peters</surname>
               <given-names>Ted</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>01</day>
         <month>09</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781925679212</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781925679236</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">1925679233</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>ATF Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Hindmarsh, SA</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>the authors</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvrnfpwx"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>Will advances in AI (Artificial Intelligence) or IA (Intelligence Amplification) lead to the extinction of the human race as we know it? Or, will superintelligence lead to utopia? In this collection of thoughtful essays, we must first get clear on the question: is artificial intelligence actually intelligent or not? Only with an affirmative answer could our techies proceed toward their goal: the creation of a superintelligence that leads through transhumanism to a posthuman entity that would replace today's human. Should today's moderately intelligent human species voluntarily go extinct to make way for a more intelligent species to succeed us in evolutionary history? These scientific questions are addressed in this volume in light of their theological, ethical, and social implications.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="188"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>v</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Human Utopia or Human Extinction?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Peters</surname>
                           <given-names>Ted</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The fast-moving frontier of Artificial Intelligence (AI) in league with Intelligence Amplification (IA) prompt anxiety in some quarters. When it comes to smart phones or autonomous gadgets for vacuuming our living room carpets, a brief moment of ‘ wow’ is quickly superseded by ‘ oh, hum’ Robotic intelligence, though initially fascinating, seems to prompt no worries about the short-range future. But, what about the long-range future? When we forecast the evolution of posthuman superintelligence that will either bring a technological utopia or render <italic>Homo sapiens</italic> extinct, anxiety causes us to ask existential questions. In this issue of <italic>Ethics,</italic> we ask</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>The Enchantment of Artificial Intelligence</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Herzfeld</surname>
                           <given-names>Noreen</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Noreen L Herzfeld is Nicholas and Bernice Reuter Professor of Science and Religion at the College of St. Benedict and St. John’s University in Collegeville, Minnesota. She is author of <italic>In Our Image: Artificial Intelligence and the Human Spirit</italic> (Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 2002). In July 2017 at a meeting of the National Governor’s Association, Tesla founder and CEO Elon Musk issued the following warning regarding the future of artificial intelligence: ‘AI is a fundamental existential risk for human civilization, and I don’t think people fully appreciate that.’ Claiming access to cutting-edge AI technology, Musk called for proactive government regulation, noting</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Artificial Intelligence, Transhumanism, and Frankenfear</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Peters</surname>
                           <given-names>Ted</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Ted Peters teaches systematic theology and ethics at the Graduate Theological Union in Berkeley, California, USA. He co-edits the journal, Theology and Science, at the Center for Theology and the Natural Sciences. He is author of God--<italic>The World’s Future</italic> (Fortress, 3rd ed, 2015) and co-author of <italic>Evolution from Creation to New Creation</italic> (Abingdon 2002). Along with two colleagues he is editing a new book, <italic>Religious Transhumanism and its Crit-</italic> 
                        <italic>ics</italic> (Lexington). He is author of a fiction thriller with a Transhumanist plot, Cyrus Twelve, with Aprocryphile Press. Visit his website: TedsTimelyTake. com.</p>
                     <p>In the climax of Dan Brown’s best-selling thriller,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Somnambulating Towards AI Dystopia?</title>
                     <subtitle>The Future of Rights and Freedoms</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Rochow</surname>
                           <given-names>Neville Grant</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>43</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Neville Rochow SC, LLB (Hons), LLM, (Adelaide), LLM (Deakin) is a senior barrister who holds an adjunct associate professorship at Adelaide Law School. He has practised in areas of commercial, corporate, and constitutional law. Currently, he is writing a PhD thesis that explores the constitutional limits of freedoms of conscience and religion.</p>
                     <p>In Yevgeny Zamyatin’s 1924 novel <italic>We,</italic>² OneState controls the planet. Happiness is guaranteed to all Numbers, the inhabitants of this future world, by OneSate’s scientific method, the Table of Hours. The Table is drawn by Zamyatin from the efficiency theories of Frederick Taylor³ and the Soviet management practices</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Artificial Intelligence and Intelligence Amplification:</title>
                     <subtitle>Salvation, Extinction, Faulty Assumptions, and Original Sin</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Weissenbacher</surname>
                           <given-names>Alan</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>69</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Alan Weissenbacher is book review editor for <italic>Theology and Science.</italic> He served many years as a counselor to homeless addicts, removing them from the urban setting and empowering them to run a farm while receiving coun- seling, spiritual care, and job training. His work with these clients inspires his research into neuroscience and spiritual formation, exploring ways to improve religious care and addiction recovery through understanding how the brain works.</p>
                     <p>It is easy to find gloomy predictions that in the near future robots will drive the majority of humanity into unemployment, or worse, result in its extinction. This extinction is</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>What a Piece of Work is Man:</title>
                     <subtitle>On Being and Becoming Human in Science Fiction</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Hewlett</surname>
                           <given-names>Martinez J</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>89</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Martinez (Marty) Hewlett is currently a Research Scholar at the University of New Mexico, Taos. He is Professor Emeritus from the Department of Molecular and Cellular Biology, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona. He holds a PhD in Biochemistry and is also a Life Professed lay member of the Order of Preachers (Dominicans). His scientific specialty is molecular virology and he is the co-author of a major textbook in this field, Basic Virology , now entering its 4<sup>th</sup> edition. He has co-authored three books on evolution and theology with Ted Peters. He has co-edited a number of books in the science</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>On the Faith of Droids</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Peterson</surname>
                           <given-names>Daniel J</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>107</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Daniel J Peterson is pastor of Queen Anne Lutheran Church in Seattle. Formerly a member of the faculty at Pacific Lutheran University and Seattle University, he is the author of <italic>Tillich:</italic> 
                        <italic>A Brief Introduction to the Life and Writings of Paul Tillich</italic> (Minneapolis: Lutheran University Press, 2013) and co-editor of <italic>Resurrecting the Death of God:</italic> 
                        <italic>The Origins, Influence and Return of Radical Theology</italic> (Albany: SUNY Press, 2014).</p>
                     <p>Genesis 1: 1–2:4a, the first account of creation in the Hebrew Bible, offers much to ponder: a world that that blooms with vegetation in the blink of a day (vv11– 12); the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>From Heidegger on Technology to an Inclusive Puralistic Theology</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Sampath</surname>
                           <given-names>Rajesh</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>117</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Bio. Rajesh Sampath is Associate Professor of the Philosophy of Justice, Rights, and Social Change at Brandeis University.</p>
                     <p>This article explores Heidegger’s later philosophy and what that means for possible theological interpretations of the relationship between humans and automated technology, such as Artificial Intelligence (AI). We will inquire into the possibility, limits, and hope for faith in a futuristic age.</p>
                     <p>The paper has three parts. First, I will explore ethical arguments for or against the possibility of AI superseding human intelligence and making moral decisions on its own. This will set up the question: Could AI have non-natural rights to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>AI Reading Theology:</title>
                     <subtitle>Promises and Perils</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Graves</surname>
                           <given-names>Mark</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>133</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Mark Graves is currently Visiting Research Assistant Professor at University of Notre Dame’s Center for Theology, Science &amp; Human Flourishing with his research occurring at the intersection of artificial intelligence, psychology, and theology. He earned his doctorate in computer science at University of Michigan in the area of artificial intelligence; held postdoctoral fellowships in genomics at Baylor College of Medicine and in moral psychology at Fuller Theological Seminary; and completed additional studies in systematic and philosophical theology at Graduate Theological Union (GTU) and Jesuit School of Theology at Berkeley. He has published technical and scholarly works in computer science, biology,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Idle Hands and the Omega Point:</title>
                     <subtitle>Labor Automation and Roman Catholic Social Teaching</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Checketts</surname>
                           <given-names>Levi</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>153</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Levi Checketts is a Roman Catholic ethicist who teaches at Holy Names University in Oakland and St Mary’s College of California in Moraga. He is working on issues related to Catholic ethics of technologies at the intersection of philosophy of technology and Science, Technology and Society (STS) studies. His work has been featured in <italic>Religions</italic>, <italic>Communications Research Trends</italic>, and <italic>Theology and Science</italic> among other publications.</p>
                     <p>‘The Singularity is near!’ So proclaimed Ray Kurzweil in 2005. This monumental event is expected to arrive as early as 2045. When it hap- pens, ‘all the changes of the past million years will be</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvrnfpwx.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Back Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>173</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
