

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>ISO 27001 controls – A guide to implementing and auditing</book-title>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>KENYON</surname>
               <given-names>BRIDGET</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>16</day>
         <month>09</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787781443</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787781450</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Ely, Cambridgeshire, United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Bridget Kenyon</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvj4sxjm"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;<bold>
               <italic>A must-have resource for anyone looking to establish, implement and maintain an ISMS.</italic>
            </bold> &lt;p&gt;Ideal for information security managers, auditors, consultants and organisations preparing for ISO 27001 certification, this book will help readers understand the requirements of an ISMS (information security management system) based on ISO 27001. Similarly, for anyone involved in internal or external audits, the book includes the definitive requirements that auditors must address when certifying organisations to ISO 27001. &lt;p&gt;The book covers: &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Implementation guidance - what needs to be considered to fulﬁl the requirements of the controls from ISO/IEC 27001, Annex A. This guidance is aligned with ISO/IEC 27002, which gives advice on implementing the controls;</p>
         <p>&lt;li&gt;Auditing guidance - what should be checked, and how, when examining the ISO/IEC 27001 controls to ensure that the implementation covers the ISMS control requirements.</p>
         <p> &lt;p&gt;The implementation guidance gives clear descriptions covering what needs to be considered to achieve compliance against the requirements, with examples given throughout. The auditing guidance covers what evidence an auditor should look for in order to satisfy themselves that the requirement has been met. Useful for internal auditors and consultants, the auditing guidance will also be useful for information security managers and lead implementers as a means of confirming that their implementation and evidence to support it will be sufficient to pass an audit. &lt;p&gt;This guide is intended to be used by those involved in: &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Designing, implementing and/or maintaining an ISMS; &lt;li&gt;Preparing for ISMS audits and assessments; or &lt;li&gt;Undertaking both internal and third-party ISMS audits and assessments  &lt;p&gt;<bold>About the author</bold> &lt;p&gt;Bridget Kenyon (CISSP) is global CISO for Thales eSecurity. Her experience in information security started in 2000 with a role in network vulnerabilities at DERA, following which she has been a PCI Qualified Security Assessor, information security officer for Warwick University and head of information security for UCL, and has held a variety of roles in consultancy and academia. &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bridget has been contributing to international standards since 2006, when she first joined BSI Panel 1, coordinating development of information security management system standards; she is currently editor for ISO/IEC 27014. Bridget has also co-authored three textbooks on information security. She strongly believes that "information security is fundamental to reliable business operations, not a nice-to-have". In 2018, she was named one of the top 25 women in tech by UK publication<italic>PCR</italic>.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="237"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>2</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FOREWORD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <contrib-group>
                     <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1" xlink:type="simple">
                        <name name-style="western">
                           <surname>Kenyon</surname>
                           <given-names>Bridget</given-names>
                        </name>
                     </contrib>
                  </contrib-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Information is one of your organisation’s most valuable assets. The objectives of information security are to protect the confidentiality, integrity and availability of information. These basic elements of information security help to ensure that an organisation can protect against:</p>
                     <p>sensitive or confidential information being given away, leaked or otherwise exposed, both accidentally or deliberately;</p>
                     <p>personally identifiable information being compromised;</p>
                     <p>critical information being accidentally or intentionally modified without the organisation’s knowledge;</p>
                     <p>important business information being lost without a trace or hope of recovery; and</p>
                     <p>important business information being unavailable when needed.</p>
                     <p>It should be the responsibility of all managers, information system</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>8</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>DISCLAIMER</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>10</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>GENERAL</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>11</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This guide provides instructions on the implementation of ISMS control requirements and on auditing existing control implementations to help organisations prepare for certification in accordance with ISO/IEC 27001.</p>
                     <p>The contents of this guide include the ISMS control requirements that should be addressed by organisations considering certification. Part 2 of this guide discusses each of the controls in Annex A of ISO/IEC 27001 from two different viewpoints:</p>
                     <p>implementation guidance – what needs to be considered to fulfil the control requirements when implementing the controls from ISO/IEC 27001, Annex A. This guidance is aligned with ISO/IEC 27002, which gives advice on the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>IMPLEMENTING AND AUDITING ISMS CONTROL OBJECTIVES AND CONTROLS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>15</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this section, each of the control objectives and control requirements in ISO/IEC 27001, Annex A are discussed from implementation and auditing viewpoints, taking into account the implementation advice given for each control in ISO/IEC 27002, the code of practice for information security management. The complete control objectives from ISO/IEC 27002 are included in this document to clarify the requirements.</p>
                     <p>Readers are encouraged to read both the implementing and auditing sections to obtain a clear view of what is required and how it might be tested.</p>
                     <p>“Objective: To provide management direction and support for information security in accordance with business</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvj4sxjm.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>235</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
