

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">HV6432 .M38 2019</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Terrorism</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">United States</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">Prevention</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject content-type="lcsh">Information services</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">National security</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">United States</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">Information services</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Intelligence service</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">United States</subject>
            <subj-group>
               <subject content-type="lcsh">Information services</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Interagency coordination</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">United States</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Criminology &amp; Criminal Justice</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Sociology</subject>
         <subject>International Relations</subject>
         <subject>Political Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Pacifying the Homeland</book-title>
         <subtitle>Intelligence Fusion and Mass Supervision</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>McQUADE</surname>
               <given-names>BRENDAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>06</day>
         <month>08</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780520299740</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780520971349</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0520971345</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>University of California Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Oakland, California</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <edition>1</edition>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Brendan McQuade</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvpb3wrf"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> The United States has poured over a billion dollars into a network of interagency intelligence centers called "fusion centers." These centers were ostensibly set up to prevent terrorism, but politicians, the press, and policy advocates have criticized them for failing on this account. So why do these security systems persist?<italic>Pacifying the Homeland</italic> travels inside the secret world of intelligence fusion, looks beyond the apparent failure of fusion centers, and reveals a broader shift away from mass incarceration and toward a more surveillance- and police-intensive system of social regulation.    Provided with unprecedented access to domestic intelligence centers, Brendan McQuade uncovers how the institutionalization of intelligence fusion enables decarceration without fully addressing the underlying social problems at the root of mass incarceration. The result is a startling analysis that contributes to the debates on surveillance, mass incarceration, and policing and challenges readers to see surveillance, policing, mass incarceration, and the security state in an entirely new light.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="304"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgments</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Prologue: Policing Camden’s Crisis</title>
                     <subtitle>Intelligence Fusion, Pacification, and the Fabrication of Social Order</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The creation of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence was the largest reorganization of the federal government since the reforms following World War II. Since these reforms sought to improve intelligence sharing, they did not remain limited to federal agencies. Not only did state governments set up their own homeland security agencies and offices, they also worked with federal agencies, professional associations, and private companies to build a series of interagency intelligence centers: what is now called the National Network of Fusion Centers. At these secure and secretive government facilities, teams</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1.</label>
                     <title>Connecting the Dots beyond Counterterrorism and Seeing Past Organizational Failure</title>
                     <subtitle>The Critique of Security and the Prose of Pacification</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>21</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>On September 9, 2001, a Maryland state trooper stopped Ziad Jarrah for a traffic violation. Having no reason to do otherwise, the trooper sent Jarrah on his way. Two days later, he was the hijacker-pilot of Flight 93, which crashed in rural Pennsylvania. Citing incidents like this stop, the 9/11 Commission found that the intelligence community had failed to “connect the dots.”¹ In response, the new Department of Homeland Security (DHS) promised to link the entirety of domestic intelligence—from municipal police departments to the federal intelligence community—with a new National Network of Fusion Centers. At the same time,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2.</label>
                     <title>The Rise and Present Demise of the Workfare-Carceral State</title>
                     <subtitle>The Lineages of the United States</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>45</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Connecting the dots beyond counterterrorism creates a more complicated picture of fusion centers. It reveals that the apparent failure of the fusion centers recognized by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is a shortsighted explanation that obscures a deeper history. “The terror attacks of 9/11 have created a kind of amnesia,” Jonathan Simon maintains, “wherein a quarter of a century of fearing crime and securing social spaces has been suddenly recognized, but misidentified as a response to an astounding act of terrorism, rather than a generation-long pattern of political and social change.”¹ Indeed, the National Network of Fusion Centers may</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3.</label>
                     <title>The Institutionalization of Intelligence Fusion</title>
                     <subtitle>Points of Conflict and Pockets of Intelligence Sharing</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>71</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In the decade following 9/11, the United States invested $7.6 trillion into the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the war on terror. This commitment to “security” seems irreversible. The 2008 market crash, the Great Recession, and the Obama administration have all come and gone. Yet the war on terror still rages, and DHS funding continues to creep up. Recalling chapter 1, fusion centers are no exception to this trend. In 2012, the Senate slammed them for producing “ ‘intelligence’ of uneven quality—oftentimes shoddy, rarely timely, sometimes endangering citizens’ civil liberties and Privacy Act protections, occasionally taken from already-published</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4.</label>
                     <title>Policing Decarceration</title>
                     <subtitle>Mass Supervision, Manhunts, and the Continuing Advance of Workfare</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>89</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In 2010, the US prison population had declined for three straight years. There year-to-year reductions were not dramatic, three tenths of percent in 2010, but it was trend.¹ In 2011, the prison population continued to fall, dropping by some fifteen thousand, a mere nine-tenths of a percent decrease.² The next year, the trend accelerated: 27,770 less people behind bars, nearly a 2 percent drop.³ Significant reforms underpinned this reduction in the overall prison population. In 2008, Congress passed the Second Chance Act, which established grants for reentry initiatives. Two years later, the Fair Sentencing Act reduced the notorious sentencing disparity</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5.</label>
                     <title>Beyond COINTELPRO</title>
                     <subtitle>Intelligence Fusion and Patchwork Political Policing</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>113</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>From 1956 through 1971, the FBI engaged in a counterintelligence campaign to pacify social movements. Known as COINTELPRO, the program started to “increase factionalism, cause disruption and win defections” within the Communist Party USA. It soon targeted the newly formed Southern Christian Leadership Conference, the civil rights organization led by Martin Luther King Jr.¹ By the time the Citizen’s Commission to Investigate the FBI broke into an FBI field office, stole documents, and exposed the program, the FBI was targeting every major left group in the United States.² No mere surveillance program, COINTELPRO sought to “ ‘expose, disrupt, misdirect, discredit,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6.</label>
                     <title>Pacifying Poverty</title>
                     <subtitle>Police Power and Moral Economies of Poverty</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>140</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>While activists worry about a new COINTELPRO, reformers bemoan waste and mission failures, and watchdogs fret about civil liberties, intelligence fusion subjects entire populations to constant surveillance and aggressive intelligence-led policing (ILP) operations. These activities continue with little controversy because they target a group with almost no formal political power: the surplus populations warehoused in hyperghettoized communities doubly segregated by race and class. As I learned during my first visit to a fusion center and explained in the prologue, this “criminal element” is the main object of intelligence fusion. This situation reflects the basic mandate of police power: to regulate</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Conclusion: The Camden Model and the Chicago Challenge</title>
                     <subtitle>Police Reform and Abolition</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>162</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In 2015, President Obama traveled to Camden to highlight the success of the new county police force. After the budget crisis, layoffs, and crime surge in 2011 and 2012, the Camden County Police committed to community policing. By the end of 2014, the number of violent crimes fell by over 20 percent and the number homicides was cut in half. Obama praised the city as “a symbol of promise for the nation.” He noted its community policing practices: officers “walk[ing] the beat” and “actually getting to know the residents—to set up basketball games, to volunteer in schools, to participate</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX:</title>
                     <subtitle>Research and the World of Official Secrets A Methodological Note</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>175</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Notes</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>183</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Works Cited</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>241</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvpb3wrf.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>279</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
