

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvfjd00r</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Biological Sciences</subject>
         <subject>Philosophy</subject>
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Artificial You</book-title>
         <subtitle>AI and the Future of Your Mind</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>SCHNEIDER</surname>
               <given-names>SUSAN</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>01</day>
         <month>10</month>
         <year>2019</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691180144</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780691197777</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0691197776</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Susan Schneider</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvfjd00r"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;<bold>A sober-minded philosophical exploration of what AI can and cannot achieve</bold>  &lt;p&gt;Humans may not be Earth's most intelligent beings for much longer: the world champions of chess, Go, and<italic>Jeopardy!</italic> are now all AIs. Given the rapid pace of progress in AI, many predict that it could advance to human-level intelligence within the next several decades. From there, it could quickly outpace human intelligence. What do these developments mean for the future of the mind?  &lt;p&gt;In <italic>Artificial You</italic>, Susan Schneider says that it is inevitable that AI will take intelligence in new directions, but urges that it is up to us to carve out a sensible path forward. As AI technology turns inward, reshaping the brain, as well as outward, potentially creating machine minds, it is crucial to beware. Homo sapiens, as mind designers, will be playing with "tools" they do not understand how to use: the self, the mind, and consciousness. Schneider argues that an insufficient grasp of the nature of these entities could undermine the use of AI and brain enhancement technology, bringing about the demise or suffering of conscious beings. To flourish, we must grasp the philosophical issues lying beneath the algorithms.  &lt;p&gt;At the heart of her exploration is a sober-minded discussion of what AI can truly achieve: Can robots really be conscious? Can we merge with AI, as tech leaders like Elon Musk and Ray Kurzweil suggest? Is the mind just a program? Examining these thorny issues, Schneider proposes ways we can test for machine consciousness, questions whether consciousness is an unavoidable byproduct of sophisticated intelligence, and considers the overall dangers of creating machine minds.  </p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>[i]</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>[vii]</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION:</title>
                     <subtitle>Your Visit to the Center for Mind Design</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>
                        <italic>It is 2045. Today, you are out shopping. Your first stop is the Center for Mind Design. As you walk in, a large menu stands before you. It lists brain enhancements with funky names. “Hive Mind” is a brain chip allowing you to experience the innermost thoughts of your loved ones. “Zen Garden” is a microchip for Zen master-level meditative states. “Human Calculator” gives you savant-level mathematical abilities. What would you select, if anything? Enhanced attention? Mozart-level musical abilities? You can order a single enhancement, or a bundle of several</italic>.</p>
                     <p>
                        <italic>Later, you visit the android shop. It is time to</italic>
                     </p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER ONE</label>
                     <title>THE AGE OF AI</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>You may not think about AI on a daily basis, but it is all around you. It’s here when you do a Google search. It’s here beating the world <italic>Jeopardy!</italic> and Go champions. And it’s getting better by the minute. But we don’t have general purpose AI yet—AI that is capable of holding an intelligent conversation on its own, integrating ideas on various topics, and even, perhaps, outthinking humans. This sort of AI is depicted in films like <italic>Her</italic> and <italic>Ex Machina</italic>, and it may strike you as the stuff of science fiction.</p>
                     <p>I suspect it’s not that far</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER TWO</label>
                     <title>THE PROBLEM OF AI CONSCIOUSNESS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>16</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Consider what it is like to be a conscious being. Every moment of your waking life, and whenever you dream, it feels like something to be you. When you hear your favorite piece of music or smell the aroma of your morning coffee, you are having conscious experience. Although it may seem a stretch to claim that today’s AIs are conscious, as they grow in sophistication, could it eventually feel like something to be them? Could synthetic intelligences have sensory experiences, or feel emotions like the burning of curiosity or the pangs of grief, or even have experiences that are</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER THREE</label>
                     <title>CONSCIOUSNESS ENGINEERING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>33</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Machine consciousness, if it ever exists, may not be found in the robots that tug at our heartstrings, like R2D2. It may instead reside in some unsexy server farm in the basement of a computer science building at MIT. Or perhaps it will exist in some top-secret military program and get snuffed out, because it is too dangerous or simply too inefficient. AI consciousness likely depends on phenomena that we cannot, at this point, gauge, such as whether some microchip yet to be invented has the right configuration, or whether AI developers or the public want conscious AI. It may</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER FOUR</label>
                     <title>HOW TO CATCH AN AI ZOMBIE:</title>
                     <subtitle>TESTING FOR CONSCIOUSNESS IN MACHINES</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>46</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Samantha, the sentient program in the film <italic>Her</italic>, reflects on her disembodiment and immortality in the above passage. We might think: How could a remark of this sophistication not stem from a conscious mind? Unfortunately, Samantha’s statement could be a program feature only, designed to convince us she feels even when she doesn’t. Indeed, androids are already being built to tug at our heartstrings. Can we look beneath the surface and tell whether an AI is truly conscious?</p>
                     <p>You might think that we should just examine the architecture of the Samantha program. But even today, programmers are having difficulties understanding</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER FIVE</label>
                     <title>COULD YOU MERGE WITH AI?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>72</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>
                        <italic>Suppose it is 2035, and being a technophile, you decide to add a mobile Internet connection to your retina. A year later, you enhance your working memory by adding neural circuitry. You are now officially a cyborg. Now skip ahead to 2045. Through nanotechnological therapies and enhancements, you are able to extend your lifespan, and as the years progress, you continue to accumulate more far-reaching enhancements</italic>.</p>
                     <p>
                        <italic>By 2060, after several small but cumulatively profound alterations, you are a “posthuman.” Posthumans are future beings who are no longer unambiguously human, because they have mental capacities that radically exceed those of present-day</italic>
                     </p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER SIX</label>
                     <title>GETTING A MINDSCAN</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>82</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>
                        <italic>You and I, we are just informational patterns, and we can be upgraded to a new, superior version—human 2.0, if you will. And from there, as AI developments continue, further versions of us can be created, until one day, when the science is just right, in the ultimate Nietzschean act of self-overcoming, we merge with AI</italic>.</p>
                     <p>Thus spoke our fusion-optimist.</p>
                     <p>Let’s consider whether the fusion-optimists are right by mulling over a scenario depicted in the science fiction novel <italic>Mindscan</italic> by Robert Sawyer. The protagonist Jake Sullivan has an inoperable brain tumor. Death could strike him at any moment. Luckily,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER SEVEN</label>
                     <title>A UNIVERSE OF SINGULARITIES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>98</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In your mind’s eye, zoom away from Earth. Envision Earth becoming but a “pale blue dot” in outer space, to use an expression of Carl Sagan’s. Now zoom out of the Milky Way Galaxy. The scale of the universe is truly staggering. We are but one planet in an immense, expanding universe. Astronomers have already discovered thousands of exoplanets, planets beyond our solar system, many of which are Earthlike—they seem to have the sort of conditions that led to the development of life on Earth. As we gaze up into the night sky, life could be all around us.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER EIGHT</label>
                     <title>IS YOUR MIND A SOFTWARE PROGRAM?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>120</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>One morning I awoke to a call from a <italic>New York Times</italic> reporter. She wanted to talk about Kim Suozzi, a 23-year-old who had died of brain cancer. A cognitive-science major, Kim was eagerly planning for graduate school in neuroscience. But the day she learned she had an exciting new internship, she also learned she had a brain tumor. She posted on Facebook: “Good news: got into The Center for Behavioral Neurosciences’ BRAIN summer program…. Bad news: a tumor got into my BRAIN.”²</p>
                     <p>In college, Kim and her boyfriend, Josh, had shared a common passion for transhumanism. When conventional treatments</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>CONCLUSION:</title>
                     <subtitle>THE AFTERLIFE OF THE BRAIN</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>148</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>At the heart of this book is a dialogue between philosophy and science. We’ve seen that the science of emerging technologies can challenge and expand our philosophical understanding of the mind, self, and person. Conversely, philosophy sharpens our sense of what these emerging technologies can achieve: whether there can be conscious robots, whether you could replace much of your brain with microchips and be confident that it would still be you, and so on.</p>
                     <p>This book has attempted, very provisionally, to explore mind design space. Although we do not know whether there will be places like Immortex or the Center</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX:</title>
                     <subtitle>TRANSHUMANISM</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>151</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>153</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>157</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>REFERENCES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>165</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">j.ctvfjd00r.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>173</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
