

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">j.ctt195sdw9</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Library Science</subject>
         <subject>Philosophy</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Engines of Order</book-title>
         <subtitle>A Mechanology of Algorithmic Techniques</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Rieder</surname>
               <given-names>Bernhard</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>28</day>
         <month>05</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9789048537419</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Amsterdam University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>Amsterdam</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>B. Rieder</copyright-holder>
         <copyright-holder>Amsterdam University Press B.V.</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctv12sdvf1"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p>Software has become a key component of contemporary life and algorithmic techniques that rank, classify, or recommend anything that fits into digital form are everywhere. This book approaches the field of information ordering conceptually as well as historically. Building on the philosophy of Gilbert Simondon and the cultural techniques tradition, it first examines the constructive and cumulative character of software and shows how software-making constantly draws on large reservoirs of existing knowledge and techniques. It then reconstructs the historical trajectories of a series of algorithmic techniques that have indeed become the building blocks for contemporary practices of ordering. Developed in opposition to centuries of library tradition, coordinate indexing, text processing, machine learning, and network algorithms instantiate dynamic, perspectivist, and interested forms of arranging information, ideas, or people. Embedded in technical infrastructures and economic logics, these techniques have become engines of order that transform the spaces they act upon.</p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="360"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Acknowledgements</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>9</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Over the last decades, and in particular since the widespread adoption of the Internet, encounters with algorithmic procedures for ‘information retrieval’ – the activity of getting some piece of information out of a collection or repository of some kind – have become everyday experiences for most people in large parts of the world. We search for all kinds of things on the open web, but also for products, prices, and customer reviews in the specialized databases of online retailers, for friends, family, and strangers in social networking services or dating sites, and for the next thing to read, watch, play,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1.</label>
                     <title>Engines of Order</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>25</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Although the various practices described as ‘information ordering’ have become ubiquitous parts of online experiences, the two notions making up the term are far from self-evident. Instead of providing strict definitions, however, I take ‘information’ and ‘order’ as starting points for an investigation into a domain of techniques that intervene in deeply cultural territory in ways that come with their specific framings and epistemological perspectives. Instead of asking what information and order <italic>are</italic>, I am interested in the operational answers enacted by algorithmic techniques. This means remaining at a certain distance from common uses of the vocabulary and concepts that</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2.</label>
                     <title>Rethinking Software</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>51</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Taken together, computerization, information overload, and social diversification help us explain how algorithmic information ordering techniques have come to play such prominent roles and call attention to at least some of the social, political, and economic matters they have become entangled with. But they do not provide a clear picture of the actual technical substance that lurks behind words like ‘processing’, ‘modulating’, or ‘ordering’. The rest of this book is thus dedicated to the technicities that give functional meaning to these terms, even if the shadow of their eventual application cannot be ignored. This requires an understanding of <italic>software</italic>, as</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3.</label>
                     <title>Software-Making and Algorithmic Techniques</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>81</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>There remains a stark contrast between the increasingly accepted diagnosis that ‘[s]oftware structures and makes possible much of the contemporary world’ (Fuller, 2008, p. 1) and the attention given to the actual technical and intellectual content mobilized by developers. If software has indeed become a technology of power, a means to ‘conduct conducts’ (Foucault, 2008, p. 186), it is surprising that critical analyses of concrete technical procedures remain rare. We have recognized that computers and software have considerable impact on human life, and we invest great effort in making sense of the ways they have affected various societal domains, from</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>4.</label>
                     <title>From Universal Classification to a Postcoordinated Universe</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>145</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter delves into the question of information order and ordering through an investigation that leads from the library, long the principal institution dedicated to the organization of knowledge, to the first widely used technique in information retrieval, coordinate indexing, and its much more elaborate cousin, the relational model for database management. The goal is not to establish a narrative of progress that inevitably leads to our contemporary situation, but to highlight certain fault lines emerging around the closely related issues of knowledge organization and access, and how they relate to specific techniques. A significant part of contemporary information ordering</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>5.</label>
                     <title>From Frequencies to Vectors</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>199</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>While the potential of digital computers is recognized early on, the 1950s, 1960s, and even 1970s were marked by physical hardware that was either forbiddingly expensive or limited in terms of its computational capacity – and often both. The computer plays the role of an omnipresent ‘evocative object’ (Turkle, 1985) that stimulates (technical) imagination, but often remains practically inadequate or financially out of reach. In the context of information retrieval, the 1950s were mainly dedicated to exploring the concrete possibilities of novel hardware for document search, while the conceptual side revolved in large parts around coordinate indexing (Salton, 1987, p.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>6.</label>
                     <title>Interested Learning</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>235</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Coordinate indexing and its relational database cousin constitute a technique for laying a disjoint, atomized, and therefore highly queryable grid over the world. Ordering becomes a particular operationalization of disassembly and reassembly in a multidimensional coordinate system that affords purpose-driven grouping and ordering through logical declaration. The query specifies the coordinates or properties one is interested in and matching items are retrieved. The statistical techniques discussed in the last chapter, which often describe their work as automatic encoding or indexing, can be seen as attempts to build such a grid from the world itself, not necessarily by grammatization, ‘the process</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>7.</label>
                     <title>Calculating Networks:</title>
                     <subtitle>From Sociometry to PageRank</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>265</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>While many of the algorithmic techniques behind ordering gestures such as ranking, filtering, or recommending have indeed been pioneered in the context of information retrieval, there are other sites of inception that inform technical and conceptual trajectories. This chapter traces the development of network algorithms and the application of graph theory to information ordering through the fields of sociometry and citation analysis and then explains how these elements made their way into information retrieval, becoming part of Google’s emblematic search engine.</p>
                     <p>Network analysis has seen a stellar rise over the last two decades: network visualizations have become a common sight</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Conclusion:</title>
                     <subtitle>Toward Technical Culture</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>305</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Over the preceding chapters, I have attempted to develop a perspective on algorithmic information ordering that takes technicity as its main focus and considers ordering techniques as means for producing specific forms of function or behavior dealing with the ‘arrangement and disposition’ of data items that stand, more often than not, for something meaningful to human practice. While the chosen historical trajectories often dealt with books, articles, or other documents, I have argued that these techniques can be applied to any item that can be fitted into a common intermediate form like a feature vector or a graph. Other than</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>About the Author</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>347</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctv12sdvf1.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Index</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>349</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
