

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.7312/marc19136</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">PN4784.T34 M35 2020</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Journalism</subject>
         <subj-group>
            <subject content-type="lcsh">Technological innovations</subject>
         </subj-group>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Artificial intelligence</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>Language &amp; Literature</subject>
         <subject>Communication Studies</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Newsmakers</book-title>
         <subtitle>Artificial Intelligence and the Future of Journalism</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>Marconi</surname>
               <given-names>Francesco</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>07</day>
         <month>04</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780231191364</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780231549356</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0231549350</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Columbia University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Columbia University Press</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.7312/marc19136"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> Will the use of artificial intelligence (AI), algorithms, and smart machines be the end of journalism as we know it-or its savior? In<italic>Newsmakers</italic>, Francesco Marconi, who has led the development of the Associated Press and<italic>Wall Street Journal</italic>'s use of AI in journalism, offers a new perspective on the potential of these technologies. He explains how reporters, editors, and newsrooms of all sizes can take advantage of the possibilities they provide to develop new ways of telling stories and connecting with readers.    Marconi analyzes the challenges and opportunities of AI through case studies ranging from financial publications using algorithms to write earnings reports to investigative reporters analyzing large data sets to outlets determining the distribution of news on social media.<italic>Newsmakers</italic> contends that AI can augment-not automate-the industry, allowing journalists to break more news more quickly while simultaneously freeing up their time for deeper analysis. Marshaling insights drawn from firsthand experience, Marconi maps a media landscape transformed by artificial intelligence for the better. In addition to considering the benefits of these new technologies, Marconi stresses the continuing need for editorial and institutional oversight.<italic>Newsmakers</italic> outlines the important questions that journalists and media organizations should consider when integrating AI and algorithms into their workflow. For journalism students as well as seasoned media professionals, Marconi's insights provide much-needed clarity and a practical roadmap for how AI can best serve journalism.</p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part book-part-type="book-toc-page-order" indexed="yes">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>ix</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>WHAT IS THIS BOOK ABOUT, ACCORDING TO AI?</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>xiii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION:</title>
                     <subtitle>TECHNOLOGY MOVES FASTER THAN JOURNALISTIC STANDARDS</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Let me introduce you to the Newsmaker. She makes news using new tools at her disposal. She is a journalist, but right now, she’s also being asked to be a technologist. She represents what the media industry is becoming: an arena for story-enabling, not just storytelling. She is every journalist and every newsroom who wants not only to survive but to thrive in this current era of digital change.</p>
                     <p>The Newsmaker has worked at a well-established news company for several years, based in a city I’ll call Fairview, reporting on different issues and producing important stories. Recently, an editor called</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>1</label>
                     <title>THE PROBLEM:</title>
                     <subtitle>A JOURNALISTIC MODEL IN TRANSITION</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>17</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>While not long ago the scenario that follows might have seemed like a fantasy, one could easily imagine it happening in a few years, thanks to advancements in AI.</p>
                     <p>It’s the near future. When the Newsmaker wakes up, so do all the smart devices in her home. One device starts playing the Newsmaker’s daily news digest, timed precisely for the moment she has left the bed and taken a few steps. It knows her brain isn’t ready for full-length news stories right when she wakes up.</p>
                     <p>Meanwhile, her smart house begins preparing for the day. An algorithmic coffee maker brews</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>2</label>
                     <title>ENABLERS:</title>
                     <subtitle>THE AI TECHNOLOGIES DRIVING JOURNALISTIC CHANGE</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>55</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>There is no universal definition of artificial intelligence. For computer scientists, AI might look like algorithms capable of thinking like humans. For bioengineers, it might mean growing brain cells in a laboratory. But how should journalists think about AI?</p>
                     <p>One way of thinking about AI in news organizations is in terms of the interaction between humans and machines and the journalistic results of that collaboration.</p>
                     <p>The Newsmaker has been assigned to cover a debate between two politicians. In looking for a new angle that provides a different way for her readers to understand the event, the Newsmaker, in collaboration with</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>3</label>
                     <title>WORKFLOW:</title>
                     <subtitle>A SCALABLE PROCESS FOR NEWSROOM TRANSFORMATION</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>129</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It dawns on the Newsmaker that the real impact of these artificial intelligence tools is the way they change how she works as a journalist. The challenge for media organizations is not only about access to technology but about finding the right model for integrating it into the newsroom.</p>
                     <p>Modern news companies need to do more than just understand AI. They need to become equipped to adapt to the disruptive changes that AI will bring to journalism, moving from a siloed workplace to a more responsive and collaborative one.</p>
                     <p>Traditional editorial strategies often lock out consumers from participation. By contrast,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>CONCLUSION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>153</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Technologies like AI can augment—not automate—the industry.</p>
                     <p>In a journalism landscape altered by new technology, the next generation of newsmakers brings science to the art of storytelling. They are analytical about how they approach reporting and editing and focused on research and experimentation.</p>
                     <p>Newsrooms now have at their disposal the resources to scale production, free up journalists from time-consuming tasks, and simultaneously differentiate their reporting. Data and computer science are rapidly becoming integral to this process while changing how information is gathered, produced, distributed, and monetized.</p>
                     <p>Artificial intelligence tools can generate text directly from data, find hidden insights</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>157</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>159</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>181</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="jstor">marc19136.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>199</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
