

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n</book-id>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Technology</subject>
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Securing Cloud Services</book-title>
         <subtitle>A pragmatic approach, second edition</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>NEWCOMBE</surname>
               <given-names>LEE</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>07</day>
         <month>04</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9781787782051</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9781787782068</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>IT Governance Publishing</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>United Kingdom</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <edition>2</edition>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>Lee Newcombe</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvwcjj1n"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;<italic>Securing Cloud Services - A pragmatic guide</italic> gives an overview of security architecture processes and explains how they may be used to derive an appropriate set of security controls to manage the risks associated with working in the Cloud. The book:  &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Introduces the concepts of Cloud computing and the associated security threats; &lt;li&gt;Explains key security architectures and how they can be applied to Cloud services; and &lt;li&gt;Covers security considerations for the different Cloud service models: IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service), PaaS (Platform as a Service), SaaS (Software as a Service) and FaaS (Function as a Service).  &lt;p&gt;Cloud computing represents a major change to the IT services landscape, but it also introduces changes to the risk landscape, which need to be understood and addressed. The flexibility of Cloud computing does not come without compromise or risk.  &lt;p&gt;Security remains a major concern for CIOs (chief information officers) considering a move to Cloud-based services. This book gives organisations pragmatic guidance on how to achieve consistent and cohesive security across their IT services - regardless of whether those services are hosted on-premises, on Cloud services or using a combination of both.  &lt;p&gt;This guidance in <italic>Securing Cloud Services - A pragmatic guide</italic> is provided through the application of a Security Reference Model to the different Cloud delivery models - IaaS, PaaS and SaaS - and also considers the changes in approach required to work securely with the newer FaaS model.  &lt;p&gt;<bold>Part 1</bold> introduces the concepts embodied within Cloud computing, describes the associated security threats and lists some of the leading industry initiatives dedicated to improving the security of Cloud services.  &lt;p&gt;<bold>Part 2</bold> introduces security architecture concepts and a conceptual Security Reference Model. This model is then applied to the different Cloud service models to show how the conceptual security services within the reference model can be delivered for each Cloud service model.  &lt;p&gt;This book will help organisations looking to implement Cloud services aimed at the enterprise - such as Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform and Salesforce - and to do so in a risk-managed manner.  &lt;p&gt;It is aimed at business decision makers, senior IT stakeholders, enterprise architects, information security professionals.  &lt;p&gt;<bold>Manage the risks associated with Cloud computing - buy this book today!</bold>  
         </p>
      </abstract>
      <counts>
         <page-count count="453"/>
      </counts>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>1</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>5</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>6</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>7</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>8</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>12</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Part 1 provides the foundation for the rest of this book as it introduces the concepts embodied within Cloud computing, describes the associated security threats and lists a few of the existing industry initiatives dedicated to improving the security of Cloud services.</p>
                     <p>Part 2 introduces a number of security architecture concepts and a conceptual Security Reference Model. This model is then applied to the different Cloud service models – Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), Platform as a Service (PaaS), Software as a Service (SaaS) and Function as a Service (FaaS) – to show how the conceptual security services within the</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 1:</label>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION TO CLOUD COMPUTING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>13</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>One of the more evocative labels for an IT delivery model – certainly more so than the utility computing label to which Cloud owes much of its heritage. However, like its rain-carrying namesake, Cloud computing can be difficult to describe, with many observers having their own perspective on what is, and what is not, Cloud. Many people use Cloud services without realising that they are doing so – iTunes, Facebook and Twitter are all examples of Cloud services. However, these are consumer Cloud services, aimed at individual users, and the security of such consumer services is not discussed within this</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 2:</label>
                     <title>OVERVIEW OF EXISTING CLOUD TAXONOMIES AND MODELS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>18</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Chapter 1 provided an informal introduction to the main concepts underlying the Cloud computing model. This chapter provides a more formal set of definitions and a common terminology to enable a joint understanding of what is meant by terms such as IaaS, community Clouds and deployment models.</p>
                     <p>There are a number of different definitions of Cloud computing, with probably the most widely accepted being the definition of Cloud computing produced by NIST.³ The NIST definition describes Cloud computing as being:</p>
                     <p>[A] model for enabling ubiquitous, convenient, on-demand network access to a shared pool of configurable computing resources (e.g., networks, servers,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 3:</label>
                     <title>THE SECURITY BALANCE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>34</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter aims to give a pragmatic overview of some of the potential security benefits and potential pitfalls of working in the Cloud. From the security perspective, working in the Cloud typically tends to be neither intrinsically better nor worse than on-premises – just different.</p>
                     <p>Like beauty, security is very much in the eye of the beholder. Which is a slightly pretentious way of saying that 'good' security is (or at least should be) dependent upon the context of your organisation in terms of the nature of your business, the threats and vulnerabilities to which your business is exposed and</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 4:</label>
                     <title>SECURITY THREATS ASSOCIATED WITH CLOUD COMPUTING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>65</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The previous chapter illustrated some of the potential benefits and pitfalls associated with the security of Cloud computing.</p>
                     <p>This chapter highlights some of the threat actors that may be in a position to attack a Cloud-based service. Some of the threat actors discussed in this chapter are taken from the NIST list of important actors for public Clouds available from:</p>
                     <p>www.nist.gov/itl/cloud/actors.cfm.</p>
                     <p>Alternative threat actor lists are available from the likes of CESG/NCSC via the now withdrawn HMG Information Assurance Standard 1 (NCSC currently points towards NIST SP800-30<sup>39</sup> as an example threat taxonomy), and as part of the Information Security Forum</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 5:</label>
                     <title>PRIVACY AND REGULATORY CONCERNS</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>80</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Alongside security, compliance with legislative and regulatory requirements ranks as one of the most commonly cited concerns by those considering a move to Cloud computing.</p>
                     <p>This chapter provides a brief overview of the data privacy concerns impacting adoption of Cloud services, primarily those imposed by the EU through the GDPR. There is also a brief discussion of mechanisms to achieve compliance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) when operating in the Cloud. This chapter is not intended to provide comprehensive advice on the legality or compliance status of any particular Cloud solution – organisations should always</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>96</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Part 2 is the meat of this book, providing pragmatic advice on deploying Cloud services in a risk-managed fashion.</p>
                     <p>This book uses security architecture techniques to drive a consistent, cohesive and comprehensive approach to securing Cloud services. Part 2, therefore, begins with an overview of the security architecture processes that can be used to derive the necessary security controls associated with a proposed Cloud deployment. I then introduce a Security Reference Model (SRM) which provides the basis for discussion of the delivery of security controls across the different Cloud service models.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 6:</label>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION TO SECURITY ARCHITECTURE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>97</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Chapter 6 introduces the concepts of security architecture, drawing on well-established enterprise architecture methodologies to derive logical services that deliver consistent levels of security regardless of the technologies used to implement those services. One of the main advantages of adopting this approach is the complete traceability from business requirement to technical component. This allows the business to understand how their risks are managed and the consequences of any move to Cloud-based services.</p>
                     <p>The international software architecture standard ISO/IEC 42010<sup>71</sup> defines architecture as:</p>
                     <p>The fundamental organization of a system, embodied in its components, their relationships to each other and the environment,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 7:</label>
                     <title>APPLICATION OF SECURITY ARCHITECTURE TO CLOUD COMPUTING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>114</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Chapter 6 introduced some fundamental concepts of security architecture. In this chapter we begin to apply some of these concepts to the area of Cloud computing. The use of a security architecture methodology allows organisations to approach Cloud-based deliveries with the confidence that their security concerns have been identified and appropriately managed. Rather than acting as a blocker, we can use security as a mechanism for enabling organisations to take advantage of the undoubted benefits of Cloud computing.</p>
                     <p>I shall use a Security Reference Model that I have used elsewhere to act as a framework for the discussion of approaches</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 8:</label>
                     <title>SECURITY AND THE CLOUD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>148</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter begins with a brief overview of the existing guidance available to those with an interest in Cloud security. I then propose mechanisms for delivering those security services within the SRM – see Figure 7 – that are common to all three traditional Cloud service models, and where the delivery of those services is not overly impacted by the choice of service model.</p>
                     <p>Finally, this chapter also discusses the relative merits of the different Cloud deployment models from a security point of view.</p>
                     <p>Cloud computing has been growing in popularity and acceptability over the last decade or so; more</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 9:</label>
                     <title>SECURITY AND INFRASTRUCTURE AS A SERVICE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>182</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter, I describe how the security services defined within the SRM, shown in Figure 7, can be delivered by those implementing an application upon an IaaS Cloud.</p>
                     <p>There are many IaaS providers offering a variety of different types of service. A non-exhaustive list of the different types of IaaS currently available is provided below:</p>
                     <p>Compute as a Service</p>
                     <p>Storage as a Service</p>
                     <p>Backup and Recovery/Disaster Recovery as a Service</p>
                     <p>Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) as a Service</p>
                     <p>Container Management as a Service</p>
                     <p>And here is a partial list of public Cloud providers offering IaaS services:</p>
                     <p>Amazon (https://aws.amazon.com/)</p>
                     <p>Azure (https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/)</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.17</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 10:</label>
                     <title>SECURITY AND PLATFORM AS A SERVICE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>293</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This chapter describes how the security services defined within the SRM shown in Figure 7 may be delivered by consumers implementing an application upon a PaaS Cloud.</p>
                     <p>Whilst I may occasionally provide examples of the security services offered by PaaS providers it is not my intention to provide a comprehensive overview of any particular PaaS platform. Similarly, I am not attempting to provide an exhaustive catalogue of available PaaS solutions. As with the rest of this book, my aim is to help you to adopt a way of working that enables you to find the most appropriate solution to your</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.18</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 11:</label>
                     <title>SECURITY AND SOFTWARE AS A SERVICE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>349</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter, I describe how the security services defined within the SRM, shown in Figure 7, may be delivered by consumers implementing a service using a SaaS Cloud.</p>
                     <p>There are countless SaaS services available covering a wide range of capabilities, including:</p>
                     <p>Billing</p>
                     <p>Customer relationship management (CRM)</p>
                     <p>Collaboration</p>
                     <p>Content management</p>
                     <p>Document management</p>
                     <p>Enterprise resource planning (ERP)</p>
                     <p>Environmental health and safety</p>
                     <p>Financials</p>
                     <p>Health and wellness</p>
                     <p>Human resources</p>
                     <p>IT service management (ITSM)</p>
                     <p>Personal productivity</p>
                     <p>Project management</p>
                     <p>Sales</p>
                     <p>Security</p>
                     <p>Social networks</p>
                     <p>Examples of SaaS providers include:</p>
                     <p>Salesforce.com (www.salesforce.com)</p>
                     <p>Sage (www.sageone.com)</p>
                     <p>Intuit (www.intuit.com)</p>
                     <p>Netsuite (www.netsuite.com/portal/home.shtml)</p>
                     <p>SuccessFactors (www.successfactors.com)</p>
                     <p>Oracle (www.oracle.com/applications/)</p>
                     <p>Office365 (www.office.com/)</p>
                     <p>Google Apps (https://gsuite.google.com/)</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.19</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 12:</label>
                     <title>SECURITY AND FUNCTION AS A SERVICE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>381</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>In this chapter, I describe how the security services defined within the SRM, and depicted in Figure 7, may be delivered by consumers implementing a service using a FaaS Cloud.</p>
                     <p>FaaS is the latest evolution of the Cloud model and it takes abstraction to its ultimate form: the running of individual ephemeral functions. With FaaS, there is no monolithic application constantly running in the background, instead, functions are triggered and executed on demand. In many ways, FaaS is similar to PaaS: consumers must still code the individual functions that make up their service, but the ephemeral nature of functions drives</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.20</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>402</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Part 3 presents a look ahead to the future of Cloud computing and the likely impacts of future changes on the security of Cloud consumer data and services. Finally, I conclude with a summary and some closing thoughts on the security of Cloud computing.</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.21</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 13:</label>
                     <title>LOOKING AHEAD</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>403</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>This book primarily concerns the current state of Cloud computing. I believe an appropriate way to finish is to engage in a look to the near future of Cloud computing and the attendant security implications. This chapter is purely my personal opinion on the likely evolution of Cloud computing, and you may well have different opinions.</p>
                     <p>There can be little doubt now that Cloud computing is here to stay: the agility and flexibility that Cloud offers cannot be matched by traditional delivery models; in addition, many global enterprises have materially reduced their in-house data centre footprints, so they could not</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.22</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>CHAPTER 14:</label>
                     <title>CONCLUSION AND SUMMARY</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>418</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The purpose of this book has been to act as a guide to the possibilities open to those looking to adopt Cloud computing in a risk-managed manner. In order to do so, I have adopted a fairly standard format; an introduction to the problem space, a review of past work, a suggested approach and then examples of how that approach can be implemented.</p>
                     <p>I have not tried to be exhaustive, overly comprehensive or dictatorial in tone. My aim has been to suggest an approach and a set of controls for your consideration: only you, your business stakeholders and security subject</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.23</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>APPENDIX A:</title>
                     <subtitle>SRM SECURITY SERVICE ASSIGNMENTS</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>424</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvwcjj1n.24</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>FURTHER READING</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>451</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
