

<book xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      dtd-version="0.2"
      xml:lang="eng">
   <collection-meta>
      <collection-id collection-id-type="jstor">books</collection-id>
   </collection-meta>
   <book-meta>
      <book-id book-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db</book-id>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="call-number">QA276 .H3178 2020</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Missing observations (Statistics)</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group>
         <subject content-type="lcsh">Big data</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <subj-group subj-group-type="discipline">
         <subject>Computer Science</subject>
         <subject>General Science</subject>
      </subj-group>
      <book-title-group>
         <book-title>Dark Data</book-title>
         <subtitle>Why What You Don’t Know Matters</subtitle>
      </book-title-group>
      <contrib-group>
         <contrib contrib-type="author" id="contrib1">
            <name name-style="western">
               <surname>HAND</surname>
               <given-names>DAVID J.</given-names>
            </name>
         </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
         <day>18</day>
         <month>02</month>
         <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <isbn content-type="ppub">9780691182377</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">9780691198859</isbn>
      <isbn content-type="epub">0691198853</isbn>
      <publisher>
         <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
         <publisher-loc>PRINCETON; OXFORD</publisher-loc>
      </publisher>
      <permissions>
         <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
         <copyright-holder>David J. Hand</copyright-holder>
      </permissions>
      <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctvmd85db"/>
      <abstract abstract-type="short">
         <p> &lt;p&gt;<bold>A practical guide to making good decisions in a world of missing data</bold>  &lt;p&gt;In the era of big data, it is easy to imagine that we have all the information we need to make good decisions. But in fact the data we have are never complete, and may be only the tip of the iceberg. Just as much of the universe is composed of dark matter, invisible to us but nonetheless present, the universe of information is full of dark data that we overlook at our peril. In<italic>Dark Data</italic>, data expert David Hand takes us on a fascinating and enlightening journey into the world of the data we<italic>don't</italic> see.  &lt;p&gt;<italic>Dark Data</italic> explores the many ways in which we can be blind to missing data and how that can lead us to conclusions and actions that are mistaken, dangerous, or even disastrous. Examining a wealth of real-life examples, from the Challenger shuttle explosion to complex financial frauds, Hand gives us a practical taxonomy of the types of dark data that exist and the situations in which they can arise, so that we can learn to recognize and control for them. In doing so, he teaches us not only to be alert to the problems presented by the things we don't know, but also shows how dark data can be used to our advantage, leading to greater understanding and better decisions.  &lt;p&gt;Today, we all make decisions using data. <italic>Dark Data</italic> shows us all how to reduce the risk of making bad ones.  </p>
      </abstract>
      <custom-meta-group>
         <custom-meta>
            <meta-name>
                    lang
                </meta-name>
            <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
         </custom-meta>
      </custom-meta-group>
   </book-meta>
   <body>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.1</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Front Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>i</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.2</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Table of Contents</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>vii</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.3</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>PREFACE</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>xi</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.4</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 1</label>
                     <title>DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>What We Don’t See Shapes Our World</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>3</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>First, a joke.</p>
                     <p>Walking along the road the other day, I came across an elderly man putting small heaps of powder at intervals of about 50 feet down the center of the road. I asked him what he was doing. “It’s elephant powder,” he said. “They can’t stand it, so it keeps them away.”</p>
                     <p>“But there are no elephants here,” I said.</p>
                     <p>“Exactly!” he replied. “It’s wonderfully effective.”</p>
                     <p>Now, on to something much more serious.</p>
                     <p>Measles kills nearly a 100,000 people each year. One in 500 people who get the disease die from complications, and others suffer permanent hearing loss</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.5</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 2</label>
                     <title>DISCOVERING DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>What We Collect and What We Don’t</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>28</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Data do not exist de novo. They have not been there since the beginning of time, sitting around just waiting for someone to come along and analyze them. Rather, someone has to collect them in the first place. And—as you doubtless expected—different ways of collecting data can lead to different kinds of dark data.</p>
                     <p>This chapter looks at the three fundamental ways that data sets are created, along with the dark data challenges associated with each method. The next chapter then explores some further dark data complications that can apply in many situations.</p>
                     <p>The three fundamental strategies for</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.6</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 3</label>
                     <title>DEFINITIONS AND DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>What Do You Want To Know?</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>72</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>It may be obvious, but it’s nevertheless worth emphasizing, that the usefulness of data depends on the right data having been collected in the first place and on the data being collected without distortion or misrepresentation. Each of these conditions is vulnerable to dark data risks. In fact, each of them is subject to so many potential dark data risks that an exhaustive enumeration of the relevant risks would be impossible. Nonetheless, developing an awareness of the sort of situations to look out for is vital in coping with dark data. This chapter examines what data you aim to collect,</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.7</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 4</label>
                     <title>UNINTENTIONAL DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>Saying One Thing, Doing Another</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>98</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Measurements cannot be infinitely accurate. Counts, such as the number of children in a family or even of ships on the sea, occur in convenient whole-integer numbers, but measurements like length have to be rounded to some level. They might be rounded to the nearest centimeter, millimeter, micron (a millionth of a meter), tenth of a micron, and so on, but it is not possible to take an <italic>infinite</italic> number of decimal places. Put another way, at some level we are unable to determine the details and have to live with the big picture (even though “big” might be pretty</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.8</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 5</label>
                     <title>STRATEGIC DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>Gaming, Feedback, and Information Asymmetry</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>114</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>The European Union’s so-called Gender Directive* rules prohibit insurance companies from using sex when deciding on premiums; that is, they require that sex be treated as dark data when they make such decisions.¹ In principle, this means that, all else being equal, a man and a woman would pay the same premium. In Canada, however, things are different. In 1992 the Canadian Supreme Court permitted sex to continue to be included in risk assessment models. This ruling led one man from Alberta, taken aback by the amount he would be charged to insure his new Chevrolet Cruze, to obtain a</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.9</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 6</label>
                     <title>INTENTIONAL DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>Fraud and Deception</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>140</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Some fraudsters become famous. Victor Lustig had nothing to do with the Eiffel Tower, but this did not stop his selling it. In 1925 he gathered together a group of scrap-metal dealers and told them that the cost of maintaining the tower was so expensive that the city of Paris had decided to sell it for scrap. This did not seem unreasonable, because the tower was originally intended to be only temporary, having been built for the 1889 Paris Exposition. Lustig explained that, naturally, such a sale would cause something of a public outcry, so it was important to keep</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.10</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 7</label>
                     <title>SCIENCE AND DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>The Nature of Discovery</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>167</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Science is all about discovering the nature of things and how they work. It’s all about shedding light on the unseen. But dark data also lie at the root of science in a very practical sense. Fundamental to the practice of science is the Popperian notion (after Karl Popper) of “testability” or “falsifiability.” The basic idea is that you come up with a potential explanation—a theory, conjecture, or hypothesis—for the phenomenon being studied, and then you test that explanation by seeing how well its consequences or predictions match what actually occurs. Recast in our terms, we know what</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.11</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 8</label>
                     <title>DEALING WITH DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>Shining a Light</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>223</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We’ve seen that dark data can occur for many reasons and that while we might know that the data we see are potentially misleading, we might be entirely unaware that we are not seeing everything. We’ve seen also that the consequences of such ignorance can be serious—in financial terms and also possibly in terms of loss of life. The picture is not a good one!</p>
                     <p>So what can we do about it? This chapter looks at ways in which we can peer into the shadows to discern what’s hidden there, and ways in which we might be able to</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.12</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 9</label>
                     <title>BENEFITTING FROM DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>Reframing the Question</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>262</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>Dark data might seem to have only a downside. It is certainly true that caution is the key message of this book. But there are ways in which we can use dark data to our advantage, provided we know what we are doing and tread very carefully. That is, there are ways in which we can turn the apparent obscurity implied by dark data against itself to enable us to gain greater understanding, make better predictions, choose more effective courses of action, and even save money. We do this by strategically ignoring parts of the data and by deliberately throwing</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.13</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <label>Chapter 10</label>
                     <title>CLASSIFYING DARK DATA:</title>
                     <subtitle>A Route through the Maze</subtitle>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>291</fpage>
                  <abstract>
                     <p>We have seen many examples of dark data in this book, looked at why the data were dark and the consequences of their being dark, and what we might try to do about the difficulties caused by their being dark. However, situations are often complicated because data might be dark for multiple reasons. Here’s an example.</p>
                     <p>The UK government’s Behavioural Insights Team has been called the “Nudge Unit” by the media. This unit searches for small strategically applied policy changes (nudges) that can have big impacts on behavior. A recent report from the team said “several reports and media articles</p>
                  </abstract>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.14</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>NOTES</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>307</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.15</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>INDEX</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>319</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
      <book-part indexed="true" xlink:type="simple">
         <body>
            <book-part>
               <book-part-meta>
                  <book-part-id book-part-id-type="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85db.16</book-part-id>
                  <title-group>
                     <title>Back Matter</title>
                  </title-group>
                  <fpage>331</fpage>
               </book-part-meta>
            </book-part>
         </body>
      </book-part>
   </body>
</book>
