<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284840</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Resonance of a Spring Opposed Free Piston Engine Device</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Robinson</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Clark</surname>
                  <given-names>Nigel N.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Famouri</surname>
                  <given-names>Parviz</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>West Virginia University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>576</fpage>
         <lpage>587</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284840"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Recent free piston engine research reported in the literature has included development efforts for single and dual cylinder devices through both simulation and prototype operation. A single cylinder, spring opposed, oscillating linear engine and alternator (OLEA) is a suitable architecture for application as a steady state generator. Such a device could be tuned and optimized for peak efficiency and nominal power at unthrottled operation. One of the significant challenges facing researchers is startup of the engine. It could be achieved by operating the alternator in a motoring mode according to the natural system resonant frequency, effectively bouncing the translator between the spring and cylinder, increasing stroke until sufficient compression is reached to allow introduction of fuel and initiation of combustion. To study the natural resonance of the OLEA, a numeric model has been built to simulate multiple cycles of operation. The MATLAB® model combines differential relationships (for cylinder pressure and translator dynamics), empirical relationships (for heat transfer and friction), and simplifications (for gas exchange and a mechanical spring) to describe the primary dynamic elements acting on the translator. The translator is excited from rest by a sinusoidal forcing function which is defined by frequency and force amplitude. As an example, an engine with a 1 kg translator mass, 30 mm bore, maximum stroke of 45 mm, atmospheric intake pressure, and spring stiffness of 250 kN/m is given. When the motor applies a sine wave at 85 Hz with peak force at 400 N, the steady state stroke is found to be 30 mm with a compression ratio of 20 after 70 strokes. For the same system motored at a forcing frequency of 75 Hz, the resulting steady state stroke is reduced to 17 mm and the compression ratio to 3.2. Knowledge of the natural resonance for a given device will enable controlled motoring to achieve a desired stroke and compression ratio. This paper investigates the resonant nature of the OLEA and parametrically explores the forcing amplitude and frequency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanipah, M., Mikalsen, R., and Roskilly, A., "Recent Commercial Free-Piston Engine Developments for Automotive Applications," Applied Thermal Engineering, 75:493-503, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2014.09.039.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikalsen, R. and Roskilly, A., "The Control of a Free-Piston Engine Generator. Part 1: Fundamental Analyses," Applied Energy, 87(4):1273- 1280, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2009.06.036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, K., Zhang, C., and Sun, Z., "Precise Piston Trajectory Control for a Free Piston Engine," Control Engineering Practice, 34:30-38, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.conengprac.2014.09.016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kosaka, H., Akita, T., Moriya, K., Goto, S. et al., "Development of Free Piston Engine Linear Generator System Part 1 - Investigation of Fundamental Characteristics," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1203, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goto, S., Moriya, K., Kosaka, H., Akita, T. et al., "Development of Free Piston Engine Linear Generator System Part 2 - Investigation of Control System for Generator," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1193, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kock, F. and Ferrari, C. "Flatness-Based High Frequency Control of a Hydraulic Actuator," Journal of Dynamic Systems Measurement and Control-Transactions of the ASME, 134(2):7, 2012, doi:10.1115/1.4005047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eid, A., Suh, K., Choi, K., Han, H., et al, "A Unique Starting Scheme of Linear-Engine Tubular PM Linear Generator System Using Position Feedback Controlled PWM Inverter," in 37th IEEE Power Electronics Specialist Conference, Cheju Isl., South Korea, 1308-1312, 2006, doi:10.1109/PESC.2006.1712166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jia, B., Zuo, Z., Feng, H., Tian, G. et al., "Development Approach of a Spark-Ignited Free-Piston Engine Generator," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2894, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2894.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y. Zuo, Z., Feng, H., and Jia, B., "Parameters Matching Requirements for Diesel Free Piston Linear Alternator Start- Up," Advances in Mechanical Engineering, 7(3):8, 2015, doi:10.1177/1687814015574408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kock, F., Haag, J., and Friedrich, H., "The Free Piston Linear Generator - Development of an Innovative, Compact, Highly Efficient Range-Extender Module," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1727, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1727.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikalsen, R. and Roskilly, A., "The Control of a Free-Piston Engine Generator. Part 2: Engine Dynamics and Piston Motion Control," Applied Energy, 87(4):1281-1287, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2009.06.035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Famouri, P., Cawthorne, W., Clark, N., Nandkumar, C., et al, “Design and Testing of a Novel Linear Alternator and Engine System for Remote Electrical Power Generation,” in IEEE Power Engineering Society 1999 Winter Meeting, New York, NY, 108-112, 1999, doi:10.1109/PESW.1999.747434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tóth-Nagy, C., "Linear Engine Development for Series Hybrid Electric Vehicles," Ph.D. Dissertation, West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldsborough, S. and Van Blarigan, P., "A Numerical Study of a Free Piston IC Engine Operating on Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0619, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0619.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jia, B., Zuo, Z., Tian, G., Feng, H., “Development and Validation of a Free-Piston Engine Generator Numerical Model,” Energy Conversion and Management, 91: 333-341, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2014.11.054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blair, G., “Design and Simulation of Two-Stroke Engines,” (Warrendale, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc., 1996), doi:10.4271/R-161.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, J., Güralp, O., Filipi, Z., Assanis, D. et al., "New Heat Transfer Correlation for an HCCI Engine Derived from Measurements of Instantaneous Surface Heat Flux," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2996, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., "A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine," SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi:10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Annand, W., "Heat Transfer in the Cylinders of Reciprocating Internal Combustion Engines," Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, 177(1):973-996, 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Broekaert, S., De Cuyper, T., Chana, K., De Paepe, M. et al., "Assessment of Empirical Heat Transfer Models for a CFR Engine Operated in HCCI Mode," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1750, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1750.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hohenberg, G., "Advanced Approaches for Heat Transfer Calculations," SAE Technical Paper 790825, 1979, doi:10.4271/790825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zulkifli, S., Karsiti, M., and A-Aziz, A., “Investigation of Linear Generator Starting Modes by Mechanical Resonance and Rectangular Current Commutation,” in IEEE International Electric Machines &amp; Drives Conference, Miami, FL, 425-433, 2009, doi:10.1109/iemdc.2009.5075241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
