<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275471</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>High Resolution Scalar Dissipation and Turbulence Length Scale Measurements in an Internal Combustion Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Petersen</surname>
                  <given-names>Ben R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ghandhi</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaal B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>65</fpage>
         <lpage>83</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275471"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>High resolution planar laser-induced fluorescence (PLIF) measurements were performed in an optically accessible internal combustion (IC) engine to investigate the behavior of scalar dissipation and the fine-scale structures of the turbulent scalar field. The fluorescent tracer fluorobenzene was doped into one of the two intake streams and nitrogen was used as the carrier gas to permit high signal-to-noise ratio fluorescence measurements without oxygen quenching effects. The resulting two-dimensional images allowed for an analysis of the structural detail of the scalar and scalar dissipation fields defined by the mixing of the two adjacent intake streams. High levels of scalar dissipation were found to be located within convoluted, sheet-like structures in accordance with previous studies. The fluorescence data, which were acquired during the intake stroke, were also used to examine the scalar energy and dissipation spectra. The measured spectra were found to closely match model turbulent energy and dissipation spectra over the full range of wavenumbers for all conditions. The Batchelor length scale was directly measured using the point where the dissipation spectrum fell to 2% of its peak value and was found to range from 29 to 34 μm. The integral length scale and Taylor microscale, were determined from the spatial autocorrelation of the scalar field, and were found to range from 3.03 to 7.95 mm and from 0.54 to 1.30 mm, respectively. In general, the turbulence length scales were slightly different in the two dimensions captured in the fluorescence images, suggesting the turbulent scalar field is slightly anisotropic during the intake stroke. The length scales were found to vary only slightly with intake manifold pressure (60 - 109 kPa) and engine speed (600 - 1200 RPM).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope, S., “Turbulent Flows,” Cambridge University Press, 2000, pp. 183-263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y., Ghandhi, J., Rutland, C., and Petersen, B., “Large Eddy Simulation of Scalar Dissipation Rate in an Internal Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0625, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buch, K. and Dahm, W., “Experimental Study of the Fine- Scale Structure of Conserved Scalar Mixing in Turbulent Shear Flows, Part 1. Sc≫1,” J. Fluid Mech., Vol. 317, pp. 21-71, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buch, K. and Dahm, W., “Experimental Study of the Fine- Scale Structure of Conserved Scalar Mixing in Turbulent Shear Flows, Part 2. Sc∼1,” J. Fluid Mech., Vol. 364, pp. 1-29, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rehm, J. and Clemens, N., “The Association of Scalar Dissipation Rate Layers and OH Zones with Strain, Vorticity, and 2-D Dilatation Fields in Turbulent Nonpremixed Jets and Jet Flames,” AIAA, Vol. 99-0676, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, L. and Clemens, N., “Planar Measurements of the Full Three-Dimensional Scalar Dissipation Rate in Gas-Phase Turbulent Flows,” Exp. Fluids, Vol. 27, pp. 507-521, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, L., “Measurements of the Three-Dimensional Scalar Dissipation Rate in Gas-Phase Planar Turbulent Jets,” Center for Turbulence Research Annual Briefs, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, L. and Clemens, N., “The Structure of Fine-Scale Scalar Mixing in Gas-Phase Planar Turbulent Jets,” J. Fluid Mech., Vol. 488, pp. 1-29, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kothnur, P. and Clemens, N., “Experimental Investigation of the Relationship Between Strain and Scalar Dissipation in Gas-Phase Turbulent Jets,” AIAA, Vol. 2001-1023, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurikov, M. and Clemens, N., “The Structure of Dissipative Scales in Axisymmetric Turbulent Gas-Phase Jets,” AIAA, Vol. 2002-0164, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pitts, W., Richards, C., and Levenson M., “Large- and Small-Scale Structures and their Interaction in an Axisymmetric Jet,” NIST Report, Vol. NISTR 6393, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G., Clemens, N., and Varghese, P., “Two-Point, High-Repetition-Rate Rayleigh Thermometry in Flames: Techniques to Correct for Apparent Dissipation Induced Noise,” Applied Optics, Vol. 44, pp. 6741-6751, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G., Barlow, R., and Clemens, N., “Quantification of Resolution and Noise Effects on Thermal Dissipation Measurements in Turbulent Non-Premixed Jet Flames,” Proc. Comb. Inst., Vol. 31, pp. 1525-1532, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G., Karpetis, A., and Barlow, R., “Dissipation Length Scales in Turbulent Nonpremixed Jet Flames,” Comb. and Flame, Vol. 148, pp. 62-75, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G., and Barlow, R., “Spatial Resolution Effects on the Measurement of Scalar Variance and Scalar Gradient in Turbulent Nonpremixed Jet Flames,” Exp. Fluids, Vol. 44, pp. 633-645, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiser, S. and Frank, J., “Imaging of Dissipative Structures in the Near Field of a Turbulent Non-Premixed Jet Flame,” Proc. Comb. Inst., Vol. 31, pp. 1515-1523, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Probst, D. and Ghandhi, J., “An Experimental Study of Spray Mixing in a Direct Injection Engine,” Int. J. Engine Res., 4:27-45, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiles, M.A., Probst, D.M., and Ghandhi, J.B., “Bulk Cylinder Flow Field Effects on Mixing in DISI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0096, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mi J. and Nathan, G., “The Influence of Probe Resolution on the Measurement of a Passive Scalar and its Derivatives,” Exp. Fluids, Vol. 34, pp. 687-696, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ghandhi, J., “Spatial Resolution and Noise Considerations in Determining Scalar Dissipation Rate from Passive Scalar Image Data,” Exp. Fluids, Vol. 40, pp. 577-588, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Southerland, K. and Dahm, W., “A Four-Dimensional Experimental Study of Conserved Scalar Mixing in Turbulent Flows,” University of Michigan, Report No. 026779-12, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang G., Clemens N., Barlow N. and Varghese P., “A System Model for Assessing Scalar Dissipation Measurement Accuracy in Turbulent Flows,” Meas. Sci. Technol., Vol. 18, pp. 1287-1303, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G., and Clemens, N., “Effects of Imaging System Blur on Measurements of Flow Scalars and Scalar Gradients,” Exp. in Fluids, Vol. 37, pp. 194-205, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Antonia, R., Abe, H., and Kawamura, F., “Analogy Between Velocity and Scalar Fields in a Turbulent Channel Flow,” J. Fluid Mech., Vol. 628, pp. 241-268, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B.R. and Ghandhi, J.B., “High Resolution Scalar Dissipation Measurements in an IC Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 475-491, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iverson, R.J., “The Effects of Intake Charge Stratification on HCCI Combustion,” MS Thesis, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herold, R.E., “Optical Investigations of the Effects of Stratification on Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Combustion,” PhD Thesis, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Ghandhi, J. and Koch, J., “Fluorescence Saturation Measurements of 3-Pentanone,” Appl. Phys. B, Vol. 93, pp. 639-644, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siegman, A., “How to (Maybe) Measure Laser Beam Quality,” OSA TOPS 17, pp. 184-199, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G. and Clemens, N., “Effect of Imaging System Blur on Measurements of Flow Scalars and Scalar Gradients,” Exp. in Fluids, Vol. 37, pp. 194-205, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bracco, F., “Structure of Flames in Premixed-Charge IC Engines,” Comb. Sci. Tech., Vol. 58, pp. 209-230, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Heim, D., and Ghandhi, J., “High Resolution Scalar and Velocity Measurements in an IC Engine.” ASME ICES2009-76097, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lele, S., “Compact Finite Difference Schemes with Spectral-Like Resolution,” J. Comp. Phys., Vol. 103, pp. 16-42, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
