<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">annurevifinaecon</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50010571</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Annual Review of Financial Economics</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Annual Reviews</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19411367</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19411375</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</volume>
         <issue-id>i40206480</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44864051</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Governance of Family Firms</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Belén</given-names>
                  <surname>Villalonga</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Raphael</given-names>
                  <surname>Amit</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>María-Andrea</given-names>
                  <surname>Trujillo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
                  <surname>Guzmán</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>635</fpage>
         <lpage>654</lpage>
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>COPYRIGHT © 2015 ANNUAL REVIEWS</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44864051"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We review what the financial economics literature has to say about the unique ways in which the following three classic agency problems manifest themselves in family firms: (a) shareholders versus managers, (b) controlling (family) shareholders versus noncontrolling shareholders, and (c) shareholders versus creditors. We also call attention to a fourth agency problem that is unique to family firms: the conflict of interest between family shareholders and the family at large, which can be thought of as the "superprincipal" in a multi-tier agency structure akin to those found in other concentrated ownership structures in which the controlling owner is the state, a bank, a corporation, or other institutions. We then discuss the solutions or corporate governance mechanisms that have been devised to address these problems and what research has taught us about these mechanisms' effectiveness at solving these four conflicts in family firms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>LITERATURE CITED</title>
        <ref id="d2435e161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e165" publication-type="other">
Adams R, Almeida H, Ferreira D. 2009. Understanding the relationship between founder-CEOs and firm
performance. J. Empir. Finance 16:136-50</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e175a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e179" publication-type="other">
Agnblad J, Berglof E, Hogfeldt P, Švancar H. 2001. Ownership and control in Sweden: strong owners, weak
minorities, and social control. In The Control of Corporate Europe, ed. F Barca, M Becht, pp. 228-58.
London: Oxford Univ. Press</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e192a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e196" publication-type="other">
Amit R, Ding Y, Villalonga B, Zhang H. 2015. The role of institutional development in the prevalence and
value of family firms. J. Corp. Finance 31:284-305</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e206a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e210" publication-type="other">
Amit R, Perl R. 2012. Family Governance Report: Sources and Outcomes of Family Conflict. Philadelphia: Wharton
Glob. Fam. Alliance</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e221a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e225" publication-type="other">
Amit R, Villalonga B. 2013. A Pnmer on Governance of the Family Enterprise. Geneva: World Econ. Forum</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e232a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e236" publication-type="other">
Amit R, Villalonga B. 2014. Financial performance of family firms. In The SAGE Handbook of Family Business,
ed. L Melin, M Nordqvist, P Sharma, pp. 157-78. London: Sage</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e250" publication-type="other">
Amoako-Adu B, Smith B. 2001. Dual class firms: capitalization, ownership structure and recapitalization back
into a single class. J. Bank. Finance 25:1083-111</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e260a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e264" publication-type="other">
Anderson R, Mansi S, Reeb D. 2003. Founding family ownership and the agency cost of debt. J. Financ. Econ.
68:263-85</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e278" publication-type="other">
Anderson R, Reeb D. 2003 a. Founding-family ownership and firm performance: evidence from the S&amp;P 500.
J. Finance 58:1301-27</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e292" publication-type="other">
Anderson R, Reeb D. 2003 b. Founding-family ownership, corporate diversification, and firm leverage. J. Law
Econ. 46:653-84</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e303a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e307" publication-type="other">
Anderson R, Reeb D. 2004. Board composition: balancing family influence in S&amp;P 500 firms. Adm. Sci. Q.
49:209-37</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e317a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e321" publication-type="other">
Andres C. 2008. Large shareholders and firm performance -an empirical examination of founding-family
ownership. J. Corp. Finance 14:431-45</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e331a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e335" publication-type="other">
Arugaslan O. 2007. Why are dual class shares unified? Work. Pap., West. Mich. Univ., Kalamazoo</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e346" publication-type="other">
Astrachan J, Shanker M. 2003. Family businesses' contribution to the U.S. economy: a closer look. Fam. Bus.
Rev. 16:211-19</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e356a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e360" publication-type="other">
Attig N, Guedhami O, Mishra D. 2008. Multiple large shareholders, control contests, and implied cost of
equity. J. Corp. Finance 14:721-37</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e370a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e374" publication-type="other">
Barclay M, Holderness C. 1 989. Private benefits from control of public corporations. J. Financ. Econ. 25:371-95</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e386" publication-type="other">
Barontini R, Caprio L. 2006. The effect of family control on firm value and performance: evidence from
continental Europe. Eur. Financ. Manag. 12:689-723</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e400" publication-type="other">
Barth E, Gulbrandsen T, Schone P. 2005. Family ownership and productivity: the role of owner-management.
J. Corp. Finance 11:107-27</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e410a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e414" publication-type="other">
Becht M, Bolton P, Röell A. 2003. Corporate governance and control. In The Handbook of the Economics of
Finance, Vol. 1A, ed. GM Constantinides, M Harris, R Stulz, pp. 1-109. Amsterdam: Elsevier</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e424a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e428" publication-type="other">
Bennedsen M, Nielsen K, Pérez-González F, Wolfenzon D. 2007. Inside the family firm: the role of families
in succession decisions and performance. Q.J. Econ. 20:647-91</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e438a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e442" publication-type="other">
Bennedsen M, Wolfenzon D. 2000. The balance of power in closely held corporations. J. Financ. Econ. 58:113-
39</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e452a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e456" publication-type="other">
Berle A, Means G. 1932. The Modern Corporation and Private Property. Piscataway, NJ: Trans. Pubi.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e464a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e468" publication-type="other">
Bertrand M, Mehta P, Mullainathan S. 2002. Ferreting out tunneling: an application to Indian business groups.
Q.J. Econ. 117:121-48</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e482" publication-type="other">
Bertrand M, Schoar A. 2006. The role of family in family firms. J. Econ. Perspect. 20:73-96</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e493" publication-type="other">
Bettinelli C. 2011. Board of directors in family firms: an exploratory study of structure and group process.
Fam. Bus. Rev. 24:151-69</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e503a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e507" publication-type="other">
Bigelli M, Mehrotra V, Rau R. 2007. Expropriation through unification: wealth effects of dual class share unifications
in Italy. ECGI Work. Pap. 180-2007, Eur. Corp. Gov. Inst., Brussels</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e517a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e521" publication-type="other">
Blumentritt T, Keyt A, Astrachan J. 2007. Creating an environment for successful nonfamily CEOs: an
exploratory study of good principals. Farn. Bus. Rev. 20:321-35</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e531a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e535" publication-type="other">
Burkart M, Panunzi F, Shleifer A. 2003. Family firms. J. Finance 58:2167-202</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e543a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e547" publication-type="other">
Caprio L, Croci E. 2008. 1 he determinants ot the voting premium in Italy: the evidence from 1974 to 2003.
J. Bank. Finance 32:2433-43</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e557a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e561" publication-type="other">
Caprio L, Croci E, Del Giudice A. 2011. Ownership structure, family control, and acquisition decisions.
J. Corp. Finance 17:1636-57</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e571a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e575" publication-type="other">
Carrasco-Hernández A, Sánchez-Marín G. 2007. The determinants of employee compensation in family firms:
empirical evidence. Farn. Bus. Rev. 20:215-28</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e589" publication-type="other">
Carvalhal A. 2012. Do shareholder agreements affect market valuation? Evidence from Brazilian listed firms.
J. Corp. Finance 18:919-33</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e603" publication-type="other">
Caselli F, Gennaioli N. 2013. Dynastic management. Econ. Inq. 51:971-96</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e610a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e614" publication-type="other">
Claessens S, Djankov S, Fan J, Lang L. 2002. Disentangling the incentive and entrenchment effects of large
shareholdings. J. Finance 57:2741-71</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e625a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e629" publication-type="other">
Claessens S, Djankov S, Lang L. 2000. The separation of ownership and control in East Asian Corporations.
J. Financ. Econ. 58:81-112</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e639a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e643" publication-type="other">
Ciaessens S, Yurtoglu B. 2013. Corporate governance in emerging markets: a survey. Emerg. Mark. Rev.
15:1-33</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e653a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e657" publication-type="other">
Coffee J. 1999. The future as history: the prospects for global convergence in corporate governance and its
implications. Northwest. Univ. Law Rev. 93:641-707</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e667a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e671" publication-type="other">
Combs J, Penney C, Crook T, Short J. 2010. The impact of family representation on CEO compensation.
Entrep. Theory Pract. 34:1125-44</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e681a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e685" publication-type="other">
Croci E, Gonenc H, Ozkan N. 2012. CEO compensation, family control, and institutional investors in con-
tinental Europe. J. Bank. Finance 36:3318-35</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e695a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e699" publication-type="other">
Cucculelli M, Micucci G. 2008. Family succession and firm performance: evidence from Italian family firms.
J. Corp. Finance 14:17-31</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e710a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e714" publication-type="other">
D'Aurizio L, Oliviero T, Romano L. 2015. Family firms, soft information and bank lending in a financial
crisis. J. Corp. Finance 33:279-92</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e724a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e728" publication-type="other">
Davis J. 2002. The Family Constitution Handbook. Cambridge, MA: Cambridge Farn. Enterp. Group Advisors
to Family Enterprise</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e738a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e742" publication-type="other">
Davis J. 2007. Governance of the business family. Harv. Bus. Sch. Note 807-020, Boston</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e749a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e753" publication-type="other">
DeAngelo H, DeAngelo L. 1985. Managerial ownership of voting rights: a study of public corporations with
dual classes of common stock. J. Financ. Econ. 14:33-69</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e763a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e767" publication-type="other">
Dyck A, Zingales L. 2004. Private benefits of control: an international comparison. J. Finance 59:537-600</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e774a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e778" publication-type="other">
Ellul A, Guntay L, Lei U. 2007. External governance and debt agency costs of family firms. Fed. Reserve Int.
Finance Discuss. Pap. 908, Board Gov. Fed. Reserve Syst., Washington, DC</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e789a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e793" publication-type="other">
Enriques L, Volpin P. 2007. Corporate governance reforms in continental Europe. J. Econ. Perspect. 21:117-40</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e800a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e804" publication-type="other">
Faccio M. 2006. Politically connected firms. Am. Econ. Rev. 96:369-86</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e815" publication-type="other">
Faccio M, Lang L. 2002. The ultimate ownership of Western European corporations. J. Financ. Econ. 65:365-
95</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e829" publication-type="other">
Faccio M, Lang L, Young L. 2001. Dividends and expropriation. Am. Econ. Rev. 91:54-78</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e836a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e840" publication-type="other">
Fahlenbrach R. 2009. Founder-CEOs, investment decisions, and stock market performance. J. Financ. Quant.
Anal. 44:439-66</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e850a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e854" publication-type="other">
Fama E, Jensen M. 1983. Agency problems and residual claims. J. Law Econ. 26:327-49</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e862a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e866" publication-type="other">
Fama E, Miller M. 1972. The Theory of Finance. Hinsdale, IL: Holt Rinehart &amp; Winston</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e873a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e877" publication-type="other">
Feldman E, Amit R, Villalonga B. 2014. Corporate divestitures and family control. Strat. Manag. J. doi:
10.1002/smj.2329</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e887a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e891" publication-type="other">
Friedman E, Johnson S, Mitton T. 2003. Propping and tunneling. J. Comp. Econ. 31:732-50</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e898a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e902" publication-type="other">
Gersick K, Feliu N. 2014. Governing the family enterprise: practices, performance and research. In The SAGE
Handbook of Family Business, ed. L Melin, M Nordqvist, P Sharma, pp. 196-225. London: Sage</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e912a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e916" publication-type="other">
Gianfrate G. 2007. What do shareholders' coalitions really want? Evidence from Italian voting trusts. Corp.
Gov. Int. Rev. 15:122-32</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e930" publication-type="other">
Gomes A, Novaes W. 2005. Sharing of control as a corporate governance mechanism. PIER Work. Pap. 01-029,
Penn Inst. Eicon. Res., Univ. Pa., Philadelphia</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e941a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e945" publication-type="other">
Gómez-Mejía L, Haynes K, Núñez-Nickel M, Jacobson K, Moyano-Fuentes H. 2007. Socioemotional wealth
and business risk in family-controlled firms: evidence from Spanish olive oil mills. Adm. Sci. Q. 52:106-37</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e955a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e959" publication-type="other">
Gómez-Mejía L, Larraza-Kintana M, Makri M. 2003. The determinants of executive compensation in family-
controlled public corporations. Acad. Manag. J. 46:226-37</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e969a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e973" publication-type="other">
Gompers P, IshiiJ, Metrick A. 2003. Corporate governance and equity prices. Q.J. Econ. 118:107-55</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e980a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e984" publication-type="other">
Gompers P, IshiiJ, Metrick A. 2010. Extreme governance: an analysis of dual-class firms in the United States.
Rev. Financ. Stud. 23:1051-88</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e994a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e998" publication-type="other">
González M, Guzmán A, Pombo C, Trujillo M-A. 2012. Family firms and financial performance: the cost of
growing. Emerg. Mark. Rev. 13:626-49</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1008a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1012" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez M, Guzmán A, Pombo C, Trujillo M-A. 2013. Family firms and debt: risk aversion versus risk of
losing control. J. Bus. Res. 66:2308-20</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1023a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1027" publication-type="other">
González M, Guzmán A, Pombo C, Trujillo M-A. 2014a. Family involvement and dividend policy in closely
held firms. Farn. Bus. Rev. 27:365-85</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1037a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1041" publication-type="other">
González M, Guzmán A, Pombo C, Trujillo M-A. 2014b. The role of family involvement on CEO turnover:
evidence from Colombian family firms. Corp. Gov. Int. Rev. 23:266-84</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1051a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1055" publication-type="other">
Grossman S, Hart O. 1980. Takeover bids, the free-rider problem, and the theory of the corporation. RAND
J. Econ. 11:42-64</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1069" publication-type="other">
Harris M, Raviv A. 1991. The theory of capital structure. J. Finance 46:297-355</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1076a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1080" publication-type="other">
Hauser S, Lauterbach B. 2004. The value of voting rights to majority shareholders: evidence from dual-class
stock unifications. Rev. Financ. Stud. 17:1167-84</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1090a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1094" publication-type="other">
Holderness C, Sheehan D. 1988. The role of majority shareholders in publicly held corporations: an ex-
ploratory analysis. J. Financ. Econ. 20:317-46</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1105a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1109" publication-type="other">
Jara-Bertin M, López-Iturriaga F, López-de-Foronda 0. 2008. The contest to the control in European family
firms: how other shareholders affect firm value. Corp. Gov. Int. Rev. 16:146-59</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1119a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1123" publication-type="other">
Jensen M. 1986. Agency costs of free cash flow, corporate finance, and takeovers. Am. Econ. Rev. 76:323-29</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1130a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1134" publication-type="other">
Jensen M, Meckling W. 1976. Theory of the firm: managerial behavior, agency costs and ownership structure.
J. Financ. Econ. 3:305-60</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1144a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1148" publication-type="other">
Jensen M, Murphy K. 1990. Performance pay and top-management incentives. J. Polit. Econ. 98:225-64</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1155a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1159" publication-type="other">
Jetha H. 1993. The Industrial Fortune 500 study. Work. Pap., Loyola Univ., Chicago</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1166a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1170" publication-type="other">
Johnson S, La Porta R, Lopez-de-Silanes F, Shleifer A. 2000. Tunneling. Am. Econ. Rev. 90:22-27</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1178a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1182" publication-type="other">
Klein P, Shapiro D, Young J. 2005. Corporate governance, family ownership and firm value: the Canadian
evidence. Corp. Gov. Int. Rev. 13:769-84</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1192a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1196" publication-type="other">
Lansberg I. 1988. The succession conspiracy. Farn. Bus. Rev. 1:119-43</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1203a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1207" publication-type="other">
La Porta R, Lopez-De-Silanes F, Shleifer A. 1999. Corporate ownership around the world. J. Finance 54:471-
517</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1217a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1221" publication-type="other">
La Porta R, Lopez-De-Silanes F, Shleifer A, Robert V. 1997. Legal determinants of external finance. J. Corp.
Finance 52:1131-50</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1231a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1235" publication-type="other">
La Porta R, Lopez-De-Silanes F, Shleifer A, Robert V. 1998. Law and finance. J. Polit. Econ. 106:1113-55</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1242a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1246" publication-type="other">
La Porta R, Lopez-De-Silanes F, Shleifer A, Robert V. 2002. Investor protection and corporate valuation.
J. Corp. Finance 57:1147-70</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1257a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1261" publication-type="other">
Lease R, McConnell J, Mikkelson W. 1983. The market value of control in publicly traded corporations.
J. Financ. Econ. 11:439-71</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1271a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1275" publication-type="other">
Li F, Srinivasan S. 2011. Corporate governance when founders are directors. J. Financ. Econ. 102:454-69</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1282a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1286" publication-type="other">
Lins K. 2003. Equity ownership and firm value in emerging markets. J. Financ. Quant. Anal. 38:159-84</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1297" publication-type="other">
Manne H. 1965. Mergers and the market for corporate control. J. Polit. Econ. 73:110-20</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1308" publication-type="other">
MassMutual Financ. Group. 2003. American Family Business Survey. Springfield, MA: MassMutual Financ.
Group</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1318a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1322" publication-type="other">
Maury B. 2006. Family ownership and firm performance: empirical evidence from Western European corpo-
rations. J. Corp. Finance 12:321-41</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1333a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1337" publication-type="other">
Maury B, Pajuste A. 2005. Multiple large shareholders and firm value. J. Bank. Finance 29:1813-34</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1344a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1348" publication-type="other">
McConaughy D, Walker M, Henderson G Jr, Mishra C. 1998. Founding family controlled firms: efficiency
and value. Rev. Financ. Econ. 7:1-19</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1358a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1362" publication-type="other">
Mehrotra V, Morek R, Shim J, Wiwattanakantang Y. 2013. Adoptive expectations: rising sons in Japanese
family firms. J. Financ. Econ. 108:840-54</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1372a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1376" publication-type="other">
Michaely R, Roberts M. 2012. Corporate dividend policies: lessons from private firms. Rev. Financ. Stud.
25:711-46</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1386a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1390" publication-type="other">
Morek R, Shleifer A, Vishny R. 1988. Management ownership and market valuation: an empirical analysis.
J. Financ. Econ. 20:293-315</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1404" publication-type="other">
Morek R, Stangeland D, Yeung B. 2000. Inherited wealth, corporate control, and economic growth. In
Concentrated Corporate Ownership, ed. R Morek, pp. 319-382. Chicago: Univ. Chicago Press</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1415a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1419" publication-type="other">
Morek R, Wolfenzon D, Yeung B. 2005. Corporate governance, economic entrenchment, and growth. J. Econ.
Lit. 43:655-720</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1429a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1433" publication-type="other">
Morek R, Yeung B. 2004. Family control and the rent-seeking society. Entrep. Theory Pract. 28:391-409</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1440a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1444" publication-type="other">
Myers S. 1977. The determinants of corporate borrowing. J. Financ. Econ. 5:147-76</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1451a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1455" publication-type="other">
Myers S. 2003. Financing of corporations. In The Handbook of the Economics of Finance, Vol. 1A, ed. GM
Constantinides, M Harris, R Stulz, pp. 215-53. Amsterdam: Elsevier</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1465a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1469" publication-type="other">
Nenova T. 2003. The value of corporate voting rights and control: a cross-country analysis. J. Financ. Econ.
68:325-51</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1479a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1483" publication-type="other">
Pajuste A. 2005. Determinants and consequences of the unification of dual-class shares. Eur. Cent. Bank Work. Pap.
Ser. 465, Eur. Cent. Bank, Frankfurt</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1494a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1498" publication-type="other">
Palia D, Ravid A, Wang C. 2008. Founders versus non-founders in large companies: financial incentives and
the call for regulation. J. Regul. Econ. 33:55-86</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1508a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1512" publication-type="other">
Pérez-González F. 2006. Inherited control and firm performance. Am. Econ. Rev. 96:1559-88</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1519a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1523" publication-type="other">
Shanker M, Astrachan J. 1996. Myths and realities: family businesses' contribution to the U.S. economy -a
framework for assessing family business statistics. Earn. Bus. Rev. 9:107-23</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1533a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1537" publication-type="other">
Shleifer A, Vishny R. 1986. Large shareholders and corporate control. J. Polit. Econ. 94:461-88</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1548" publication-type="other">
Shleifer A, Vishny R. 1997. A survey of corporate governance. J. Finance 52:737-83</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1559" publication-type="other">
Smith B, Amoako-Adu B. 1999. Management succession and financial performance of family controlled firms.
J. Corp. Finance 5:341-68</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1570a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1574" publication-type="other">
Sraer D, Thesmar D. 2007. Performance and behavior of family firms: evidence from the French stock market.
J. Eur. Econ. Assoc. 5:709-51</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1584a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1588" publication-type="other">
Stacchini M, Degasperi P. 2015. Trust, family businesses and financial intermediation. J. Corp. Finance 33:293-
316</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1598a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1602" publication-type="other">
Stulz R. 1988. Managerial control of voting rights: financing policies and the market for corporate control.
J. Financ. Econ. 20:25-54</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1616" publication-type="other">
Tagiuri R, Davis J. 1996. Bivalent attributes of the family firm. Farn. Bus. Rev. 9:199-208</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1623a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1627" publication-type="other">
Ugurlu M. 2000. Agency cost and corporate control devices in the Turkish manufacturing industry. J. Econ.
Stud. 27:566-99</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1637a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1641" publication-type="other">
Van der Heyden L, Blondel C, Carlock R. 2005. Fair process: striving for justice in family business. Farn. Bus.
Rev. 18:1-21</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1652a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1656" publication-type="other">
Villalonga B. 201 la. Note on financing growth in family firms. Harv. Bus. Sch. Note 211-074, Boston</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1663a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1667" publication-type="other">
Villalonga B. 2011b. Does the value of family control change with economic conditions? Evidence from the 2007-2009
crisis. Work. Pap., Harv. Bus. Sch., Boston</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1677a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1681" publication-type="other">
Villalonga B, Amit R. 2006. How do family ownership, control and management affect firm value? J. Financ.
Econ. 80:385-417</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1691a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1695" publication-type="other">
Villalonga B, Amit R. 2009. How are U.S. family firms controlled? Rev. Financ. Stud. 22:3047-91</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1702a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1706" publication-type="other">
Villalonga B, Amit R. 2010. Family control of firms and industries. Financ. Manag. 39:863-904</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1713a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1717" publication-type="other">
Volpin P. 2002. Governance with poor investor protection: evidence from top executive turnover in Italy.
J. Financ. Econ. 64:61-90</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1728a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1732" publication-type="other">
Ward J. 2010. The family constitution: Its the process that counts, not the content. Kellogg Sch. Manag. Tech. Note
KEL 601, Northwest. Univ., Evanston, IL</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1742a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1746" publication-type="other">
Wiwattanakantang Y. 1999. An empirical study on the determinants of the capital structure of Thai firms.
Pac.-Basin Financ. J. 7:371-403</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2435e1756a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2435e1760" publication-type="other">
Zingales L. 1995. What determines the value of corporate votes? Q. J. Econ. 110:1047-73</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


