<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285044</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Computational Multiaxial Model for Stress-Strain Analysis of Ground Vehicle Notched Components</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ince</surname>
                  <given-names>Ayhan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Purdue University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>316</fpage>
         <lpage>322</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285044"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Driveline and suspension notched components of off-road ground vehicles often experience multiaxial fatigue failures along notch locations. Large nominal load histories may induce local elasto-plastic stress and strain responses at the critical notch locations. Fatigue life prediction of such notched components requires detailed knowledge of local stresses and strains at notch regions. The notched components that are often subject to multiaxial loadings in services, experience complex stress and strain responses. Fatigue life assessment of the components utilizing non-linear Finite Element Analysis (FEA) require unfeasibly inefficient computation times and large data. The lack of more efficient and effective methods of elasto-plastic stress-strain calculation may lead to the overdesign or earlier failures of the components or costly experiments and inefficient non-linear FEA. An analytical computational model is developed to calculate actual elasto-plastic stresses and strains of notched components based linear-elastic FEA solution. The model is based on the integration of the material constitutive theory and the multiaxial notch correction method along with computational modeling techniques. The computation model is validated using non-linear FEA data of 1045 steel notched bar/shaft subjected to non-proportional multiaxial loadings. The comparison showed that calculated notch elasto-plastic stresses and strains from the model are in good agreement with the non-linear FEA data. The model is further assessed against experimental fatigue data of SAE 1045 steel notched shaft under multiaxial loadings. The notch stresses and strains estimated by the model have been subsequently used to perform fatigue life predictions and predicted lives showed good correlations with experimental fatigue data of the SAE 1045 steel notched shaft.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neuber, H., “Theory of Stress Concentration for Shear Strained Prismatic Bodies with Arbitrary Stress–Strain Law”, Journal of Appl. Mechanics, 28:544–550, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Molski, K. and Glinka, G., “A Method of Elastic-Plastic Stress and Strain Calculation at a Notch Root, Materials Science and Engineering”, 50:93– 100, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koettgen, V.B., Schoen, M. and Seeger, T., “Application of Multiaxial Load- Notch Strain Approximation Procedure to Autofrettage of Pressurized Components”, Advances in Multiaxial Fatigue, ASTM STP 1191, Philadelphia, 375–396, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koettgen, V.B., Barkey, M.E., and Socie, D.F., “Pseudo Stress and Pseudo Strain Based Approaches to Multiaxial Notch Analysis”, Fatigue of Engineering Materials and Structures, 34:854–867, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ince, A., and Glinka, G. “A Numerical Method for Elasto-Plastic Notch- Root Stress-Strain Analysis”, Journal of Strain Analysis for Engineering Design, 48(4):229–224, 2013, doi:10.1177/0309324713477638.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ince, A., Glinka, G., and Buczynski, A., “A Computational Modeling Technique of Elasto-Plastic Stress-Strain Response for Notched Components”, International Journal of Fatigue, 62:42–52, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2013.10.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, Y., Chiang, Y. and Wong, H., “A Constitutive Model for Estimating Multiaxial Notch Strains”, Journal of Engineering Materials and Technology, ASME, 117:33–40, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gu, R. and Lee, Y., “A New Method for Estimating Non-proportional Notch-Root Stresses and Strains” Journal of Engineering Materials and Technology, ASME, 119:40–44, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karolczuk, A. and Macha, E., "A review of critical plane orientations in multiaxial fatigue failure criteria of metallic materials", International Journal of Fracture, 134: 267–304, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, B., Reis L. and Freitas M. de, “Comparative study of multiaxial damage models for ductile structural steels and brittle materials”, International Journal of Fatigue, 31:1895–1906, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ince A. and Glinka G. “A generalized damage parameter for multiaxial fatigue life prediction under proportional and non-proportional loadings”, International Journal of Fatigue 62:34–41, doi:10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2013.10.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garud, Y.S., “A New Approach to the Evaluation of Fatigue under Multiaxial Loadings”, Journal of Engineering Materials and Technology, 103:118– 125, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, M.N.K., “Notch Tip Stress-Strain Analysis in Bodies Subjected to Non-Proportional Cyclic Loads”, Ph.D. Dissertation, Dept. Mech. Eng., University of Waterloo, Ontario, Canada, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ince A., "Numerical validation of computational stress and strain analysis model for notched components subject to non-proportional loadings", Theoretical and Applied Fracture Mechanics, 84:26–37, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.tafmec.2015.12.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Owen, D. R. J, Prakash, A., Zienkiewicz, O. C., “Finite Element Analysis of Non-Linear Composite Materials by Use of Overlay Systems”, Computers and Structures, 6:1251–1267, 1974.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kurath, P. S., Downing, D. and Galliart, D., “Summary of non-hardened notched shaft rounded robin program. In: Multiaxial Fatigue”, AE-14: 13–32, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fash, J.W., “An evaluation of damage development during multiaxial fatigue of smooth and notched specimens”, Report No. 123, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ince, A., “A novel technique for multiaxial fatigue modelling of ground vehicle notched components”, International Journal of Vehicle Design, 67(3):294–313, 2015, doi:10.1504/IJVD.2015.069486.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ince, A. and Glinka, G. “Innovative Computational Modeling of Multiaxial Fatigue Analysis for Notched Components”, International Journal of Fatigue, 82(2):134–145, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2015.03.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ince, A., "A mean stress correction model for tensile and compressive mean stress fatigue loadings", Fatigue and Fracture of Engineering Materials and Structures, 2016, doi:10.1111/ffe.12553</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koch, J.L., "Proportional and Nonproportional Biaxial Fatigue of Inconel 718", Report No. 121, University of Illinois, Urbana- Champaign, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
