<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023213</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Design of the EITC</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Are In-Work Tax Credits Effective in the Presence of Generous Public Assistance? Evidence from the 1975 Earned Income Tax Credit</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bastian</surname>
                  <given-names>Jacob</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>†</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>†</sup>Department of Economics, University of Michigan</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>44</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023213"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>It is well known that the Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC) expansions in the 1980s and 1990s had a positive impact on female employment. In contrast, the original 1975 EITC has commonly been described as a modest program that did not keep up with inflation; furthermore, during this time public assistance was twice as generous as it would be two decades later. For these reasons, there has been a general assumption that the incentives of the 1975 EITC were insufficient to induce much of a female employment response. In this paper I find strong evidence that the original EITC did have a positive and permanent impact on female employment. Using samples from two different populations of women, I use difference in differences to show that EITC-eligible women increased their relative employment by 3 to 5 percentage points (or about 5% to 8%). These findings are robust to triple differences analysis, model choice, state-specific time trends, choice of sample years, reweighting, and potentially endogenous fertility responses to the EITC. Subgroup analysis shows that this employment response varied by education, cost of living, race, age, marital status, and spousal income in a manner consistent with a standard labor supply model. The largest responses came from subgroups of women more likely to be EITC-eligible and women eligible for more EITC benefits. As far as I am aware, this is the first paper to empirically examine the introduction of the EITC and its first decade of existence.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ai, Chunrong, and Edward C. Norton. 2003. “Interaction Terms in Logit and Probit Models.” Economics Letters, 80(1): 123-129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angrist, Joshua D., and Jörn-Steffen Pischke. 2008. Mostly Harmless Econometrics: An Empiricist’s Companion. Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Autor, David H., and Mark G. Duggan. 2003. “The Rise in the Disability Rolls and the Decline in Unemployment.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 118(1): 157-206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Averett, Susan L., H. Elizabeth Peters, and Donald M. Waldman. 1997. “Tax Credits, Labor Supply, and Child Care.” Review of Economics and Statistics, 79(1): 125-135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bailey, Martha J. 2006. “More Power to the Pill: The Impact of Contraceptive Freedom on Women’s Life Cycle Labor Supply.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 121(1): 289-320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Batchelder, Lily L., Fred T. Goldberg Jr, and Peter R. Orszag. 2006. “Efficiency and Tax Incentives: The Case for Refundable Tax Credits.” Stanford Law Review, 59(1): 23-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baughman, Reagan, and Stacy Dickert-Conlin. 2003. “Did Expanding the EITC Promote Motherhood?” American Economic Review, 93(2): 247-251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blau, Francine D., and Lawrence M. Kahn. 2005. “Changes in the Labor Supply Behavior of Married Women: 1980-2000.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 11230.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blundell, Richard, and Thomas MaCurdy. 1999. “Labor Supply: A Review of Alternative Approaches.” In Handbook of Labor Economics Volume 3, ed. Orley Ashenfelter and David Card, 1559-1695. New York: New-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bound, John and Richard Freeman. 1992. “What Went Wrong? The Erosion of the Relative Earnings and Employment Among Young Black Men in the 1980s.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 107(1): 201-232</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burtless, Gary, and Jerry A. Hausman. 1978. “The Effect of Taxation on Labor Supply: Evaluating the Gary Negative Income Tax Experiment.” Journal of Political Economy, 86(6): 1103-1130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Busso, Matias, John DiNardo, and Justin McCrary. 2014. “New Evidence on the Finite Sample Properties of Propensity Score Reweighting and Matching Estimators.” Review of Economics and Statistics, 96(5): 885-897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Butcher, Kristin F., and John DiNardo. 2002. “The Immigrant and Native-Born Wage Distributions: Evidence from United States Censuses.” Industrial and Labor Relations Review, 56(1): 97-121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cameron, A. Colin, Jonah B. Gelbach, and Douglas L. Miller. 2008. “Bootstrap-Based Improvements for Inference with Clustered Errors.” Review of Economics and Statistics, 90(3): 414-427.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cameron, A. Colin, Jonah B. Gelbach, and Douglas L. Miller. 2011. “Robust Inference with Multiway Clustering.” Journal of Business &amp; Economic Statistics, 29(2): 238-249.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chetty, R., and J. N. Friedman. E. Saez. 2013. “Using Differences in Knowledge Across Neighborhoods to Uncover the Impacts of the EITC on Earnings.” American Economic Review, 103(7): 2683-2721.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cohen, Abby J. 1996. “A Brief History of Federal Financing for Child Care in the United States.” Future of Children, 6(2): 26-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Currie, Janet. 2003. “U.S. Food and Nutrition Programs.” In Means-Tested Transfer Programs in the United States, ed. Robert Moffitt, 199-290. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dickert-Conlin, Stacy, and Scott Houser. 2002. “EITC and Marriage.” National Tax Journal, 55(1): 25-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dickert, Stacy, Scott Houser, and John Karl Scholz. 1995. “The Earned Income Tax Credit and Transfer Programs: A Study of Labor Market and Program Participation.” In Tax Policy and the Economy Volume 9, ed. James Poterba, 1-50. Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DiNardo, John. 2002. “Propensity Score Reweighting and Changes in Wage Distributions.” University of Michigan Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DiNardo, John, Nicole M. Fortin, and Thomas Lemieux. 1996. “Labor Market Institutions and the Distribution of Wages, 1973-1992: A Semiparametric Approach.” Econometrica, 64(5): 1001-1044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Djebbari, Habiba, and Jeffrey Smith. 2008. “Heterogeneous Impacts in PROGRESA.” Journal of Econometrics, 145(1): 64-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eissa, Nada, and Hilary Williamson Hoynes. 1998. “The Earned Income Tax Credit and the Labor Supply of Married Couples.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 6856.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eissa, Nada, and Hilary Williamson Hoynes. 2004. “Taxes and the Labor Market Participation of Married Couples: The Earned Income Tax Credit.” Journal of Public Economics, 88(9): 1931-1958.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eissa, Nada, and Jeffrey B. Liebman. 1996. “Labor Supply Response to the Earned Income Tax Credit.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 111(2): 605-637.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eissa, Nada, Henrik Jacobsen Kleven, and Claus Thustrup Kreiner. 2008. “Evaluation of Four Tax Reforms in the United States: Labor Supply and Welfare Effects for Single Mothers.” Journal of Public Economics, 92(3): 795-816.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellwood, David T. 2000. “The Impact of the Earned Income Tax Credit and Social Policy Reforms on Work, Marriage, and Living Arrangements.” National Tax Journal, 53(4): 1063-1105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fernández, Raquel. 2013. “Cultural Change as Learning: The Evolution of Female Labor Force Participation over a Century.” American Economic Review, 103(1): 472-500.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fitzpatrick, Katie, and Jeffrey P. Thompson. 2010. “The Interaction of Metropolitan Cost-of-Living and the Federal Earned Income Tax Credit: One Size Fits All?” National Tax Journal, 63(3): 419-446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraker, Thomas, and Robert Moffitt. 1998. “The Effect of Food Stamps on Labor Supply: A Bivariate Selection Model.” Journal of Public Economics, 35(1): 25-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedman, Milton. 1962. Capitalism and Freedom. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldin, Claudia. 1990. Understanding the Gender Gap: An Economic History of American Women. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldin, Claudia. 2006. “The Quiet Revolution That Transformed Women's Employment, Education, and Family.” American Economic Review, 96(2): 1-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grogger, Jeffrey. 2003. “The Effects of Time Limits, the EITC, and Other Policy Changes on Welfare Use, Work, and Income Among Female-Headed Families.” Review of Economics and Statistics, 85(2): 394-408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gruber, Jonathan. 1994. “State-Mandated Benefits and Employer-Provided Health Insurance.” Journal of Public Economics, 55(3): 433-464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gruber, Jonathan, and Jeffrey D. Kubik. 1997. “Disability Insurance Rejection Rates and the Labor Supply of Older Workers.” Journal of Public Economics, 64(1): 1-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagstrom, Paul. 1996. The Food Stamp Participation and Labor Supply of Married Couples: An Empirical Analysis of Joint Decisions. Journal of Human Resources, 31(2): 383–403.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herbst, Chris M. 2011. “The Impact of the Earned Income Tax Credit on Marriage and Divorce: Evidence from Flow Data.” Population Research and Policy Review, 30(1): 101-128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirsch, Barry T., and Edward J. Schumacher. 2004. “Match Bias in Wage Gap Estimates Due to Earnings Imputation.” Journal of Labor Economics, 22(3): 689-722.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Holtzblatt, Janet. 1991. “Administering Refundable Tax Credits: Lessons from the EITC Experience.” In Proceedings of the Annual Conference on Taxation Held under the Auspices of the National Tax Association-Tax Institute of America Volume 84, pp. 180-186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Holtzblatt, Janet, Janet McCubbin, and Robert Gillette. 1994. “Promoting Work through the EITC.” National Tax Journal, 47(3): 591-607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hotz, V. Joseph, and John Karl Scholz. 2006. “Examining the Effect of the Earned Income Tax Credit on the Labor Market Participation of Families on Welfare.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 11968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoynes, Hilary, Marianne Page, and Ann Huff Stevens. 2011. “Can Targeted Transfers Improve Birth Outcomes? Evidence from the Introduction of the WIC Program.” Journal of Public Economics, 95(7): 813-827.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, William R., and Jonathan Skinner. 1986. “Labor Supply and Marital Separation.” American Keane, Michael, and Robert Moffitt. 1998. “A Structural Model of Multiple Welfare Program Participation and Labor Supply.” International Economic Review, 39(3): 553-589.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LaLumia, Sara. 2008. “The Effects of Joint Taxation of Married Couples on Labor Supply and Non-Wage Income.” Journal of Public Economics, 92(7): 1698-1719.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liebman, J. B. 1995. “Noncompliance and the Earned Income Tax Credit: Taxpayer Error or Taxpayer Fraud?” Harvard University. Unpublished.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liebman, J. B. 1995. “Who Are the Ineligible EITC Recipients?” Harvard University. Unpublished.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liebman, Jeffrey B. 1998. “The Impact of the Earned Income Tax Credit on Incentives and Income Distribution.” In Tax Policy and the Economy Volume 12, ed. James Poterba, 83-120. Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer, Bruce D. 2002. “Labor Supply at the Extensive and Intensive Margins: The EITC, Welfare, and Hours Worked.” American Economic Review, 92(2): 373-379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer, Bruce D., and Dan T. Rosenbaum. 2000. “Making Single Mothers Work: Recent Tax and Welfare Policy and its Effects.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 7491.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer, Bruce D., and Dan T. Rosenbaum. 2001. “Welfare, the Earned Income Tax Credit, and the Labor Supply of Single Mothers.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 116(3): 1063-1114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Michelmore, Katherine. 2014. “Timing of Income Transfers and Educational Attainment: Evidence from State Earned Income Tax Credit Expansions.” University of Michigan Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mincer, Jacob. 1962. “Labor Force Participation of Married Women: A Study of Labor Supply.” In Aspects of Labor Economics, 63-106. Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munnell, Alicia H. 1986. “Lessons from the Income Maintenance Experiments.” In Proceedings of a Conference Sponsored by the Federal Reserve Bank of Boston and the Brookings Institution. Melvin Village, NH.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parkman, Allen M. 1992. “Unilateral Divorce and the Labor-Force Participation Rate of Married Women, Revisited.” American Economic Review, 82(3): 671-678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, H. Elizabeth. 1986. “Marriage and Divorce: Informational Constraints and Private Contracting.” American Economic Review, 76(3): 437-454.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rhys-Williams, Lady Juliet. 1943. Something to Look Forward To: A Suggestion for a New Social Contract. Macdonald.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robins, Philip K. 1985. “A Comparison of the Labor Supply Findings from the Four Negative Income Tax Experiments.” Journal of Human Resources, 20(4): 567-582.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saez, Emmanuel. 2003. “The Effect of Marginal Tax Rates on Income: a Panel Study of ‘Bracket Creep’.” Journal of Public Economics, 87(5): 1231-1258.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scholz, John Karl. 1994. “The Earned Income Tax Credit: Participation, Compliance, and Antipoverty Effectiveness.” National Tax Journal, 47(1): 63-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Solon, Gary, Steven J. Haider, and Jeffrey Wooldridge. 2013. “What Are We Weighting For?” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 18859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trattner, Walter I. 2007. From Poor Law to Welfare State: A History of Social Welfare in America. Simon and Schuster.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ventry Jr, Dennis J. 2000. “The Collision of Tax and Welfare Politics: The Political History of the Earned Income Tax Credit, 1969–99.” National Tax Journal, 53(4): 983-1026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wooldridge, Jeffrey. 2012. Introductory Econometrics: A Modern Approach. Cengage Learning.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
