<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466894</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466900</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Home away from Home: Geography of Information and Local Investors</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gennaro</given-names>
                  <surname>Bernile</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alok</given-names>
                  <surname>Kumar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Johan</given-names>
                  <surname>Sulaeman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2009</fpage>
         <lpage>2049</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466900"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We develop a 10-K-based multidimensional measure of firm locations. Using this measure, we show that firm-level information is geographically distributed and institutional investors are able to exploit the resulting information asymmetry. Specifically, institutional investors overweigh firms whose 10-K frequently mentions the investors' state even when those firms are not headquartered locally and earn superior returns on those stocks. These ownership and performance patterns are stronger among hard-to-value firms. Local investor performance increases with the degree of local bias and with the local economic exposure of portfolio firms. Overall, geographical variation in firm-level information generates economically significant location-based information asymmetry.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1305535e257a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e264" publication-type="other">
For example, although Boeing Co. is headquartered in Chicago, Illinois, most of its operations are in the state
of Washington. Similarly, Whole Foods Market is headquartered in Austin, Texas, but has a large number of
stores and significant exposure in other states - for example, Massachusetts, Florida, and Colorado. Xerox Corp.,
which many perceive as a Rochester, New York company because of its large local presence, is headquartered
in Stamford, Connecticut.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e283a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e290" publication-type="other">
For example, Gurun and Butler (2012) show that conflicts of interests may hamper the role of local media as
external monitors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e300a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e307" publication-type="other">
Whereas our study focuses on the multidimensional nature of firm location, recent studies by Pool, Stoffman, and
Yonker (2012) and Shu, Sulaeman, and Yeung (2012) examine the multidimensional nature of investor location
and find that an investor's portfolio decisions are related to the location at which she was born and/or went to
college, in addition to that at which she is currently employed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e323a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e330" publication-type="other">
Although we refer to annual reports as 10-K forms throughout the paper, we collect and employ data from three
types of forms: 10-K, 10-KSB, or 20-F. The latter two forms correspond to small businesses and foreign issuers,
respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e344a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e351" publication-type="other">
Appendix B provides more details on the information contained in the relevant sections of the annual financial
reports, and Appendix C provides sample excerpts from some 10-K forms filed for the 1996 to 2008 sample
period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e364a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e371" publication-type="other">
Our parsing algorithm would miss instances in which the 10-K filing mentions a city but not the state. We also
would be unable to capture cases in which the 10-K filings use state abbreviations. Inspection of a randomly
selected set of filings indicates that both cases are rare. Further, there is no reason to believe that certain types
of firms or firms located in certain states are more likely to abbreviate states or mention only city names in their
reports. Thus, the citation counts may be noisy, but the relative frequency measure across firms would not exhibit
a systematic bias due to these exclusions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e394a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e401" publication-type="other">
For brevity, we do not tabulate these results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e408a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e415" publication-type="other">
Section 3 presents more formal tests of whether the 10-K-based metrics provide a meaningful measure of the
availability of local information about firm value.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e425a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e432" publication-type="other">
Although this approach may be too conservative for firms that significantly change their exposure across states
from one year to the next, the firm-state citation share and citation share rankings are quite persistent, as previously
discussed. To be conservative, we use potentially stale location data, which in principle should work against
finding significant results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e448a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e455" publication-type="other">
The Web site is http://mba.tuck.dartmouth.edu/pages/faculty/ken.french/data_library.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e463a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e470" publication-type="other">
The Web site is http://www.smith.umd.edu/faculty/rwermers/ftpsite/Dgtw/coverpage.htm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e477a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e484" publication-type="other">
Sections 1, 2, 6, and 7 of the 10-K filing do not mention the firm's HQ state for slightly less than 5% (4.37%) of
the firm-years in our sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e494a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e501" publication-type="other">
As reported in Table 1, the mean citation share of ERj state is 21.6%, whereas the mean combined citation share
of ERj_3 states is 49.1%.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e511a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e518" publication-type="other">
Several earlier studies use similar proxies for measuring the difficulty of valuing a firm. See, among others, Jiang,
Lee, and Zhang (2005), Zhang (2006), and Kumar (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e528a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e535" publication-type="other">
We do find that these relations are stronger and statistically significant when we use raw returns instead, as in
BKK.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e545a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e552" publication-type="other">
For the reasons explained at the end of Section 4, we shift our focus from the full set of cited states, as in Tables
4 through 6, to the top three non-HQ cited states, in Table 7 onwards. In previous versions of this paper, we used
the top five non-HQ cited states, which yielded similar, but as expected weaker results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e566a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e573" publication-type="other">
This variable has a significant coefficient estimate when raw returns are used instead of characteristics-adjusted
returns, consistent with the findings in Garcia and Norli (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e583a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e590" publication-type="other">
In unreported analysis, we find that there is similar evidence of local bias in various subsamples of institutions
defined using investor self-reported types or portfolio sizes. Our finding that large institutions have weaker local
bias is consistent with previous evidence obtained using different samples, for example, mutual funds during an
earlier period in Coval and Moskowitz (2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e606a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e613" publication-type="other">
This performance measure is identical to the "Portfolio Change Measure" introduced by Grinblatt and Titman
(1993) and referred to as the GT measure by Daniel et al. (1997). More precisely, the trading performance is
calculated as the difference between the performance of the investor portfolio as reported at the end of the
previous quarter and that of the investor portfolio as reported at the beginning of the previous quarter. Because
the returns from the part of the portfolio that does not change over the quarter cancel out, the measured trading
performance is solely attributed to the part of the portfolio that changes during the previous quarter.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1305535e636a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1305535e643" publication-type="other">
The reduction in local HQ performance over time is consistent with the trend observed by Coval and Moskowitz
(2001), in which the performance differential between local and nonlocal mutual fund holdings is not significant
in the second half of their sample period (1985 to 1994), both statistically (r-statistic = 0.09) and economically
(annualized performance differential = 0.04%). Sulaeman (2014) extends this analysis to 2005 and reports
similar patterns. Bernile, Kumar, and Sulaeman (2014) report that the decline in HQ performance coincide with
the reduction in local HQ bias of institutional investors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1305535e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e679" publication-type="other">
Aarland, K., J. C. Davis, J. V. Henderson, and Y. Ono. 2007. Spatial organization of firms: The decision to split
production and administration. RAND Journal of Economics 38:480-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e689a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e693" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y. 2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: Cross-section and time-series effects Journal of Financial Markets
5:31-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e703a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e707" publication-type="other">
Baik, B., J. Kang, and J. Kim. 2010. Local institutional investors, information asymmetries, and equity returns.
Journal of Financial Economics 97:81-106.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e717a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e721" publication-type="other">
Bernile, G, A. Kumar, and J. Sulaeman. 2014. Leveling the playing field: Financial regulation and disappearing
local bias of institutional investors Working Paper, University of Miami.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e732a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e736" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e747" publication-type="other">
Christoffersen, S. E. K., and S. Sarkissian. 2009. City size and fund performance. Journal of Financial Economics
92:252-275</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e761" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., A. Frazzini, and C. J. Malloy. 2008. The small world of investing: Board connections and mutual
fund returns. Journal of Political Economy 116:951-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e771a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e775" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and T. J. Moskowitz. 1999. Home bias at home: Local equity preference in domestic portfolios.
Journal of Finance 54:2045-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e785a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e789" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and T. J. Moskowitz. 2001. The geography of investment: Informed trading and asset prices. Journal
of Political Economy 109:811-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e799a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e803" publication-type="other">
Daniel, K. D., M. Grinblatt, S. Titman, and R. Weimers. 1997. Measuring mutual fund performance with
characteristic-based benchmarks. Journal of Finance 52:1035-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e818" publication-type="other">
Dyck, A., A. Morse, and L. Zingales. 2010. Who blows the whistle on corporate fraud? Journal of Finance
65:2213-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e828a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e832" publication-type="other">
Dyck, A., N. Volchkova, and L. Zingales. 2008. The corporate governance role of the media: Evidence from
Russia. Journal of Finance 63:1093-135.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e842a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e846" publication-type="other">
Engelberg, J. E., and C. A. Parsons. 2011. The causal impact of media in financial markets. Journal of Finance
66:67-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e856a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e860" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1992. The cross-section of expected stock returns. Journal of Finance 47:427-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e871" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and J. D. MacBeth. 1973. Risk, return, and equilibrium: Empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy
81:607-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e885" publication-type="other">
Garcia, D., and O. Norli. 2012. Geographic dispersion and stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics
106:547-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e896a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e900" publication-type="other">
Giroud, X. 2013. Proximity and investment: Evidence from plant-level data. Quarterly Journal of Economics
128:861-915.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e910a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e914" publication-type="other">
Griffin, J. M. 2002. Are the Fama and French factors global or country specific? Review of Financial Studies
15:783-803.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e928" publication-type="other">
Grinblatt, M., and S. Titman. 1993. Performance measurement without benchmarks: An examination of mutual
fund returns. Journal of Business 66:47-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e942" publication-type="other">
Gurun, U. G, and A. Butler. 2012. Don't believe the hype: Local media slant, local advertising, and firm value.
Journal of Finance 67:561-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e952a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e956" publication-type="other">
Hong, H., J. D. Kubik, and J. C. Stein. 2005. Thy neighbor's portfolio: Word-of-mouth effects in the holdings
and trades of money managers. Journal of Finance 60:2801-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e970" publication-type="other">
Hou, K., G A. Karolyi, and B.-C. Kho. 2011. What factors drive global stock returns? Review of Financial Studies
24:2527-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e985" publication-type="other">
Jiang, G, C. M. Lee, and Y. Zhang. 2005. Information uncertainty and expected returns. Review of Accounting
Studies 10:185-221.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e995a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e999" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A. 2009 Hard-to-value stocks, behavioral biases, and informed trading Journal of Financial and
Quantitative Analysis 44:1375—401.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1009a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1013" publication-type="other">
Miller, G S. 2006. The press as a watchdog for accounting fraud. Journal of Accounting Research 44:1001-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1020a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1024" publication-type="other">
Newey, W. K., and K. D. West. 1987. A simple, positive semi-definite heteroskedasticity and auto-correlation
consistent variance-covariance matrix. Econometrica 55:703-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1034a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1038" publication-type="other">
Pirinsky, C., and Q. Wang. 2006. Does corporate headquarters location matter for stock returns? Journal of
Finance 61:1991-2015.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1048a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1052" publication-type="other">
Pool, V. K., N. Stoffman, and S. E. Yonker. 2012. No place like home: Familiarity in mutual fund manager
portfolio choice. Review of Financial Studies 25:2563-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1067" publication-type="other">
Shu, T., J. Sulaeman, and P. E. Yeung. 2012. Local religious beliefs and mutual fund risk-taking behaviors.
Management Science 58:1779-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1077a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1081" publication-type="other">
Sulaeman, J. 2014. Do local investors know more? Evidence from mutual fund location and investments.
Quarterly Journal of Finance 4:1450010</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1091a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1095" publication-type="other">
van Nieuwerburgh, S., and L. Veldkamp. 2009. Information immobility and the home bias puzzle. Journal of
Finance 64:1187-215.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1305535e1105a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1305535e1109" publication-type="other">
Zhang, X. F. 2006. Information uncertainty and stock returns. Journal of Finance 61:105-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


