<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277982</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation on Multiple Injection Strategies for Gasoline PPC Operation in a Newly Designed 2-Stroke HSDI Compression Ignition Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Benajes</surname>
                  <given-names>Jesus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Novella</surname>
                  <given-names>Ricardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Lima</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniela</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tribotte</surname>
                  <given-names>Pascal</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Renault</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>758</fpage>
         <lpage>774</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277982"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Partially Premixed Combustion (PPC) of fuels in the gasoline octane range has proven its potential to achieve simultaneous reduction in soot and NO<sub>X</sub>emissions, combined with high indicated efficiencies; while still retaining proper control over combustion phasing with the injection event, contrary to fully premixed strategies. However, gasoline fuels with high octane number as the commonly available for the public provide a challenge to ensure reliable ignition especially in the low load range, while fuel blends with lower octane numbers present problems for extending the ignition delay in the high load range and avoid the onset of knocking-like combustion. Thus, choosing an appropriate fuel and injection strategy is critical to solve these issues, assuring successful PPC operation in the full engine map.</p>
            <p>In this framework, the objective of the present investigation consists of evaluating the use of multiple injection strategies for achieving stable PPC operation, attaining low NO<sub>X</sub>and soot emissions together with high efficiencies. This research was carried out in a single-cylinder DOHC 2-stroke HSDI CI engine using 95 Research Octane Number (RON) gasoline fuel. Three different operating conditions in terms of indicated mean effective pressure (IMEP) and speed were investigated: 3.1 bar IMEP and 1250 rpm, 5.5 bar IMEP and 1500 rpm and 10.4 bar IMEP and 1500 rpm. Parametric variations of injection timings, at different rail pressures and different fuel split between injections were experimentally performed to analyze the effect of the injection strategy over the combustion process, exhaust emissions and efficiency levels.</p>
            <p>Experimental results confirm how using an appropriate injection strategy helps to achieve stable PPC operation in the selected operating conditions; with competitive combustion stability, lower NO<sub>X</sub>and soot levels, and moderate CO and HC emissions with combustion efficiency over 96%, compared to Conventional Diesel Combustion (CDC).</p>
            <p>Finally, a detailed analysis of the local cylinder conditions was performed by means of 3D-CFD simulations in order to provide guidelines for further optimization of the gasoline PPC concept, when using multiple injection strategies in the 2-stroke engine under development.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging*,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Canaan, R., “PLIF Imaging of NO Formation in a DI Diesel Engine1,” SAE Technical Paper 980147, 1998, doi:10.4271/980147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitamura, Y., Mohammadi, A., Ishiyama, T., and Shioji, M., “Fundamental Investigation of NOx Formation in Diesel Combustion Under Supercharged and EGR Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005- 01-0364, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0364.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flynn, P., Durrett, R., Hunter, G., zur Loye, A. et al., “Diesel Combustion: An Integrated View Combining Laser Diagnostics, Chemical Kinetics, And Empirical Validation,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0509, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, Y. and Lee, C., “Investigation of Soot Formation in Diesel Combustion Using Forward Illumination Light Extinction (FILE) Technique,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1411, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):1207-1227, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1491.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berggren, C., and Magnusson, T., “Reducing automotive-emissions - The potentials of combustion engine technologies and the power of policy.” Energy Policy 41(0):636-643, 2012, doi:http://dx.doi. org/10.1016/j.enpol.2011.11.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Squaiella, L.L.F., Martins, C.A., and Lacava, P.T., “Strategiesfor emission control in diesel engine to meet Euro VI.” Fuel 104(0):183- 193, 2013, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2012.07.027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, M., Zheng, Z., and Liu, H., “Progress and recent trends inhomogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engines.” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 35(5):398-437, 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.pecs.2009.05.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tribotte, P., Ravet, F., Dugue, V., Obernesser, P., et al., “Two Strokes Diesel Engine - Promising Solution to Reduce CO2 Emissions.” Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences 48:2295-2314, 2012, doi: 10.1016/j.sbspro.2012.06.1202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., De Lima, D., Tribotte, P., et al., “Analysis of the combustion process, pollutant emissions and efficiency of an innovative 2-stroke HSDI engine designed for automotive applications.” Appl. Therm. Eng. 58:181-193, 2013,doi: 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2013.03.050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., De Lima, D., Dugue, V. et al., “The Potential of Highly Premixed Combustion for Pollutant Control in an Automotive Two-Stroke HSDI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1104, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., De Lima, D., Quechon, N., et al., “Implementation of the early injection highly premixe dcombustion concept in a two-stroke HSDI engine,” SIA Diesel Powertrain Congress 2012 June 5-6 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takeda, Y., Keiichi, N., and Keiichi, N., “Emission Characteristics of Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion with Extremely Early Staged Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 961163, 1996, doi:10.4271/961163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryan, T. and Callahan, T., “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition of Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 961160, 1996, doi:10.4271/961160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walter, B. and Gatellier, B., “Development of the High Power NADI™ Concept Using Dual Mode Diesel Combustion to Achieve Zero NOx and Particulate Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1744, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1744.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hardy, W. and Reitz, R., “A Study of the Effects of High EGR, High Equivalence Ratio, and Mixing Time on Emissions Levels in a Heavy- Duty Diesel Engine for PCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006- 01-0026, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa, A.J., Broatch, A., García, A., and Mónico, L.F., “Sensitivity of combustion noise and NOx and soot emissions topilot injection in PCCI Diesel engines.” Appl. Energy104(0):149-157, 2013, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2012.11.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Machrafi, H., Cavadias, S., and Amouroux, J., “A parametricstudy on the emissions from an HCCI alternative combustionengine resulting from the auto-ignition of primary referencefuels.” Appl. Energy 85(8):755- 764, 2008, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2008.02.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okude, K., Mori, K., Shiino, S., and Moriya, T., “Premixed Compression Ignition (PCI) Combustion for Simultaneous Reduction of NOx and Soot in Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1907, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noehre, C., Andersson, M., Johansson, B., and Hultqvist, A., “Characterization of Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3412, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S. et al., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y., and Aiyoshizawa, E., “Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low-Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., “Advantages of Fuels with High Resistance to Auto-ignition in Late-injection, Low-temperature, Compression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01- 3385, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., “Partially Pre-Mixed Auto- Ignition of Gasoline to Attain Low Smoke and Low NOx at High Load in a Compression Ignition Engine and Comparison with a Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0006, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Kalghatgi, G., Tait, N., Johansson, B. et al., “Fuel Octane Effects in the Partially Premixed Combustion Regime in Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2648, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P., and Cannella, W., “Effects of Different Type of Gasoline Fuels on Heavy Duty Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):71-88, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009- 01-2668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewander, M., Johansson, B., and Tunestål, P., “Investigation and Comparison of Multi Cylinder Partially Premixed Combustion Characteristics for Diesel and Gasoline Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1811, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1811.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Solaka, H., Aronsson, U., Tuner, M., and Johansson, B., “Investigation of Partially Premixed Combustion Characteristicsin Low Load Range with Regards to Fuel Octane Number in aLight-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0684, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0684.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borgqvist, P., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., “Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion in a Light Duty Engine at Low Load and Idle Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0687, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiadi, M., Johansson, B., Lundgren, M., and Gaynor, J.A., “Sensitivity Analysis Study on Ethanol Partially Premixed Combustion.” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1), 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0269.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., “Effects of Ethanol and Different Type of Gasoline Fuels on Partially Premixed Combustion from Low to High Load,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0871, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0871.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall, A., and Collings, N., “Gasoline Fuelled Partially Premixed Compression Ignition in a Light Duty Multi Cylinder Engine: A Study of Low Load and Low Speed Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01- 1791, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Das Adhikary, B., Ra, Y., Reitz, R., and Ciatti, S., “Numerical Optimization of a Light-Duty Compression Ignition Engine Fuelled With Low-Octane Gasoline,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1336, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Das Adhikary, B., Reitz, R., and Ciatti, S., “Study of In-Cylinder Combustion and Multi-Cylinder Light Duty Compression Ignition Engine Performance Using Different RON Fuels at Light Load Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0900, 2013, doi: 10.4271/2013-01-0900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ciatti, S., Johnson, M., Das Adhikary, B., Reitz, R., et al., “Efficiency and Emissions performance of Multizone Stratified Compression Ignition Using Different Octane Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01- 0263, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Operating a Heavy-Duty Direct-Injection Compression-Ignition Engine with Gasoline for Low Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1442, 2009,doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M., Sinnamon, J., Hoyer, K., and Husted, H., “Gasoline Direct Injection Compression Ignition (GDCI) - Diesel-like Efficiency with Low CO2 Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1386, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M.C., Sinnamon, J., Hoyer, K., and Husted, H., “Full-Time Gasoline Direct-Injection Compression Ignition (GDCI) for High Efficiency and Low NOx and PM.” SAE Int. J. Engines5(2), 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0384.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M.C., Sinnamon, J., Hoyer, K., Kim, J., et al., “Part-Load Operation of Gasoline Direct-Injection Compression Ignition (GDCI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0272, 2013, doi: 10.4271/2013- 01-0272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Molina, S., Novella, R., and De Lima, D., “Implementation of the Partially Premixed Combustion concept in a 2-stroke HSDI diesel engine fueled with gasoline.” Appl. Energy 122(0):94-111, 2014, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2014.02.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., Martín, J., and De Lima, D., “Analysis of the Load Effect on the Partially Premixed Combustion Concept in a 2-Stroke HSDI Diesel Engine Fueled with Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1291, 2014, doi: 10.4271/2014-01-1291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolodziej, C.P., Ciatti, S., Vuilleumier, D., Das Adhikary, B., et al., “Extension of the Lower Load Limit of Gasoline Compression Ignition with 87 AKI Gasoline by Injection Timing and Pressure,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1302, 2014, doi: 10.4271/2014-01-1302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., De Lima, D., and Tribotté, P., “Analysis of combustion concepts in a newly designed 2-strokeHSDI compression ignition engine.” Int. J. Engine Res. (Special Issue Article):1-16, 2014, doi:10.1177/1468087414562867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiadi, M., Johansson, B., Lundgren, M., and Gaynor, J.A., “Experimental Investigation on different Injection Strategies for Ethanol Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0281, 2013, doi: 10.4271/2013-01-0281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pohorelsky, L., Brynych, P., Macek, J., Vallaude, P.-Y., et al., “Air System Conception for a Downsized Two-Stroke Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0831, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0831.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., Gimeno, J., and Bracho, G., “A new methodology for correcting the signal cumulative phenomenon on injection rate measurements.” Exp. Tech. 32(1):46-49, 2008,doi:10.1111/j.1747-1567.2007.00188.x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., García, J.M., Salvador, F., and Gimeno, J., “Using spray momentum flux measurements to understand the influence of diesel nozzle geometry on spray characteristics.” Fuel84(5):551-561, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2004.10.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsen, D., Hutcherson, G., Wilson, B., and Mitchell, C., “Development of the Tracer Gas Method for Large Bore Natural Gas Engines: Part 1 - Method Validation.” J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power 124(3):678-685, 2002, doi:10.1115/1.1454116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsen, D., Hutcherson, G., Wilson, B., and Mitchell, C., “Development of the Tracer Gas Method for Large Bore Natural Gas Engines: Part 2 - Measurement of Scavenging Parameters.”J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power 124(3):686-694, 2002, doi:10.1115/1.1454117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Austen, A.E.W., and Priede, T., “Origins of Diesel engine noise,” Proc. IMechE Symp. on Engine Noise and Noise Suppression pp 19-32, 1958, doi.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Torregrosa, A.J., Broatch, A., and Monelletta, L., “Assessment of diesel combustion noise overall level intransient operation.” Int. J. Automot. Technol. 10(6):761-769,2009, doi: 10.1007/s12239-009- 0089-y.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa, A.J., Broatch, A., Martín, J., and Monelletta, L., “Combustion noise level assessment in direct injection Diesel engines by means of in-cylinder pressure components.” Meas. Sci. Technol. 18(7):2131-2142, 2007, doi: 10.1088/0957-0233/18/7/045.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dukowicz, J.K., “A particle-fluid numerical model for liquid sprays.” J. Comput. Phys. 35(2):229-253, 1980, doi:10.1016/0021- 9991(80)90087-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale, J.C., and Reitz, R.D., “Modeling Spray Atomization with the Kelvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh-Taylor Hybrid Model.” Atomization Sprays 9(6):623-650, 1999, doi: 10.1615/AtomizSpr.v9.i6.40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., and Reitz, R.D., “A temperature wall function formulation for variable-density turbulent flows with application to engine convective heat transfer modeling.” Int. J. Heat Mass Transfer 40(3):613-625, 1997, doi: 10.1016/0017-9310(96)00117-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brakora, J.L. “A Comprehensive Combustion Model for Biodiesel- Fueled Engine Simulations.” PhD Dissertation, University of Wisconsin- Madison, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., and Kadota, T., “Models for Combustion and Formation of Nitric Oxide and Soot in Direct Injection Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 760129, 1976, doi:10.4271/760129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagle, J., and Strickland-Constable, R., “Oxidation of carbon between 1000-2000 C,” Proceedings of the Fifth Carbon Conference 1962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Miles, P.C., and Pickett, L.M., “Conceptual models for partially premixed low-temperature diesel combustion.” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 39(2-3):246-283,2013, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.pecs.2012.09.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
