<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">103</volume>
         <issue-id>i40192732</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44612473</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of a Ceramic Particle Trap and Copper Fuel Additive on Heavy-Duty Diesel Emissions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>George D.</given-names>
                  <surname>Harvey</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Kirby J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Baumgard</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Linda D.</given-names>
                  <surname>Gratz</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Susan T.</given-names>
                  <surname>Bagley</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David G.</given-names>
                  <surname>Leddy</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1994</fpage>
         <lpage>2012</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1995 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44612473"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This research quantifies the effects of a copper fuel additive on the regulated [oxides of nitrogen (NOx),hydrocarbons (HC) and total paniculate matter (TPM)] and unregulated emissions [soluble organic fraction (SOF), vapor phase organics (XOC), polynuclear aromatic hydrocarbons (PAH), nitroparticle 1988 Cummins LTA10 diesel engine using a low sulfur fuel. The engine was operated at two steady state modes (EPA modes 9 and 11, which are 75 and 25% load at rated speed, respectively) and five additive levels (0, 15, 30, 60 and 100 ppm Cu by mass) with and without a ceramic trap. Measurements of PAH and mutagenic activity were limited to the 0, 30 and 60 ppm Cu levels. Data were also collected to assess the effect of the additive on regeneration temperature and duration.Copper species collected within the trap were identified and exhaust copper concentrations quantified. The fuel additive had little effect on baseline emissions (without the trap) of TPM, SOF, XOC, HC or NOX. Particle size distributions indicated that there was a trend towards more nuclei mode particles with increasing additive level, but an overall increase in mass emissions was not detected. Use of the additive generally resulted in reductions of PAH in both the SOF and XOC. Additive effects on mutagenic activity appeared to be mode dependent, with decreases in activity at mode 9 and relatively little change at mode 11. The trap reduced TPM from 72 to 93% compared to baseline, had no effect on NOX, and reduced HC about 30% at mode 9 with no consistent change at mode 11. The trap's SOF removal efficiency was greater at mode 9 (84 to 91%) than at mode 11 (55 to 88%). The XOC reductions were less than 48% at mode 9, with mode 11 again showing no consistent change.Collection of copper by the trap was greater than 95%, resulting in a 44 mg/m³ emission rate at mode 9 with 100 ppm copper in the fuel. PAH were generally reduced in the SOF by the trap, but displayed no change or were slightly increased in the XOC. As found in previous studies at MTU with traps, the particle and vapor phase associated mutagenic response generally decreased over time with continued use of the trap (this occurred at all additive levels in this study). The additive reduced the trap regeneration temperature from 510°C to about 375°C and reduced the regeneration time from about 90 minutes with no additive to about 1 minute with 30 ppm and greater additive concentrations. Trap ash analysis showed that approximately 89.5% of the material was CuO, 2.5% was Cu₂O, and 8% was CaSO₄.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d407e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e454" publication-type="other">
Bagley ST, Gratz LD, Leddy DG, Johnson JH. 1993. Charac-
terization of particle and vapor phase organic fraction emis-
sions from a heavy-duty diesel engine equipped with a particle
trap having regeneration controls. Research Report No 56.
Health Effects Institute, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e473a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e477" publication-type="other">
Bagley ST, Baumgard KJ, Gratz LD, Johnson JH, Leddy DG.
1994. Characterization of fuel and aftertreatment device effects
on diesel emissions. Final project report. In review. Health
Effects Institute, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e493a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e497" publication-type="other">
Baumgard KJ, Kittelson DB. 1985. The influence of a ceramic
particle trap on the size distribution of diesel particles. SAE
Paper No. 850009. SAE Transactions V. 1:56-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e510a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e514" publication-type="other">
Baumgard KJ, Bickel KL. 1987. Development and
effectiveness of ceramic diesel particle filters. Bureau of Mines
Information Circular IC9141 pp 94 -102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e532" publication-type="other">
Baumgard KJ, Johnson JH. 1992. Hie effect of low sulfur fuel
and a ceramic particle filter on diesel exhaust particle size
distributions. SAE Paper No. 920566. SAE Transactions
101:691-699.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e548a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e552" publication-type="other">
Dainty E, Lawson A, Vergeer H, Manicom B, Kreuzer T,
Engler B. 1987. Diesel emissions reduction by ceramic filters
employing catalysts or a fuel additive. SAE Paper No. 870014.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e565a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e569" publication-type="other">
DeMarini DN, Dallas MM, Lewtas J. 1989. Cytotoxicity and
effect on mutagenicity of buffers in a microsuspension assay.
Teratogen Carcinogen Mutagen 9:289-295.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e582a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e586" publication-type="other">
Johnson JH, Bagley ST, Gratz LD, Leddy DG. 1994. A review
of diesel particulate control technology and emission effects.
SAE Paper No. 940233.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e603" publication-type="other">
Kado NY, Langley D, Eisenstadt E. 1983. A simple
modification of the Salmonella liquid-incubation assay -
Increased sensitivity for detecting mutagens in human urine.
MutatRes 121:125-132.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e619a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e623" publication-type="other">
Kantola T, Bagley S, Gratz L, Leddy D, Johnson J. 1992. Hie
influence of a low sulfur fuel and a ceramic particle trap on the
physical, chemical, and biological character of heavy-duty die-
sel emissions. SAE Paper No. 920565. SAE Transactions
101:675-690.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e643a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e647" publication-type="other">
Kittelson DB, Dolan DF, Diver RB, Aufderheide E. 1978.
Diesel exhaust particle size distributions-fuel and additive
effects. SAE Paper No. 780787.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e660a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e664" publication-type="other">
Kojetin P, Janezich F, Sura L, Tuma D. 1993. Production
experience of a ceramic wall flow electric regeneration diesel
particulate trap. SAE Paper N. 930129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e677a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e681" publication-type="other">
Liu BYH, Kapadia A. 1978. U of MN Particle Technology
Laboratory Publication No. 325.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e691a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e695" publication-type="other">
Ludecke OA, Bly K. 1984. Diesel exhaust particle control by
monolith trap and fuel additive regeneration. SAE Paper No.
840077.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e708a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e712" publication-type="other">
McCabe R, Sinkevitch R. 1986. A laboratory combustion
study of (hesel particulates containing metal additives. SAE
Paper No. 860011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e729" publication-type="other">
Maron DN, Ames BN. 1983. Revised methods for the
Salmonella mutagenicity test. Mutat Res 113: 173-215.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e740a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e744" publication-type="other">
MacCrehan WA, May WE, Yung SD, Benner BA Jr. 1988.
Determination of nitro-polynuclear aromatic hydrocarbons in
air and diesel particulate matter by liquid chromatography with
electrochemical and fluorescence detection. Anal. Chem.
60:194-199.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e763a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e767" publication-type="other">
Opris CN, Gratz LD, Bagley ST, Baumgard KJ, Leddy DG,
Johnson JH. 1993. The effects of fuel sulfur concentration on
regulated and unregulated heavy-duty diesel emissions. SAE
Paper No. 930730.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e783a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e787" publication-type="other">
Pataky GM, Baumgard KJ, Gratz LD, Bagley ST, Leddy DG,
Johnson JH. 1994. Effects of an oxidation catalytic converter
on regulated and unregulated diesel emissions. SAE Paper No.
940243.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e803a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e807" publication-type="other">
SAS Institute, Inc. 1985. SAS User's Guide: Statistics, version
5. SAS Institute, Inc., Cary, NC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e817a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e821" publication-type="other">
Tuteja AD, Hoffman MB, Lopez-Crevillen JM, Singh S,
Stomber RR, Wallace GC. 1992. Selection and development of
a particulate trap system for a light duty diesel engine. SAE
Paper No. 920142.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e837a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e841" publication-type="other">
Wade W, White J, Florek J, Cikánek H. 1983. Thermal and
catalytic regeneration of diesel particulate traps. SAE Paper
No. 830083.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e855a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e859" publication-type="other">
Waldenmaier DA, Gratz LD, Bagley ST, Johnson JH, Leddy
DG. 1990. The influence of sampling conditions on the
repeatability of diesel particulate and vapor phase hydrocarbon
and PAH measurements. SAE Paper No 900642. SAE
Transactions V.99:1431-1448.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


