<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169048</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Control Variables Optimization and Feedback Control Strategy Design for the Blended Operating Regime of an Extended Range Electric Vehicle</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Škugor</surname>
                  <given-names>Branimir</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cipek</surname>
                  <given-names>Mihael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Deur</surname>
                  <given-names>Joško</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ of Zagreb</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169031</issue-id>
         <fpage>152</fpage>
         <lpage>162</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169048"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>In an authors' previous SAE publication, an energy management control strategy has been proposed for the basic, charge-depleting/charge-sustaining (CD/CS) regime of an Extended Range Electric Vehicle (EREV). The strategy is based on combining a rule-based controller, including a state-of-charge regulator, with an equivalent consumption minimization strategy. This paper presents an extension of the control strategy, which can provide a favorable vehicle behavior in the more general blended (BLND) operating regime, as well. Dynamic programming-based control variables optimization is first conducted to gain an insight into the vehicle optimal behavior in the BLND regime, facilitate the feedback control strategy development/extension, and serve as a benchmark for the control strategy verification. Next, a parameter optimization method is applied to find optimal values of critical engine on/off thresholds. Finally, the control strategy is verified against the optimal benchmark for several repetitive certified driving cycles, and the results are compared with those obtained for the basic CD/CS regime.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Conlon et al., “Output Split Electrically-Variable Transmission with Electric Propulsion using one or two Motors,” U.S. Patent No. 7 867 124, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, M., Holmes, A., Conlon, B., and Savagian, P., “The GM “Voltec” 4ET50 Multi-Mode Electric Transaxle,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1102-1114, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deur, J., Cipek, M., Skugor, B. and Petric, J., “Modeling and Low-level Control of Range Extended Electric Vehicle Dynamics,” International Conference on Powertrain Modeling and Control (PMC 2012), Bradford, UK, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skugor, B. and Deur, J., “Instantaneous Optimization-based Energy Management Control Strategy for Extended Range Electric Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1460, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1460.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tribioli, L., Onori, S., “Analysis of energy management strategies in plug-in hybrid electric vehicles: Application to the GM Chevrolet Volt,” (2013) Proceedings of the American Control Conference, art. no. 6580774, pp. 5966-5971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shankar, R., Marco, J., Assadian, F., “Design of an optimized charge-blended energy management strategy for a plugin hybrid vehicle,” (2012) Proceedings of the 2012 UKACC International Conference on Control, CONTROL 2012, art. no. 6334701, pp. 619-624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sivertsson, M., “Adaptive control using map-based ECMS for a PHEV,” (2012) IFAC Proceedings Volumes (IFAC-PapersOnline), pp. 357-362.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, M., Yang, Y., Chunting, C., “Analytical Approach for the Power Management of Blended-Mode Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles”, IEEE Transactions on vehicular technology, vol. 61, No. 4, May 2012, pp. 1554-1566.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sharer, P., Rousseau, A., Karbowski, D., and Pagerit, S., “Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle Control Strategy: Comparison between EV and Charge-Depleting Options,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0460, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0460.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cipek, M., Deur, J. and Petric, J., “Bond Graph Modeling and Power-flow Analysis of Range Extended Electric Vehicle Transmission”, International Conference on Bond Graph Modeling and Simulation (ICBGM 2012), Genoa, Italy, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bin, Y., Li, Y. and Feng, N., “Nonlinear Dynamic Battery Model with Boundary and Scanning Hysteresis,” Proceedings of the ASME 2009 Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cipek, M., Čorić, M., Škugor, B., Kasać, J. and Deur, J., “Control Variable Optimization for an Extended Range Electric Vehicle”, International Journal of Powertrains (IJPT), (submitted)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paganelli, G., Guezennec, Y., and Rizzoni, G., “Optimizing Control Strategy for Hybrid Fuel Cell Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0102, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cipek, M., Čorić, M., Škugor, B., Kasać, J. et al., “Dynamic Programming-based Optimization of Control Variables of an Extended Range Electric Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1481, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1481.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bellman, R. E. and Dreyfus, S. E., “Applied Dynamic Programming”, Princeton University Press, New Jersey, 1962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pierre, D. A., “Optimization Theory with Applications”, Dover, New York, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finkel, E. D., “DIRECT Optimization Algorithm User Guide”, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
