<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169013</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Design of Efficient Air-Conditioning Systems for Electric Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Torregrosa-Jaime</surname>
                  <given-names>Bárbara</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Payá</surname>
                  <given-names>Jorge</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Corberan</surname>
                  <given-names>Jose</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Universitat Politècnica de València</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>July 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169008</issue-id>
         <fpage>291</fpage>
         <lpage>303</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169013"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Among all the auxiliary components in conventional and electric vehicles, air-conditioning (AC) systems present the highest energy consumption. In fully electrical vehicles (FEVs), the heating of the cabin becomes an additional challenge as there is less waste heat available. Therefore, a careful design of the air-conditioning system and of the operation strategies is necessary to reach a reasonable FEV autonomy without compromising the thermal comfort.</p>
            <p>This paper presents a tool for the design, analysis and optimization of an efficient air-conditioning system for an electric minibus. It consists of dynamic models of each component of the system that have been developed and fully validated individually. Finally, they have been coupled together to simulate the overall vehicle performance of the vehicle in MATLAB-SIMULINK.</p>
            <p>The core of the system is a water-to-water reversible heat pump with a variable speed compressor. The internal water loop connects the heat pump to the air-coolers inside the cabin while the external water loop is integrated within the heat rejection system of the power electronics. An automatic control system regulates the speed of the compressor, the blowers and the circulation pumps to reach thermal comfort.</p>
            <p>The power consumption has been analysed under different working conditions and control settings using the overall vehicle model. The latter is a powerful tool not only to design and select MAC equipment, but also to find the most efficient operation strategies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payá, J., Corberán, J.M., Torregrosa-Jaime, B., Vasile-Muller, C., “Innovative air-conditioning systems for conventional and electric vehicles”, presented at EAEC European Automotive Congress, Spain, June 14-16, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suzuki, T. and Ishii, K., “Air Conditioning System for Electric Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 960688, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960688.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrington, R., et al., “Fuel consumption and associated CO2 emissions due to MACs”, presented at Mac Summit 2003, Belgium, February, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clodic, D., Zgheib, E., Mortada, S., “Impacts of heating and cooling on electrified vehicles”, presented at 4th European Workshop MAC and Vehicle Thermal Systems, Italy, December 1-2, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa, B., Payá, J., Corberán, J.M., “Modelling of mobile airconditioning systems for electric vehicles”, presented at 4th European Workshop MAC and Vehicle Thermal Systems, Italy, December 1-2, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ICE Project FP7, GC-SST.2010.7-2, Grant Agreement no 265434: http://www.ice-mac-ev.eu.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Mathworks Inc., MATLAB &amp; Simulink R2009b, Computer Software, Natick, Massachusetts, USA, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa-Jaime, B., “Modelado y análisis de un sistema de aire acondicionado para vehículos basado en la refrigeración magnetica”, Master Thesis, Universitat Politècnica de València, Valencia, Spain, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gado Amr El-SayedAlaa El-Din, “Development of a dynamic test facility for environmental control systems”, PhD Thesis, University of Maryland, Maryland, USA, pp.21-32, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mezrhab, A., Bouzidi, M.,“Computation of thermal comfort inside a passenger car compartment”, Applied Thermal Engineering 26:1697-1704, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corberán, J.M., et al. IMST-ART. A simulation tool to assist the selection, design and optimization of refrigeration equipment and components, Computer Software, Investigación y Modelado de Sistemas Térmicos, Instituto de Ingeniería Energética, Universitat Politècnica de València, Valencia, Spain, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa-Jaime, B., Corberán, J.M., Vasile, C., Muller, C., Risser, M., Payá-Herrero, J., “Design of a magnetocaloric air-conditioning system for an electric minibus”. Proceedings of Fifth IIF-IIR International Conference on Magnetic Refrigeration at Room Temperature, Grenoble, ISBN 978-2-913149-96-0: 583-590, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engineered Machined Products, Inc. “EMP WP29 Electric Water Pump”, MI, USA, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Di Sciullo, F., “ICE Project: A magnetocaloric based mobile air conditioning system”, presented at 4th European Workshop MAC and Vehicle Thermal Systems, Italy, December 1-2, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Declaye, S., Delfosse, R., Lemart, V., “Testing and modeling a reversible heat pump for a passenger car”, presented at 4th European Workshop MAC and Vehicle Thermal Systems, Italy, December 1-2, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hafner, A., “TIFFE environmental impact tool”, presented at 4th European Workshop MAC and Vehicle Thermal Systems, Italy, December 1-2, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
