<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association (NTA)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26418798</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>INTERNATIONAL TAX PLANNING UNDER THE DESTINATION-BASED CASH FLOW TAX</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Auerbach</surname>
                  <given-names>Alan J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of California, Berkeley, CA, USA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Devereux</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation, Saïd Business School, Oxford, UK</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Keen</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>International Monetary Fund, Washington DC, USA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vella</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Faculty of Law, University of Oxford, UK</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December, 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>70</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26418793</issue-id>
         <fpage>783</fpage>
         <lpage>802</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26418798"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper considers the implications of the destination-based cash flow tax (DBCFT) for three common ways of shifting taxable profits between countries: through manipulation of transfer prices, the use of debt, and locating intangible assets in low taxed jurisdictions. It shows that none of these planning devices would be available under a DBCFT, if adopted universally. This is because intra-group payments between two countries do not affect tax liabilities in either country. If adopted unilaterally, however, there would be an incentive to shift profit to the adopting country, at the expense of non-adopting countries.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label> 
            <kwd>destination-based cash flow tax</kwd> 
            <kwd>international taxation</kwd> 
            <kwd>tax avoidance</kwd> 
            <kwd>tax planning</kwd> 
            <kwd>transfer pricing</kwd> 
            <kwd>profit shifting</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Avi Yonah, Reuven S., and Kimberly Clausing, 2017. “Problems with Destination-Based Corporate Taxes and the Ryan Blueprint.” Columbia Journal of Tax Law 8 (2), 229–255.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., 2010. “A Modern Corporate Tax.” The Center for American Progress/The Hamilton Project; available at https://www.americanprogress.org/wp-content/uploads/issues/2010/12/pdf/auerbachpaper.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., Michael P. Devereux, and Helen Simpson, 2010. “Taxing Corporate Income.” In Mirrlees, James, et al. (eds.), Dimensions of Tax Design: The Mirrlees Review, 837–893. Oxford University Press, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and Michael P. Devereux, 2013. “Cash Flow Taxes in an International Setting.” Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper No. 13/11. Oxford, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., Michael P. Devereux, Michael Keen, and John Vella, 2017. “Destination-Based Cash-Flow Taxation.” Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper No. 17/01. Oxford, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., 2017. “Demystifying the Destination-Based Cash-Flow Tax.” Paper presented to the Brookings Panel on Economic Activity. The Brookings Institution, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bankman, Joseph, and Michael L. Schler, 2007.“Tax Planning under the Flat Tax.” In Aaron, Henry J., Leonard Burman, and C. Eugene Steurele (eds.), Taxing Capital Income, 245–284. The Urban Institute Press, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brauner, Yariv, 2016. “Changes? BEPS, Transfer Pricing for Intangibles, and CCAS.” University of Florida Levin College of Law Research Paper No. 16-14. Gainesville, FL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bond, Stephen R., and Michael P. Devereux, 2002. “Cash Flow Taxes in an Open Economy.” CEPR Discussion Paper No. 3401. Centre for Economic Policy Research, London, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruce, Donald, William F. Fox, and LeAnn Luna, 2015. “E-Tailer Sales Nexus and State Tax Policies.” National Tax Journal 68 (3S), 735–766.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clausing, Kimberly, 2016. “The Effect of Profit Shifting on the Corporate Tax Base in the United States and Beyond.” National Tax Journal 69 (4), 905–934.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collier, Richard, and Joseph Andrus, 2017. Transfer Pricing and the Arm’s Length Principle after BEPS. Oxford University Press, Oxford, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collier, Richard, Michael P. Devereux, and Strahil Lepoev, 2017. “Proposed UK Changes on the Tax Deductibility of Corporate Interest Expense.” British Tax Review 1, 60–79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collier, Richard, and Michael P. Devereux, 2017. “The Destination–Based Cash Flow Tax and Double Tax Treaties.” Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper No. 17/06. Oxford, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cristea, Anca D., and Daniel Nguyen, 2016. “Transfer Pricing by Multinational Firms: Evidence from Foreign Firm Ownerships.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 8 (3), 170–202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crivelli, Ernesto, Ruud De Mooij, and Michael Keen, 2016. “Base Erosion, Profit Shifting and Developing Countries.” FinanzArchiv 72 (4), 268–301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cui, Wei, 2015, “Taxation of Non-Residents’ Capital Gains.” In Alt, Hugh and Brian Arnold (eds.), United Nations Handbook on Selected Issues in Protecting the Tax Base of Developing Countries, 107–154. United Nations, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Mooij, Ruud A., 2011. “The Tax Elasticity of Corporate Debt: A Synthesis of Size and Variations.” IMF Working Paper No. 11/95. International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">European Commission, 2016. “Proposal for a Council Directive on a Common Consolidated Corporate Tax Base (CCCTB).” COM(2016) 683 final.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flaaen, Aaron, 2017. “The Role of Transfer Prices in Profit-Shifting by U.S. Multinational Firms: Evidence from the 2004 Homeland Investment Act.” FEDS Working Paper No. 2017-055. Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Finance and Economics Discussion Series, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graetz, Michael, 2017. “The Known Unknowns of the Business Tax Reforms Proposed in the House Republican Blueprint.” Columbia Journal of Tax Law 8 (2), 117–170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grinberg, Itai, 2017. “The House GOP Blueprint Can Be Drafted to Comply with WTO Rules.” April 26, available at https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2956048.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guvenen, Faith, Raymond J. Mataloni, Jr., Dylan G. Rassier, and Kim J. Ruhl, 2017. “Offshore Profit Shifting and Domestic Productivity Measurement.” NBER Working Paper No. 23324.National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hebous, Shafik, and Niels Johannesen, 2016. “At Your Service! The Role of Tax Havens in International Trade with Services.” CESifo Working Paper No. 5414. Center for Economic Studies and Ifo Institute, Munich, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hariton, David P., 2017. “Planning for Border Adjustments: A Practical Analysis.” Tax Notes (February 20), 965–977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IMF, 2014. Spillovers in International Corporate Taxation. IMF Policy Paper, May 9, available at https://www.imf.org/external/np/pp/eng/2014/050914.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keen, Michael, and Stephen Smith, 2006. “VAT Fraud and Evasion: What Do We Know, and What Can Be Done?” National Tax Journal 59 (4), 861–887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleinbard, Edward, 2011. “Stateless Income.” Florida Tax Review 11, 733.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lamensch, Marie, 2015. European Value Added Tax in the Digital Era. IBFD Doctoral Series Vol. 36. International Bureau of Fiscal Documentation, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meade Committee, 1978. “The Structure and Reform of Direct Taxation.” Report of a committee chaired by Professor J.E. Meade. George Allen &amp; Unwin, London, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, David S., 2017. “Tax Planning under the Destination Based Cash Flow Tax: A Guide for Policy Makers and Practitioners.” Columbia Journal of Tax Law 8 (2), 295–308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OECD, 2013. “Addressing Base Erosion and Profit Shifting.” OECD Publishing, Paris, France, available at http://www.oecd.org/tax/beps/addressing-base-erosion-and-profit-shifting-9789264192744-en.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OECD, 2015a. “Measuring and Monitoring BEPS, Action 11 – 2015 Final Report.” OECD/G20 Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Project. OECD Publishing, Paris, France, available at http://www.oecd.org/tax/measuring-and-monitoring-beps-action-11-2015-final-report-9789264241343-en.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OECD, 2015b. “Limiting Base Erosion Involving Interest Deductions and Other Financial Payments, Action 4 – 2015 Final Report.” OECD/G20 Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Project. OECD Publishing, Paris, France, available at http://www.oecd.org/tax/limiting-base-erosion-involvinginterest-deductions-and-other-financial-payments-action-4-2015-final-report-9789264241176-en.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OECD, 2017. “International VAT/GST Guidelines.” OECD Publishing, Paris, France, available at http://www.oecd.org/ctp/international-vat-gst-guidelines-9789264271401-en.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">President’s Advisory Panel on Federal Tax Reform, 2005. “Simple, Fair and Pro Growth: Proposals to Fix America’s Tax System,” available at https://www.treasury.gov/resource-center/tax-policy/Documents/Report-Fix-Tax-System-2005.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Riedel, Nadine, 2014. “Quantifying International Tax Avoidance: A Review of the Academic Literature.” European Tax Policy Forum Policy Paper No. 2, available at http://www.etpf.org/papers/PP002QuantAvoid.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schön, Wolfgang, 2016. “Destination-Based Income Taxation and WTO Law: A Note.” Working Paper of the Max Planck Institute for Tax Law and Public Finance No. 2016-3. Munich, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schizer, David M., 2017. “Border Adjustments and the Conservation of Tax Planning.” Tax Notes 155, June 5, 1451–1459.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ways and Means Committee of the House of Representatives, 2016. A Better Way Forward: Our Vision for a Confident America, available at https://abetterway.speaker.gov/_assets/pdf/ABetterWay-Tax-PolicyPaper.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
