<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">ctbuhj</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016544</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CTBUH Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19461186</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19461194</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90020855</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Research</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject>Architecture/Design</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Micro-MACRO Living in the Global High-Rise</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hoang</surname>
                  <given-names>Mimi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>nARCHITECTS</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>68 Jay Street</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Brooklyn NY 11201</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>United States</addr-line>
               </aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mimi Hoang is a principal of nARCHITECTS and an Adjunct Assistant Professor at Columbia’s Graduate School of Architecture. Along with partner Eric Bunge, she co-founded nARCHITECTS with the goal of addressing contemporary issues in architecture through conceptually driven, socially engaging and technologically innovative work. Their work instigates interactions between architecture, public space, and their dynamically changing contexts. nARCHITECTS was honored with an American Academy of Arts and Letters Award in Architecture and the AIANY’s Andrew J. Thomson Award for Pioneering in Housing. Mimi received an MArch from Harvard’s Graduate School of Design and a BSc from MIT.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vandal</surname>
                  <given-names>Ammr</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Ammr Vandal is an Associate Principal of nARCHITECTS. Ammr received a MArch from GSAPP at Columbia University, after earning her BA in Economics from the College of Wooster, Ohio. Prior to joining nARCHITECTS, she trained in New York, Caracas, and Pakistan. At nARCHITECTS, Ammr has led several award-winning projects at the office, including Carmel Place, Wyckoff House Museum in Brooklyn, and Forest Pavilion in Taiwan and is currently Associate Principal-in-Charge of A/D/O in Brooklyn. She has taught with Eric Bunge at GSAPP and has been a guest critic at Pratt, Parsons, and CUNY.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90020846</issue-id>
         <fpage>32</fpage>
         <lpage>37</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90020855"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>What housing models should dense urban cities pursue to address population rise, housing shortages, and changes in demographics? As cities seek to address large discrepancies between their housing stock and their population, many developments opt for buildings with large footprints and massing bulk. While these multi-family housing developments offer large quantities of units, they diminish the street environment with their monumental bases – often occupied by a single use or a few large uses. This paper explores the viability of “micro-macro” living, in which one’s private residential unit decreases in size, in favor of increased social interaction, sense of community, and density and diversity of neighborhood amenities. “Small” or “micro” need not connote a living experience that is diminished or isolated. By understanding the challenges and opportunities in the design and construction of micro-unit apartments, cities can address growth and density without undermining diversity and social interaction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>Micro-Units</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Affordable Housing</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Density</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">HONG KONG CENSUS. 2017. www.censtatd.gov.hk</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">COOKSON SMITH, P. 2011. “The Culture of Compactness: Dimensions of Density in Hong Kong.” CTBUH Journal 2011 Issue I: 34–9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">HONG KONG 2030+. 2017. www.hk2030plus.hk/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NYC PLANNING. 2017. www1.nyc.gov/site/planning/data-maps/nyc-population/page</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PERINE, J. &amp; WATSON, S. 2011. “One Size Fits Some.” Acessed May 2017. http://www.chpcny.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/One-Size-Fits-Some.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PERRY, M. 2016. “New US Homes Today are 1,000 Square Feet Larger than in 1973 and Living Space per Person has Doubled.” Accessed May 2017. http://www.aei.org/publication/new-us-homes-today-are-1000-square-feet-larger-than-in-1973-and-living-space-per-person-has-nearly-doubled/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ZHAO, S. 2016. “Planning Chiefs Reveal Vision for More Public Space in Heaving Hong Kong.” South China Morning Post, December 31, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
