<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">ctbuhj</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016544</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CTBUH Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19461186</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19461194</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90006429</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Research</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject>MEP</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Bioclimatic Comfort Design Toolkit For High-Rise Buildings</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Janssen</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeroen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90006422</issue-id>
         <fpage>20</fpage>
         <lpage>26</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90006429"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>Building in an ever more urbanized world, with high-rise buildings increasing in both height and number, makes it essential to ensure we create comfortable urban spaces, as the urban microclimate in and around towers is affected dramatically. This paper proposes a new method of computational design that creates a continuous workflow, one that synthesizes the interaction of dynamic structural behavior, climate, and thermal comfort directly into the digital design process. The author’s team has developed a custom software interface that connects different aspects of the design (geometry, BIM, structural analysis, and computational fluid dynamics) in one workflow, allowing different members of the design team to interact simultaneously and inform the design in real time.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>MEP Engineering</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Thermal Comfort</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Environmental Engineering</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>C</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AMERICAN SOCIETY OF HEATING VENTILATING AND AIR-CONDITIONING ENGINEERS (ASHRAE). 2013. ASHRAE Standard 55 – Thermal Environmental Conditions for Human Occupancy. Atlanta: ASHRAE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BLOCKEN, B. 2015. “Computational Fluid Dynamics for Urban Physics: Importance, Scales, Possibilities, Limitations and 10 Tips and Tricks Towards Accurate and Reliable Simulations.” Building and Environment 91: 219–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BLOCKEN, B.; JANSSEN, W. D. &amp; VAN HOOFF, T. 2012. “CFD Simulation for Pedestrian Wind Comfort and Wind Safety in Urban Areas: General Decision Framework and Case Study for the Eindhoven University Campus.” Environmental Modelling &amp; Software 30: 15–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BRÖDE, P.; FIALA, D.; BLAZEJCZYK, K.; EPSTEIN, Y.; HOLMÉR, I.; JENDRITZKY, G.; KAMPMANN, B. et al. 2009. “Calculating UTCI Equivalent Temperature.” Paper presented at the 13th International Conference on Environmental Ergonomics, Boston, MA, August 2–7, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FANGER, P. 1970. Thermal Comfort: Analysis and Applications in Environmental Engineering. New York: McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FIALA, D.; HAVENITH, G.; BRÖDE, P.; KAMPMANN, B. &amp; JENDRITZKY, G. 2011. “UTCI-Fiala Multi-Node Model of Human Heat Transfer and Temperature Regulation.” International Journal of Biometeorology Special Issue: 1–13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FRANKE, J.; HELLSTEN, a.; SCHLÜNZEN, H. &amp; CARISSIMO, B. 2010. “The Best Practice Guideline for the CFD Simulation of Flows in the Urban Environment: An Outcome of COST 732.” Paper presented at the Fifth International Symposium on Computational Wind Engineering (CWE 2010), Chapel Hill, NC, May 23–27, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LAWSON, T. 2001. Building Aerodynamics. London: Imperial College Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LINDBERG, F. HOLMER, B. &amp; THORSSON, S. 2008. “SOLWEIG 1.0 – Modelling Spatial Variations of 3D Radiant Fluxes and Mean Radiant Temperature in Complex Urban Settings.” International Journal of Biometeorology 52(7): 697–713.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NEN. 2006. NEN 8100: 2006 – Wind Comfort and Wind Danger in the Built Environment. Delft: NEN.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NIKOLOPOULOU, M.; LYKOUDIS, S. &amp; KIKIRA, M. 2004. “Thermal Comfort Models for Open Urban Spaces.” In RUROS – Rediscovering the Urban Realm and Open Spaces, edited by Marialena Nikolopoulou: 2–6. Athens: Centre for Renewable Energy Sources (CRES).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NORRIS, S. E. &amp; RICHARDS, P. J. 2010. “Appropriate Boundary Conditions for Computational Wind Engineering Models Revisited.” Paper presented at the Fifth International Symposium on Computational Wind Engineering (CWE 2010), Chapel Hill, NC, May 23–27, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">TOMINAGAA, Y.; MOCHIDA, A.; YOSHIE, R.; KATAOKA, H.; NOZU, T.; YOSHIKAWA, M. &amp; SHIRASAWA, T. 2008. “AIJ Guidelines for Practical Applications of CFD to Pedestrian Wind Environment around Buildings.” Journal for Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 96(10–11): 1749–61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">TROEN, I. &amp; PETERSEN, E. L. 1989. European Wind Atlas. Roskilde: Risø National Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
