<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000371</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40006954</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Bilingual Sentence Alignment: Balancing Robustness and Accuracy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michel</given-names>
                  <surname>Simard</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Pierre</given-names>
                  <surname>Plamondon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>59</fpage>
         <lpage>80</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1998 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40006954"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>Sentence alignment is the problem of making explicit the relations that exist between the sentences of two texts that are known to be mutual translations. Automatic sentence-alignment methods typically face two kinds of difficulties. First, there is the question of robustness. In real life, discrepancies between a source text and its translation are quite common: differences in layout, omissions, inversions, etc. Sentence-alignment programs must be ready to deal with such phenomena. Then, there is the question of accuracy. Even when translations are "clean", alignment is still not a trivial matter: some decisions are hard to make, even for humans. We report here on the current state of our ongoing efforts to produce a sentence-alignment program that is both robust and accurate. The method that we propose relies on two new alignment engines: one that produces highly reliable and robust character-level alignments, and one that relies on statistical lexical knowledge to produce accurate mappings. Experimental results are presented which demonstrate the method's effectiveness, and highlight where problems remain to be solved.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>bilingual sentence alignment</kwd>
            <kwd>bitext</kwd>
            <kwd>translation analysis</kwd>
            <kwd>statistical translation model</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d364162e226a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e230" publication-type="other">
Aarts, E. and J. Korst: 1989, Simulated Annealing and Boltzmann Machines: A Stochastic
Approach to Combinatorial Optimization and Neural Computing. John Wiley and Sons, Chich-
ester, England.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e243a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e247" publication-type="other">
Brown, P.F., J.C. Lai, and R.L. Mercer: 1991, 'Aligning Sentences in Parallel Corpora', in 29th
Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Berkeley, Calif., pp. 89-94.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e257a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e261" publication-type="other">
Brown, P.F., S.A. Delia Pietra, VJ. Delia Pietra, and R.L. Mercer: 1993, The Mathematics of
Machine Translation: Parameter Estimation', Computational Linguistics 19, 263-311.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e271a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e275" publication-type="other">
Catizone, R., G. Russell, and S. Warwick: 1989, 'Deriving Translation Data from Bilingual Texts',
in Proceedings of the 1st International Lexical Acquisition Workshop, Detroit, MI, pp. 15-21.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e286a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e290" publication-type="other">
Chen, S.F.: 1993, 'Aligning Sentences in Bilingual Corpora Using Lexical Information', in 31st
Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Columbus, Ohio, pp. 9-16.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e300a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e304" publication-type="other">
Church, K.W.: 1993, "Charjilign: A Program for Aligning Parallel Texts at the Character Level', in
31st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Columbus, Ohio, pp. 1-8.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e314a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e318" publication-type="other">
Dagan, I., K.W. Church, and W.A. Gale: 1993, 'Robust Bilingual Word Alignment for Machine
Aided Translation', in Proceedings of the Workshop on Very Large Corpora: Academic and
Industrial Perspectives, Columbus, Ohio, pp. 164-171.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e331a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e335" publication-type="other">
Fung, P. and K.R. McKeown: 1994, 'Aligning Noisy Parallel Corpora Across Language Groups:
Word Pair Feature by Dynamic Time Warping', in Technology Partnerships for Crossing the Lan-
guage Barrier: Proceedings of the First Conference of the Association for Machine Translation
in the Americas, Columbia, Maryland, pp. 81-89.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e351a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e355" publication-type="other">
Gale, W.A. and K.W. Church: 1991, 'A Program for Aligning Sentences in Bilingual Corpora', in
29th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Berkeley, Calif., pp. 177-
183.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e368a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e372" publication-type="other">
Isabelle, P., M. Dymetman, G. Foster, J-M. Jutras, E. Macklovitch, F. Perrault, X. Ren. and M.
Simard: 1993, 'Translation Analysis and Translation Automation', in Proceedings of Fifth In-
ternational Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation TMI
'93: MT in the Next Generation, Kyoto, Japan, pp. 15-22.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e389a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e393" publication-type="other">
Kay, M. and M. Roscheisen: 1993, 'Text-Translation Alignment', Computational Linguistics 19,
121-142.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e403a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e407" publication-type="other">
Klavans, J. and E. Tzoukermann: 1995, 'Combining Corpus and Machine-Readable Dictionary Data
for Building Bilingual Lexicons', Machine Translation 10, 59-75.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e417a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e421" publication-type="other">
Melamed, I.D.: 1996, 'A Geometric Approach to Mapping Bitext Correspondence', in Proceedings
of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, Philadelphia, PA,
pp. 93-101.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e434a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e438" publication-type="other">
Palmer, D.D. and M.A. Hearst: 1994, Adaptive Sentence Boundary Disambiguation, Report No.
UCB/CSD 94/797, Computer Science Division (EECS), University of California, Berkeley, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e448a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e452" publication-type="other">
Simard, M.: 1997, BAF : un corpus de bi-texte anglais-francais annote a la main,
http : / /www-rali.iro . umontreal . ca/arc-a2 /BAF.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e462a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e466" publication-type="other">
Simard, M., G. Foster, and P. Isabelle: 1992, 'Using Cognates to Align Sentences in Bilingual
Corpora', in Quatriéme colloque international sur les aspects théoriques et méthodologiques
de la traduction automatique, Fourth International Conference on Theoretical and Methodolog-
ical Issues in Machine Translation: Méthodes empiristes versus méthodes rationalistes en TA,
Empiricist vs. Rationalist Methods in MT, TMI-92, Montréal, Canada, pp. 12-20.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d364162e486a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d364162e490" publication-type="other">
Simard, M., G. Foster, and F. Perrault: 1993, Trans Search: un concordancier bilingue, CITI Technical
Report, Montréal, Canada.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
