<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277779</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Potential of a Variable Compression Ratio Gasoline SI Engine with Very High Expansion Ratio and Variable Valve Actuation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ferrey</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miehe</surname>
                  <given-names>Yves</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Constensou</surname>
                  <given-names>Cyrille</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Collee</surname>
                  <given-names>Vincent</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>MCE-5 Development</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>468</fpage>
         <lpage>487</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277779"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Combustion simulations and single cylinder engine tests show a clear potential when coupling the Variable Compression Ratio (VCR) engine with the Variable Valve Actuation (VVA) technologies.</p>
            <p>Simulations demonstrate the thermodynamic benefit from increasing the geometric Compression Ratio (CR&gt;18:1) in combination with VVA compared to VVT strategies, thanks to the use of Atkinson / Miller Cycles. 3D combustion simulations of high compression ratio combustion chamber geometries used with Early or Late Intake Valve Closing strategies have been carried out with IFP-C3D™. They show an indicated efficiency increase up to 12 or 13% between compression ratio 10:1 and 18-20:1 at low loads (BMEP &lt; 8 bar).</p>
            <p>Single cylinder engine tests have been performed with specific combustion chambers up to CR 23:1 and have confirmed the simulation results.</p>
            <p>0D GT-POWER™ simulations have been correlated to the engine tests and used to extrapolate them to a 3 cylinders 1.1L TGDI VCR-VVA engine, for both EIVC and LIVC intake valve lift strategies.</p>
            <p>Finally, simulations and tests show correlated thermodynamic benefits of the association of VCR and VVA, improving fuel consumption on driving cycles between 8 and 11% compared to a 10.5:1 fixed compression ratio engine equipped with 2 VVT. Combining the VCR and VVA optimizes each potential far more than when separated (alone). Furthermore, the fuel consumption benefit is robust through driving cycles and downsizing level.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS:</label>
            <kwd>VCR</kwd>
            <kwd>VVA</kwd>
            <kwd>Compression ratio</kwd>
            <kwd>Expansion Ratio</kwd>
            <kwd>Miller</kwd>
            <kwd>Atkinson</kwd>
            <kwd>EIVC</kwd>
            <kwd>LIVC</kwd>
            <kwd>Gasoline</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schernus C., Ewald J., DI Matteo F., Morcinkowski B. - FEV GmbH “Methods to Reduce End Gas Temperature for Lower Knocking Sensitivity - A simulation Study” - SIA conference, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benz A., Rieβ M., Sens M., Wöbke M. - IAV GmbH “Valve Train Variabilities on Gasoline Engines between Dethrottling and Turbulence Generation” - SIA conference, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomazic D., Kleeberg H., Bowyer S., Dohmen J., Wittek K., Haake B. - FEV Inc and GmbH “Two-Stage Variable Compression Ratio (VCR) System to Increase Efficiency in Gasoline Powertrains” - DEER Conference, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Constensou C., Kapus P., Prevedel K., Bandel W. - “Performance measurements of a GDI variable compression ratio engine fitted with a 2-stage boosting system and external cooled EGR” - 20. Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knop V., Michel J.B., Colin O. - On the use of a tabulation approach to model auto-ignition during flame propagation in SI engines”, Applied Energy - Elsevier Ltd., 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamakawa, M., Youso, T., Fujikawa, T., Nishimoto, T. et al., “Combustion Technology Development for a High Compression Ratio SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):98-105, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1871.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos C.D., Kosmadakisa G.M., Dimaratosa A.M. and Pariotisb E.G. - “Investigating the effect of crevice flow on internal combustion engines using a new simple crevice model implemented in a CFD code”, Applied Energy vol. 88 p 111-126, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihisa, D. and Daisaku, S., “Research on Improving Thermal Efficiency through Variable Super-High Expansion Ratio Cycle,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0174, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01- 0174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laget, O., Zaccardi, J., Gautrot, X., Mansion, T. et al., “Establishing New Correlations Between In-Cylinder Charge Motion and Combustion Process in Gasoline Engines Through a Numerical DOE,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):183-201, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010- 01-0349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bohbot J., Gillet N. and Benkenida A. - “IFP-C3D: an Unstructured Parallel Solver for Reactive Compressible Gas Flow with Spray”, Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology - Rev. IFP, Vol. 64, No. 3, pp. 309-335, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boust B., “Etude expérimentale et modélisation des pertes thermiques pariétales lors de l'interaction flamme-paroi instationnaire”, PhD Poitiers Univ., 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angelberger, C., Poinsot, T., and Delhay, B., “Improving Near- Wall Combustion and Wall Heat Transfer Modeling in SI Engine Computations,” SAE Technical Paper 972881, 1997, doi:10.4271/972881.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw Hill, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
