<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277658</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Multi-Dimensional CFD-Chemical Kinetics Approach in Detection and Reduction of Knocking Combustion in Diesel-Natural Gas Dual-Fuel Engines Using Local Heat Release Analysis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Maghbouli</surname>
                  <given-names>Amin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>National University of Singapore</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shafee</surname>
                  <given-names>Sina</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Middle East Technical University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Saray</surname>
                  <given-names>Rahim Khoshbakhti</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sahand University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Wenming</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>National University of Singapore</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hosseini</surname>
                  <given-names>Vahid</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sharif Univ of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>An</surname>
                  <given-names>Hui</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>National University of Singapore</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>777</fpage>
         <lpage>787</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277658"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Dual-fuel diesel-natural gas (NG) engine exhibits higher power density and lower specific emissions compared to dedicated diesel engines. However, high intake temperatures, high compression ratios, combined with high engine loads may lead to engine knock. This is potentially a limiting factor on engine downsizing and getting higher power. In the present study, the combustion process under knocking conditions has been investigated in a dual-fuel diesel-NG engine. A comprehensive multi-dimensional simulation framework was generated by integrating the CHEMKIN chemistry solver into the KIVA-3V code. A detailed chemical kinetics mechanism was used for<italic>n</italic>-heptane and methane as diesel and NG surrogates. Combination of detailed chemical kinetics and detailed fluid dynamics calculation enabled the model to take into account the characteristics of most pronounced knock type in dual-fuel engines, so called end-gas knock. Within the CFD computational domain, eight regions that are the representatives of the dual-fuel heat release patterns have been selected to extract local properties. Using local knock identification factors, end-gas knock was observed in abnormal combustion cases. A new Knock Intensity factor (K.I) was introduced based on local heat release rate. Using developed knock prediction method, results showed knock could be mitigated by using EGR. Moreover, effect of premixed methane equivalence ratio on knocking combustion was investigated.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J, B. “Internal combustion engine fundamentals” New York: McGraw-Hill; 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turns, S, R. “An Introduction to Combustion, concepts and applications” McGraw Hill. International Edition; 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kusaka, J., Ito, S., Mizushima, N., Daisho, Y. et al., “A Numerical Study on Combustion and Exhaust Gas Emissions Characteristics of a Dual Fuel Natural Gas Engine Using a Multi-Dimensional Model Combined with Detailed Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1939, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G., Liu, Z., and Jones, W., “Exhaust Emissions from Dual Fuel Engines at Light Load,” SAE Technical Paper 932822, 1993, doi: a10.4271/932822.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saidi, M., Far, K., and Pirouzpanah, V., “Analysis of Combustion Process in Dual Fuel Diesel Engines: Knock Phenomenon Approach,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1132, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G, A., Klat S, R., Moore, N, P.W. “Knock in dual fuel engines” Proc Inst of Mech Engrs. Vol. 181, 1967, p. 453.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kubesh, J. and Brehob, D., “Analysis of Knock in a Dual-Fuel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 922367, 1992, doi: 10.4271/922367.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G. and Zhaoda, Y., “An Analytical Model for Knock in Dual Fuel Engines of the Compression Ignition Type,” SAE Technical Paper 880151, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G. and Liu, Z., “A Predictive Model for Knock in Dual Fuel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 921550, 1992, doi: 10.4271/921550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pirouzpanah, V. Jeihouni, Y. Afghani, M. Reduction of pollutants emissions of OM-355 diesel engine to Euro2 by converting to dual-fuel engine (diesel/gas)” Proc first Conf Auto Fuel CNG 2003; 84-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalil, S., Camal, R., Olivier, L., and Laurent, T., “Description of Knock Limit in a CFR Engine: Effects of Engine Settings and Gas Quality,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2620, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2620.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, G. and Gao, J., “A Predictive Model for Knock in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 922366, 1992, doi: 10.4271/922366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, J, R. Green, R, M. Westbrook, C, K. Pitz, W, J. “An experimental and modeling study of engine knock” Twentieth symposium on combustion/the combustion Institute, 1984/pp. 91-100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S, S. Vaglieco, B, M. “Knock investigation by flame and radical species detection in spark ignition engine for different fuels” En Con Man 2007, doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2007.07.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ho, S., Amlee, D., and Johns, R., “A Comprehensive Knock Model for Application in Gas Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 961938, 1996, doi: 10.4271/961938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xiaofeng, G., Stone, R., Hudson, C., and Bradbury, I., “The Detection and Quantification of Knock in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 932759, 1993, doi: 10.4271/932759.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noda, T., Hasegawa, K., Kubo, M., and Itoh, T., “Development of Transient Knock Prediction Technique by Using a Zero-Dimensional Knocking Simulation with Chemical Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0618, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0618.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Reitz, R., Iyer, C., and Yi, J., “Modeling Knock in Spark- Ignition Engines Using a G-equation Combustion Model Incorporating Detailed Chemical Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0165, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westbrook, C, K. Warnatz, J. Pitz, W, J. “A detailed chemical kinetic reaction mechanism for the oxidation of the oxidation of iso-octane and n-heptane over an extended temperature range and its application to analysis of engine knock” 1988. Twenty-second Symposium (International) on combustion/the combustion Institute/pp. 893-901.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cowart, J, S., Keck J, C. Heywood, J, B. Westbrook, C, K. Pitz, W, J. “Engine knock predictions using a fully-detailed and a reduced chemical kinetic mechanism” 1990. Twenty-Third Symposium (International) on combustion/the combustion Institute/pp. 1055-1062.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A, A. “KIVA-3V: a block structured KIVA program for engines with vertical or canted valves” Technical Report No.LA-13313- MS, Los Alamos National Laboratory; 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, R, J., Rupley, F, M. Miller, J, A. “CHEMKIN-II: A FORTRAN chemical kinetics package for the analyses of gas phase chemical kinetics” Sandia Report 1989; SAND 89-8009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, P, N. Byrne, G, D. Hindmarsh, A, C. “VODE: A variable coefficient ODE solver” J Sci Stat Comput 1989; 10: 1038-105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z. Reitz, R, D. “A temperature wall function formulation for variable-density turbulent flows with application to engine convective heat transfer modeling” Intl J Heat Mass Transfer 1997; 40: 613-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, Z. Yao, M. “Charge stratification to control HCCI: experiments and CFD modeling with n-heptane as fuel” Fuel 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2008;09.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www-cms.llnl.gov/combustion/archive.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, S., Williams, F., and Gebert, K., “A Reduced Reaction Mechanism for Predicting Knock in Dual-Fuel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0957, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.dieselgas.co.nz</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pirouzpanah, V. Khoshbakhti, Saray, R. Sohrabi, Niaei A,. “A Comparison of thermal and radical effects of EGR gases on combustion process in dual fuel engines at part loads” En Con Man 2007, doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2007.01.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
