<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007080</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Simulation of Damage for Wind Turbine Blades Due to Airborne Particles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fiore</surname>
                  <given-names>Giovanni</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Selig</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>Ph.D. Candidate, Department of Aerospace Engineering, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, lllinois 61801, USA</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Associate Professor, Department of Aerospace Engineering, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, lllinois 61801, USA</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007075</issue-id>
         <fpage>399</fpage>
         <lpage>418</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007080"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A mathematical model and simulation of airborne particle collisions with a 38 m, 1.5 MW horizontal axis wind turbine blade are presented. Two types of particles were analyzed, namely insects and sand grains. Computations were performed using a two-dimensional inviscid flowfield solver coupled with a particle position code. Three locations along the blade were considered and characterized by airfoils of the DU series. The insect simulations estimated the residual debris thickness on the blade, while sand simulations computed the surface erosion rate. Results show that the impact locations along the blade depend on angle of attack, freestream velocity, airfoil shape, and particle mass. Particles were found to collide primarily at the leading edge. The volume of insect debris per unit span was maximum at <italic>r</italic>/<italic>R</italic> = 0.75. The erosion rate due to sand was maximum on the low pressure side of the blade. An erosion rate approximately ten times higher was observed at <italic>r</italic>/<italic>R</italic> = 0.75, as compared with the section at <italic>r</italic>/<italic>R</italic> = 0.35. Near the leading edge, large angles of impact occurred and erosion rate had a minimum, while it reached maximum values slightly downstream where the impact angle was more skewed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dalili, N., Edrisy, A. and Carriveau, R. 2007. “A Review of Surface Engineering Issues Critical to Wind Turbine Performance”. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 13, pp. 428–438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayman, B., Wedel-Heinen, J. and Brondsted, P. 2008. “Materials Challenges in Present and Future Wind Energy”. MRS Bulletin, 33, Apr., pp. 343–353.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., Bhatti, T. S. and Kothari, D. P. 2012. “A Review of Wind-Resource-Assessment Technology”. Centre for Energy Studies, Indian Institute of Technology. Hauz Khas, New Delhi 110016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, C. W., Yang, K., Liu, Q., Zhang, L., Bai, J. Y. and Xu, J. Z. 2011. “A Study on Performance Influences of Airfoil Aerodynamic Parameters and Evalutation Indicators for the Roughness Sensitivity on Wind Turbine Blade”. Science China - Technological Sciences, 54(11), pp. 2993–2998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siochi, E. J., Eiss, N. S., Gilliam, D. R. and Wightman, J. P. 1987. “A Fundamental Study of the Sticking of Insect Residues to Aircraft Wings”. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science, 115(2), pp. 346–356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Croom, C. and Holmes, B. 1986. “Insect Contamination Protection for Laminar Flow Surfaces”. NASA Langley Research Center, N88-14954/7, Hampton, VA, Dec.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carmichael, B. H. 1979. “Summary of Past Experience in Natural Laminar Flow and Experimental Program for Resilient Trailing Edge”. Low Energy Transportation Systems, Capistrano Beach, CA 92624, for Ames Research Center, NASA CR 152276, May.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shankar, P. 2001. “Can Insects Seriously Affect the Power Output of Wind Turbines?”. Current Science, 81(7), pp. 747–748.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corten, G. P. and Veldkamp, H. F. 2001. “Insects can Halve Wind-Turbine Power”. Nature, 412, pp. 41–42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragheb, A. and Selig, M. S. 2011. “Multi-Element Airfoil Configurations for Wind Turbines”. In Proceedings of the 29th AIAA Conference, AIAA Paper 2011–3971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schneiderhan, T., Schulz-Stellenfleth, J., Lehner, S. and Hortsmann, J. 2002. “Sar Wind Fields for Off-shore Wind Farming”. DLR, Oberpfaffenhofen, 82230 Wessling, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DNV, 2010. “Design and Manufacture of Wind Turbine Blades, Offshore and Onshore Wind Turbines - October 2010”. Standard DNV-DS-J102, Det Norske Veritas, Oct.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arrighetti, C., Pratti, G. D. and Ruscitti, R. 2003. “Performance Decay Analysis of New Rotor Blade Profiles for Wind Turbines Operating in Offshore Environments”. Wind Engineering, 27(5), pp. 371–380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khakpour, Y., Bardakji, S. and Nair, S. 2007. “Aerodynamic Performance of Wind Turbine Blades in Dusty Environments”. In International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition, Seattle, Washington, IMECE2007–43291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tilly, G. 1969. “Erosion Caused by Airborne Particles”. Wear, 14(1), pp. 63–79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davis, J. R., ed., 2001. Surface Engineering for Corrosion and Wear Resistance. ASM International - The Materials Information Society. 10M Communications, Materials Park, OH 44073-0002, ch. 3, pp. 43–86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wood, R. J. K. 1999. “The Sand Erosion Performance of Coatings”. Materials and Design, 20(4), pp. 179–191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tabakoff, W. and Balan, C. 1983. “A Study of the Surface Deterioration due to Erosion”. Presented at the 28th ASME Interational Gas Turbine Conference and Exhibit, Phoenix, Arizona, 105, pp. 834–838.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rempel, L. 2012. “Rotor Blade Leading Edge Erosion - Real Life Experiences”. Oct. URL http://www.windsytemsmag.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sareen, A., Sapre, C. A. and Selig, M. S. 2012. “Effects of Leading-Edge Protection Tape on Wind Turbine Blade Performance”. Wind Engineering, 36(5), pp. 525–534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayman, B., 2007. “Approaches to Damage Assessment and Damage Tolerance for FRP Sandwich Structures”. Journal of Sandwich Structures and Materials, 9, pp. 571–596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragheb, A. M. and Ragheb, M. 2011. “Wind Turbine Gearbox Technologies”. In Fundamental and Advanced Topics in Wind Power, R. Carriveau, ed. In-Tech, pp. 189–206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ciang, C. C., Lee, J. R. and Bang, H. J. 2008. “Structural Health Monitoring for a Wind Turbine System: a Review of Damage Detection Methods”. Measurement Science and Technology, 19(12), Oct., pp. 122001–122021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soltani, M. R., Birjandi, A. H. and Seddighi-Moorani, M. 2011. “Effect of Surface Contamination on the Performance of a Section of a Wind Turbine Blade”. Scientia Iranica B, 18(3), pp. 349–357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayor, G. S., Moreira, A. B. B. and Munoz, H. C. 2013. “Influence of Roughness in Protective Strips of Leading Edge for Generating Wind Profiles”. In 22nd International Congress of Mechanical Engineering, COBEM 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ren, N. and Ou, J. 2009. “Dust Effect on the Performance of Wind Turbine Airfoils”. Journal of Electromagnetic Analysis and Applications, 1(2), pp. 102–107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Romero-Sanz, I. and Matesanz, A., 2008. “Noise Management on Modern Wind Turbines”. Wind Engineering, 32(1), pp. 27–44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arjula, S. and Harsha, A. P. 2006. “Study of Erosion Efficiency of Polymers and Polymer Composites”. Polymer Testing, 25(2), pp. 188–196.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Challener, C. 2010. “coatings critical for wind energy efficiency”. JCT CoatingsTech, Jan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>[30]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragheb, M. 2010. “USA Wind Energy Resources”. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, NPRE 475 lecture notes, Urbana, IL 61801, Jan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>[31]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bragg, M. B. and Maresh, J. L., 1986. A Numerical Method To Predict The Effect of Insect Contamination on Airfoil Drag. Aeronautical and Astronautical Engineering Report AARL 86-01, The Ohio State University Research Foundation, OH 43212, Mar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>[32]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drela, M. 1989. “XFOIL: An Analysis and Design System for Low Reynolds Number Airfoils”. In Low Reynolds Number Aerodynamics, T. J. Mueller, ed., Vol. 54 of Lecture Notes in Engineering. Springer-Verlag, New York, June, pp. 1–12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>[33]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roskam, J. 1995. Airplane Flight Dynamics and Automatic Flight Controls. DARcorp, Lawrence, KS 66044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>[34]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bragg, M. B. 1982. “Rime Ice Accretion and Its Effect on Airfoil Performance”. NASA Lewis Research Center, NASA CR-165599, Mar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>[35]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langmuir, I. and Blodgett, K. 1946. Mathematical Investigation of Water Droplet Trajectories. Tech. Rept. 5418, U.S. Army Air Force.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>[36]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hamed, A. A., Tabakoff, W., Rivir, R. B., Das, K. and Arora, P. 2005. “Turbine Blade Surface Deterioration by Erosion”. Journal of Turbomachinery, 127(3), pp. 445–452.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>[37]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilson, R. E. 2009. “Wind Turbine Aerodynamics Part A: Basic Principles”. In Wind Turbine Technology, Fundamental Concepts of Wind Turbine Engineering, Second Edition, D. A. Spera, ed. ASME Press, Three Park Avenue, New York City, NY 10016, pp. 281–350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>[38]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Timmer, W. A. and van Rooij, R. P. J. O. M. 2003. “Summary of the Delft University Wind Turbine Dedicated Airfoils”. Journal of Solar Energy Engineering, 125(4), pp. 571–596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>[39]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Freeman, J. 1945. “Studies in the Distribution of Insects by Aerial Currents”. Journal of Animal Ecology, 14(2), pp. 128–154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>[40]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nachtigall, W. 1974. Insects in Flight. HarperCollins Publishers LLC, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>[41]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vogel, S., 1967. “Flight in Drosophila, III, Aerodynamic Characteristics of Fly Wings and Wing Models”. Journal of Experimental Biology, 46, pp. 431–443.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>[42]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, M. and Wu, J. H. 2003. “Aerodynamic Force Generation and Power Requirements in Forward Flight in a Fruit Fly with Modeled Wing Motion”. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 206(17), pp. 3065–3083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>[43]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoerner, S. F. 1965. Fluid-Dynamic Drag. Hoerner Fluid Dynamics, Bakersfield, CA 93390.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>[44]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nachtigall, W. 2001. “Some Aspects of Reynolds Number Effects in Animals”. Mathematical Methods in the Applied Sciences, 24, pp. 1401–1408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>[45]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lehmann, F. O. 2002. “The Constraints of Body Size on Aerodynamics and Energetics in Flying Fruit Flies: An Integrative View”. Zoology, 105(4), pp. 287–295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>[46]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haider, A. and Levenspiel, O. 1989. “Drag Coefficient and Terminal Velocity of Spherical and Nonspherical Particles”. Powder Technology, 58(1), pp. 63–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>[47]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coleman, W. S. 1961. “Roughness Due to Insects”. In Boundary Layer and Flow Control, G. V. Lachmann, ed., Vol. 2. Pergamon Press, pp. 682–747.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>[48]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feuerstein, A. and Kleyman, A. 2009. “Ti-N Multilayer Systems for Compressor Airfoil Sand Erosion Protection”. Surface and Coatings Technology, 204(6–7), pp. 1092–1096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>[49]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maozhong, Y., Baiyun, H. and Jiawen, H. 2002. “Erosion Wear Behaviour and Model of Abradable Seal Coating”. Wear, 252(1–2), pp. 9–15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>[50]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wood, K. 2011. “Blade Repair: Closing the Maintenance Gap,” Composites World, Apr. URL http://www.compositesworld.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>[51]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zahavi, J. and Jr., G. F. S. 1981. “Solid Particle Erosion of Polymeric Coatings”. Wear, 71(2), pp. 191–210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>[52]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arjula, S., Harsha, A. P. and Ghosh, M. K. 2008. “Solid-particle Erosion Behavior of High-Performance Thermoplastic Polymers”. Journal of Material Science, 43(6), pp. 1757–1768.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>[53]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harsha, A. P. and Thakre, A. A. 2007. “Investigation on Solid Particle Erosion Behaviour of Polyetherimide and its Composites”. Wear, 262(7–8), pp. 807–818.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>[54]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barkoula, N.-M. and Karger-Kocsis, J. 2002. “Review – Processes and Influencing Parameters of the Solid Particle Erosion of Polymers and Their Composites”. Journal of Materials Science, 37, pp. 3807–3820.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>[55]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drela, M. 2014. Flight Vehicle Aerodynamics. The MIT Press, Cambridge, Massachusetts – London, England.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>[56]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kharde, Y. R. and Saisrinadh, K. V. 2008. “Effect of Particle Velocity, Temperature and Impingement Angle on the Erosive Wear Behavior of Polymer Matrix Composites”. International Journal of Applied Engineering Research, 12, pp. 1689–1695.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>[57]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tangler, J. L. 2000. “The Evolution of Rotor and Blade Design”. In Presented at the American Wind Energy Association, Wind Power 2000, NREL CP-500-28410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>[58]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomsen, O. T. 2009. “Sandwich Materials for Wind Turbine Blades - Present and Future”. Journal of Sandwich Structures and Materials, 11(7), pp. 7–26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>[59]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahmed, T. J. Ninho, G. F., Bersee, H. E. N. and Beukers, A., 2009. “Improving Erosion Resistance of Polymer Reinforced Composites”. Journal of Thermoplastic Composite Materials, 22, pp. 703–725.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>[60]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drensky, G., Hamed, A., Tabakoff, W. and Abot, J. 2011. “Experimental Investigation of Polymer Matrix Reinforced Composite Erosion Characteristics”. Wear, 270(3–4), pp. 146–151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>[61]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Biswas, S. and Satapathy, A. 2009. “Erosion Wear Behavior of Polymer Composites: a Review”. Journal of Reinforced Plastics and Composites, 29, pp. 2898–2924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
