<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812176</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Financing Higher Education</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FEDERAL FINANCIAL AID ELIGIBILITY AND STUDENT DEBT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dubnicki</surname>
                  <given-names>Alissa L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>53</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812176"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper presents estimates of the impact of student eligibility for federal financial aid on total student debt using a natural experiment created by the 1992 Amendment to the Higher Education Act of 1965. The amendment removed assets from the calculation of federal aid eligibility for families with earned income of less than $50,000 and excluded housing assets from eligibility calculation for all students. My results suggest each dollar of eligibility increases student debt by about 40 cents.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Bailey, Martha J., and Susan M. Dynarski, 2011. “Inequality in Postsecondary Attainment.” In Duncan, Greg J. and Richard J. Murnane (eds.), Whither Opportunity: Rising Inequality, Schools, and Children’s Life Chances. Russell Sage Foundation: New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bettinger, Eric P., Bridget T. Long, Philip Oreopoulos, and Lisa Sanbonmatsu, 2009. “The role of simplification and information in college decisions: Results from the H&amp;R Block FAFSA experiment.” NBER Working Paper No. 15361. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bettinger, Eric P., 2004. “How Financial Aid Affects Persistence.” In Dynarski, Susan M. and Caroline Hoxby (eds.), How the Great Recession Affected Higher Education. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Babiarz, Patryk, and Tansel Yilmazer, 2009. “The Impact of College Financial Aid Rules on Household Portfolio Choice.” National Tax Journal 62 (4), 635-655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bureau of Labor Statistics, 2013. National Compensation Survey - Employment Cost Index Historical Listing - Volume 5. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Buss, Christian, Jeffrey Parker, and John Rivenburg, 2004. “Cost, Quality and Enrollment Demand at Liberal Arts Colleges.” Economics of Education Review 23 (1), 57-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Cameron, Stephen V. and James J. Heckman, 2001. “The Dynamics of Education Attainment for Black, Hispanic, and White Males.” Journal of Political Economy 109 (3), 455-499.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Cameron, Stephen V. and Christopher Taber, 2004. “Estimation of Educational Borrowing Constraints Using Returns to Schooling.” Journal of Political Economy 112 (1), 132-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Caucutt, Elizabeth M. and Krishna B. Kumar, 2003. “Higher Education Subsidies and Heterogeneity: A Dynamic Analysis.” Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 27 (8), 1459-1502.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Chopra, Rohit, 2012. Too Big to Fail: Student Debt Hits a Trillion. Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Cornwell, Christopher, David B. Mustard, and Deepa J. Sridhar, 2006. “The Enrollment Effects of Merit-Based Financial Aid: Evidence from Georgia’s HOPE Program.” Journal of Labor Economics 24 (4), 761-786.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Davies, Antony and James R. Harrison, 2012. “Why the Education Bubble Will Be Worse than the Housing Bubble.” U.S. News and World Report, June 12, http://www.usnews.com/opinion/blogs/economic-intelligence/2012/06/12/the-government-shouldnt-subsidize-higher-education.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Deming, David and Susan M. Dynarski, 2009. “Into College, Out of Poverty? Policies to Increase the Postsecondary Attainment of the Poor.” NBER Working Paper No. 15387. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dowd, Alicia C., 2008. “Dynamic Interactions and Intersubjectivity: Challenges to Causal Modeling in Studies of College Student Debt.” Review of Educational Research 78 (2), 232-259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Dynarski, Susan M., 2000. “Hope for Whom? Financial Aid for the Middle Class and Its Impact on College Attendance.” NBER Working Paper No. 7756. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Dynarski, Susan M., 2002. “Loans, Liquidity, and Schooling Decisions.” Kennedy School of Government Working Paper, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Dynarski, Susan M., 2003. “Does Aid Matter? Measuring the Effect of Student Aid on College Attendance and Completion.” American Economic Review 93 (1), 279-288.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Dynarski, Susan M., and Judith Scott-Clayton, 2013. “Financial Aid Policy: Lessons from Research.” NBER Working Paper No. 18710. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Research and Statistics Group, Microeconomic Studies, Federal Reserve Bank of New York, 2013. Quarterly Report on Household Debt and Credit. Federal Reserve Bank of New York, August, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Feldstein, Martin, 1995. “College Scholarship Rules and Private Saving.” American Economic Review 85 (3), 552-566.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Field, Erica, 2009. “Educational Debt Burden and Career Choice: Evidence from a Financial Aid Experiment in NYU Law School.” American Economic Journal: Applied Economics 1 (1), 1-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Gross, Jacob P., Osman Cekic, Don Hossler, and Nick Hillman, 2009. “What Matters in Student Loan Default: A Review of the Research Literature.” Journal of Student Financial Aid 39 (1), 19-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hannah, Susan B., 1996. “The Higher Education Act of 1992: Skills, Constraints, and the Politics of Higher Education.” The Journal of Higher Education 67 (5), 498-527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Horn, Laura J., Xianglei Chen, and Chris Chapman, 2003. Getting Ready to Pay for College: What Students and Their Parents Know about the Cost of College Tuition and What They Are Doing to Find Out. NCES Report 2003-030. National Center for Education Statistics, United States Department of Education, Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Hoxby, Caroline M., 2004). College Choices: The Economics of Where to Go, When to Go, and How to Pay for It. The University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Ikenberry, Stanley O., and Terry W. Hartle, 1998. Too Little Knowledge Is a Dangerous Thing: What the Public Thinks about Paying for College. American Council on Education: Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Ionescu, Felicia A., 2008a. “Consolidation of Student Loan Repayments and Default Incentives.” The B.E. Journal of Macroeconomics 8 (1), 1935-1690.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Ionescu, Felicia A., 2008b. “The Federal Student Loan Program: Quantitative Implications for College Enrollment and Default Rates.” Review of Economic Dynamics 12 (1), 205-231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Ionescu, Felicia A., 2009. “Risky College Investment under Alternative Bankruptcy Regimes for Student Loans”. Colgate University Working Paper, Hamilton, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Johnson, Matthew T., 2013. “Borrowing Constraints, College Enrollment, and Delayed Entry.” Journal of Labor Economics 31 (4), 669-725.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Kane, Thomas J., 1995. “Rising Public College Tuition and College Entry: How Well Do Public Subsidies Promote Access to College?” NBER Working Paper No. 5164. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Levine, Ross, and Yona Rubinstein, 2013. “Liberty for More: Finance and Educational Opportunities.” NBER Working Paper No. 19380. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Lewin, Tamar, 2013. “Obama’s Plan Aims to Lower Cost of College.” The New York Times, August 22, http://www.nytimes.com/2013/08/22/education/obamas-plan-aims-to-lower-cost-of-college.html?_r=0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Lochner, Lance, Todd Stinebrickner, and Utku Suleymanoglu, 2012. “Understanding Student Loan Repayment Problems: Evidence from the Canada Student Loans Program.” University of Western Ontario Working Paper, London, ON.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Long, Mark, 2004. “The Impact of Asset-Tested College Financial Aid on Household Savings.” Journal of Public Economics 88 (1), 63-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Lovenheim, Michael F., and Emily G. Owens, 2013. “Does Federal Financial Aid Affect College Enrollment? Evidence from Drug Offenders and the Higher Education Act of 1998.” NBER Working Paper No. 18749. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">McPherson, Michael S., and Morton O. Schapiro, 1998. The Student Aid Game: Meeting Need and Rewarding Talent in American Higher Education. Princeton University Press, Princeton, NJ.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Monks, James, 2003. “An Empirical Examination of the Impact of College Financial Aid on Family Savings.” National Tax Journal 57 (2), 189-207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Monks, James, 2012. “The Role of Tuition, Financial Aid Policies, and Student Outcomes on Average Student Debt.” Cornell Higher Education Research Institute Working Paper No. 150. Cornell Higher Education Research Institute, Ithaca, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">National Center for Education Statistics, 2012. Digest of Education Statistics, 2011 - Tuition Costs of Colleges and Universities. National Center for Education Statistics, U.S. Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Poterba, James M., 1992. “Taxation and Housing Markets.” In Shoven, John B., and John Whalley (eds.), Canada-U.S. Tax Comparisons. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Rothstein, Jesse, and Cecilia E. Rouse, 2011. “Constrained after College: Student Loans and Early-Career Occupational Choices.” Journal of Public Economics 95 (1), 149-163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Scott-Clayton, Judith, 2011. “On Money and Motivation: A Quasi-Experimental Analysis of Financial Incentives for College Achievement.” Journal of Human Resources 46 (3), 614-646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Scott-Clayton, Judith, 2012a. “What Explains Trends in Labor Supply Among U.S. Undergraduates?” National Tax Journal 65 (1), 181-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Scott-Clayton, Judith, 2012b. “Information Constraints and Financial Aid Policy.” NBER Working Paper No. 17811. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Seftor, Neil S., and Sarah E. Turner, 2002. “Back to School: Federal Student Aid Policy and Adult College Enrollment.” Journal of Human Resources 37 (2), 336-352.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Total Undergraduate Federal Loans</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Undergraduate Federal Loans per Student</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Total Undergraduate Federal Loans Surrounding the 1992 Amendment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Undergraduate Federal Loans per Student Surrounding the 1992 Amendment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Undergraduate Financial Aid Sources as a Proportion of Total Financial Aid</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Student Loans by Year of Study for Dependent Students in 1989-90</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Changes in Federal Student Aid Eligibility for a Model Family</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>1989-90 Mean Demographic Characteristics by Income Group for Dependent Students</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>The Effect of Federal Aid Eligibility on Loans for Dependent Students</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Effects of Federal Aid Eligibility (in Thousands of Dollars) for Dependent Students</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>The Effect of Federal Aid Eligibility on Loans for Selected Samples of Dependent Students</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>The Effect of Federal Aid Eligibility on Loans for Dependent Students from Families with $40,000 to $60,000 of Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>The Effect of Federal Aid Eligibility on Loans for Subsamples of Dependent Students</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>IV Estimates of the Effect of Federal Aid Eligibility on Aid for Dependent Students</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A1</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Adjusted Net Worth of Family Business or Farm (in 1992 Dollars)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A2</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Education Savings and Asset Protection Allowance (in 1992 Dollars)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A3</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Income Protection Allowance (in 1992 Dollars)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A4</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Assessment Schedule and Rates (in 1992 Dollars)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A5</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>1990 NPSAS and 1996 NPSAS Mean Demographic Characteristics by Income Group for Dependent Students</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
