<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437861</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Savings and Wealth in the UK: Evidence from Micro-Data</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>JAMES</given-names>
                  <surname>BANKS</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>SARAH</given-names>
                  <surname>TANNER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>1996</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">17</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437857</issue-id>
         <fpage>37</fpage>
         <lpage>63</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1996</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437861"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d8e266a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e273" publication-type="other">
In the UK, the personal saving rate has picked up since 1990 after a sharp fall in the late 1980s, whereas the US
saving rate remains low at below 5 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e283a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e290" publication-type="other">
See Deaton (1992) for further discussion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e297a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e304" publication-type="other">
This is obviously the case for a defined contribution private pension, but even the return on a defined benefit
scheme will be subject, indirectly, to equity risk through the overall performance of the scheme.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e314a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e321" publication-type="other">
In the most recent year of FES data (1994—95). questions on all National Savings products except post office
savings accounts were omitted, leaving a smaller number of asset types.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e332a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e339" publication-type="other">
There are several other sources of household data in the UK that will not be used in this study. This is primarily
because they currently contain little or no information on household wealth or asset holdings. However, three of
these household surveys are worth mentioning, since it is likely that in future years they will prove important
sources of information on household saving. The British Household Panel Survey, first collected in 1991, is an
important source of data on the experiences of the same households over time. The wave containing asset
information is still being processed and is therefore unavailable to us at the time of writing. However, in the longer
term, the survey will be a good source of information on both the dynamics of household asset holding decisions
across time and the way in which individuals interact in making household saving decisions. The survey will also
provide useful data on attitudes to saving. The Family Resources Survey (available from 1993-94 onwards) has
been designed to replace the income information in the FES and, as such, will eventually provide the information
on asset holding and asset income currently available in the FES. Since this survey is only in its second year, we
will not use it in what follows. Finally, the General Household Survey, collected by the Office of Population
Censuses and Surveys, contains information on pensions, health insurance and life insurance, institutional forms
of saving that have important implications for a household's decision about how much it needs to hold in
non-institutional form, i.e. banks, building society accounts, shares etc. However, there is no direct information
on these non-institutional forms of saving. In addition, batteries of questions regarding a particular topic are only
asked intermittently and analysis of trends in saving or asset holding is difficult. For a detailed analysis of the
pensions information available in the General Household Survey, see Dilnot, Disney, Johnson and Whitehouse
(1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e403a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e410" publication-type="other">
The distribution of households is estimated using a standard non-parametric Kernel estimator (see Hardie ( 1990)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e417a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e424" publication-type="other">
The number of adult equivalents is computed using values of 0.66 for second and subsequent adults and 0.43 for
each child. These values were estimated from 1992 FES data and are comparable with the scales used in OECD
statistics on UK income and spending (see Banks and Johnson (1993)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e437a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e444" publication-type="other">
Source: Economic Trends Annual Supplement, 1995.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e451a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e458" publication-type="other">
In the years for which both types of information are available, these two measures of asset information yield
comparable ownership measures.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e468a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e475" publication-type="other">
These figures are available for each year since the introduction of TESSAs in 1991, but as the percentages remain
reasonably constant, we report the final year only.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d8e494a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e498" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. B. and Harrison, A. J. (1978), The Distribution of Personal Wealth in Britain, London:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e508a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e512" publication-type="other">
— and Micklewright, J. ( 1983), 'On the reliability of income data in the Family Expenditure Survey',
Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, vol. 146, part 1, pp. 33-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e522a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e526" publication-type="other">
Attanasio, O. P. and Weber, G. (1994), 'Consumption growth, the interest rate and aggregation',
Review of Economic Studies, vol. 60, pp. 631 -51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e536a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e540" publication-type="other">
Banks, J. W. and Blundell, R. W. (1994), 'Household saving behaviour in the UK', in J. Poterba (ed.),
International Comparisons of Household Saving, Chicago: Chicago University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e551a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e555" publication-type="other">
—, — and Tanner, S. (1995), 'Consumption growth, saving and retirement in the UK', Richerche
Economiche, vol. 49, pp. 255-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e565a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e569" publication-type="other">
—, Dilnot, A. W. and Low, H. (1994), The Distribution of Wealth in the UK, Commentary no. 45,
London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e579a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e583" publication-type="other">
— and Johnson, P. (1993), Children and Household Living Standards, London: Institute for Fiscal
Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e593a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e597" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. W., Browning, M. J. and Meghir, C. (1994), 'Consumer demand and the life-cycle
allocation of household expenditure', Review of Economic Studies, vol. 61, pp. 57-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e607a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e611" publication-type="other">
Deaton, A. (1992), Understanding Consumption, Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e618a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e622" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A., Disney, R., Johnson, P. and Whitehouse, E. (1994), Pensions Policy in the UK: An
Economic Analysis, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e633a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e637" publication-type="other">
Duesenberry, J. S. (1949), Income, Saving and the Theory of Consumer Behaviour, Cambridge:
Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e647a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e651" publication-type="other">
Friedman, M. (1957), A Theory of the Consumption Function, Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e658a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e662" publication-type="other">
Goodman, A. and Webb, S. (1994), For Richer, for Poorer: The Changing Distribution of Income in
the UK 1961-91, Commentary no. 42, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e672a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e676" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. (1978), 'Stochastic implications of the permanent income hypothesis', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 86, pp. 971-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e686a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e690" publication-type="other">
Härdle, W. (1990), Applied Non-Parametric Regression, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e697a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e701" publication-type="other">
Hochguertal, S., Alessie, R. and van Soest, A. (1995), 'Household portfolio allocation in the
Netherlands: savings accounts versus stocks and bonds', Tilburg University, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e712a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e716" publication-type="other">
Inland Revenue (1994), Inland Revenue Statistics 1994, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
