<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">40</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24459470</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24459475</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Exploring the Impact of Inadequate Funding for English Language Learners in Colorado School Districts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Al</given-names>
                  <surname>Ramirez</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dick M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Carpenter</surname>
                  <suffix>II</suffix>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Maureen</given-names>
                  <surname>Breckenridge</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>60</fpage>
         <lpage>79</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 Board of Directors of the Journal of Education Finance, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24459475"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This study investigates the relationship between the academic achievement of all students and inadequate funding for English language learners in Colorado school districts. Several stochastic frontier analysis models were used in lieu of traditional production functions in order to achieve clearer estimates. The analyses detected only a few effects. Results suggest limited funding eventually has a small impact over time (i.e., districts with greater shortfalls will see declining achievement over time). These results may add insight to "the achievement gap"—in the face of inadequate resources for ELL students, school districts may be shortchanging other various targeted populations by using federal dollars to supplant state obligations and state dollars.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e196a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e200" publication-type="other">
Adkins, Lee C., and Ronald L. Moomaw. 2008. Determinants of technical efficiency in Oklahoma
schools: A stochastic frontier analysis. Available from http://economy.okstate.edu/papers/
school3.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e217" publication-type="other">
Alexander, Celeste D., Heather Boyer, Amanda B. Brownson, Catherine Clark, Judy Jennings, and
Ertha S. Patrick. 2000. Resource allocation practices and student achievement: An examination of
district expenditures by performance level with interviews from twenty-one districts. Austin, TX:
University of Texas, Charles A. Dana Center.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e233a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e237" publication-type="other">
Augenblik, Palaich and Associates. 2011. Costing out the resources needed to meet education
standards and requirements. Available from www.ednewscolorado.org/wp-content/
uploads/201 l/08/APACostStudy8081 l.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e250a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e254" publication-type="other">
Baraldi, Amanda N., and Craig K. Enders. 2010. An introduction to modern missing data analyses.
Journal of School Psychology no. 48:5-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e265a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e269" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, Dick M. 2012. Charter school efficiency: Comparing Hawai'i's charters to non-charter
public schools. Pacific Education Research Journal no. 13(1):27—42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e279a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e283" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, Dick M., and Paul Medina. 2011. Exploring the competitive effects of charter schools.
International Journal of Educational Reform no. 20(11):33—56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e297" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, DickM., and Scott Noller. 2010. Measuring charter school efficiency: An early appraisal.
Journal of Education Finance no. 35(4):398—416.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e307a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e311" publication-type="other">
Coelli, T. J. (1996). Frontier (Version 4.1). Brisbane, Australia: Centre for Efficiency and
Productivity Analysis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e321a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e325" publication-type="other">
Coelli, Timothy J., D. S. Prasada Rao, Christopher J. O'Donnell, and George E. Battese. 2005. An
introduction to efficiency and productivity analysis, 2nd ed. New York, NY: Springer.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e339" publication-type="other">
Colorado Department of Education. 2012. Understanding Colorado school finance and categorical
funding. Available from www.cde.state.co.us/cdefinance/generalinfo.htm</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e354" publication-type="other">
Condron, Dennis J., and Vincent J. Roscigno. 2003. Disparities within: Unequal spending and
achievement in an urban school district. Sociology of Education no. 76(l):18-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e368" publication-type="other">
Crampton, Faith E. 1991. The measurement of efficiency and equity in Oregon school finance: The
beginning stages. Journal of Education Finance no. 16:348-359.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e382" publication-type="other">
ELPA. English Language Proficiency Act, Colorado Revised Statutes, Article 24 of Title 22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e389a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e393" publication-type="other">
Frontier 4.1. Centre for Efficiency and Productivity Analysis, Brisbane, Australia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e404" publication-type="other">
Grosskopf, Shawna, Kathy J. Hayes, Lori L. Taylor, and William L. Weber. 1997. Budget-constrained
frontier measures of fiscal equality and efficiency in schooling. Review of Economics and
Statistics no. 79(1):116—124.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e417a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e421" publication-type="other">
Hall, Joshua. 2007. Local school finance and productive efficiency: Evidence from Ohio. Atlantic
Economic Journal no. 35:289-301.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e436" publication-type="other">
Hanushek, Eric A. 1986. The economics of schooling: Production and efficiency in public schools.
Journal of Economic Literature no. 24(3):1141-1177.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e446a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e450" publication-type="other">
Hummel-Rossi, Barbara, and Jane Ashdown. 2002. The state of cost-benefit and cost-effectiveness
analyses in education. Review of Educational Research no. 72(1): 1-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e460a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e464" publication-type="other">
Jimenez-Castellanos, Oscar, and Amelia M. Topper. 2012. The cost of providing an adequate
education to English language learners: A review of literature. Review of Educational Research
no. 82(2):179-232.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e477a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e481" publication-type="other">
Keyes v. School Dist. No. 1, Denver, 413 U.S. 189 (1973).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e492" publication-type="other">
Kumbhakar, Subal C., and C. A. Knox-Lovell. 2000. Stochastic frontier analysis. Cambridge, UK:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e502a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e506" publication-type="other">
Lau v. Nichols, 414 U.S. 563 (1974).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e514a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e518" publication-type="other">
Levin, Henry M. 1997. Raising school productivity: An X-efficiency approach. Economics of
Education Review no. 16(3):303-311.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e532" publication-type="other">
Monk, David H. 1981. Toward a multilevel perspective on the allocation of educational resources.
Review of Educational Research no. 51 (2):215—236.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e542a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e546" publication-type="other">
Monk, David H. 1989. The education production function: Its evolving role in policy analysis.
Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis no. 11(1):31—45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e556a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e560" publication-type="other">
Palardy, Joseph, and Todd Nesbit. 2007. Traditional public schools versus charter schools: A
comparison of technical efficiency. Economics Bulletin no. 9(9):1—10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e570a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e574" publication-type="other">
Ramirez, Al, Michael Siegrist, Patrick Krumholz, and Trade Rainey. 2013. Equity, adequacy,
and categorical funding in Colorado school finance: A focus on English language learners.
Education and Urban Society no. 45(6):700-713.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e587a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e591" publication-type="other">
Wenglinsky, Harold. 1998. Finance equalization and within-school equity: The relationship
between education spending and the social distribution of achievement. Educational Evaluation
and Policy Analysis no. 20(4):269-283.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


