<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466863</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466869</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Invisible Hand of Short Selling: Does Short Selling Discipline Earnings Management?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Massimo</given-names>
                  <surname>Massa</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Bohui</given-names>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hong</given-names>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1701</fpage>
         <lpage>1736</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466869"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We hypothesize that short selling has a disciplining role vis-à-vis firm managers that forces them to reduce earnings management. Using firm-level short-selling data for thirty-three countries collected over a sample period from 2002 to 2009, we document a significantly negative relationship between the threat of short selling and earnings management. Tests based on instrumental variable and exogenous regulatory experiments offer evidence of a causal link between short selling and earnings management. Our findings suggest that short selling functions as an external governance mechanism to discipline managers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d925918e213a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e220" publication-type="other">
Please see Miller (1977), Diamond and Verrecchia (1987), Duffie, Garleanu, and Pedersen (2002), Bris,
Goetzmann, and Zhu (2007), Boehmer, Jones, and Zhang (2008), Boehmer and Wu (2013), Saffi and Sigurdsson
(2011 ), and Akbas et al. (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e233a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e240" publication-type="other">
The general public concern is the potential that short selling is inherently speculative and exerts downward price
pressure that may destabilize the market. The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), for instance, believes
that the adoption of a short sale-related circuit breaker is beneficial as it avoids the price impact of manipulative
or abusive short selling (http://www.sec.gov/rules/final/2010/34-61595.pdf).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e256a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e263" publication-type="other">
Even with limits to arbitrage, small short sellers can also affect stock prices of hard-to-short companies by using
media campaigns (Ljungqvist and Qian 2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e273a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e280" publication-type="other">
Activist investors have less incentive to lend out their shares because the ownership and voting rights of lendable
shares will be transferred because of the short sale—and the lack of voting rights is known to discourage the
participation of active institutional investors (e.g., Li, Ortiz-Molina, and Zhao 2008). Indeed, lending may occur
precisely to transfer voting rights rather than exercising voting rights (e.g., Christoffersen et al. 2007), and
majority lenders do not seem to actively exercise the voting power of their lendable shares, evident by the fact
that only less than 2% of shares on loan are called back on the proxy voting record date (Aggarwal, Saffi, and
Sturgess forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e307a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e314" publication-type="other">
Our results are also robust to regressions by industry and year, by country, or by year only. We do not run
regressions by country, year, and industry, as many countries do not have sufficient observations to support
regressions at the industry level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e327a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e334" publication-type="other">
Our results are also robust to alternative illiquidity measures, such as the proportion of zero daily returns in a
year, the turnover ratio, proportional effective spread, and proportional relative spread. Here, we primarily rely
on the Amihud measure because of its importance in the global market (e.g., Karolyi, Lee, and Van Dijk 2012).
We tabulate the results for the alternative liquidity measures in Table IA11 in the Internet Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e350a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e357" publication-type="other">
Compared with Saffi and Sigurdsson (2011), we further control for industry-level fixed effects to remove industry-
specific factors that affect earnings management (e.g., Yu 2008; Dechow, Ge, and Schrand 2010). However, Saffi
and Sigurdsson (2011) adopt firm-year double clustering following Petersen (2009) and Thompson (2010).
Tables IA4 and IA13 will show that our results are robust to the use of double clustering.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e373a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e380" publication-type="other">
The economic impact is computed as the regression coefficient multiplied by the one-standard-deviation change
in Lendable, which is scaled by the standard deviation of discretionary accruals in the sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e390a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e397" publication-type="other">
Based on the Arellano-Bond test for both AR( 1 ) and AR (2) specifications and Hansen's test of overidentifying
restrictions, our estimation satisfies the zero-autocorrelation request for the residuals.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e407a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e414" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, Teoh, and Yu (2011) use institutional ownership as an instrument for the amount of lendable shares to
proxy for the ease of short arbitrage. Our approach is in the same spirit, except we further require the instrument
to be uncorrected with internal governance. This consideration motivates us to use ETFs to identify the passive
component of lendable supply as a general control to alleviate concerns related to internal governance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e431a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e438" publication-type="other">
Following Conley, Hansen, and Rossi (2012), when the dependent variable y, the independent variable x, and
the instrument z are included in the same regression as y=ß xx+y x z+e, the exclusion restriction is equivalent
to the condition of y =0. We also conduct overidentification tests based on the Hansen J—statistic in Table IA6.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e451a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e458" publication-type="other">
We also apply the plausible exogeneity test of Conley, Hansen, and Rossi (2012) to compute the confidence
interval of ß when the y coefficient may take nonzero values (ß and y are specified in note 9). For instance,
when firm-level ETF ownership is used as the instrument, the 95% confidence interval for the impact of S SP
can be estimated as [-.169, -.035] under the assumption that y may take values from the support of [-25,25],
where 5 is the estimated standard deviation of y. The results further confirm that the negative impact of SSP is
statistically robust.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e481a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e488" publication-type="other">
ETF ownership, however, is not a necessary condition for SSP to affect earnings management. We show in
Table IA5 that the disciplining effect of short selling is not attenuated when the level of ETF ownership is
low. This result is logical because other (passive) institutional investors, such as pension funds and insurance
companies, may also be willing to lend shares to short sellers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e504a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e511" publication-type="other">
The regulation was announced in 2004 and implemented in 2005. Because firms may have begun reducing
earnings management immediately after the announcement of the policy, the important change in management
for our purposes is from 2003 to 2005, not from 2004 to 2005.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e524a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e531" publication-type="other">
The details are available at http://www.sec.gov/rules/other/34-50104.htm. The experiment was performed by the
Office of Economic Analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e541a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e548" publication-type="other">
We divide the coefficient of HK SS(AHK SS) by the standard deviation of discretionary accruals in Hong Kong
to obtain the magnitude.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e559a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e566" publication-type="other">
We also examine the impact of short selling on earnings management in subsamples of countries sorted by the
feasibility of short selling and by controlling for firm-level investments. The results are tabulated in Table IA10.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d925918e576a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d925918e583" publication-type="other">
Our results are also robust to other accrual variables, such as Francis, LaFond, et al. (2005) and Allent, Larson,
and Sloan's (2013) residual accruals. To save space, these results are tabulated in Table IA12.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d925918e602a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e606" publication-type="other">
Admati, A. R., and R Pfleiderer. 2009. The Wall Street walk and shareholder activism: Exit as a form of voice.
Review of Financial Studies 22:2645-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e616a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e620" publication-type="other">
Aggarwal, R., I. Erel, M. Ferreira, and R Matos. 2011. Does governance travel around the world? Evidence from
institutional investors. Journal of Financial Economics 100:154—81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e630a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e634" publication-type="other">
Aggarwal, R., P. A. C. Saffi, and J. Sturgess. Forthcoming. The role of institutional investors in voting: Evidence
from changes in lendable. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e644a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e648" publication-type="other">
Akbas, F., E. Boehmer, B. Erturk, and S. Sorescu. 2013. Short interest, returns, and fundamentals. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e656a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e660" publication-type="other">
Allent, E., C. Larson, and R. Sloan. 2013. Accrual reversals, earnings and stock returns. Journal of Accounting
Economics 56:113-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e670a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e674" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y. 2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: Cross-section and time-series effects. Journal of Financial Markets
5:31-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e684a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e688" publication-type="other">
Aitken, M., A. Frino, M. McCorry, and P. Swan. 1998. Short sales are almost instantaneously bad news: Evidence
from the Australian Stock Exchange. Journal of Finance 53:2205-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e698a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e702" publication-type="other">
Arellano, M., and S. Bond. 1991. Some tests of specification for panel data: Monte Carlo evidence and an
application to employment equations. Review of Economic Studies 58:277-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e712a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e716" publication-type="other">
Asquith, P., and L. Meulbroek. 1995. An empirical investigation of short interest. Working Paper, Massachusetts
Institute of Technology.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e726a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e730" publication-type="other">
Barth, M., Landsman, W., and Lang, M. 2008. International accounting standards and accounting quality. Journal
of Accounting Research 46:467-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e741a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e745" publication-type="other">
Boehmer, E., C. Jones, and X. Zhang. 2008. Which shorts are informed? Journal of Finance 63:491-527.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e752a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e756" publication-type="other">
Boehmer, E., and J. Wu. 2013. Short selling and the price discovery process. Review of Financial Studies
26:287-322.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e766a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e770" publication-type="other">
Bris, A., W. Goetzmann, and N. Zhu. 2007. Efficiency and the bear: Short sales and markets around the world.
Journal of Finance 62:1029-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e780a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e784" publication-type="other">
Burgstahler, D., and I. Dichev. 1997. Earnings management to avoid earnings decreases and losses. Journal of
Accounting and Economics 24:99-126.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e794a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e798" publication-type="other">
Chang, E. C., J. W. Cheng, and Y. Yu. 2007. Short-sales constraints and price discovery: Evidence from the Hong
Kong market. Journal of Finance 62:2097-2121.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e808a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e812" publication-type="other">
Christoffersen, S. K., C. Geczy, D. K. Musto, and A. V. Reed. 2007. Vote trading and information aggregation.
Journal of Finance 62:2897-2929.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e823a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e827" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., K. Diether, and C. Malloy. 2007. Supply and demand shifts in the shorting market. Journal of Finance
62:2061-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e837a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e841" publication-type="other">
Conley, T. G, C. B. Hansen, and P. E. Rossi. 2012. Plausibly exogenous. Review of Economics and Statistics
94:260-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e851a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e855" publication-type="other">
Cumming, D. J., S. A. Johan, and D. Li. 2011. Exchange trading rules and stock market liquidity. Journal of
Financial Economics 99:651-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e865a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e869" publication-type="other">
Das, S., and H., Zhang. 2003. Rounding-up in reported EPS, behavioral thresholds, and earnings management.
Journal of Accounting and Economics 35:31-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e879a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e883" publication-type="other">
DeAngelo, L. 1981. Auditor independence, "low balling," and disclosure regulation. Journal of Accounting and
Economics 3:113-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e893a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e897" publication-type="other">
Dechow, P., and I. Dichev. 2002. The quality of accruals and earnings: The role of accrual estimation errors.
Accounting Review 77:35—59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e908a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e912" publication-type="other">
Dechow, P., W. Ge, and C. Schrand. 2010. Understanding earnings quality: A review of the proxies, their
determinants and their consequences. Journal of Accounting and Economics 50:344-401.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e922a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e926" publication-type="other">
Dechow, P., R. Sloan, and A. Sweeney. 1995. Detecting earnings management. Accounting Review 70:193-225.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e933a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e937" publication-type="other">
DeFond, M., and C. Park. 1997. Smoothing income in anticipation of future earnings. Journal of Accounting and
Economics 23:115-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e947a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e951" publication-type="other">
Degeorge, F., J. Patel, and R. Zeckhauser. 1999. Earnings management to exceed thresholds. Journal of Business
72:1-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e961a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e965" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D. W., and R. E. Verrecchia. 1987. Constraints on short-selling and asset price adjustment to private
information. Journal of Financial Economics 18:277-311.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e975a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e979" publication-type="other">
Diether, K. L, K. H. Lee, and I. M. Werner. 2009. It is SHO time! Short-sale price tests and market quality.
Journal of Finance 64:37-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e990a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e994" publication-type="other">
Doidge, C., G A. Karolyi, and R. M. Stulz. 2004. Why are foreign firms listed in the U.S. worth more? Journal
of Financial Economics 71:205-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1004a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1008" publication-type="other">
Doidge, C., G A. Karolyi, and R. M. Stulz. 2007. Why do countries matter so much for corporate governance?
Journal of Financial Economics 86:1-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1018a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1022" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., N. Garleanu, and L. H. Pedersen. 2002. Securities lending, shorting, and pricing. Journal of Financial
Economics 66:307-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1032a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1036" publication-type="other">
Dyck, A., A. Morse, and L. Zingales. 2010. Who blows the whistle on corporate fraud? Journal of Finance
65:2133-2255.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1046a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1050" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A. 2009. Blockholder trading, market efficiency, and managerial myopia. Journal of Finance 64:2481—
2513.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1060a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1064" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., V. W. Fang, and E. Zur. 2013. The effect of liquidity on governance. Review of Financial Studies
26:1443-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1079" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., and G Manso. 2011. Governance through trading and intervention: A theory of multiple blockholders.
Review of Financial Studies 24:2395-2428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1093" publication-type="other">
Fang, V., A. Huang, and J. Karpoff. 2014. Short selling and earnings management: A controlled experiment.
Working Paper</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1107" publication-type="other">
Faure-Grimaud, A., and D. Gromb. 2004. Public trading and private incentives. Review of Financial Studies
17:985-1014.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1121" publication-type="other">
Ferreira, M., and P. Matos. 2008. The colors of investors' money: The role of institutional investors around the
world? Journal of Financial Economics 88:499-533.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1131a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1135" publication-type="other">
Francis, J., R. LaFond, P. Olsson, and K. Schipper. 2005. The market pricing of accruals quality. Journal of
Accounting and Economics 39:295-327.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1145a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1149" publication-type="other">
Francis, J., P. Michas, and S. Seavey. 2013. Does market concentration harm the quality of audited earnings?:
Evidence from audit markets in 42 countries. Contemporary Accounting Research 30:325-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1160a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1164" publication-type="other">
Francis, J., and D. Wang. 2008. The joint effect of investor protection and Big 4 audits on earnings quality around
the world. Contemporary Accounting Research 25:157-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1174a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1178" publication-type="other">
Grullon, G, S. Michenaud, and J. P. Weston. 2012. The real effects of short-selling constraints. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1189" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D., S. H. Teoh, and J. Yu. 2011. Short arbitrage, return asymmetry and the accrual anomaly. Review
of Financial Studies 24:2429-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1203" publication-type="other">
Jain, A., P. Jain, T. Mclnish, and M. McKenzie. 2013. Worldwide reach of short selling regulations. Journal of
Financial Economics 109:177-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1217" publication-type="other">
Jin, L., and S. Myers. 2006. R-squared around the world: New theory and new tests. Journal of Financial
Economics 79:257-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1231" publication-type="other">
Jones, J. 1991. Earnings management during import relief investigations. Journal of Accounting Research 29:193-
228.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1242a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1246" publication-type="other">
Kahn, C., and A. Winton. 1998. Ownership structure, speculation, and shareholder intervention. Journal of
Finance 53:99-129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1260" publication-type="other">
Karolyi, G A. 2004. The role of American depositary receipts in the development of emerging equity markets.
Review of Economics and Statistics 86:670-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1270a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1274" publication-type="other">
Karolyi, G A. 2006. The world of cross-listings and cross-listings of the world: Challenging conventional wisdom.
Review of Finance 10:99-152.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1288" publication-type="other">
Karolyi, G A., K. Lee, and M. A. Van Dijk. 2012. Understanding commonality in liquidity around the world.
Journal of Financial Economics 105:82-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1298a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1302" publication-type="other">
Karpoff, J. M., and X. Lou. 2010. Short sellers and financial misconduct. Journal of Finance 65:1879-1913.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1309a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1313" publication-type="other">
Kothari, S., A. Leone, and C. Wasley. 2005. Performance matched discretionary accrual measures. Journal of
Accounting and Economics 39:163-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1324a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1328" publication-type="other">
Kolasinski, A. C., A. V. Reed, and M. C. Ringgenberg. 2013. A multiple lender approach to understanding supply
and search in the equity lending market. Journal of Finance 68:559-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1338a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1342" publication-type="other">
La Porta, R., F. Lopez-de-Silanes, and A. Shleifer. 2006. What works in securities laws? Journal of Finance
61:1-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1352a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1356" publication-type="other">
Leuz, C., D. Nanda, and P. D. Wysocki. 2003. Earnings management and investor protection: An international
comparison. Journal of Financial Economics 69:505-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1370" publication-type="other">
Li, K., H. Ortiz-Molina, and X. Zhao. 2008. Do voting rights affect institutional investment decisions? Evidence
from dual-class firms. Financial Management 37:713—45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1380a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1384" publication-type="other">
Ljungqvist, A., and W. Qian. 2014. How constraining are limits to arbitrage? Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1391a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1395" publication-type="other">
Maug, E. 1998. Large shareholders as monitors: Is there a tradeoff between liquidity and control? Journal of
Finance 53:65-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1406a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1410" publication-type="other">
Miller, E. M. 1977. Risk, uncertainty, and divergence of opinion. Journal of Finance 32:1151-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1417a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1421" publication-type="other">
Morck, R., B. Yeung, and W. Yu. 2000. The information content of stock markets: Why do emerging markets
have synchronous stock price movements? Journal of Financial Economics 59:215-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1431a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1435" publication-type="other">
Morsfield, S., and C. Tan. 2006. Do venture capitalists influence the decision to manage earnings in initial public
offerings? Accounting Review 81:1119-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1445a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1449" publication-type="other">
Nissim, D., and S. Penman. 2001. Ratio analysis and equity valuation: From research to practice. Review of
Accounting Studies 6:109-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1459a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1463" publication-type="other">
Pagano, M., and P. F. Volpin. 2005. The political economy of corporate governance. American Economic Review
95:1005-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1473a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1477" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M. A. 2009. Estimating standard errors in finance panel data sets: Comparing approaches. Review of
Financial Studies 22:435-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1492" publication-type="other">
Prado, M. P., P. A. C. Saffi, and J. Sturgess. 2013. Ownership structure, limits to arbitrage and stock returns:
Evidence from equity lending markets. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1502a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1506" publication-type="other">
Saffi, P., and K. Sigurdsson. 2011. Price efficiency and short selling. Review of Financial Studies 24:821-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1513a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1517" publication-type="other">
Senchack, A. J., and L. Starks. 1993. Short-sale restrictions and market reaction to short-interest announcements.
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 28:177-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1531" publication-type="other">
Staiger, D., and J. H. Stock. 1997. Instrumental variables regression with weak instruments. Econometrica
65:557-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1541a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1545" publication-type="other">
Thompson, S. 2010. Simple formulas for standard errors that cluster by both firm and time. Journal of Financial
Economics 99:1-10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1559" publication-type="other">
Watts, R., and J. Zimmerman. 1986. Positive accounting theory. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d925918e1567a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d925918e1571" publication-type="other">
Yu, F. 2008. Analyst coverage and earnings management. Journal of Financial Economics 88:245-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


