<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308342</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Computational Investigation of Two-Stage Combustion in a Light-Duty Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kokjohn</surname>
                  <given-names>Sage L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Engine Research Center, University of Wisconsin – Madison</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>1083</fpage>
         <lpage>1104</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308342"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The objective of this investigation is to optimize light-duty diesel engine operating parameters using Adaptive Injection Strategies (AIS) for optimal fuel preparation. A multi-dimensional Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) code with detailed chemistry, the KIVA-CHEMKIN code, is employed and a Multi-Objective Genetic Algorithm (MOGA) is used to study a Two-Stage Combustion (TSC) concept. The combustion process is considered at a light load operating condition (nominal IMEP of 5.5 bar and high speed (2000 rev/min)), and two combustion modes are combined in this concept. The first stage is ideally Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) combustion and the second stage is diffusion combustion under high temperature and low oxygen concentration conditions. Available experimental data on a 1.9L single-cylinder research engine is used for model validation. The results show that the computations are able to adequately predict the emissions trends and quantities over an injection timing sweep for the Partially Premixed Compression Ignition (PCCI) cases investigated. A preliminary investigation was performed to gain an understanding of two-stage combustion in the light duty engine. At this condition it was found that pure HCCI combustion could yield very low engine out emissions, but extreme pressure rise rates would lead to excessive combustion noise. A multi-dimensional optimization code, NSGAII, was used for optimization of six objectives (NOx, soot, CO, HC, ISFC, and peak PRR) by adjusting four parameters (boost pressure, EGR rate, fraction of premixed fuel, and start of late injection timing). The optimization has shown that two-stage combustion is a feasible concept for noise reduction while maintaining reasonable emissions and fuel consumption. A Pareto solution yielding a peak pressure rise rate of 4.3 bar/deg was found using a high EGR rate (54%), relatively low IVC pressure (1.74 bar), premixing 36% of the total fuel, and injecting the remainder of the fuel at 2.9 degrees after TDC.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bression, G., Soleri, D., Savy, S., Dehoux, S. et al., “A Study of Methods to Lower HC and CO missions in Diesel HCCI” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):37-49, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. L. Hardy, and R. D. Reitz, "A Study of the Effects f High EGR, High Equivelance Ratio, and Mixing ime on Emisssions Levels in a Heavy-Duty Diesel ngine for PCCI Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0026, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Opat, Ra, Y. , Gonzalez D., M.A. , Krieger, R. ,Reitz, R.D., Foster, D.E., Siewert, R. , Durrett, R., "Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on C/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low emperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel ngine," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. M. Pickett, and D. L. Siebers, "Non-Sooting, Low lame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel ombustion," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1399, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Akihama, Y. Takatori, K. Inagaki, S. Sasaki, and . M. Dean, "Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich iesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature," SAE echnical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Sun, “Diesel combustion optimization and missions reduction using adaptive injection trategies (AIS) with improved numerical models,” hesis (Ph D ), University of Wisconsin--Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Kamimoto, and M. Bae, "High Combustion emperature for the Reduction of Particulate in iesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 880423, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Hasegawa, and H. and Yanagihara, "HCCI ombustion in DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical aper 2003-01-0745, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Sun, and R. D. Reitz, "Modeling Diesel Engine Ox and Soot Reduction with Optimized Two-Stage ombustion," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0027, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Amsden, "KIVA-3V, Release 2, Improvements to IVA-3V," LA-UR-99-915, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abani, N., Munnannur, A., and Reitz, R.D., "Reduction of numerical parameter dependencies in iesel spray models," J. Engng for Gas Turbines and ower (Vol.130, Iss.3, 032809) DOI: 10.1115/1.2830867, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Abani, S. L. Kokjohn, S. W. Park, M. Bergin, A. unnannur, W. Ning, S. Y., and R. D. Reitz,, "An mproved Spray Model for Reducing Numerical arameters Dependencies in Diesel Engine CFD imulations," SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0970, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. C. Beale, and R. D. Reitz, “Modeling Spray tomization With the Kelvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh- aylor Hybrid Model,” Atomization and Sprays, vol. 9, pp. 623-650, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Han, and R. D. Reitz, “Turbulence Modeling of nternal Combustion Engines Using RNG k-e odels,” Combustion Science and Technology, vol. 106, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Ra, and R. D. Reitz, “The Application of a Multicomponent roplet Vaporization Model to DI asoline Engines,” International Journal of Engine esearch, vol. 4, pp. 193-218, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patel, S.-C. Kong, and R. D. Reitz, "Development nd Validation of a Reduced Reaction Mechanism or HCCI Engine Simulations," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0558, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. J. O'Rourke, and A. A. Amsden, "A Particle umerical Model for Wall Dynamics in Port-Injected ngines," SAE Technical Paper 961961, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. J. O'Rourke, and A. A. Amsden, "A Spray/Wall nteraction Submodel for the KIVA-3 Wall Film odel," SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0271, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S.-C. Kong, Y. Sun, and R. D. Reitz, “Modeling iesel Spray Flame Lift-Off, Sooting Tendency and Ox Emissions Using Detailed Chemistry with henomenological Soot Model,” ASME Journal of as Turbines and Power, vol. 129, pp. 245-251, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Hiroyasu, and T. Kadota, "Models for Combustion nd Formation of Nitric Oxide and Soot in DI Diesel ngines," SAE Technical Paper 760129, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Frenklach, T. Bowman, G. Smith, and B. ardiner. "http://www.me.berkeley.edu/gri-mech/."</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shi, Y. and Reitz, R.D., “Assessment of Optimization ethodologies to Study the Effects of Bowl eometry, Spray Targeting and Swirl Ratio for a eavy-Duty Diesel Engine Operated at High-Load” AE Int. J. Engines 1(1):537-557, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Deb, A. Pratap, S. Agarwal, and T. Meyarivan, "A ast and Elitist Multiobjective Genetic Algorithm: SGA-II," IEEE Transactions on Evolutionary omputation, 2, 2002, pp. 182-197.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Ra, Private Communication, University of isconsin-Madison, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Juneja, “Injection rate-shape optimization as a eans of controlling comustion of diesel sprays,” hesis (M S ), University of Wisconsin--Madison, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. L. Siebers, "Scaling Liquid-Phase Fuel enetration in Diesel Sprays Based on Mixing- imited Vaporization," SAE Technical Paper 1999- 01-0528, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Deb, and S. Jain, "Running Performance Metrics or Evolutionary Multi-Objective Optimization," anGAL Report No. 2002004, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lachaux, T., Musculus, M.P.B., Singh, S., and Reitz, .D., "Optical Diagnostics of a Late Injection Low- emperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel ngine," Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines nd Power (Vol.130, ss.3, 032808) DOI: 10.1115/1.2830864, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
