<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23027450</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>BANK LOAN REQUIREMENT AND AVAILABILITY FOR NIGERIAN SMALL FARMERS: A COMPARATIVE ANALYSIS OF EXPERIENCES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>P.B.</given-names>
                  <surname>Imoudu</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Onosakponome</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23027445</issue-id>
         <fpage>49</fpage>
         <lpage>61</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23027450"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This study compares the size of bank loan requirement vis-a-vis its availability among Nigerian small farmers growing arable food crops, using Ondo State as a representative sample area. The state is a major food basket area for Nigeria, particularly the Southern parts. Various works which have been done on the need, inadequacy, appropriate sources of loan and the contributions of Nigerian banks to the overall national growth and development of agriculture were reviewed. The study concentrated on small farmers and banks as units of analysis. The size of loan required by small farmers and the size of loan available to them without collateral security were determined via statistical tests. It was revealed that there is no significant difference between the size of loan required by small farmers growing arable food crops and the size of loan available to them in the banks. Consumptive loan was not included in the representative mean size of loan used for the test for reasons well documented in the paper. The role of extension services in motivating small farmers towards bank borrowing was found to be inadequate. Bank loan was found to be essential for the growth and development of the Nigerian small farmers in particular and the agricultural sector at large. L'étude compare l'importance des besoins de crédit bancaire vis-à-vis de leur disponibilité parmi les petits agriculteurs du Nigeria, en prenant l'Etat de Ondo comme échantillon représentatif. Cet Etat, surtout dans sa partie Sud, est un important centre de production alimentaire du Nigeria. Une revue a été effectuée des recherches qui ont été faites sur les besoins, les manques et les sources de prêts appropriés et la contribution des banques nigériennes au développement national et plus spécialement au développement de l'agriculture. L'étude a focalisé ses recherches sur les petits agriculteurs et les banques. L'importance du prêt demandé par les petits agriculteurs comparée au montant disponible de prêt fourni par les banques (il s'agit de prêts accordés sans garantie) ont fait l'objet de tests statistiques. On a découvert aussi qu'il n'y a pas de différence notable entre le montant du prêt demandé par les petits agriculteurs et le prêt qui leur est proposé par les banques. Les prêts à la consommation n'ont pas été inclus pour des raisons largement expliquées dans l'article. Le rôle d'offre de services de la part des banques pour motiver les petits agriculteurs dans leurs emprunts a semblé inadéquat. Le prêt bancaire a été considéré comme essentiel pour le développement et la croissance des petits agriculteurs nigériens dans le secteur agricole en général.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d57e229a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e233" publication-type="other">
Adegeye, A.J. and Dittoh, J.S. (1985): Essentials of Agricultural Economics, Published by Impact Publisher Nig.
Ltd. 1985 Page 159.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e243a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e247" publication-type="other">
Akinbami, R.F. (1988): Credit Availability and Utilisation: A Case study of small-scale farmers in Ikale Local Govern-
ment Area of Ondo State. Unpublished B. Tech., project, F.U.T., Akure, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e257a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e261" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) (1989): Economic and Financial Review. Vol. 27, No. 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e268a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e272" publication-type="other">
Department of Rural Development Akure, Nigeria (1989): Unpublished Field Survey of Ondo State.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e280a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e284" publication-type="other">
Ezeugoh, S.C. (1981): "An interview" Bullion Vol. 6 No. A, Page 35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e291a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e295" publication-type="other">
Famoriyo, O.A. and Imoudu, P.B. (1988): "A Critical Evaluation of Agricultural Credit Financing in Nigeria"
FINAFRICA, African Review of Money, Finance and Banking, Vol. 1, pp 37 — 53 Milan, Italy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e305a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e309" publication-type="other">
Miller, L.F. (1977): Agricultural Credit and Finance in Africa, the Rockfeller Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e316a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e320" publication-type="other">
Olayide, etal (1979): Nigerian small farmers: Problems and prospects for solutions, A lecture delivered at the
College of Education, Ikere, Ondo State.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d57e330a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d57e334" publication-type="other">
Osuntogun, A. (1973): "Agricultural Credit Strategies for Nigerian Farmers". A.I.E. Spring Review of Small farmers
credit in Africa, Vol. VI.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
