<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">finamana</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100419</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Financial Management</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Management Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00463892</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">1755053X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">3665844</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Sinking Fund Prepurchases and the Designation Option</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
                  <surname>Kalotay</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Bruce</given-names>
                  <surname>Tuckman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i284586</issue-id>
         <fpage>110</fpage>
         <lpage>118</lpage>
         <page-range>110-118</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1992 Financial Management Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/3665844"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The corporate borrower may, from time to time, choose to purchase its outstanding bonds in the open market. Under SEC regulations, the borrower may not resell these bonds, but must retire them in a manner governed by the relevant indenture. When the only scheduled principal payment is at maturity, market purchases by the borrower have no effect on per bond value because the original cash flow pattern is not altered. In the presence of a sinking fund requirement, however, these market purchases do have an effect on bond values. The provisions of a typical sinking fund require that the borrower retire fixed principal amounts at some fixed schedule of dates either by purchasing the bonds in the open market or by calling them, by lot, at par. Any open market purchases in excess of those required are called prepurchases. Although it is not widely known, sinking fund indentures normally allow borrowers to designate prepurchased bonds, at any time, to any future sinking fund requirement. This designation option enables the borrower to alter the pattern of future cash flows. This paper discusses optimal designation policy and its effect on the value of outstanding bonds. The prevalence of sinking fund provisions and of prepurchases supports the importance of this investigation. Of industrial bonds with original maturities longer than 10 years, about 51% have sinking fund provisions. Of those with original maturities longer than 20 years, about 77% have sinking fund provisions. Furthermore, about 66% of issuers of industrial sinking fund bonds have prepurchased more than one sinking fund payment. Over 30% of these issuers have prepurchased three or more sinking fund payments. The option to designate prepurchased bonds is particularly valuable when interest rates are significantly different from the coupon rate. When interest rates are relatively low and bond prices are above par, the borrower should choose to meet sinking fund requirements by calling the required number of bonds at par. If, before exercising its call option, the borrower designates prepurchased bonds to later sinking fund dates, it lowers the amount outstanding and raises the number of bonds called away from investors at par. In this way, designation can lower the value of outstanding bonds. On the other hand, designating bonds to satisfy future sinking fund payments sacrifices those future options to call bonds at par; without the obligation to retire principal on a particular date there is no right to call bonds at par on that date. Furthermore, due to interest rate movements, it may turn out that the sacrificed options were worth quite a bit, while the options on different sinking fund dates turned out to be worthless. In other words, ex post, it might have been better to designate the prepurchased bonds to a different set of sinking fund dates. An optimal designation policy weighs the benefits of raising the number of bonds called from investors against the sacrificed options and the loss of future designation flexibility. When interest rates are relatively high and bond prices are below par, the borrower should satisfy its requirements through market purchases. But accumulators, by cornering the issue, may be able to force the borrower to pay inflated prices for its bonds. If the borrower has prepurchased some bonds, however, it could designate them to the current sinking fund requirement. In this way, the borrower postpones paying off the accumulators and lowers the value of their holdings. Thus, once again, the designation option enables the borrower to reduce the value of the remaining outstanding bonds. Our paper presents an algorithm for deriving the optimal designation policy and for the valuation of sinking fund bonds in the presence of a designation option. The discussion encompasses other options commonly granted to the borrower, namely the American call option to repurchase the bond at declining strike prices and acceleration options to call multiples of the sinking fund requirement, at par, on sinking fund dates. Numerical examples are then used to illustrate that bond prices will be lower if prepurchases have been higher. The magnitude of this effect is largest when interest rates are well below the coupon rate and when accumulators have cornered the issue at a time when interest rates are well above the coupon rate. In summary, a borrower may be able to reduce the cost of servicing sinking fund debt by adopting an active prepurchase policy and by optimally designating prepurchased bonds. Similarly, investors might profit from monitoring a borrower's prepurchase and designation policies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group>
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d85e132a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e139" publication-type="other">
Ho [4]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e146a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e153" publication-type="other">
Ho and Singer [5], [6]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e160a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e167" publication-type="other">
Dunn and Spatt [3]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e173" publication-type="other">
Kalotay [8]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e180a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e187" publication-type="other">
American Bar Foundation [1, p. 42]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e195a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e202" publication-type="other">
American Bar Foundation [1, p. 517].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e209a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e216" publication-type="other">
American Bar Foundation [1, pp. 516-519]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e223a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e230" publication-type="other">
American Bar Foundation [1, p. 41].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e237a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e244" publication-type="other">
Ingersoll [7, chapter 2]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e251a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e258" publication-type="other">
Dunn and Spatt [3]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d85e265a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e272" publication-type="other">
Black, Derman, and Toy [2]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d85e288a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e295" publication-type="book">
American Bar Foundation, Corporate Debt Financing Project, Com-
mentaries on Model Debenture Provisions, American Bar Founda-
tion, 1971.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>American Bar Foundation</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <source>Commentaries on Model Debenture Provisions</source>
               <year>1971</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e324a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e331" publication-type="journal">
F. Black, E. Derman, and W. Toy, "A One-Factor Model of Interest
Rates and Its Application to Treasury Bond Options," Financial
Analysts Journal (January-February 1990), pp. 33-39.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Black</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>January</issue>
               <fpage>33</fpage>
               <source>Financial Analysts Journal</source>
               <year>1990</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e366a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e373" publication-type="journal">
K. Dunn and C. Spatt, "A Strategic Analysis of Sinking Fund
Bonds," Journal of Financial Economics (September 1984), pp.
399-423.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Dunn</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>September</issue>
               <fpage>399</fpage>
               <source>Journal of Financial Economics</source>
               <year>1984</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e408a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e415" publication-type="book">
T. Ho, "The Value of a Sinking Fund Bond Provision Under Interest
Rate Risk," in Recent Advances in Corporate Finance, E. Altman
and M. Subrahmanyam (eds.), Richard D. Irwin Press, 1985, pp.
55-77.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ho</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <comment content-type="section">The Value of a Sinking Fund Bond Provision Under Interest Rate Risk</comment>
               <fpage>55</fpage>
               <source>Recent Advances in Corporate Finance</source>
               <year>1985</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e454a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e461" publication-type="journal">
T. Ho and R. Singer, "Bond Indenture Provisions and the Risk of
Corporate Debt," Journal of Financial Economics (December 1982),
pp. 375-406.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ho</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>December</issue>
               <fpage>375</fpage>
               <source>Journal of Financial Economics</source>
               <year>1982</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e496a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e503" publication-type="journal">
T. Ho and R. Singer, "The Value of Corporate Debt With a Sinking
Fund Provision," Journal of Business (July 1984), pp. 315-336.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2352865</object-id>
               <fpage>315</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e519a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e526" publication-type="book">
J. Ingersoll, Theory of Financial Decision Making, Rowman and
Littlefield Publishers, 1987.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Ingersoll</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <source>Theory of Financial Decision Making</source>
               <year>1987</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e551a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e558" publication-type="journal">
A. Kalotay, "On the Management of Sinking Funds," Financial
Management (Summer 1981), pp. 34-40.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/3665047</object-id>
               <fpage>34</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e574a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e581" publication-type="journal">
A. Kalotay and G. Williams, "The Valuation and Management of
Bonds With Sinking Fund Provisions," Financial Analysts Journal
(March-April 1992), pp. 59-67.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kalotay</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>March</issue>
               <fpage>59</fpage>
               <source>Financial Analysts Journal</source>
               <year>1992</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d85e616a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d85e623" publication-type="journal">
S. Myers, "Determinants of Corporate Borrowing," Journal of Fi-
nancial Economics (November 1977), pp. 147-175.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Myers</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>November</issue>
               <fpage>147</fpage>
               <source>Journal of Financial Economics</source>
               <year>1977</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
