<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">14</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830208</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830212</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FINANCIAL REPRESSION AND ITS IMPACT ON FINANCIAL DEVELOPMENT AND ECONOMIC GROWTH IN THE AFRICAN LEAST DEVELOPED COUNTRIES / LA REPRESSION FINANCIERE ET SES EFFETS SUR LE DEVELOPPEMENT DU FINANCEMENT ET LA CROISSANCE ECONOMIQUE DANS LES PAYS AFRICAINS LES MOINS AVANCES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Adera</given-names>
                  <surname>Abebe</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1990</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>55</fpage>
         <lpage>87</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830212"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The relationship between real and monetary variables is undeniable. Yet, policy makers in African LDCs have failed to follow an active policy of developing the domestic monetary and financial sector. The power of credit as an instrument of development and potential role of credit policy techniques and institutions in the scheme of overall planning has also not received adequate attention. The official attitude to resource mobilization has been extremely lax partly due to foreign resource inflows and partly due to the inexpensive rediscounting terms and facilities provided by the central bank. The direction which the evaluation of the financial structure of African LDCs should take depends on specific country circumstances. The effective functioning of a sound financial structure however presupposes the existence of appropriate financial institutions and institutional philosophy; financial instruments that are consistent with savers' and borrowers' preferences; and a rational structure of positive real interest rates. Experience suggests, that the commercial banking system will set the pace because of their principal function of credit creation. This is, however, only one element in the process for the manner in which bank credit is utilized is no less important in the growth process. The credit needs of agriculture, small businesses and industries and many traditional enterprises are still met by the non-banking traditional institutions, such as the money lender. The broadening of the scope of the banking system, in geographical and functional coverage, is necessary to meet the credit needs of these strategic sectors. The available evidence indicates that interest rate liberalization is not efficacious unless there is a competitive market. In countries where the banking system has not been nationalized, an oligopolistic financial system will have the opportunity to extract economic rents from the public, by effectively raising the asset and liability rates so as to increase its profits, while reducing the financial operations to a level below the optimum. The monetary authorities should then pursue a discretionary and flexible interest rate policy that takes into account the rate of inflation, the market conditions and the needs of the public when determining the interest rates level. La relation entre variables réelles et variables monétaires est indéniable. Cependant, les dirigeants des pays africains les moins avancés n'ont pas su appliquer des politiques dynamiques en vue de développer leur secteur monétaire et financier intérieur. De même, une attention suffisante n'a pas été accordée à l'importance du crédit comme instrument de développement et au rôle potentiel des politiques, techniques et institutions de crédit en matière de planification générale. En effet, l'attitude officielle face à la mobilisation des ressources a été extrêmement laxiste, en raison, d'une part des flux de ressources extérieures, et d'autre part, des conditions et facilités de réescompte peu coûteuses accordées par la banque centrale. L'évaluation de la structure financière des PMA africains devrait être orientée en fonction des conditions propres à chaque pays. Le fonctionnement effectif d'une structure financière saine suppose cependant l'existence d'institutions financières et d'une philosophie institutionnelle appropriées, ainsi que d'instruments financiers conformes aux préférences des épargnants et des emprunteurs et d'une structure rationnelle de taux d'intérêts réels positifs. Toutefois, l'expérience montre que le système des banques commerciales en définira les modalités en raison du rôle principal joué par ces dernières en matière de création de crédits. Néanmoins, il ne s'agit là que d'un élément du processus car la manière dont le crédit bancaire est utilisé revêt également une importance pour la croissance. Les besoins de crédit du secteur agricole, des petites entreprises et industries et de bon nombre d'entreprises traditionnelles continuent d'être satisfaits auprès d'institutions traditionnelles non bancaires telles que les prêteurs sur pages. Il est nécessaire d'élargir la portée tant géographique que fonctionnelle du système bancaire pour satisfaire les besoins en crédit de ces secteurs stratégiques. Il ressort des éléments disponibles que la libéralisation des taux d'intérêt ne peut être efficace que dans un marché compétitif. Dans les pays où le système bancaire n'est pas nationalisé, le système financier oligopolistique pourra retirer une rente économique du public en augmentant effectivement les taux de l'actif et du passif de façon à accroître ses bénéfices tout en réduisant les opérations financières à un niveau inférieur au niveau optimal. Il faudrait alors que les autorités monétaires appliquent une politique des taux d'intérêt discrétionnaire et souple qui tienne compte du taux d'inflation, des conditions du marché et des besoins de la population lors de la détermination des taux d'intérêt.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d50e227a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e234" publication-type="other">
V. Galbis, Financial Sector
Liberalization Under Oligopolistic Conditions and a Bank Holding Structure, Savings and Development, No. 2,
1986, p. 133.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e247a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e254" publication-type="other">
Adebayo Adedeji. ^Towards a Dynamic African Economy*, selected speeches and lectures,
1975-1986 (Frank Cass, London) 1989.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>Bibliography</title>
        <ref id="d50e273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e277" publication-type="other">
Abdi, Ali Issa, Commercial Banks and Economic Development: The Experience of Eastern Africa» (Prager, 1977)
pp. 114-124</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e287a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e291" publication-type="other">
Abebe, Adera, "Agricultural Credit and the Mobilization of Resources in Rural Africa,» Savings and Develop-
ment, No. 1-XI (Milan, 1987) p. 58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e305" publication-type="other">
Adams, Dale W. «Do Rural Financial Savings Matter?» Savings and Development, Denis Kessler and Pierre
Antoine Ulmo, eds (Paris Economica, 1985) p. 10</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e319" publication-type="other">
—, «Are the Arguments for Cheap Credit Sound?» in Undermining Rural Development with Cheap Credit, Dale
Adams and J.D. Von Pischke, eds (Boulder and London, Westview Press, 1984) pp. 65-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e330a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e334" publication-type="other">
—, and C. Vogel, «Rural Financial Markets in Low Income Countries: Recent Controversies and Lessons,» World
Development, vol. 14. No. 4, 1986 pp. 477-486.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e344a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e348" publication-type="other">
Adedeji, Adebayo, «Africa and the New International Economic Order: A Reassessment*, National Bank of Egypt
(Commemoration Lectures Programme), Cairo, 1979.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e358a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e362" publication-type="other">
—, «African Recovery in an Uncertain and Unstable International Economy», statement delivered at the opening
of the twenty-third session of the Commission/fourteenth meeting of the ECA Conference of Ministers 14
April 1988, Niamey (Niger) in «What Prospects for African Economic Recovery:, United Nations Economic
Commission for Africa pp. 93-115.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e382" publication-type="other">
—, «Trade, Money and Finance: Engines of Growth or Clogs in the Wheels of Africa's Development and Transfor-
mation, inaugural address at the Obasanmi Olakanpo Memorial Distinguished Social Sciences Lecture
Series, University of Lagos (Nigeria) 15 May 1989, pp. 3-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e399" publication-type="other">
—, "Towards a Dynamic African Economy», Selected Speeches and Lectures 1975-1976, Frank Cass, 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e406a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e410" publication-type="other">
Agarwala, R.K. «Price Distortions and Growth in Developing Countries," World Bank Staff Working Paper, No.
575 (Washington, D.C.: The World Bank, 1983).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e421a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e425" publication-type="other">
Agu, C.C. «lnterest Rates Policy in Nigeria and Its Attendant Distortions," Savings and Development, No. 1 -XII
(Milan, 1988) pp. 19-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e435a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e439" publication-type="other">
Awad, Mohammed Hashim, «The Supply of Risk Bearers in Underdeveloped Countries," Economic Develop-
ment and Cultural Change, No. 3, vol. 19 (April 1971), pp. 461-468.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e449a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e453" publication-type="other">
Bhaduri, Amit, «On the Formation of Usurious Interest Rates of Backward Agriculture", Cambridge Journal of
Economics, (December 1977) pp. 341-352.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e463a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e467" publication-type="other">
Bhatia Rattan J. and Deena Khatkhate, «Financial Intermediation, Savings Mobilization, and Entrepreneurial
Development: The African Experience," IMF Staff Papers, vol. XXII, No. 1, March 1975, pp. 132-138.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e477a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e481" publication-type="other">
Bhatt, V.V. «Some Aspects of Financial Policies and Central Banking in Developing Countries," EDI Seminar
Paper No. 11, The World Bank (Washington, D.C.) August 1974, p. 9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e491a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e495" publication-type="other">
—, «lmproving the Financial Structure in Developing Countries," Finance and Development, vol. 23, No. 2 (June
1986) pp. 20-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e506a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e510" publication-type="other">
Bottomley, Anthony, «The Premium for Risk as a Determinant of Interest Rates in Underdeveloped Rural Areas»,
Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 77 (November 1963), pp. 637-647.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e520a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e524" publication-type="other">
Bouman, F.J.A. ^Indigenous Savings and Credit Societies in the Third World: A Message», Savings and Develop-
ment, vol. 1, No. 4 (Milan, 1977 pp. 181-214).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e534a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e538" publication-type="other">
—, «Pawnbroking as an Instrument of Rural Banking in the Third World**, Economic Development and Cultural
Change, vol. 37, No. 1 (October 1988) pp. 69-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e548a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e552" publication-type="other">
Bourne and Graham, ^Funding and Viability of Rural Development Banks», Savings and Development No. 4-IV
(Milan, 1980) p. 308.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e562a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e566" publication-type="other">
Brown, Gilbert T., "Korean Pricing: Policies and Economic Development in the 1960s,* (Baltimore, M.D.: Johns
Hopkins University Press, 1973).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e576a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e580" publication-type="other">
Chandarvarkar, Anand, «Monetization of Developing Economies**, IMF Staff Papers, vol. XXIV, No. 3, (November
1977) p. 677.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e591a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e595" publication-type="other">
—, «Some Aspects of Interest Rate Policies in Less Developed Economies: The Experience of Selected Asian
Countries**, IMF Staff Papers, vol. XVIII, No. 1 (March 1971), pp. 48-110.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e605a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e609" publication-type="other">
Copestake, James G., «The Transition to Social Banking in India: Promises and Pitfalls**, Development Policy
Review, vol. 6, No. 2 (June 1988) pp. 139-161.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e619a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e623" publication-type="other">
Cuveas, Carlos, «Rural Finance Profiles in African Countries», (edited by Mario Masini) FINAFRICA, vol. 1, (Milan,
1987) p. 155.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e633a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e637" publication-type="other">
Dacosta, Michael, "Finance and Development*, (Boulder, Co: Westview Press, 1982), p. 106.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e644a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e648" publication-type="other">
Datey, CD. «The Financial Cost of Agricultural Credit: A Case Study of Indian Experience** World Bank Staff
Working Paper, No. 296, Washington, D.C. (October, 1978).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e658a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e662" publication-type="other">
Diaz-Alejandro, Carlos, «Good-bye Financial Repression, Hello Financial Crash,» Journal of Development
Economics, vol. 19, No. 1/2, (September-October 1985) p. 20.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e673a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e677" publication-type="other">
Donald, Gordon, "Credit for Small Farmers in Developing Countries* (Boulder, Co: Westview Press, 1976).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e684a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e688" publication-type="other">
Economic Commission for Africa, "The Balance of Payments Problems of Developing Africa: A Reassessment,*
Paper submitted to the Round Table of Governors of African Central Banks and Senior Officials of Inter-
national Financial Institutions, (Addis Ababa, 4-7 February 1985).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e701a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e705" publication-type="other">
—, Review of Economic and Social Conditions in African Least Developed Countries, E/ECA/LDCs/Exp. 7.2,
(1986-1987).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e715a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e719" publication-type="other">
Fry, Maxwell, «Financial Intermediation in Small Island Developing Economies,** Commonwealth Economic Papers:
No. 16 (September 1981) p. 62</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e733" publication-type="other">
Galbis, V. «Financial Sector Liberalization Under Oligopolistic Conditions and a Bank Holding Structure,» Sav-
ings and Development, No. 2 (Milan, 1986) pp. 117-140</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e747" publication-type="other">
Goldsmith, Raymond, "Financial Structure and Development, Yale University Press (1969) pp. 1-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e755a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e759" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez Arrieta, Gerardom interest Rates, Savings and Growth in LDCs: An Assessment of Recent Empirical
Research**, World Development, vol. 16, No.5 (May 1988) pp. 589-605.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e769a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e773" publication-type="other">
Gurley, John, «Financial Structures in Developing Economies**, in Fiscal and Monetary Problems in Developing
States,* Proceedings of the Third Rehovoth Conference (Edited by David Krivine), Prager, 1967, pp. 99-116.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e783a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e787" publication-type="other">
—, and Shaw, «Financial Structure and Economic Development**, Economic Development and Cultural Change,
vol. 15, No. 3, 1967 pp. 257-268.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e797a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e801" publication-type="other">
Hanson, James A., and Craig R. Neal, «lnterest Rate Policies in Selected Developing Countries 1970-1982»,
World Bank Staff Working Papers, No. 753. (Washington, D.C., The World Bank, September 1985) pp.
35-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e818" publication-type="other">
Hoist, J.U, «The Role of Informal Financial Institutions in the Mobilization of Savings*, Savings and Develop-
ment, Denis Kessler and Pierre-Antoine Ullmo, ed. (Paris, Economica, 1985) pp. 121-149.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e828a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e832" publication-type="other">
Joglekar, M.K. and others, «Role of Credit System as a Prime Mover of Rural Development*, Paper II at Inter-
Regional Seminar on Harnessing Financial Systems in Support of Rural Development, India, July — 11
August 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e846a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e850" publication-type="other">
Khatkhate D. and K. W. Riechel, "Multipurpose Banking: Its Nature, Scope, and Relevance for Less Developed
Countries,* IMF Staff Papers, 27 (3); September 1980.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e860a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e864" publication-type="other">
—, "Assessing the Impact of Interest Rates in Less Developed Countries*, World Development, vol. 16, No.
5, 1988, pp. 577-586.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e874a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e878" publication-type="other">
—, «National and International Aspects of Financial Policies in LDCs: A Prologue, World Development, vol. 10,
No. 9 (September 1982).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e888a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e892" publication-type="other">
—, "False Issues in the Debate on Interest Rate Policies in Less Developed Countries,* Banca Nazionale del
Lavoro Quarterly Review, No. 133 (June 1980) pp. 205-221.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e902a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e906" publication-type="other">
Lanyi, Anthony and R. Saracoglu, «lnterest Rate Policies in Selected Developing Countries*, Occasional Paper,
No. 22 (Washington, D.C. International Monetary Fund, October 1983) p. 9</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e916a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e920" publication-type="other">
Leite, Sergio P., "Interest Rate Policies in West Africa*, IMF Staff Papers, vol. 29, No. 1 March 1982, p. 58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e928a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e932" publication-type="other">
Lipton, M., (1977), Why Poor People Stay Poor: A Study of Urban Bias in World Development, (Temple Smith).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e943" publication-type="other">
Long, Millard, *A Note on Financial Theory and Economic Development*, in Rural Financial Markets in Develop-
ing Countries (edited by J.D. Von Pischke, Dale W. Adams and Gordon Donald) The Johns Hopkins Univer-
sity Press (Baltimore, 1983) p. 28</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e960" publication-type="other">
Madan, B.K. «Role of Commercial Banks in Developing Countries and Measures for Improving the Adequacy
of Banking Facilities*, Reserve Bank of India Bulletin, vol. XVIII, No. 6 (June 1964), pp. 750-764.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e970a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e974" publication-type="other">
Masini, Mario, «Rural Finance Profiles in African Countries, volume I, FINAFRICA (Milan, 1987) p. 90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e985" publication-type="other">
Mauri, Arnaldo, «Savings Banks in African Countries,* in The Mobilization of Savings in African Countries, Pro-
ceedings of an International Conference held in Milan, 20-23 September 1971, pp. 51-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e995a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e999" publication-type="other">
—, «The Potential for Savings and Financial Innovation in Africa*, Savings and Development, No. 4-VII, 1983
pp. 332-335.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1010a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1014" publication-type="other">
McKinnon, R., «Financial Policies* in Policies for Industrial Progress in Developing countries, (John Cody, Helen
Hughes and David Wall Edition). The Brookings Institution (Washington D.C. 1980) p. 93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1024a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1028" publication-type="other">
—, Money and Capital in Economic Development, (Washington D.C. 1973).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1039" publication-type="other">
Mikesell, Raymond F., and James E. Zinser, «The Nature of Savings Function in Developing Countries: A Survey of the
Theoretical and Empirical Evidence*, Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 11, No. 1 (March 1973), pp. 1-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1049a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1053" publication-type="other">
Miracle and others, «lnformal Savings Mobilization in Africa*, Economic Development and Cultural Change, vol.
28, No. 4 (July 1980) pp. 701-721.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1067" publication-type="other">
Myint, Hla, «The Economics of the Developing Countries*, (New York, Prager Publishers, 1965).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1074a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1078" publication-type="other">
Narashiman, M., «Credit Planning in India: Its Rational and Content*, in Money and Monetary Policy in Less
Developed Countries, (Warren L. Coats and Deena Khatkhate edition) 1980, pp. 617-628.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1093" publication-type="other">
Patrick, Hugh T., «Financial Development and Economic Growth in Underdeveloped Countries**, Economic
Development and Cultural Change, vol. XIV, No. 2 (January 1966).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1107" publication-type="other">
Penny, David H., «Farm Credit Policy in early stages of Agricultural Development**, Australian Journal of
Agricultural Economics, vol. 2, No. 1 (June 1968) pp. 32-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1121" publication-type="other">
Porter, R.C. «The Promotion of the Banking Habit and Economic Development**, Journal of Development Studies,
volume 2, No. 4 July, 1966 p. 353.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1131a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1135" publication-type="other">
Roe, Alan R., «High Interest Rates: A New Conventional Wisdom for Development Policy? Some Conclusions
from Sri Lankan Experience**, World Development, vol. 10, No. 3 (March 1982) pp. 211-221.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1145a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1149" publication-type="other">
Shaw, Edward S., "Financial Deepening in Economic Development*, Oxford University Press (London 1973).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1156a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1160" publication-type="other">
Wai, U. Tun, «lnterest Rates Outside the Organized Money Markets of Underdeveloped Countries**, IMF Staff
Papers, vol. 5 (August 1956), pp. 249-278.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1175" publication-type="other">
Yondo, Marcel, "Finance Currency and Credit Policies in Central Africa*, National Bank of Egypt Lectures Pro-
gramme (Cairo, 1983).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


