<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277522</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of the Impact of Real-World Aging on Diesel Oxidation Catalysts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Junhui</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Szailer</surname>
                  <given-names>Tamas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Watts</surname>
                  <given-names>Ana</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Currier</surname>
                  <given-names>Neal</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yezerets</surname>
                  <given-names>Aleksey</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Cummins Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>985</fpage>
         <lpage>994</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277522"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Real-world operation of diesel oxidation catalysts (DOCs), used in a variety of aftertreatment systems, subjects these catalysts to a large number of permanent and temporary deactivation mechanisms. These include thermal damage, induced by generating exotherm on the catalyst; exposure to various inorganic species contained in engine fluids; and the effects of soot and hydrocarbons, which can mask the catalyst in certain operating modes. While some of these deactivation mechanisms can be accurately simulated in the lab, others are specific to particular engine operation regimes.</p>
            <p>In this work, a set of DOCs, removed from prolonged service in the field, has been subjected to a detailed laboratory study. Samples obtained from various locations in these catalysts were used to characterize the extent and distribution of deactivation. The arsenal of techniques used to characterize the samples included probe reactions of NO and C₃H₆ oxidation, as well as a set of pre-treatment conditions, targeting at removing various contaminants, including hydrocarbons, soot, sulfur, and phosphorous.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, C., Schmid, M., Schmieg, S., Tan, J. et al., “The Effect of Pt-Pd Ratio on Oxidation Catalysts Under Simulated Diesel Exhaust,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1134, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Epling, W.S., Campbell, L. E., Yezerets, A., Currier, N.W., and Parks, J. E. II “Overview of the Fundamental Reactions and Degradation Mechanisms of NOx Storage/Reduction Catalysts” Catal. Reviews 46 (2004) 163-245</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamasamudram, K., Currier, N., Szailer, T., and Yezerets, A., “Why Cu- and Fe-Zeolite SCR Catalysts Behave Differently At Low Temperatures,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):664-672, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartholomew, Calvin H. “Mechanisms of catalyst deactivation” Applied Catalysis A: General 212 (2001) 17-60</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, J., Kim, C., Choung, Suk-Jin “Comparison studies on sintering phenomenon of diesel oxidation catalyst depending upon aging conditions”, Catal. Today 2011, In Press</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson, J., Antonsson, M., Eurenius, L., Olsson, E., Skoglundh, M. “Deactivation of diesel oxidation catalysts: Vehicle- and synthetic aging correlations”, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 72 (2007) 71-81</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hauff, K., Tuttlies, U., Eigenberger, G., Nieken, U. “A global description of DOC kinetics for catalysts with different platinum loadings and aging status” Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 100 (2010) 10-18</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shakir, Osama, Yezerets, Aleksey, Currier, Neal W., Epling, William S., “Spatially resolving concentration and temperature gradients during the oxidation of propylene on Pt/Al2O3” Applied Catalysis A: General 365 (2009) 301-308</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCullough, G., Douglas, R., and McDowell, N., “Deactivation of Oxidation Catalysts by Oil-Derived Sulphur,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1738, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1738.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cavataio, G., Jen, H., Dobson, D., and Warner, J., “Laboratory Study to Determine Impact of Na and K Exposure on the Durability of DOC and SCR Catalyst Formulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2823, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2823.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, A., McCormick, R., Luecke, J., Brezny, R. et al., “Impact of Biodiesel Impurities on the Performance and Durability of DOC, DPF and SCR Technologies,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 4(1):110-124, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunting, B., More, K., Lewis, S., and Toops, T., “Phosphorous Poisoning and Phosphorous Exhaust Chemistry with Diesel Oxidation Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1758, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-1758.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eaton, S., Bunting, B., Toops, T., and Nguyen, K., “The Roles of Phosphorus and Soot on the Deactivation of Diesel Oxidation Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0628, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0628.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eaton, S., Nguyen, K., and Bunting, B., “Deactivation of Diesel Oxidation Catalysts by Oil-Derived Phosphorus,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3422, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagata, M. and Tanaka, Y., “Modeling of Phosphorus Poisoning Phenomena over Diesel Oxidation Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0884, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0884.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christou, S. Y., Birgersson, H., Efstathiou, A. M., “Reactivation of severely aged commercial three-way catalysts by washing with weak EDTA and oxalic acid solutions” Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 71 (2007) 185-198</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christou, S. Y., Gasste, J., Karlsson, H. L., Fierro, J. L. G., Efstathiou, A. M. “Regeneration of Aged Commercial Three-Way Catalytic Converters” Top Catal 52 (2009) 2029-2034</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pieck, Carlos L., Vera, Carlos R., Querini, Carlos A., Parera, José M., “Differences in coke burning-off from Pt-Sn/Al2O3 catalyst with oxygen or ozone” Applied Catalysis A: General 278 (2005) 173-180</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luo, J., Kisinger, D., Abedi, A., Epling, W. S. “Sulfur release from a model Pt/Al2O3 diesel oxidation catalyst: Temperature-programmed and step-response techniques characterization” Applied Catalysis A: General 383 (2010) 182-191</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yezerets, A., Currier, N., and Eadler, H., “Experimental Determination of the Kinetics of Diesel Soot Oxidation by O2 - Modeling Consequences,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0833, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
