<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169026</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Control System for a PEM Fuel Cell Powered Heavy Duty Tactical Mobility Truck with Auxiliary Power Generation Capabilities</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Felix</surname>
                  <given-names>Rodrigo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Economou</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Knowles</surname>
                  <given-names>Kevin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Cranfield University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169025</issue-id>
         <fpage>413</fpage>
         <lpage>427</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169026"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The incorporation of hydrogen fuel cells into heavy duty tactical mobility vehicles can bring about great opportunities in reducing the pollutant emissions of this kind of platforms (GVW &gt; 30,000 kg). Furthermore the transportation of fuel to operational areas has become a key aspect for any deployment therefore optimal use of this resource is of paramount importance. Finally, it is also quite common for such platforms to serve additional purposes, besides freight delivery, such as powering external equipment (i.e. field hospitals or mobile artillery pieces).</p>
            <p>This work will describe the intelligent energy management system for a PEM Fuel Cell-Battery-Ultracapacitor Hybrid 8×8 heavy truck of the aforementioned weight class which also contemplates an internal electric/traction power generation unit. It will describe how the system optimizes the use of battery and hydrogen fuel energy while keeping system efficiency and performance at a maximum.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“U.S. Gasoline and Diesel Retail Prices”, Energy Intelligence Agency. Publication Date: March 21st. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartis, James T. and Van Bibber Lawrence. Alternative Fuels for Military Applications. Santa Monica, CA: RAND Corporation, 2011. http://www.rand.org/pubs/monographs/MG969.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">STIGLITZ, J. (2008), The $3 Trillion War. New Perspectives Quarterly, 25: 61-64. doi:10.1111/j.1540-5842.2008.00980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fenwick, William B. Maj, “Reducing Battlefield Fuel Demand: Mitigating a Marine Corp Critical Vulnerability,” MMs. thesis, Command and Staff College, Marine Corps University, Quantico. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zygarlicke, Christopher J., Aulich Ted R., Wocken Chad A., Pflughoeft- Hassett Debra F., et al. Progress in the Production of JP-8 Based Hydrogen and Advanced Tactical Fuels for Military Applications. No. ERDC/CERL-TR-11-2. ENGINEER RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTER CHAMPAIGN IL CONSTRUCTION ENGINEERING RESEARCH LAB, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SkyBuilt Power, “SkyBuilt's SkyStation,” http://www.skybuilt.com/news/pdfs_products/SkyBuilt_SkyStationTechnicalSheet.pdf, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Defence News. “Renewable Power Kits Bring Power to U.S. Soldiers,” http://www.defensenews.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article? AID=2012306120008, June, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zamora, I., San Martín, J.I., García, J., Asensio, F.J., Oñederra, O., San Martín, J.J., and Aperribay, V. “PEM Fuel Cells in Applications of Urban Public Transport,” presented at International Conference on Renewable Energies and Power Quality. Spain, April 13-15, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, Dawei, Jin Zhenhua, and Lu Qingchun. “Energy management strategy based on fuzzy logic for a fuel cell hybrid bus.” Journal of Power Sources 185, no. 1 (2008): 311-317.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thounthong, Phatiphat, Raël Stephane, and Davat Bernard. “Energy management of fuel cell/battery/supercapacitor hybrid power source for vehicle applications.” Journal of Power Sources 193, no. 1 (2009): 376-385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">García, P., Torreglosa J. P., Fernández L. M., and Jurado F.. “Viability study of a FC-battery-SC tramway controlled by equivalent consumption minimization strategy.” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy (2012).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalig, Alireza and Zhihao Li., “Battery, Ultracapacitor, Fuel Cell, and Hybrid Energy Storage Systems for Electric, Hybrid Electric, Fuel Cell, and Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles: State of the Art,” IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, Vol. 59, No. 6, July 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gou, Bei, Woon K. N. and Diong B.. “Fuel Cells: Modeling, Control, and Applications,” CRC Press, USA. 2010. ISBN 1420071610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pukrushpan, Jay T., Stephanopoulou Anna G. and Peng Huei. “Control of Fuel Cell Power Systems. Principles, Modeling, Analysis and Feedback Design,” Springer-Verlag, U.K. 2004. ISBN 1-85233-816-4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barbir, Frano. “PEM Fuel Cells. Theory and Practice,” Elsevier Academic Press. 2005. ISBN 123877105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tremblay, Olivier, and Dessaint Louis-A.. “Experimental validation of a battery dynamic model for EV applications.” World Electric Vehicle Journal 3 (2009): 13-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tremblay, Olivier, Dessaint L-A., and Dekkiche A-I.. “A generic battery model for the dynamic simulation of hybrid electric vehicles.” In Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, 2007. VPPC 2007. IEEE, pp. 284-289. IEEE, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krishnan, R. “Permanent Magnet Synchronous and Brushless DC Motor Drives,” CRC Press,USA. 2010. ISBN 978-0-8247-5384-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tie, Siang Fui, and Tan Chee Wei. “A review of power and energy management strategies in electric vehicles.” In Intelligent and Advanced Systems (ICIAS), 2012 4th International Conference on, vol. 1, pp. 412-417. IEEE, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hua, Jianfeng, Lu Languang, Ouyang Minggao, Li Jianqiu, and Xu Liangfei. “Proton exchange membrane fuel cell system diagnosis based on the signed directed graph method.” Journal of Power Sources 196, no. 14 (2011): 5881-5888</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Filipi, Z., Louca, L., Stefanopoulou, A., Pukrushpan, J. et al., “Fuel Cell APU for Silent Watch and Mild Electrification of a Medium Tactical Truck,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1477, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1477.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
