<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437242</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Taxation and Savings: A Survey</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>ROBIN</given-names>
                  <surname>BOADWAY</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>DAVID</given-names>
                  <surname>WILDASIN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437238</issue-id>
         <fpage>19</fpage>
         <lpage>63</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1994</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437242"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e119a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e126" publication-type="other">
Of course, earnings could also be made endogenous by allowing the labour supply to vary. Since we are
concentrating on savings decisions, we ignore this possibility for simplicity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e136a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e143" publication-type="other">
There is an enormous literature on the issue of Ricardian equivalence and the circumstances under which it applies.
A summary of opposing positions can be found in Boadway and Wildasin (1993).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e153a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e160" publication-type="other">
If instead the increase in wealth is anticipated, consumption will rise in earlier periods and saving will fall to
finance the increase in consumption.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e170a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e177" publication-type="other">
In this example, the same result would apply if households were altruistic towards their heirs. Since no
intergenerational transfers are involved, there is no need for bequest behaviour to change in response to the
tax-transfer scheme.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e191a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e198" publication-type="other">
To see this, suppose population grows at the rate n and that there is no technical progress, so g - n. In the
two-period life-cycle case, if T is the tax per worker, the transfer per retiree will be T(l+n). The present value of
the scheme over the life cycle will be -T+T(l+n)/(l+r), which will be positive or negative according to whether
n is greater or less than r. More generally, the same result would hold if cohorts live for several periods and if
technical progress occurs. The implicit rate of return on the intergenerational transfer scheme would be g.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e217a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e224" publication-type="other">
A general consumption tax is a uniform tax on C{ and C2. A wage tax is a tax on L, or, equivalently by the budget
constraint, a uniform tax on Cj and C2. A capital income tax is a tax on C2. An income tax is a system of taxes on
C, and C2 with that on C2 being higher. And C| and C2 can be selectively taxed by excise taxes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e237a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e244" publication-type="other">
One would expect some further results could be obtained in the case in which lifetime utility was a separable
function of the first-period consumption bundle, the second-period consumption bundle and leisure. Then
per-period consumption could be treated as a composite commodity, and one could rely on wage and capital income
taxes alone.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e260a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e267" publication-type="other">
Technically, this is so if utility is homothetic in goods, and if the marginal rate of substitution between all pairs
of goods is independent of the level of leisure (i.e. goods are separable from leisure in the utility function).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e277a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e284" publication-type="other">
See Heady (1993) for a non-technical survey of this literature.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e291a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e298" publication-type="other">
One way to do this would be to combine a tax on income with one on consumption. By varying the rates on the
two, any combination of a tax on present and future consumption could be attained. It is interesting to note that
many countries' income tax systems are essentially of this sort, given that they shelter part of capital income.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e312a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e321" publication-type="other">
Specifically, he derived that the present value to society of an increase in saving by £1 was given by
(r_g)(l+S)/((5_g)(l+d)), where S is society's discount rate between present and future consumption (reflecting
differences in the marginal utility of consumption caused by growth in consumption) and d is the individual':
discount rate (which is less than r because of capital income taxation).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e337a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e344" publication-type="other">
In an ingenious argument, Bemheim and Bagwell (1988) have argued that saving for bequests becomes a public
good even in a Ricardian world in which each person only cares about their own direct heirs. In this world, people
care indirectly about all their future descendants. But, by the natural process of intermarriage among persons of
different family lines, all persons become interrelated in the long run and care about each other's heirs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e360a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e367" publication-type="other">
The weighting of welfare levels in different generations could reflect their population. For example, if the
intergenerational social welfare function is the population-weighted sum of total (rather than per capita) utilities
A A
and if total utilities are discounted at the rate a, then per capita utilities will be discounted at a = a - n. The economy
converges to an optimum in which r = a.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e386a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e393" publication-type="other">
There is an issue as to whether bequests and gifts given ought to be deducted from the right-hand side of the
equation. If the giving of gifts and bequests is considered an act of consumption, they should not be deducted. Of
course, the gift will then be double-counted to the extent that it gives rise to consumption by the recipient. However,
this may be reasonable in that the gift gave rise to two acts of consumption. This issue need not concern us here
since precisely the same problem arises under consumption taxation as under income taxation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e412a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e419" publication-type="other">
It should be noted that the choice between an income tax and a personal consumption tax revolves around the
base only. In principle, virtually any degree of progressivity can be attained for a given base by the choice of a
suitable rate structure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d29e441a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e445" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. B. (1985), 'Precautionary saving and accidental bequests', American Economic Review, vol.
75, pp. 777-91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e455a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e459" publication-type="other">
Altig, D. and Davis, S. J. ( 1992), 'The timing of intergenerational transfers, tax policy, and aggregate
savings', American Economic Review, vol. 82, pp. 1199-220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e469a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e473" publication-type="other">
Altonji, J. G., Hayashi, F. and Kotlikoff, L. J. (1992), 'Is the extended family altruistically linked?
Direct tests using microdata', American Economic Review, vol. 82, pp. 1177-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e483a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e487" publication-type="other">
Alvarez, Y., Burbidge, J., Ferrall, T. and Palmer, L. (1992), 'Optimal taxation in a life-cycle model',
Canadian Journal of Economics, vol. 25, pp. 111-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e498a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e502" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. B. and Stiglitz, J. E. (1976), 'The design of the tax structure: direct versus indirect
taxation', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 6, pp. 55-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e512a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e516" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. J. and Kotlikoff, L. J. ( 1987), Dynamic Fiscal Policy, Cambridge: Cambridge University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e526a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e530" publication-type="other">
—, — and Skinner, J. (1983), 'The efficiency gains from dynamic tax reform', International Economic
Review, vol. 24, pp. 81-100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e540a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e544" publication-type="other">
Banks, J. and Blundell, R. (1992), 'Taxation and personal saving incentives in the U.K.', unpublished.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e551a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e555" publication-type="other">
— and — (n.d ), 'Household saving behaviour in the UK', unpublished.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e562a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e566" publication-type="other">
Barro,R. J. (1974), 'Are government bonds net wealthT, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 82, pp.
1095-117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e577a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e581" publication-type="other">
Barsky, R. B., Mankiw, N. G. and Zeldes, S. P. (1986), 'Ricardian consumers with Keynesian
propensities', American Economic Review, vol. 76, pp. 676-91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e591a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e595" publication-type="other">
Beach, C. M., Boadway, R. W. and Bruce, N. (1988), Taxation and Savings in Canada, Ottawa:
Minister of Supply and Services Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e605a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e609" publication-type="other">
—, — and Gibbons, J. O. (1984), 'Social security and aggregate wealth accumulation revisited:
dynamic simultaneous estimates in a wealth-generation model', Economic Inquiry, vol. 22, pp.
68-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e622a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e626" publication-type="other">
Bernheim, B. D. (1987), 'Dissaving after retirement: testing the pure life cycle hypothesis', in Z.
Bodie, J. B. Shoven and D. A. Wise (eds), Issues in Pension Economics, Chicago: University of
Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e639a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e643" publication-type="other">
— (1991), 'How strong are bequest motives? Evidence based on estimates of the demand for life
insurance and annuities', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 99, pp. 899-927.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e653a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e657" publication-type="other">
—andBagwell, K. (1988), 'Is everything neutral?', Journal ofPolitical Economy, vol. 96, pp. 308-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e665a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e669" publication-type="other">
—, Shleifer, A. and Summers, L. H. (1985), 'The strategic bequest motive', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 93, pp. 1045-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e679a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e683" publication-type="other">
— and Shoven, J. B. (1988), 'Pension funding and saving', in Z. Bodie, J. B. Shoven and D. A. Wise
(eds), Pensions in the US Economy, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e693a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e697" publication-type="other">
Blinder, A. S. and Deaton, A. (1985), 'The time series consumption function revisited', Brookings
Papers on Economic Activity, pp. 465-511.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e707a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e711" publication-type="other">
Boadway, R. W. and Bruce, N. (1992), 'Problems with integrating corporate and personal income
taxes in an open economy', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 48, pp. 39-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e721a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e725" publication-type="other">
— and Wildasin, D. E. (1993), 'Long-term debt strategy: a survey', in F. van Winden and H. A. A.
Verbon (eds), The Political Economy of Government Debt, Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e735a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e739" publication-type="other">
Boskin, M. J. (1978), 'Taxation, saving, and the rate of interest', Journal of Political Economy, vol.
86, pp. S3-S27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e750a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e754" publication-type="other">
Bosworth, B., Burtless, G. and Sabelhaus, J. ( 1991 ), 'The decline in savings: evidence from household
surveys', Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, pp. 183-256.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e764a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e768" publication-type="other">
Carroll, C. and Summers, L. H. (1987), 'Why have private savings rates in the United States and
Canada diverged?', Journal of Monetary Economics, vol. 20, pp. 249-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e778a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e782" publication-type="other">
Chamley, C. P. (1986), 'Optimal taxation of capital income in general equilibrium with infinité lives',
Econometrica, vol. 54, pp. 607-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e792a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e796" publication-type="other">
Cox, D. W. (1990), 'Intergenerational transfers and liquidity constraints', Quarterly Journal of
Economics, vol. 105, pp. 187-218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e806a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e810" publication-type="other">
— and Japelli, T. (1990), 'Credit rationing and private transfers: evidence from survey data\ Review
of Economics and Statistics, vol. 72, pp. 445-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e820a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e824" publication-type="other">
Davies, J. B. and St.-Hilaire, F. (1987), Reforming Capital Income Taxation in Canada, Ottawa:
Minister of Supply and Services Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e835a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e839" publication-type="other">
Diamond, P. A. ( 1977), 'A framework for social security analysis', Journal of Public Economics, vol.
8, pp. 275-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e849a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e853" publication-type="other">
— and Hausman, J. A. (1984), 'Individual retirement and savings behavior', Journal of Public
Economics, vol. 23, pp. 81-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e863a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e867" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A., Disney, R., Johnson, P. and Whitehouse, E. (1994), Pensions Policy in the UK: An
Economic Analysis, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e877a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e881" publication-type="other">
Economic Council of Canada (1987), Road Map for Tax Reform, Ottawa: Minister of Supply and
Services Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e891a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e895" publication-type="other">
Edwards, J., Keen, M. and Tuomala, M. (1992), 'Pareto efficiency, mixed taxation and the provision
of public goods', mimeo, University of Essex; also Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper
no. 93/10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e908a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e912" publication-type="other">
Feldstein, M. S. (1974), 'Social security, induced retirement and aggregate capital accumulation',
Journal of Political Economy, vol. 82, pp. 905-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e923a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e927" publication-type="other">
— ( 1977), ' Does the United States save too little? ', American Economic Review, vol. 67, pp. 162-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e934a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e938" publication-type="other">
Fischer, S. (1980), 'Dynamic inconsistency, cooperation and the benevolent dissembling
government', Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control, vol. 2, pp. 93-107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e948a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e952" publication-type="other">
Friedman, B. M. and Warshawsky, M. (1989), 'The cost of annuities: implications for savings behavior
and bequests', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 105, pp. 135-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e962a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e966" publication-type="other">
Gahvari, F. (1984), 'Incidence and efficiency aspects of differential taxation of residential and
industrial capital in a growing economy', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 25, pp. 211-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e976a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e980" publication-type="other">
Gravelle, J. G. (1991), 'Do individual retirement accounts increase savings?', Journal of Economic
Perspectives, vol. 5, pp. 133-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e994" publication-type="other">
Guiso, L., Japelli, T. and Terlizzese, D. (1992), 'Earnings uncertainty and precautionary saving',
Journal of Monetary Economics, vol. 30, pp. 307-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1005a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1009" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. E. (1978), 'Stochastic implications of the life cycle-permanent income hypothesis: theory
and evidence', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 86, pp. 971-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1019a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1023" publication-type="other">
— (1988), 'Intertemporal substitution in consumption', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 96, pp.
339-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1033a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1037" publication-type="other">
— and Mishkin, F. S. (1982), 'The sensitivity of consumption to transitory income: estimates from
panel data on households', Econometrica, vol. 50, pp. 461-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1047a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1051" publication-type="other">
Harberger, A. C. (1964), 'Taxation, resource allocation, and welfare', in J. Due (ed.), The Role of
Direct and Indirect Taxes in the Federal Revenue System, Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1061a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1065" publication-type="other">
Hayashi, F. (1985), 'The effect of liquidity constraints on consumption: a cross-sectional analysis',
Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 100, pp. 183-206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1075a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1079" publication-type="other">
Heady,C. (1993), 'Optimal taxation asaguide to policy: a survey', Fiscal Studies, vol. 14,no. l,pp.
14—41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1090a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1094" publication-type="other">
Howrey, E. P. and Hymans, S. H. (1978), 'The measurement and determination of loanable-funds
savings', Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, pp. 655-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1104a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1108" publication-type="other">
Hubbard, R. G. and Judd, K. L. (1987), 'Social security and individual welfare: precautionary saving,
liquidity constraints, and the payroll tax', American Economic Review, vol. 77, pp. 630-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1118a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1122" publication-type="other">
Hurd, M. D. (1992), 'Wealth depletion and life-cycle consumption by the elderly', in D. A. Wise (ed.),
Topics in the Economics of Aging, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1132a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1136" publication-type="other">
Japelli, T. ( 1990), 'Who is credit-constrained in the US economy?', Quarterly Journal of Economics,
vol. 105, pp. 219-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1146a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1150" publication-type="other">
— and Pagano, M. (1989), 'Consumption and capital market imperfections', American Economic
Review, vol. 79, pp. 1089-105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1160a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1164" publication-type="other">
Kaldor, N. (1955),/!» Expenditure Tax, London: Allen and Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1176" publication-type="other">
King, M. A. ( 1980), ' Savings and taxation', in G. M. Heal and G. A. Hughes (eds), Public Policy and
the Tax System, London: Allen and Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1190" publication-type="other">
— and Dicks-Mireaux, L.-D. L. (1982), 'Asset holdings and the life-cycle', Economic Journal, vol.
92, pp. 247-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1200a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1204" publication-type="other">
Kotlikoff, L. J. (1988), 'Intergenerational transfers and savings', Journal of Economic Perspectives,
vol. 2, pp. 41-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1218" publication-type="other">
— ( 1992), Generational Accounting, New York: Free Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1225a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1229" publication-type="other">
— and Summers, L. H. (1981), 'The role of intergenerational transfers in aggregate capital
accumulation ', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 89, pp. 706-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1239a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1243" publication-type="other">
Leimer, D. R. andLesnoy, S. D. (1982), 'Social security and private saving: new time-series evidence',
Journal of Political Economy, vol. 90, pp. 606-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1254a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1258" publication-type="other">
Lord, W. (1989), 'The transition from payroll to consumption receipts with endogenous human
capital', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 38, pp. 53-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1268a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1272" publication-type="other">
Manchester, J. M. and Poterba, J. M. (1989), 'Second mortgages and household savings', Regional
Science and Urban Economics, vol. 19, pp. 325—46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1282a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1286" publication-type="other">
Mankiw, N. G., Rotemberg, J. J. and Summers, L. H. (1985), 'Intertemporal substitution in
macroeconomics', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 100, pp. 225-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1296a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1300" publication-type="other">
Mariger, R. P. (1986), Consumption Behavior and the Effects of Government Fiscal Policies,
Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1310a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1314" publication-type="other">
Meade, J. E. (1978), The Structure and Reform of Direct Taxation: Report of a Committee Chaired
by Professor J. E. Meade, London: George Allen and Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1324a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1328" publication-type="other">
Menchik, P. L. (1988), 'Unequal estate division: is it altruism, reverse bequest, or simply noise?', in
D. Kessler and A. Masson(eds),Modelling the Accumulation and Distribution ofWealth, Oxford:
Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1342a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1346" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F. ( 1988), 'The role of intergenerational transfers and life cycle saving in the accumulation
of wealth', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 2, pp. 1540.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1356a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1360" publication-type="other">
Papke, L. E., Petersen, M. and Poterba, J. M. (1993), 'Did 401(k) plans replace other employer
provided pensions? ', National Bureau of Economic Research, Working Paper no. 4501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1370a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1374" publication-type="other">
Poterba, J. M. (1987), 'Tax policy and corporate saving', Brookings Papers on Economic Activity,
pp. 455-503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1384a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1388" publication-type="other">
—, Venti, S. F. and Wise, D. A. (1993), 'Do 401(k) contributions crowd out other personal saving?',
National Bureau of Economic Research, Working Paper no. 4391.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1398a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1402" publication-type="other">
Rogers, C. A. (1987), 'Expenditure taxes, income taxes and time-inconsistency', Journal of Public
Economics, vol. 32, pp. 215-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1412a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1416" publication-type="other">
Romer, P. M. (1986), 'Increasing returns and long-run growth', Journal of Political Economy, vol.
94, pp. 1002-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1427a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1431" publication-type="other">
Sen, A. K. (1967), 'Isolation, assurance and the social rate of discount', Quarterly Journal of
Economics, vol. 81, pp. 112-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1441a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1445" publication-type="other">
Skinner, J. (1989), 'Housing wealth and aggregate saving', Regional Science and Urban Economics,
vol. 19, pp. 305-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1455a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1459" publication-type="other">
Sorensen, P. B. (1994), 'From the global income tax to the dual income tax: recent tax reforms in the
Nordic countries', International Tax and Public Finance, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1469a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1473" publication-type="other">
Starrett, D. (1972), 'On golden rules, the "biological theory of interest", and competitive
inefficiency ', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 80, pp. 276-91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1483a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1487" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J. E. (1987), 'Pareto efficient and optimal taxation and the new new welfare economics', in
A. J. Auerbach and M. Feldstein (eds), Handbook of Public Economics, vol. 2, Amsterdam:
North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1500a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1504" publication-type="other">
Summers, L. H. (1981), 'Capital taxation and accumulation in a life cycle growth model', American
Economic Review, vol. 71, pp. 533-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1515a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1519" publication-type="other">
Tomes, N. (1988), 'Inheritance and inequality within the family: equal division among unequals, or
do the poor get more?', in D. Kessler and A. Masson (eds), Modelling the Accumulation and
Distribution of Wealth, Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1532a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1536" publication-type="other">
US Treasury ( 1977), Blueprints for Basic Tax Reform, Washington DC: Government Printing Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1543a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1547" publication-type="other">
Venti, S. F. and Wise, D. A. (1990), 'But they don't want to reduce housing equity', in D. A. Wise
(ed.), Issues in the Economics of Aging, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1557a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1561" publication-type="other">
— and — ( 1992), 'Government policy and personal retirement saving', Tax Policy and the Economy,
vol. 6, pp. 1-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1571a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1575" publication-type="other">
Wilcox, D. W. (1989), 'Social security benefits, consumption expenditure, and the life-cycle
hypothesis', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 97, pp. 288-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1585a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1589" publication-type="other">
Zeldes, S. P. (1989a), 'Optimal consumption with stochastic income', Quarterly Journal of
Economics, vol. 104, pp. 275-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1600a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1604" publication-type="other">
— (1989b), 'Consumption and liquidity constraints: an empirical investigation', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 97, pp. 305-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
