<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023229</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Volatility</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Consumption Taxes, Income Taxes, and Revenue Stability</article-title>
            <subtitle>States and the Great Recession</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Chernick</surname>
                  <given-names>Howard</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Reimers</surname>
                  <given-names>Cordelia</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Hunter College, City University of New York</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>48</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023229"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper translates state reliance on income versus consumption taxes into tax burdens by income slice and uses those burdens, together with changes in Adjusted Gross Income by income slice, to explain state tax revenue changes during the Great Recession. We find that more unequal income distributions increased tax base volatility, but greater base volatility did not systematically translate into more volatile tax revenues. While regressivity is decreased in states with higher income tax shares, and increased where there are higher consumption tax shares, simulation results from imposing national average income and consumption tax shares challenge the conventional wisdom that consumption taxes are more stable than income taxes. Volatility would have been <italic>greater </italic> in high income tax share states, and <italic>lower </italic> in high consumption share states, if they had more balanced tax structures. The <italic>interaction </italic> between tax burdens and base volatility by income slice is key to these surprising results.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chernick, Howard and Andrew Reschovsky. 1997. “Who Pays the Gasoline Tax?” National Tax Journal 50: 233-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chernick, Howard, Adam Langley, and Andrew Reschovsky. 2011. “The Impact of the Great Recession and the Housing Crisis on the Financing of America's Largest Cities.” Regional Science and Urban Economics 41:372-381.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chernick, Howard, Cordelia Reimers, and Jennifer Tennant. 2014. “Tax Structure and Revenue Instability: The Great Recession and the States.” IZA Journal of Labor Policy 3(3), February 12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dadayan, Lucy and Donald Boyd. 2009. “State Tax Revenues Show Record Drop, For Second Consecutive Quarter.” State Revenue Report, October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dye, Richard and Therese McGuire. 1991 “Growth and Variability of State Individual Income and General Sales Taxes.” National Tax Journal 44:55-66</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dye, Richard. 2004. “State Revenue Cyclicality.” National Tax Journal 57, March:133-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Holcombe, Randall and Russell Sobel. 1997. Growth and Variability in State Tax Revenue: An Anatomy of State Fiscal Crises. Westport, CT: Greenwood Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Internal Revenue Service, SOI Tax Statistics: Historic Table 2. Available at http://www.irs.gov/uac/SOI-Tax-Stats-Historic-Table-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Institute for Taxation and Economic Policy, 2009. 3<sup>rd</sup> Edition. “Who Pays? A Distributional Analysis of the Tax Systems in All 50 States.” Available at http://www.itepnet.org/state_reports/whopays.php.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kodrzycki,Yolanda. 2014. “Smoothing State Tax Revenues over the Business Cycle: Gauging Fiscal Needs and Opportunities.” Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, Working Paper No. 14-11. Available at http://www.bostonfed.org/economic/wp/wp2014/wp1411.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lurie, Ithai and James Pearce. 2012. “Are Capital Gains Realization Dynamics in the Great Recession Different than the Early 2000’s Recession? A Markov Chain Analysis Using Tax Data.” Office of Tax Analysis, U.S. Department of Treasury, October 24, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matoon, Richard and Leslie McGranahan. 2012. “Revenue Bubbles and Structural Deficits: What’s a State To Do? Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago, Working Paper 2008-15, Revised 2012. Available at http://www.chicagofed.org/digital_assets/publications/working_papers/2008/wp2008_15.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba, James M. 1989. “Lifetime Incidence and the Distributional Burden of Excise Taxes.” American Economic Review 79(2), May:325-330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba, James. M. 1994. “State Responses to Fiscal Crises: The Effects of Budgetary Institutions and Politics.” Journal of Political Economy, 102(4):799-821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saez, Emmanuel. 2012. “Striking it Richer: The Evolution of Top Incomes in the United States (Updated with 2008 estimates).” March. Available at elsa.berkeley.edu/~saez/saez-UStopincomes-2010.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seegert, Nathan. 2012. “Optimal Taxation with Volatility: A Theoretical and Empirical Decomposition.” Unpublished, University of Michigan. Available at http://wwwpersonal.umich.edu/~seegert/papers/OptimalTaxationwithVolatility_Seegert.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tax Foundation. 2013. “Comments on Who Pays: A Distributional Analysis of the Tax Systems in All 50 States.” Available at http://taxfoundation.org/article/comments-who-pays-distributional-analysis-tax-systems-all-50-states. Accessed 13 Jan 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tax Foundation. 2014. “State Individual Income Tax Rates.” Available at http://taxfoundation.org/article/state-individual-income-tax-rates.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Census Bureau, various years. “State Government Tax Collections.” Available at http://www.census.gov/govs/statetax/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
