<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26169166</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling and Experiment Validation of the DC/DC Converter for Online AC Impedance Identification of the Lithium-Ion Battery</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hong</surname>
                  <given-names>Po</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Jiang</surname>
                  <given-names>Hongliang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Jian qiu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Liangfei</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ouyang</surname>
                  <given-names>Minggao</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Tsinghua University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>July 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>6</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26169161</issue-id>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169166"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The lithium-ion battery plays an important role in saving energy and lowering emissions. Many parameters like temperature have an influence on the characteristic of the battery and this phenomenon becomes more serious in an electric vehicle. In this paper, the application of a boost DC/DC converter to the battery system of high power for online AC impedance identification is proposed. The function of the converter is to inject a current excitation signal into the battery at work and the normal output current is drawn by a load. Through analyzing the average state space equations and deriving the small signal model of the converter, the gain function is deduced of the fluctuated current signal against the fluctuated duty cycle which controls the converter. The control algorithm is designed and the system model is verified using Matlab/Simulink with respect to the disturbance current signal generation, the gain function and its variation with frequency range. Then the converter is designed and implemented to conduct the experiment on a power battery of 175Ah and the nominal voltage is 100V. The measured AC impedance of several single cells is presented and it demonstrates the feasibility of applying this DC/DC converter to the practical electric vehicle.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fleischer Christian, Waag Wladislaw, Heyn Hans-Martin, Sauer Dirk Uwe, “On-line adaptive battery impedance parameter and state estimation considering physical principles in reduced order equivalent circuit battery models: Part 1 Requirements, critical review of methods and modeling.” Journal of Power Sources, 260(2014): 276–291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lim KaiChin, Bastawrous Hany Ayad, Duong Van-Huan, See Khay Wai, , “Fading Kalman filtered-based real-time state of charge estimation in LiFePO4 battery-powered electric vehicles.” Applied Energy, 169(2016): 40–48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu Jun, Mi Chunting Chris, Cao Binggang, Cao Junyi, “A new method to estimate the state of charge of lithium-ion batteries based on the battery impedance model.” Journal of Power Sources, 233(2013): 277–284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petit Martin, Prada Eric, Sauvant-Moynot Valérie, “Development of an empirical aging model for Li-ion batteries and application to assess the impact of Vehicle-to-Grid strategies on battery lifetime.” Applied Energy, 172(2016): 398–407.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Waag Wladislaw, Käbitz Stefan, Sauer Dirk Uwe, “Experiment investigation of the lithium-ion battery impedance characteristic at various conditions and aging states and its influence on the application.” Applied Energy, 102(2013): 885–897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raijmakers, L.H.J. Danilov, D.L. van Lammeren, J.P.M. Lammers, M.J.G. , “Sensor-less battery temperature measurements based on electrochemical impedance spectroscopy.” Journal of Power Sources, 247(2014): 539–544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feng Xuning, Sun Jing, Ouyang Minggao, He Xiangming, , “Characterization of large format lithium ion battery exposed to extremely high temperature.” Journal of Power Sources, 272(2014): 457–467.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barsoukov Evgenij and Macdonald J. Ross. Impedance spectroscopy theory, experiment, and applications.New Jersey: Hoboken, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cho Hyung-Man, Choi Woo-Sung, Go Joo-Young, Bae Sang-Eun, , “A study on time-dependent low temperature power performance of a lithium-ion battery.” Journal of Power Sources, 198(2012): 273–280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andre, D. Meiler, M. Steiner, K. Wimmer Ch., , “Characterization of high-power lithium-ion batteries by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy.” Journal of Power Sources, 2011, 196(12): 5334–5341.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beelen, H.P.G.J. Raijmakers, L.H.J. Donkers, M.C.F. Notten, P.H.L. , “A comparison and accuracy analysis of impedance-based temperature estimation methods for li-ion batteries.” Applied Energy, 175(2016): 128–140.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Randles J.E.B., “Kinetics of rapid electrode reactions.” Discuss. Faraday Soc., 1(1947): 111–19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cimenti M., Bessarabov D., Tam M., Stumper J., “Investigation of proton transport in the catalyst layer of PEM fuel cells by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy.” ECS Trans., 28(2010): 147–157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt Jan Philipp, Arnold Stefan, Loges André, Werner Daniel, , “Measurement of the internal cell temperature via impedance: evaluation and application of a new method.” Journal of Power Sources, 243(2013): 110–117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Monem Mohamed Abdel, Trad Khiem, Omar Noshin, Hegazy Omar, , “Lithium-ion battery: evaluation study of different charging methodologies based on aging process.” Applied Energy, 152(2015): 143–155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Waag Wladislaw, Fleischer Christian, Sauer Dirk Uwe, “Online Estimation of lithium-ion battery impedance parameters using a novel varied-parameters approach.” Journal of Power Sources, 237(2013): 260–269.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li J., Jia B., Mazzola M., Xin M., “On-line battery state of charge estimation using Gauss-Hermite quadrature filter.” Proceedings of Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition (APEC), 2012: 434–438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu C., Youn B.D., Chung J., “A multiscale framework with extended Kalman filter for lithium-ion battery SOC and Capacity estimation.” Applied Energy, 92(2012): 694–704.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu X.-s., Sun F.-c., Cheng X.-m., “Recursive calibration for a lithium iron phosphate battery for electric vehicles using extended Kalman filtering.” Journal of Zhejiang University Science A, 12(2012): 818–825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun F., Hu X., Zou Y., Li S., “Adaptive unscented Kalman filtering for state of charge estimation of a lithium-ion battery for electric vehicles.” Energy, 36(2011): 3531–3540.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depernet Daniel, Ba Oumar, Berthon Alain, “Online impedance spectroscopy of lead acid batteries for storage management of a standalone power plant.” Journal of Power Sources, 219(2012): 65–74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitamura, N., Manabe, K., Nonobe, Y., and Kizaki, M., "Development of Water Content Control System for Fuel Cell Hybrid Vehicles Based on AC Impedance," SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1088, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
