<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277917</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Combined Effects of Late IVC and EGR on Low-load Diesel Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sjöblom</surname>
                  <given-names>Jonas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chalmers University of Tech.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>January 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277910</issue-id>
         <fpage>60</fpage>
         <lpage>67</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277917"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The increasing demand for improved efficiency of diesel engines requires more advanced combustion solutions. These solutions include the use of variable valve timings in combination with more traditional methods such as EGR, turbocharging and advanced injection systems. By modifying the characteristics of the charge air, further hardware optimization becomes possible.</p>
            <p>In the current investigation, the effect of late intake valve closing (LIVC) was investigated together with the effect of (external) exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) in a single cylinder heavy duty diesel engine. Different injection timings and injection pressures were investigated. The mass flow of oxygen was kept constant in order to show how the density and temperature of the reactant mixture affect the combustion and emission characteristics.</p>
            <p>The combustion results showed that if the oxygen mass flow is kept constant, an EGR approach is more efficient than LIVC in lowering fuel consumption due to the effects of increased cylinder gas flow which improves fuel conversion efficiency. It was shown that the ignition delay for a fixed combustion phasing was independent of EGR but could be increased by LIVC. The peak pressure was more strongly affected by EGR due to the larger gas flow but this response can be reduced by means of LIVC. After compensating for combustion timing effects, the reduced peak pressure was mainly attributed to reduced effective compression ratio resulting from the LIVC.</p>
            <p>The results show how variable valve timing can be used as one important tool to obtain better combustion characteristics and thus enable more efficient powertrains.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, R., “Supercharged engine”, US Patent US2817322 A, 1957</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CORE, EU-project, GA SCP1-GA-2012-284909, 2011, www. CO2re.eu</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Ideal models of engine cycles”, in “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw-Hill, Singapore, ISBN 0-07-100499-9, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ebrahimi, R., “Performance analysis of an irreversible Miller cycle with considerations of relative air-fuel ratio and stroke length”, Applied Mathematical Modelling, 36(9): 4073-4079, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.apm.2011.11.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatamura, K., Hayakawa M., Goto T. and Hitomi M., “A study of the improvement effect of Miller-cycle on mean effective pressure limit for high-pressure supercharged gasoline engines”, JSAE Review, 18(2): 101-106, 1997, doi:10.1016/S0389- 4304(96)00069-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murata, Y., Nishio Y., Kusaka J., Daisho Y., et al., “Numerical analysis of Miller-premixed charge compression ignition combustion on a dynamic phi-T map”, International Journal of Engine Research, 11(2): 89-98, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Imperato, M., Antila, E., Sarjovaara, T., Kaario, O. et al., “NOX Reduction in a Medium-Speed Single-Cylinder Diesel Engine using Miller Cycle with Very Advanced Valve Timing,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0112, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brijesh, P. and Sreedhara S., “Exhaust emissions and its control methods in compression ignition engines: A review”, International Journal of Automotive Technology, 14(2): 195-206, 2013, doi:10.1007/s12239-013-0022-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ehleskog, M., Gjirja, S., and Denbratt, I., “Effects of Variable Inlet Valve Timing and Swirl Ratio on Combustion and Emissions in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1719, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1719.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, S., Frankle, G., Wirbeleit, F., and Raab, A., “The Potential of a Combined Miller Cycle and Internal EGR Engine for Future Heavy Duty Truck Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 980180, 1998, doi:10.4271/980180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Mallamo, F., and Mego, G., “The Potential of Dual Stage Turbocharging and Miller Cycle for HD Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0221, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Gianoglio Bernardi, M., and Delneri, D., “Computational Analysis of Internal and External EGR Strategies Combined with Miller Cycle Concept for a Two Stage Turbocharged Medium Speed Marine Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1319- 1330, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., Arthozoul, S., and Kolodziej, C., “Particle Size Distribution Measurements from Early to Late Injection Timing Low Temperature Combustion in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):567-581, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Molina S., Martín J. and Novella R., “Effect of advancing the closing angle of the intake valves on diffusioncontrolled combustion in a HD diesel engine”, Applied Thermal Engineering, 29(10): 1947-1954, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2008.09.014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martins, J., Uzuneanu, K., Ribeiro, B., and Jasasky, O., “Thermodynamic Analysis of an Over-Expanded Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0617, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ribeiro, B. and Martins, J., “Direct Comparison of an Engine Working under Otto, Miller and Diesel Cycles: Thermodynamic Analysis and Real Engine Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0261, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heikkilä, J., Happonen M., Murtonen T., Lehto K., et al., “Study of Miller timing on exhaust emissions of a hydrotreated vegetable oil (HVO)-fueled diesel engine”, Journal of the air &amp; waste management association, 62(11): 1305-1312, 2012, doi:10.1080/1 0962247.2012.708383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higuchi, N., Sunaga, Y., Tanaka, M., and Shimada, H., “Development of a New Two-Motor Plug-In Hybrid System,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 2(1):135-145, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, X., Durrett, R., and Sun, Z., “Late Intake Valve Closing as an Emissions Control Strategy at Tier 2 Bin 5 Engine-Out NOx Level,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):427-443, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008- 01-0637.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Doosje, E., Willems, F., Baert, R., and Van Dijk, M., “Experimental Study into a Hybrid PCCI/CI Concept for Next-Generation Heavy- Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1114, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Ojeda, W., “Effect of Variable Valve Timing on Diesel Combustion Characteristics,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1124, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, B., Yu, H., Pak, P., Pei, Y. et al., “Effects of Late Intake Valve Closing Timing on Thermal Efficiency and Emissions Based on a Two-stage Turbocharger Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0276, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Serrano J.R., Molina S. and Novella R., “Potential of Atkinson cycle combined with EGR for pollutant control in a HD diesel engine”, Energy Conversion and Management, 50(1): 174- 183, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2008.08.034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murata, Y., Kusaka, J., Daisho, Y., Kawano, D. et al., “Miller-PCCI Combustion in an HSDI Diesel Engine with VVT,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):444-456, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0644.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Delphi. “Delphi F2e Ultra High Pressure Heavy Duty Diesel Common Rail System”. 2014 [cited 2014 2014-04-23]; F2 common rail system]. Available from: http://delphi.com/manufacturers/cv/powertrain/common-rail-systems/f2-distributedpump- diesel/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Miles P.C. and Pickett L.M., “Conceptual models for partially premixed low-temperature diesel combustion”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 39(2-3): 246-283, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2012.09.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
