<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">accohistjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000849</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Accounting Historians Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Accounting Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01484184</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">44</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40219307</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">45120242</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Influence of Accounting Theory on the FASB Conceptual Framework</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>C. Richard</given-names>
                  <surname>Baker</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>109</fpage>
         <lpage>124</lpage>
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 American Accounting Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/45120242"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>During the first half of the 20th century, "accounting theory" developed primarily by accounting scholars and academics provided the primary basis for the practice and teaching of financial accounting in the United States. Since the creation of the Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB) in the early 1970s, the FASB Conceptual Framework has provided the primary basis for accounting standards-setting, as well as for the practice and teaching of financial accounting. While the purpose of creating a Conceptual Framework has been to develop an agreed-upon set of concepts and principles to guide accounting standards-setting, a related goal has been to reduce diversity in accounting practice and to move toward greater uniformity. This paper traces the influence of accounting theory on the Conceptual Framework and explores some of the consequences of this influence.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d993e141a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e145" publication-type="other">
American Accounting Association (AAA). 1936. A tentative statement of accounting principles underlying corporate reports. The
Accounting Review 11 (20): 187-191.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e155a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e159" publication-type="other">
American Accounting Association (AAA). 1966. A Statement of Basic Accounting Theory. Evanston, IL: American Accounting
Association.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e169a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e173" publication-type="other">
American Institute of Accountants (AIA). 1931. Resume of Special Report of the Accounting Procedures Committee of the American
Institute of Accountants. Manuscript File. New York, NY: AICPA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e183a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e187" publication-type="other">
American Institute of Accountants (AIA). 1934. Audits of Corporate Accounts: Correspondence between the Special Committee on Co-
operation with Stock Exchanges of the American Institute of Accountants and the Committee on Stock List of the New York Stock
Exchange. New York, NY: American Institute of Accountants.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e201a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e205" publication-type="other">
American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA). 1973. Objectives of Financial Statements: Report of the Study Group on the
Objectives of Financial Statements. Trueblood Report. New York, NY: American Institute of Certified Public Accountants Study
Group on the Objectives of Financial Statements.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e218a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e222" publication-type="other">
Biondi, Y. 2013. Accounting, economics, and the law of the enterprise entity: A. C. Littleton and the German-American connection. In
Accounting and Business Economics: Insights from National Traditions, edited by Biondi, Y., and S. Zambón, 363-386. London,
U.K.: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e235a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e239" publication-type="other">
Braeman, J. 1966. The German influence on American education: A review essay. Journal of Higher Education 37 (2): 101-103. doi: 10.
2307/1979349</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e249a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e253" publication-type="other">
Carey, J. L. 1969. The Rise of the Accounting Profession: From Technician to Professional 1896-1936. New York, NY: American
Institute of Certified Public Accountants.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e263a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e267" publication-type="other">
Deegan, C., and J. Unerman. 2006. Financial Accounting Theory. London, U.K.: McGraw-Hill Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e278" publication-type="other">
Douglas, W., and G. Bates. 1933. The Federal Securities Act of 1933. Yale Law Journal 43 (2): 171-217. doi: 10.2307/79 1346</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e290" publication-type="other">
Evans, L. 2005. Accounting history in the German language arena. Accounting Business and Financial History 15 (3): 229-233. doi: 10.
1080/09585200500284146</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e304" publication-type="other">
Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB). 1974. Consideration of the Report of the Study Group on the Objectives of Financial
Statements. Stamford, CT: Financial Accounting Standards Board.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e318" publication-type="other">
Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB). 1976a. Tentative Conclusions on Objectives of Financial Statements of Business
Enterprises. Stamford, CT: Financial Accounting Standards Board.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e332" publication-type="other">
Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB). 1976b. Elements of Financial Statements and Their Measurement. Stamford, CT:
Financial Accounting Standards Board.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e346" publication-type="other">
Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB). 1980. Qualitative Characteristics of Accounting Information. Concepts Statement No. 2.
Stamford, CT: Financial Accounting Standards Board.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e356a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e360" publication-type="other">
Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB). 1985. Statement of Financial Accounting Concepts No. 6, Elements of Financial
Statements: A Replacement of FASB Concepts Statement No. 3 (Incorporating an Amendment of FASB Concepts Statement No. 2).
Norwalk, CT: Financial Accounting Standards Board.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e374a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e378" publication-type="other">
Hatfield, H. R. 1909. Modern Accounting: Its Principles and Some of Its Problems. New York, NY: Appleton.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e385a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e389" publication-type="other">
Heier, J. R. 2006. America's railroad depreciation debate, 1907 to 1913: A study of divergence in early 20th century accounting standards.
Accounting Historians Journal 33 (1): 89-124. doi: 10.2308/0148-4184.33. 1.89</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e403" publication-type="other">
Hines, R. D. 1988. Financial accounting: In communicating reality, we construct reality. Accounting, Organizations and Society 13 (3):
25 1-261. doi:10.1016/0361-3682(88)90003-7</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e417" publication-type="other">
Hommel, M., and S. Schmitz. 2013. Insights on German accounting theory. In Accounting and Business Economics: Insights from
National Traditions, edited by Biondi, Y., and S. Zambón, 331-361. London, U.K.: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e431" publication-type="other">
Kieso, D. E., J. J. Weygandt, and T. D. Warfield. 2013. Intermediate Accounting. 13th edition. New York, NY: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e438a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e442" publication-type="other">
Kuhn, T. A. 1970. The Structure of Scientific Revolutions. 2nd edition. Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e454" publication-type="other">
Littleton, A. C. 1929. Price and value in accounting. The Accounting Review 4: 149-159.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e461a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e465" publication-type="other">
Mattessich, R., and H. Küpper. 2003. Accounting research in the German language area -First half of the 20th century. Review of
Accounting and Finance 2 (3): 106-137. doi:10.1108/eb027015</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e475a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e479" publication-type="other">
Moonitz, M. 1961. The Basic Postulates of Accounting. Accounting Research Study No. 1. New York, NY: American Institute of Certified
Public Accountants.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e493" publication-type="other">
Napier, C. 2013. Accounting and the absence of a business economics tradition in the United Kingdom. In Accounting and Business
Economics: Insights from National Traditions, edited by Biondi, Y., and S. Zambón, 273-305. London, U.K.: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e503a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e507" publication-type="other">
Parrish, M. E. 1970. Securities Regulation and the New Deal. New Haven, CT: Yale University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e514a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e518" publication-type="other">
Patón, W. A. 1922. Accounting Theory: With Special Reference to the Corporate Enterprise. New York, NY: The Ronald Press
Company.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e529a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e533" publication-type="other">
Patón, W. A., and A. C. Littleton. 1940. An Introduction to Corporate Accounting Standards. Urbana, IL: American Accountmg
Association.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e543a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e547" publication-type="other">
Previts, G. J., and B. D. Merino. 1998. A History of Accountancy in the United States: The Cultural Significance of Accounting.
Columbus, OH: Ohio State University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e557a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e561" publication-type="other">
Richard, J. 2005. The concept of fair value in French and German accounting regulations from 1673 to 1914 and its consequences for the
interpretation of the stages of development of capitalist accounting. Critical Perspectives on Accounting 16 (6): 825-850. doi: 10.
101 6/j.cpa.2003. 06.008</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e574a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e578" publication-type="other">
Sanders, T., H. R. Hatfield, and U. Moore. 1938. A Statement of Accounting Principles. New York, NY: American Institute of
Accountants.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e588a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e592" publication-type="other">
Schmalenbach, E. 1919. Grundlagen der dynamischen Bilanztheorie. (Foundations of dynamic accounting). Zeitschrift für
handelswissenschaftliche. Forschung 13: 1-101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e602a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e606" publication-type="other">
Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). 2003. Study Pursuant to Section 108(d) of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 on the Adoption
by the United States Financial Reporting System of a Principles-Based Accounting System. Washington, DC: United States
Securities and Exchange Commission.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e620a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e624" publication-type="other">
Sprague, C. 1880. The algebra of accounts. Book-Keeper (July 20): 2-4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e631a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e635" publication-type="other">
Sprague, C. 1908. The Philosophy of Accounts. New York, NY: Sprague.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e642a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e646" publication-type="other">
Sprouse, R. T., and M. Moonitz. 1962. A Tentative Set of Broad Accounting Principles for Business Enterprises. Accounting Research
Study No. 3. New York, NY: American Institute of Certified Public Accountants.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e656a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e660" publication-type="other">
Walton, S. 1909. Earnings and mcome. Journal of Accountancy 9 (2): 452-469.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e667a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e671" publication-type="other">
Zeff, S. A. 1984. Some junctures in the evolution of the process of establishing accounting principles in the U.S.A.: 1917-1972. The
Accounting Review 59 (3): 447-468.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d993e681a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d993e685" publication-type="other">
Zeff, S. A. 1999. The evolution of the conceptual framework for business enterprises in the United States. Accounting Historians Journal
26 (2): 89-131. doi: 10.2308/01484184.26.2.89</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


