<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278030</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Operating Parameters on Soot Emissions in GDI Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jiao</surname>
                  <given-names>Qi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1322</fpage>
         <lpage>1333</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278030"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Due to the upcoming regulations for particulate matter (PM) emissions from GDI engines, a computational fluid dynamic (CFD) modeling study to predict soot emissions (both mass and solid particle number) from gasoline direct injection (GDI) engines was undertaken to provide insights on how and why soot emissions are formed from GDI engines. In this way, better methods may be developed to control or reduce PM emissions from GDI engines. In this paper, the influence of engine operating parameters was examined for a side-mounted fuel injector configuration in a direct-injection spark-ignition (DISI) engine. The present models are able to reasonably predict the influences of the variables of interest compared to available experimental data or literature. For a late injection strategy, effects of the fuel composition, and spray cone angle were investigated with a single-hole injector. For an early injection strategy, the effects of multi-component fuel surrogates for gasoline, SOI timings and wall temperatures were studied with a six-hole injector. The investigations confirmed the necessity to consider the multi-component fuel composition and also demonstrate how and why wall films significantly contribute to soot emissions from DISI engines.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CARB, Preliminary Discussion Paper - Proposed Amendments to California's Low-emission Vehicle Regulations - Particulate Matter Mass, Ultrafine Solid Particle Number, and Black Carbon Emissions., in California Air Resources Board2010: Sacramento, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., Lai, M. C., Harrington, D. L., Automotive Spark-Ignited Direct-Injection Gasoline Engines. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 1999. 25(5): p. 437-562.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B., Engines and Nanoparticles: A Review. Journal of Aerosol Science, 1998. 29(5-6): p. 575-588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eastwood, P., Particulate Emissions from Vehicles. 2008: Wiley- PEPublishing SeriesJohn Wiley and Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Myung, C.L., Park, S., Exhaust Nanoparticle Emissions from Internal Combustion Engines: A Review. International Journal of Automotive Technology, 2012. 13(1): p. 9-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mathis, U., Kaegi, R., Mohr, M., Zenobi, R., TEM Analysis of Volatile Nanoparticles from Particle Trap Equipped Diesel and Direct-Injection Spark-Ignition Vehicles. Atmospheric Environment, 2004. 38(26): p. 4347-4355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdul-Khalek, I., Kittelson, D., Graskow, B., Wei, Q. et al., “Diesel Exhaust Particle Size: Measurement Issues and Trends,” SAE Technical Paper 980525, 1998, doi:10.4271/980525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdul-Khalek, I., Kittelson, D., and Brear, F., “The Influence of Dilution Conditions on Diesel Exhaust Particle Size Distribution Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1142, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kong, S.-C., Drop/Wall Interaction Criteria and Their Applications in Diesel Spray Modeling. Atomization and Sprays, 2007. 17(6): p. 473-499.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lippert, A.M., Modeling of Multi-component Fuels with Application to Sprays and Simulation of Diesel Engne Cold Start, 1999, University of Wisconsin-Madison.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drake, M., Fansler, T., Solomon, A., and Szekely, G., “Piston Fuel Films as a Source of Smoke and Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Wall- Controlled Spark-Ignited Direct-Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0547, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Svensson, K.I., Effects of Fuel Molecular Structure and Composition on Soot Formation in Direct-Injection Spray Flames., in Mechanical Engineering, 2005, Brigham Young University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., Harrington, D., and Lai, M-C., “Automotive Gasoline Direct- Injection Engines,” (Warrendale, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc., 2002), doi:10.4271/R-315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nogi, T., Shiraishi, T., Nakayama, Y., Ohsuga, M. et al., “Stability Improvement of Direct Fuel Injection Engine under Lean Combustion Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 982703, 1998, doi:10.4271/982703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., Yi, J., and Trigui, N., “Stratified Mixture Formation and Piston Surface Wetting in a DISI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2655, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., Reitz, R., Yang, J., and Anderson, R., “Effects of Injection Timing on Air-Fuel Mixing in a Direct-Injection Spark-Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 970625, 1997, doi:10.4271/970625.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maricq, M., Podsiadlik, D., Brehob, D., and Haghgooie, M., “Particulate Emissions from a Direct-Injection Spark-Ignition (DISI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1530, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seong, H., Lee, K., and Choi, S., “Effects of Engine Operating Parameters on Morphology of Particulates from a Gasoline Direct Injection (GDI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2574, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2574.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oh, H., Bae, C., Effects of the Injection Timing on Spray and Combustion Characteristics in a Spray-guided DISI Engine under Leanstratified Operation. Fuel, 2013. 107: p. 225-235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farron, C., Matthias, N., Foster, D., Andrie, M. et al., “Particulate Characteristics for Varying Engine Operation in a Gasoline Spark Ignited, Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1220, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iiyama, A., et al., Attainment of High Power with Low Fuel Consumption and Exhaust Emisssions in a Direct-Injection Gasoline Engine. 1998 FISITA Technical Paper No. F98T048, 1998b.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iiyama, A., et al., Realization of High Power and Low Fuel Consumption with Low Fuel Consumption with Low Exhaust Emissions in a Direct- Injection Gasoline Engine. Proceedings of GPC'98, Advanced Engine Design and Performance, 1998a: p. 76-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, J., Munoz, R., Anderson, R., and Lavoie, G., “Study of a Stratified-Charge DISI Engine with an Air-Forced Fuel Injection System,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2901, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000- 01-2901.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, F., Schmidt, J., Kufferath, A., and Samenfink, W., “Gasoline Wall Films and Spray/Wall Interaction Analyzed by Infrared Thermography,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):1165-1177, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiao, Q., Soot Formation in GDI/GTDI Engines, 2014, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Ph.D. Dissertation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiao, Q. and Reitz, R., “Modeling of Equivalence Ratio Effects on Particulate Formation in a Spark-Ignition Engine under Premixed Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1607, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale, J.C., Reitz, R. D., Modeling Spray Atomization with the Kelvin- Helmholtz/Rayleigh-Taylor Hybrid Model. Atomization and Spray, 1999. 9: p. 623-650.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abani, N., Munnannur, A., Reitz, R. D., Reduction of Numerical Parameter Dependencies in Diesel Spray Models. Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 2008. 130(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P.J., Collective Drop Effects on Vaporizing Liquid Sprays, 1981: PhD, Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., Reitz, R. D., A Vaporization Model for Discrete Multi-component Fuel Sprays. International Journal of Multiphase Flow, 2009. 35: p. 101-117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., Reitz, R.D., Turbulent Modeling of Internal Combustion Engines Using RNG k-eps Model. Comb. Sci. Tech, 1995. 106: p. 267-295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, B.L., Lee, C. W., Reitz, R. D., Miles, P. C., Han, Z., A Generalized RNG Turbulent Model and its Application to a Light-duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Low Temperature Combustion Regime. International Journal of Engine Research, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P. and Amsden, A., “A Particle Numerical Model for Wall Film Dynamics in Port-Injected Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 961961, 1996, doi:10.4271/961961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P. and Amsden, A., “A Spray/Wall Interaction Submodel for the KIVA-3 Wall Film Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0271, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vishwanathan, G., Reitz, R. D., Development of a Practial Soot Modeling Approach and Its Application to Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion. Combustion Science and Technology, 2010. 182: p. 1050-1082.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fan, L. and Reitz, R., “Development of an Ignition and Combustion Model for Spark-Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2809, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tan, Z., Kong, S., and Reitz, R., “Modeling Premixed and Direct Injection SI Engine Combustion Using the G-Equation Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1843, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L. and Reitz, R., “Spark Ignition Engine Combustion Modeling Using a Level Set Method with Detailed Chemistry,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0243, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perini, F., Galligani, E., Reitz, R. D., An Analytical Jacobian Approach to Sparse Reaction Kinetics for Computationally Efficient Combustion Modeling with Large Reaction Mechanisms. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2012. 26(8): p. 4804-4822.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H., Jiao, Q., Yao, M. F., Yao, B. B., Qiu, L., Reitz, R. D., Development of an N-heptane/Toluene/Polyaromatic Hydrocarbon Mechanism and its Application and Soot Prediction. International Journal of Engine Research, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VanDerWege, B., Yi, J., Personal communication: Experimental data for Ford DISI/GTDI engines at varied conditions, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., Reitz, R. D., A Combustion Model for IC Engine Combustion Simulations with Multi-component Fuels. Combustion and Flame, 2011. 158(1): p. 69-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, S., Ra, Y., Reitz, R. D., VanDerWege, B., Yi, J., Integration of a Discrete Multi-component Fuel Evaporation Model with a G-equation Flame Propagation Combustion Model and its Validation. International J. of Engine Research, 2012. 13(4): p. 370-384.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, X., Ra, Y., and Reitz, R., “A Surrogate Fuel Formulation Approach for Real Transportation Fuels with Application to Multi-Dimensional Engine Simulations,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(1):236-249, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiao, Q., Ra, Y., and Reitz, R., “Modeling the Influence of Molecular Interactions on the Vaporization of Multi-component Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0387, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0387.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiao, Q., Reitz, R. D., Modeling Soot Emissions from Wall Films in a DISI Engine. International Journal of Engine Research, DOI:10.1177/1468087414562008, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takagi, Y., Itoh, T., Muranaka, S., Iiyama, A. et al., “Simultaneous Attainment of Low Fuel Consumption High Output Power and Low Exhaust Emissions in Direct Injection SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 980149, 1998, doi:10.4271/980149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Syzbist, J.P., Youngquist, A. D., Barone, T. L., Storey, J. M., Moore, W. R., Foster, M., Confer, K., Ethanol Blends and Engine Operating Strategy Effects on Light-Duty Spark-Ignition Engine Particle Emissions. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2011. 25: p. 4977-4985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whitaker, P., Kapus, P., Ogris, M., and Hollerer, P., “Measures to Reduce Particulate Emissions from Gasoline DI engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1498-1512, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, D. and Lee, C., “Continuous Multicomponent Fuel Film Vaporization Model for Multidimensional Engine Modeling,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0209, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
