<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169126</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Powerpack Optimal Design Methodology with Embedded Configuration Benchmarking</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ivanco</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrej</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson-ICAR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhou</surname>
                  <given-names>Kan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hofmann</surname>
                  <given-names>Heath</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Filipi</surname>
                  <given-names>Zoran S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson-ICAR</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>July 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169125</issue-id>
         <fpage>223</fpage>
         <lpage>227</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169126"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Design of military vehicle needs to meet often conflicting requirements such as high mobility, excellent fuel efficiency and survivability, with acceptable cost. In order to reduce the development cost, time and associated risk, as many of the design questions as possible need to be addressed with advanced simulation tools. This paper describes a methodology to design a fuel efficient powerpack unit for a series hybrid electric military vehicle, with emphasis on the e-machine design. The proposed methodology builds on previously published Finite element based analysis to capture basic design features of the generator with three variables, and couples it with a model reduction technique to rapidly re-design the generator with desired fidelity. The generator is mated to an off the shelf engine to form a powerpack, which is subsequently evaluated over a representative military drive cycles. An iterative procedure is developed, in which the optimization of the supervisory controller is embedded into the design optimization framework. Therefore, for every combination of design parameters the Dynamic Programming routine develops a benchmark control for minimum fuel consumption. This ensures realistic numbers for every function call, and convergence on a true optimum. Results can then guide the development of the new generator for a selected production engine and SHEV configuration.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ebbesen, S., Dönitz C., and Guzzella L., Particle swarm optimisation for hybrid electric drive-train sizing. International Journal of Vehicle Design, 2012. 58(2): p. 181-199.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buerger, S., Lohmann B., Merz M., Vogel-Heuser B., and Hallmannsegger M.. Multi-objective optimization of hybrid electric vehicles considering fuel consumption and dynamic performance. in Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference (VPPC), 2010 IEEE. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murgovski, N., Johannesson L., Sjöberg J., and Egardt B., Component sizing of a plug-in hybrid electric powertrain via convex optimization. Mechatronics, 2012. 22(1): p. 106-120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tate, E., Harpster, M., and Savagian, P., "The Electrification of the Automobile: From Conventional Hybrid, to Plug-in Hybrids, to Extended-Range Electric Vehicles," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Electron. Electr. Syst. 1(1):156-166, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundstrom, O., Guzzella L., and Soltic P.. Optimal Hybridization in Two Parallel Hybrid Electric Vehicles using Dynamic Programming. in 17th IFAC World Congress. 2008. Seoul, Korea.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, K., Ivanco A., Filipi Z., and Hofmann H., Finite-Element-Based Computationally-Efficient Scalable Electric Machine Model Suitable for Electrified Powertrain Simulation and Optimization. Industry Applications, IEEE Transactions on industry applications, 2015. PP(99): p. 1-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou, K., Pries J., Hofmann H., Youngki K., Lee T.-K., and Filipi Z.. Computationally-efficient finite-element-based thermal models of electric machines. in Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference (VPPC), 2011 IEEE. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wipke, K.B., Cuddy M.R., and Burch S.D., ADVISOR 2.1: A User-Friendly Advanced Powertrain Simulation Using a Combined Backward/Forward Approach. IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Systems Technology, 1999. 48(6): p. 1751-1761.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ivanco, A., Zhou, K., Hofmann, H., and Filipi, Z., "A Framework for Optimization of the Traction Motor Design Based on the Series-HEV System Level Goals," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1801, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1801.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundstrom, O. and Guzzella L., A Generic Dynamic Programming Matlab Function, in 18th IEEE International Conference on Control Applications. 2009: Saint Petersburg, Russia. p. 1625-1630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ivanco, A. and Filipi Z., Framework for Powerpack Optimization in the SHEV. Two stage optimization for best efficiency in the hybrid electric vehicle powertrain design, in IEEE VPPC. 2015: Montreal, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
