<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308255</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Spray Hot-impingement System Optimization for Premixed Diesel Homogeneous Charge Preparation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hu</surname>
                  <given-names>Zongjie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>School of Automotive Studies, Tongji University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wu</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhijun</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>School of Automotive Studies, Tongji University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Liguang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>School of Automotive Studies, Tongji University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gao</surname>
                  <given-names>Guanghai</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>SAIC Motor Passenger Vehicle Cooperation</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>10</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308255"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In this study, a spray hot-impingement system was set up to analyze the spray characteristics when spray impinged onto a flat hot surface by high-speed photography technology. The angle between spray axis and normal line of the flat surface could be changed, and the surface temperature could exceed 400°C. The influences of surface temperature and heating power on spray atomization were investigated too. At atmospheric pressure, when the wall temperature was 340~380°C, the impinging diesel spray was well atomized. In this experiment, the wall heating power could be set at 1~25 Wcm-2. When the heating power was about 1.6 Wcm-2, the impinging spray atomized well, and when it was about 10.1 Wcm-2 the spray atomized better though the heating power requirement should be high. The angle (α) between nozzle hole axis and wall normal line apparently affected wall jet velocity</p>
            <p>Then a segment of steel tube was fixed between the intake manifold and cylinder head in a direct injection natural aspirated diesel engine. The tube wall could be heated to be over 400°C by the heater enwrapped outside. Diesel sprays would impinge onto the hot inner surface of the tube and atomize quickly when the tube wall temperature was high enough. Then the fuel-air mixture would be drawn into the cylinder in intake stroke, and HCCI combustion could be fulfilled. The tube, heater, and injector constituted a spray hot-impingement system used on engines. And a new method for diesel homogeneous charge preparation was realized.</p>
            <p>Based on charge homogeneity and inducted fuel ratio, the nozzle hole number and α were optimized through comparison of 5 nozzle cases for premixed diesel homogeneous charge preparation by spray hot-impingement at intake manifold. The charge homogeneity was estimated by engine NO<sub>X</sub>emission and exhaust opacity. When α=15°, the hole number increase would reduce the exhaust opacity, but could not effectively increase the inducted fuel ratio. But when α=45°, it would effectively increase the inducted fuel ratio, whereas could not reduce the exhaust opacity. And NO<sub>X</sub>emission would decrease when hole number increased. If α decreases, the inducted fuel ratio could be enhanced, but there was a best α for NO<sub>X</sub>and exhaust opacity. For the 5 nozzle cases, the nozzle with 6 holes and α=30° was the optimized case.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuquan (Frank) Zhao, Thomas W. Asmus and Dennis N. Assanis et al. “Homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engines: key research and development issues” [M], Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc. U.S.A. 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rudolf H. Stanglmaier and Charles E. Roberts, “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI): enefits, Compromises, and Future Engine Applications”, AE Paper 1999-01-3682</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen W. Gray Iii and Thomas W. Ryan Iii, “Homogeneous harge Compression Ignition (HCCI) of Diesel Fuel”, SAE aper 971676</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Magnus Christensen, Anders Hultqvist, and Bengt ohansson, “Demonstrating the Multi Fuel Capability of a omogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine with ariable Compression Ratio”, SAE Paper 1999-01-3679</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Arcoumanis and J-C. Chang, ”Flow and Heat Transfer haracteristics of Impinging Transient Diesel Sprays”, AE Paper 940678</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber J. D., Droplet Impingement on Heated Surface, Ph. . Thesis, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 1992</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liguang Li, Yezhou Huang, and Yunyi Gong, “Droplet Size haracteristics of Wall Impinging Diesel Fuel Spray at igh Injection Pressure”, Transactions of CSICE, Vol. 14, o. 2, pp. 119-126, 1996</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liguang Li, Zongjie Hu, Guanghai Gao and Guangyu ong, “Homogeneous Charge Preparation of Diesel Fuel y Spray Impingement onto a Hot Surface at Intake anifold”, SAE Paper 2006-01-3322</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber J D and Farrell P V, Hydrodynamics of droplet mpingement on a heated surface, SAE Paper 930919</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
