<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26789707</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Efficient Supercapacitors Based on Co₉S₈/Graphene Composites for Electric Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ma</surname>
                  <given-names>Fangwu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Wei</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Junzhi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cao</surname>
                  <given-names>Junming</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhao</surname>
                  <given-names>Ying</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wu</surname>
                  <given-names>Liang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">WCX18 Best Papers Special Issue</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26789698</issue-id>
         <fpage>289</fpage>
         <lpage>296</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26789707"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Nowadays, SC is recognized as a key element of hybrid energy storage system in modern energy supply chain for electric vehicles (EVs). Co₉S₈ as a promising electrode material attracts much attention for supercapacitor owing to its superior electrochemical capacity. However, its poor stability and electronic conductivity, which result in inferior cycling performance and rate capability, have seriously limited the practical application of Co₉O₈ in supercapacitors.</p>
            <p>In this article, Co₉S₈ nanoparticles were embedded in reduced graphene oxide (rGO) via a simple anneal approach as high efficient and stable electrodes for SCs. The Co₉S₈/rGO composites were characterized by scanning electron microscopy (SEM), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and X-ray diffraction (XRD). The Co₉S₈ nanoparticles were inserted tightly between the rGO layers due to strong intermolecular forces, preventing the cluster in reduction process of rGO from graphene oxide (GO). The rGO provides the conductive network for Co₉S₈ and shortens the ion diffusion paths, improving rate performance and enhancing the stability of the electrode material. The as-prepared Co₉S₈/rGO takes full advantages of high capacitance performance of Co₉S₈ nanoparticles and excellent conductivity and electrochemical stability of rGO. Thus, Co₉S₈/rGO composites exhibit high specific capacity of 708.3 F g<sup>−1</sup> with the active material mass of 2 mg at current density of 1A g<sup>−1</sup>. In addition, the asymmetric hybrid SC (Co₉S₈/rGO//rGO) delivered an excellent energy density of 41.1 Wh kg<sup>−1</sup> and a high power density of 750.3 W kg<sup>−1</sup>. The Co₉S₈/rGO composites introduced here represent a high efficiency ideal electrode that can be easily applied in automotive field with excellent performance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Dou, S., Li, T., Jia, H., Wang, S. et al., “Etched and Doped Co9S8/Graphene Hybrid for Oxygen Electrocatalysis,” Energy Environ Sci 9:1320-1326, 2016, doi:10.1039/c6ee00054a.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Li, D., Yang, D., Zhu, X., Jing, D. et al., “Simple Pyrolysis of Cobalt Alginate Fibres into Co3O4/C Nano/Microstructures for a High-Performance Lithium Ion Battery Anode,” J Mater Chem A 2:18761-18766, 2014, doi:10.1039/c4ta03052d.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Li, D., Lv, C., Liu, L., Xia, Y. et al., “Egg-Box Structure in Cobalt Alginate: A New Approach to Multifunctional Hierarchical Mesoporous N-Doped Carbon Nanofibers for Efficient Catalysis and Energy Storage,” ACS Cent Sci 1:261-269, 2015, doi:10.1021/acscentsci.5b00191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bui, P.T.M., Song, J.H., Li, Z.Y. et al., “Low Temperature Solution Processed Mn3O4 Nanoparticles: Enhanced Performance of Electrochemical Supercapacitors,” Journal of Alloys and Compounds 694:560-567, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. jallcom. 2016.10.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Yu, J., Lu, W., Joseph, P., Smith, K. et al., “A High Performance Stretchable Asymmetric Fiber-Shaped Supercapacitor with a Core-Sheath Helical Structure,” Advanced Energy Materials 7:1600976-1600984, 2017, doi:10.1002/aenm.201600976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Wang, S., Liu, N., Su, J., Li, L. et al., “Highly Stretchable and Self-Healable Supercapacitor with Reduced Graphene Oxide Based Fiber Springs,” ACS Nano 11:2066-2074, 2017, doi:10.1021/acsnano.6b08262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Atchudan, R., Thomas, N., Jebakumar, I. et al., “Green Synthesis of Nitrogen-Doped Graphitic Carbon Sheets with Use of Prunus Persica for Supercapacitor Applications,” Applied Surface Science 393:276-286, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. apsusc.2016.10. 030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Zhao, J., Lai, H., Lyu, Z., Jiang, Y. et al., “Hydrophilic Hierarchical Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Nanocages for Ultrahigh Supercapacitive Performance,” Adv Mater 27:3541-3445, 2015, doi:10.1002/adma.201500945.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Rajesh, S., Rajesh, K. et al., “Graphene Oxide: Strategies for Synthesis, Reduction and Frontier Applications,” RSC Adv 6:64993-65011, 2016, doi:10.1039/c6ra07626b.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Xiao, F., Yang, S., Zhang, Z., Liu, H. et al., “Scalable Synthesis of Freestanding Sandwich-Structured Graphene/Polyaniline/Graphene Nanocomposite Paper for Flexible All-Solid-State Supercapacitor,” Sci Rep 5:9359, 2015, doi:10.1038/srep09359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Zhang, L., Hu, X., Wang, Z. et al., “Experimental Impedance Investigation of an Ultracapacitor at Different Conditions for Electric Vehicle Applications,” Journal of Power Sources 287:129-138, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2015.04.043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Zhang, L., Hu, X., Wang, Z. et al., “Multi-Objective Optimal Sizing of Hybrid Energy Storage System for Electric Vehicles,” IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology 2:1027-1035, 2017, doi:10.1109/TVT.2017.2762368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Zhang, L., Hu, X., Wang, Z. et al., “A Review of Supercapacitor Modeling, Estimation, and Applications: A Control/Management Perspective,” Renewable &amp; Sustainable Energy Reviews 81:1868-1878, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.rser.2017.05.283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Feng, H., Hu, H., Dong, H., Xiao, Y. et al., “Hierarchical Structured Carbon Derived from Bagasse Wastes: A Simple and Efficient Synthesis Route and Its Improved Electrochemical Properties for High-Performance Supercapacitors,” Journal of Power Sources 302:164-173, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour. 2015.10.063.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Lamberti, A., Arnaud, G., Stefano, B., Marco, F. et al., “Self- Assembly of Graphene Aerogel on Copper Wire for Wearable Fiber-Shaped Supercapacitors,” Carbon 105:649-654, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.carbon.2016.05.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Zhu, D., Cheng, K., Wang, Y., Sun, D. et al., “Nitrogen- Doped Porous Carbons with Nanofiber-Like Structure Derived from Poly (Aniline-Co-P-Phenylenediamine) for Supercapacitors,” Electrochimica Acta 224:17-24, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.electacta.2016.12.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Xie, Y. and Wang, D., “Supercapacitance Performance of Polypyrrole/Titanium Nitride/Polyaniline Coaxial Nanotube Hybrid,” Journal of Alloys and Compounds 665:323-332, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.jallcom.2016.01.089.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Chang, Y., Sui, Y., Qi, J., Jiang, L. et al., “Facile Synthesis of Ni3S2 and Co9S8 Double-Size Nanoparticles Decorated on rGO for High-Performance Supercapacitor Electrode Materials,” Electrochimica Acta 226:69-78, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. electacta.2016.12.184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Li, H., Gao, Y., Shao, Y., Su, Y. et al., “Vapor-Phase Atomic Layer Deposition of Co9S8 and Its Application for Supercapacitors,” Nano Lett 15:6689-6695, 2015, doi:10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b02508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Liu, S., Tong, M., Liu, G., Zhang, X. et al., “S,N-Containing Co-MOF Derived Co9S8@S,N-Doped Carbon Materials as Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysts and Supercapacitor Electrode Materials,” Inorg Chem Front 4:491-498, 2017, doi:10.1039/c6qi00403b.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Wen, J., Li, S., Li, B., Song, Z. et al., “Synthesis of Three Dimensional Co9S8 Nanorod@Ni(OH)2 Nanosheet Core- Shell Structure for High Performance Supercapacitor Application,” Journal of Power Sources 284:279-286, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.jpowsour.2015.02.122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Xu, J., Wang, Q., Wang, X., Xiang, Q. et al., “Flexible Asymmetric Supercapacitors Based upon Co9S8 Nanorod//Co3O4@ RuO2 Nanosheet Arrays on Carbon Cloth,” ACS Nano 7:5453-5462, 2013, doi:10.1021/nn401450s.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Li, B., Hu, Y., Li, J., Liu, M. et al., “Mechanical Alloying Synthesis of Co9S8 Particles as Materials for Supercapacitors,” Metals 6:142-148, 2016, doi:10.3390/met6060142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Zhang, S., Li, D., Chen, S., Yang, X. et al., “Highly Stable Supercapacitors with MOF-Derived Co9S8/Carbon Electrodes for High Rate Electrochemical Energy Storage,” J Mater Chem A 5:12453-12461, 2017, doi:10.1039/c7ta03070c.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Wu, T., Ma, X., and Zhu, T., “Carbon Supported Co9S8 Hollow Spheres Assembled from Ultrathin Nanosheets for High-Performance Supercapacitors,” Materials Letters 183:290-295, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.matlet.2016.07.106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Yang, Y., Xi, Y., Li, J., Wei, G. et al., “Flexible Supercapacitors Based on Polyaniline Arrays Coated Graphene Aerogel Electrodes,” Nanoscale Res Lett 12:394-403, 2017, doi:10.1186/s11671-017-2159-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Owusu, A., Qu, L., Li, J., Wang, Z. et al., “Low-Crystalline Iron Oxide Hydroxide Nanoparticle Anode for High- Performance Supercapacitors,” Nat Commun 8:14264-14275, 2017, doi:10.1038/ncomms14264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Schematic illustration of energy storage system in electric vehicle (EV).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Schematic illustration of the synthesis process of Co₉S₈/rGO composite.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>(a) Low-magnification TEM, (b) high-magnification TEM, and (c) high-resolution transmission electron microscopy (HR-TEM) images of Co₉S₈/rGO-1. The SEM images of (d-f) Co₉S₈/rGO at different magnifications and the corresponding EDS mapping for Co, S, C elements.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>XRD patterns of Co₉S₈/rGO.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Electrochemical behaviors of the Co₉S₈/rGO electrodes in 6 M KOH. (a) Constant voltage (CV) curves at various scan rates, (b) galvanostatic charge-discharge curves at different current densities, (c) rate performance, and (d) Nyquist plots of Co₉S₈/rGO (the inset figure shows the magnified high-frequency regions of the Nyquist curves and equivalent circuit).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Electrochemical behaviors of asymmetric SCs (Co₉S₈/rGO//rGO) with 6 M KOH as electrolyte. (a) CV curves at various scan rates, (b) galvanostatic charge-discharge curves at different current densities of Co₉S₈/rGO SCs. (c) Ragone plot compared with traditional capacitor and battery. (d) Capacitance retention ratio and coulombic efficiency for Co₉S₈/rGO SCs at a charge-discharge current density of 2 A g<sup>−1</sup> for 2000 cycles.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Comparison of specific capacitance of various electrode materials based on Co₉S₈ toward the SC applications</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
