<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278081</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Characterization of Flow Asymmetry During the Compression Stroke Using Swirl-Plane PIV in a Light-Duty Optical Diesel Engine with the Re-entrant Piston Bowl Geometry</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zha</surname>
                  <given-names>Kan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Busch</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miles</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wijeyakulasuriya</surname>
                  <given-names>Sameera</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Convergent Science, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mitra</surname>
                  <given-names>Saurav</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Convergent Science, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Senecal</surname>
                  <given-names>P. K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Convergent Science, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278043</issue-id>
         <fpage>1837</fpage>
         <lpage>1855</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278081"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Flow field asymmetry can lead to an asymmetric mixture preparation in Diesel engines. To understand the evolution of this asymmetry, it is necessary to characterize the in-cylinder flow over the full compression stroke. Moreover, since bowl-in-piston cylinder geometries can substantially impact the in-cylinder flow, characterization of these flows requires the use of geometrically correct pistons. In this work, the flow has been visualized via a transparent piston top with a realistic bowl geometry, which causes severe experimental difficulties due to the spatial and temporal variation of the optical distortion. An advanced optical distortion correction method is described to allow reliable particle image velocimetry (PIV) measurements through the full compression stroke.</p>
            <p>Based on the ensemble-averaged velocity results, flow asymmetry characterized by the swirl center offset and the associated tilting of the vortex axis is quantified. The observed vertical tilting of swirl center axis is similar for tested swirl ratios (2.2 and 3.5), indicating that the details of the intake flows are not of primary importance to the late-compression mean flow asymmetry. Instead, the geometry of the piston pip likely impacts the flow asymmetry.</p>
            <p>The PIV results also confirm the numerically simulated flow asymmetry in the early and late compression stroke: at BDC, the swirl center is located closer to the exhaust valves for swirl-planes farther away from the fire deck; near TDC, the swirl center is located closer to the intake valves for swirl-planes farther away from the fire deck. It is evident from experimentally determined velocity fields that the transition between these two asymmetries has a different path for various swirl ratios, suggesting the influence of intake port flows.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P. C., “Turbulent Flow Structure in Direct-Injection, Swirl- Supported Diesel Engines,” Flow and Combustion in Reciprocating Engines (Heidelberg, Springer, 2009), p173-256, ISBN-13: 978- 3540641421.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borée, J. and Miles, P. C., “In-Cylinder Flow,” Encyclopedia of Automotive Engineering John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd, 2014), p1-31, ISBN- 13: 978-0-470-97402-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuss, D., Adrian, R., Landreth, C., French, D. et al., “Instantaneous Planar Measurements of Velocity and Large-Scale Vorticity and Strain Rate in an Engine Using Particle-Image Velocimetry,” SAE Technical Paper 890616, 1989, doi:10.4271/890616.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuss, D., Kuo, T., Khalighi, B., Haworth, D. et al., “Particle Image Velocimetry Measurements in a High-Swirl Engine Used for Evaluation of Computational Fluid Dynamics Calculations,” SAE Technical Paper 952381, 1995, doi:10.4271/952381.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P. C., Collin, R., Hildingsson, L., Hultqvist, A. and Andersson, O., “Combined measurements of flow structure, partially oxidized fuel, and soot in a high-speed, direct-injection diesel engine,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 31 II: 2963-2970, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2006.07.231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cosadia, I., Boree, J. and Dumont, P., “Coupling time-resolved PIV flow-fields and phase-invariant proper orthogonal decomposition for the description of the parameters space in a transparent Diesel engine,” Experiments in Fluids 43 (2-3): 357-370, 2007, doi:10.1007/s00348- 007-0338-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, W., Sjöberg, M. and Reuss, D. L., “Combined effects of flow/spray interactions and EGR on combustion variability for a stratified DISI engine,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 35 (3): 2907- 2914, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2014.06.106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, W., Sjöberg, M., and Reuss, D., “Using PIV Measurements to Determine the Role of the In-Cylinder Flow Field for Stratified DISI Engine Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):615-632, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1237.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baum, E., Peterson, B., Bohm, B. and Dreizler, A., “On The Validation of LES Applied to Internal Combustion Engine Flows: Part 1: Comprehensive Experimental Database,” Flow, Turbulence and Combustion 92 (1-2): 269-297, 2014, doi:10.1007/s10494-013-9468-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malbec, L. and Bruneaux, G., “Study of Air Entrainment of Multi-hole Diesel Injection by Particle Image Velocimetry - Effect of Neighboring Jets Interaction and Transient Behavior After End of Injection,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):107-123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rhim, D. and Farrell, P., “Air Flow Characteristics Surrounding Evaporating Transient Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01- 0499, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0499.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Colban, W., Miles, P., Park, S. et al., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Dilution- Controlled Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):411-430, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jainski, C., Lu, L., Dreizler, A. and Sick, V., “High-speed micro particle image velocimetry studies of boundary-layer flows in a direct-injection engine,” International Journal of Engine Research 14 (3): 247-259, 2013, doi:10.1177/1468087412455746.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, B., Baum, E., Bohm, B., Sick, V. and Dreizler, A., “Highspeed PIV and LIF imaging of temperature stratification in an internal combustion engine,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 34 (2): 3653-3660, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2012.05.051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eagle, W. E., Musculus, M. P. B., Malbec, L.-M. C. and Bruneaux, G., “Measuring transient entrainment rates of a confined vaporizing diesel jet,” ILASS Americas 26th Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, Portland, OR, May, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perini, F., Miles, P. C. and Reitz, R. D., “A comprehensive modeling study of in-cylinder fluid flows in a high-swirl, light-duty optical diesel engine,” Computers &amp; Fluids 105 (0): 113-124, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.compfluid.2014.09.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “INTERNAL COMBUSTION ENGINE FUNDAMENTALS,” (New York, McGraw-Hill, 1988), ISBN-13: ISBN 0-13-978-0070286375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nordgren, H., Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., Dahlén, L. et al., “Comparison Between In-Cylinder PIV Measurements, CFD Simulations and Steady-Flow Impulse Torque Swirl Meter Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3147, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deslandes, W., Dumont, P., Dupont, A., Baby, X. et al., “Airflow Cyclic Variations Analysis in Diesel Combustion Chamber by PIV Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1410, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deslandes, W., Dupont, A., Baby, X., Charnay, G. et al., “PIV Measurements of Internal Aerodynamic of Diesel Combustion Chamber,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3083, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soloff, S. M., Adrian, R. J. and Liu, Z. C., “Distortion compensation for generalized stereoscopic particle image velocimetry,” Measurement Science and Technology 8 (12): 1441-1454, 1997, doi:10.1088/0957- 0233/8/12/008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuss, D. L., Megerle, M. and Sick, V., “Particle-image velocimetry measurement errors when imaging through a transparent engine cylinder,” Measurement Science and Technology 13 (7): 1029-1035, 2002, doi:10.1088/0957-0233/13/7/309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P. C., Hildingsson, L. and Hultqvist, A., “The influence of fuel injection and heat release on bulk flow structures in a direct-injection, swirl-supported diesel engine,” Experiments in Fluids 43 (2-3): 273-283, 2007, doi:10.1007/s00348-007-0281-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W., Ekoto, I., Kim, D. and Miles, P. C., “In-Cylinder PIV Measurements in an Optical Light-Duty Diesel at LTC Conditions,” THIESEL 2008 Conference on Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B. and Miles, P., “PIV Measurements in the Swirl-Plane of a Motored Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1623- 1641, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Staples, L., Reitz, R., and Hergart, C., “An Experimental Investigation into Diesel Engine Size-Scaling Parameters,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1068-1084, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R. M., “Investigation of mixing and temperature effects on UHC/CO emissions for highly dilute low temperature combustion in a lightduty Diesel engine,” M.S. thesis, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prasad, A. K., “Stereoscopic particle image velocimetry,” Experiments in Fluids 29 (2): 103-116, 2000, doi:10.1007/s003480000143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munson, B. R., Young, D. F. and Okiishi, T. H., “FUNDAMENTALS OF FLUID MECHANICS,” (New York, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., 2001), p19, ISBN-13: 978-0471442509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mei, R., “Velocity fidelity of flow tracer particles,” Experiments in Fluids 22 (1): 1-13, 1996, doi:10.1007/BF01893300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adrian, R. J. and Westerweel, J., “PARTICLE IMAGE VELOCIMETRY,” (New York, Cambridge University Press, 2011), p47- 48, ISBN-13: 978-0521440080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pomraning, E., Richards, K., and Senecal, P., “Modeling Turbulent Combustion Using a RANS Model, Detailed Chemistry, and Adaptive Mesh Refinement,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1116, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clemens, N. T. and Mungal, M. G., “A planar Mie scattering technique for visualizing supersonic mixing flows,” Experiments in Fluids 11 (2- 3): 175-185, 1991, doi:10.1007/BF00190296.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tropea, C., Yarin, A. L. and Foss, J. F., “Springer Handbook of Experimental Fluid Mechanics,” (Berlin Heidelberg, Springer-Verlag, 2007), p289, ISBN-13: 978-3-540-25141-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adrian, R. J. and Westerweel, J., “PARTICLE IMAGE VELOCIMETRY,” (New York, Cambridge University Press, 2011), p9, ISBN-13: 978-0521440080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adrian, R. J. and Westerweel, J., “PARTICLE IMAGE VELOCIMETRY,” (New York, Cambridge University Press, 2011), p293-294, ISBN-13: 978-0521440080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adrian, R. J. and Westerweel, J., “PARTICLE IMAGE VELOCIMETRY,” (New York, Cambridge University Press, 2011), p350-351, ISBN-13: 978-0521440080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Busch, S., Zha, K. and Miles, P. C., “Experimental and Numerical Investigations of Close-Coupled Pilot Injections to Reduce Combustion Noise in a Small-Bore Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):660-678, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0796.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adrian, R. J. and Westerweel, J., “PARTICLE IMAGE VELOCIMETRY,” (New York, Cambridge University Press, 2011), p349, ISBN-13: 978-0521440080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graftieaux, L., Michard, M. and Nathalie, G., “Combining PIV, POD and vortex identification algorithms for the study of unsteady turbulent swirling flows,” Measurement Science and Technology 12 (9): 1422- 1429, 2001, doi:10.1088/0957-0233/12/9/307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perini, F., Zha, K., Busch, S., Miles, P. and Reitz, R., “Principal Component Analysis of Port-induced Swirl Structures in a Light-duty Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper, 2015-01-1696, 2015, In press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Miles, P., and Sahoo, D., “Equivalence Ratio Distributions in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating under Partially Premixed Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):526-537, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0692.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
