<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169051</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Multi-Objective Optimal Design of Parallel Plug-In Hybrid Powertrain Configurations with Respect to Fuel Consumption and Driving Performance</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boehme</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas Juergen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rothschuh</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Frank</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schultalbers</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schori</surname>
                  <given-names>Markus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Rostock</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jeinsch</surname>
                  <given-names>Torsten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Rostock</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169049</issue-id>
         <fpage>176</fpage>
         <lpage>192</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169051"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In the past decade, various Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles have been demonstrated which offer the potential of a significant reduction in fuel consumption and emission. However, this capability strongly depends on the sizing of the components, driver's usage profile and the quality of the energy management. These challenges require new optimization procedures for a systematical exploration of the design space with the objective of an optimal powertrain configuration. A novel optimization strategy based on a multi-objective problem formulation is proposed. The optimization procedure consists of a multi-objective genetic algorithm for determining the best design parameters with respect to fuel consumption and driving performance. The approach is combined with an analytical optimal control problem to find the optimal continuous and discrete control trajectories for the energy management.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elgowainy, A., Burnham, A., Wang, M., Molburg, J. et al, “Well-To- Wheels Energy Use and Greenhouse Gas Emissions of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):627-644, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boehme, T., Metwally, O., Becker, B., Meinhardt, N. et al., “A Simulation-Based Comparison of Different Power Split Configurations with Respect to the System Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0438, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boehme, T., Becker, B., Ruben-Weck, M., Rothschuh, M. et al., “Optimal Design Strategies for Different Hybrid Powertrain Configurations Assessed with European Drive Cycles,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1751, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1751.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundström, O., Guzzella, L., Soltic, P., “Torque-assist hybrid electric powertrain sizing: From optimal control towards a sizing law”, IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, Vol. 18, No. 4, pp. 837-849, 2010, doi:10.1109/TCST.2009.2030173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johannesson, L., Murgovski, N., Ebbesen, S., Egardt, B. et al., “Including a Battery State of Health model in the HEV component sizing and optimal control problem,” Proceedings of the 7th IFAC Symposium on Advances in Automotive Control, Tokyo, Japan, pp. 388-393, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pourabdollah, M., Grauers, A., Egardt, B., “Effect of Driving patterns on Components sizing of a Series PHEV”, Proceedings of the 7th IFAC Symposium on Advances in Automotive Control, Tokyo, Japan, pp. 17-22, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Kang, J.-M., Grizzle, J. W., Peng, H., “Energy Management Strategy for a Parallel Hybrid Electric Truck”, Proceedings of the American Control Conference (ACC), Arlington, pp. 2878-2883, 2001, doi:10.1109/ACC.2001.946337.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paganelli, G., Guezennec, Y., and Rizzoni, G., “Optimizing Control Strategy for Hybrid Fuel Cell Vehicle”, SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0102, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, J.-S., Salman, M. A., “Learning Energy Management Strategy for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Vehicle Power and Propulsion, pp. 68-73, 2005, doi:10.1109/VPPC.2005.1554593.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musardo, C., Rizzoni, G., Staccia, B., “A-ECMS: An Adaptive Algorithm for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Management,” Proceedings of the 44th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, pp. 1816-1823, 2005, doi:10.1109/CDC.2005.1582424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borhan, H. A., Vahidi, A., Phillips, A. M., Kuang, M. L. et al., “Predictive Energy Management of a Power-Split Hybrid Electric Vehicle”, Proceedings of the American Control Conference (ACC), St. Louis, pp. 3970-3976, 2009, doi:10.1109/ACC.2009.5160451.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schori, M., Boehme, T. J., Frank, B., Schultalbers, M., “Solution of a Hybrid Optimal Control Problem for a Parallel Hybrid Vehicle,” Proceedings of the 7th IFAC Symposium on Advances in Automotive Control, Tokyo, Japan, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chi, S., “Position-Sensorless Control of Permanent Magnet Synchronous Machines over wide Speed Range,” Ph.D thesis, Ohio state University, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deb, K., Pratap, A., Agarwal, S., Meyarivan, T., “A Fast and Elitist Multiobjective Genetic Algorithm: NSGA-II,” IEEE Transactions on Evolutionary Computation, Vol. 6, No., 2, pp.182-197, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nocedal, J. and Wright, S. J., “Numerical Optimization,” Second Edition, Springer Series in Operations Research, ISBN 13:978-0387-30303-1, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rechs, M., Menne, R., Tielkes, U., Pingen, B., “Torque Boost - Drehmomenterhöhung und Verbrauchsreduzierung im realen Fahrbetrieb”, 23. International Wiener Motorensymposium, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sandwell, D. “Biharmonic spline interpolation of geos-3 and seasat altimeter data,” Geophysical research letters, Vol. 14, No. 2, pp. 139-142, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Errico, J., “Surface fitting using gridfit”, http://www.mathworks. com/matlabcentral/fileexchange/8998-surface-fitting-using-gridfit, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davis, L., “The Handbook of Genetic Algorithms,” Van Nostrand Reingold, New York, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalyanmoy, D., Agarwal, R. B., “Simulated Binary Crossover for Continuous Search Space,” Complex Systems, Vol. 9, pp. 115-148, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boehme, T., Frank, B., Schultalbers, M., Schori, M. et al., “Solutions of Hybrid Energy-Optimal Control for Model-based Calibrations of HEV Powertrains,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1747, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1747.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bengea, S. C., DeCarlo, R. A., “Optimal and Suboptimal Control of Switching Systems”, Proceedings of the 42nd IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, Maui, Hawaii, pp. 5295-5300, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bengea, S., Uthaichana, K., Žefran, M., DeCarlo. R. A., “Optimal Control of Switching Systems via Embedding into Continuous Optimal Control Problems”, The control System Handbook, Second Edition:Control System Advanced Methods, Editor Levine William S., Chapter 31, CRC Press, 2011, ISBN 13:978-1420073645.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, B., Mi, C. C., Zhang, M., “Charge-Depleting Control Strategies and Fuel Optimization of Blended-Mode Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles”, IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, Vol. 60, No. 4, pp. 1516-1525, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, B., Mi, C. C., Zhang, M., “Charge-Depleting Control Strategies and Fuel Optimization of Blended-Mode Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles”, IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, Vol. 60, No. 4, pp. 1516-1525, 2011, doi:10.1109/TVT.2011.2122313.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stockar, S., Marano, V., Canova, M., Rizzoni, G. et al., “Energyoptimal control of plug-in hybrid electric vehicles for real-world driving cycles,” Vol. 60, No. 7, pp. 2949-2962, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Entwicklung der spezifischen Kohlendioxid-Emissionen des deutschen Strommix 1990-2010 und erste Schätzungen Umweltbundesamt: 2011, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
