<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277864</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Inversion-Based Intake Manifold Pressure Control System for Modern Diesel Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reß</surname>
                  <given-names>Johannes</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clausthal University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bohn</surname>
                  <given-names>Christian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clausthal University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Märzke</surname>
                  <given-names>Frank</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Meinecke</surname>
                  <given-names>Ralf</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schollmeyer</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Frase</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1539</fpage>
         <lpage>1546</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277864"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>An improved model-based two-degree of freedom control system for the intake manifold pressure in passenger car diesel engines is described in this paper. The aim of this control system is to track the air charge setpoint rapidly and precisely. To achieve this, an inverse model of the intake manifold dynamics is included in the feedforward control path. The system parameters which are necessary to calculate the inverse model are setpoints from other control loops in the gas system. These generated setpoint values allow for decoupling of the individual control loops in the gas system as far as possible. The parallel linear feedback controller is designed to further improve the accuracy of the control system. The calculated feedforward control signal and the feedback control variable additively generate the effective opened area of the intake throttle valve. Due to its model-based structure, the improved control system proposed will require less calibration effort than current production-code controllers and that the calibration can be partially carried out using simulation. This is also the main motivation for the development of this controller. The proposed control algorithm can be easily implemented on the standard electronic control unit (ECU) of passenger car diesel engines. For testing and validation, the production-code controller function of the ECU has been replaced by the new control approach using a bypass with a rapid control prototyping. Experimental results are provided and show that the new control system achieves a performance that is similar to the production-code controller.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heuck, M. Modellgestütztes Luftsystem-Management für einen Pkw-Dieselmotor mit Hoch- und Niederdruck- Abgasrückführsystem. Aachen: Shaker, 2009. (in German, Modelbased gas system management of passenger car diesel engines with high and low pressure exhaust gas recirculation).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedrich, I., Liu, C., Oehlerking, D. “Coordinated EGR-Rate Model- Based Controls of Turbocharged Diesel Engines vie Intake Throttle and EGR Valve.” Proceedings of the Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference. Dearborn, 2009. 340-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nöthen, C. Strategien zur Gassystemregelung von Pkw- Dieselmotoren. Aachen: Shaker Verlag, 2010. (in German, Strategies for gas system control of passenger car diesel engines).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knippschild, C. L. Zylinderindividuelle Regelung des Gaszustands bei Pkw-Dieselmotoren. Berlin: Logos Verlag, 2011. (in German, Cylinder-specific control of the gas condition in passenger car diesel engines).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aono, T., Kowatari, T. “Throttle-control algorithm for improving engine response based on air-intake model and throttle-response model.” IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 53, 2006. 915-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santillo, M., Karnik, A. “Model Predictive Controller design for throttle and wastegate control of a turbocharged engine.” Proceedings of the American Control Conference. Washington, DC, 2013. 2183-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herceg, M., Raff, T., Findeisen, R., Allgöwer, F. “Nonlinear Model Predictive Control of a Turbocharged Diesel Engine.” Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Control Applications. Munich, 2006. 2766-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wahlstöm, J., Eriksson, L. “Output Selection and Its Implications for MPC of EGR and VGT in Diesel Engines.” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, Vol. 21, No. 3, 2013. 932-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AL-Samarraie, S. A., Abbas, Y. K. “Design of Electronic Throttle Valve Position Control System using Nonlinear PID Controller” International Journal of Computer Applications, Vol. 59, No. 15, 2012. 27-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
