<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284798</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Prediction of the Nozzle Flow and Jet Characteristics at Start and End of Injection</article-title>
            <subtitle>Transient Behaviors</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Battistoni</surname>
                  <given-names>Michele</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Perugia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Poggiani</surname>
                  <given-names>Claudio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Perugia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Som</surname>
                  <given-names>Sibendu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>84</fpage>
         <lpage>97</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284798"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper reports investigations on diesel jet transients, accounting for internal nozzle flow and needle motion. The calculations are performed with Large Eddy Simulation (LES) turbulence model by coupling the internal and external multiphase flows simultaneously. Short and multiple injection strategies are commonly used in internal combustion engines. Their features are significantly different from those generally found in steady state conditions, which have been extensively studied in the past, however, these conditions are seldom reached in modern engines. Recent researches have shown that residual gas can be ingested in the injector sac after the end-of-injection (EOI) and undesired dribbles can be produced. Moreover, a new injection event behaves differently at the start-of-injection (SOI) depending on the sac initial condition, and the initial spray development can be affected for the first few tens of μs. To investigate these phenomena, LES of end-of-injection and start-of-injection processes have been carried out on a single hole injector, in order to provide insights in to the physics. Detailed needle motion data and orifice morphology have been measured using x-ray synchrotron source at Argonne National Laboratory. Simulations are validated against available x-ray data of the internal flow and near nozzle exit region. Results are able to realistically capture the injection rate ramp-up, the initial gas discharge followed by liquid injection, the realistic liquid tip penetration and the EOI dribbles, provided all the boundary condition details are properly included in the simulations. Such information is invaluable towards developing simulation tools for enabling and improving low temperature combustion concepts with multiple injection strategies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weigand A., Atzler F., Kastner O., Rotondi R., Schwarte A., “The effect of closely coupled pilot injections on diesel engine emissions”, IMechE, London, 29-30 November 2011, Pages 111-124, doi:10.1533/978085709 5060.3.111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Manin, J., Payri, R., Bardi, M. et al., “Transient Rate of Injection Effects on Spray Development”, SAE Technical Paper 2013- 24-0001, (2013) doi:10.4271/2013-24-0001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swantek, A.B., Duke, J.D., Tilocco, F.Z., Sovis, N., Powell, C.F., Kastengren, A.L., “End of Injection, Mass Expulsion Behaviors in Single Hole Diesel Fuel Injectors”, ILASS Americas, Portland OR, (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eagle W.E. and Musculus M.P. “Cinema-stereo imaging of fuel dribble after the end of injection in an optical heavy-duty Diesel engine”, Thiesel conference Proceedings, Valencia, (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni M., Kastengren A.L., Powell C.F., Som, S., “Fluid Dynamics Modeling of End-of-Injection Process”, ILASS Americas, Portland OR, (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitroglou N., McLorn M., Gavaises M., Soteriou C., Winterbourne M., “Instantaneous and ensemble average cavitation structures in Diesel micro-channel flow orifices”, Fuel 116 (2014) 736-742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.B., Miles, P.C., Pickett, L.M., 2013. “Conceptual Models for Partially Premixed Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, vol. 39, (2013). doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2012.09.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winterbourn M., Soteriou C.C.E., Daveau C., Mitroglou N., Gavaises M., “Visualising injection events in a fully operational diesel injector with a multi-hole transparent tip”, Thiesel conference Proceedings, Valencia, (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arienti M., and Sussman M., “An embedded level set method for sharp-interface multiphase simulations of Diesel injectors” International Journal of Multiphase Flow 59 (2014) 1-14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bode, M., Diewald, F., Broll, D., Heyse, J. et al., “Influence of the Injector Geometry on Primary Breakup in Diesel Injector Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1427, (2014), doi:10.4271/2014-01-1427.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pavlović Z., Scheidl S., Edelbauer W., Basara B., Brenn G., Jakirlić S., “Numerical investigation of the liquid core length in sprays with fully turbulent boundary condition”, ILASS - Europe 2014, Sep. (2014), Bremen, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oefelein, J., Lacaze, G., Dahms, R., Ruiz, A. et al., “Effects of Real- Fluid Thermodynamics on High-Pressure Fuel Injection Processes,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):1125-1136, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1429.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, D.P., Gopalakrishnan, S., Jasak, H., “Multidimensional simulation of thermal non-equilibrium channel flow”, Int. J. of Multiphase Flow (2010), 36, 284-292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demoulin F.X., Beau, P.A., Blokkeel G., Mura A., Borghi R., “A new model for turbulent flows with large density fluctuations: Application to liquid atomization”, Atomization and Sprays, 17 (4): 315-345 (2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue Q., Battistoni M., Powell C.F., Longman D.E., Quan S., Pomraning E., Senecal P.K., Schmidt D.P., Som S., “An Eulerian CFD Model and X-ray Radiography for Coupled Nozzle Flow and Spray in Internal Combustion Engines”, International Journal of Multi-phase Flows 70, 77-88, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alajbegovic, A., “Three-Dimensional Cavitation Calculations in Nozzles,” (1999), Second Annual Meeting of the Institute for Multifluid Science and Technology, Santa Barbara, CA, pp. 97-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang Y., Qiu L., Reitz R.D., Diwakar R., “Simulating cavitating liquid jets using a compressible and equilibrium two-phase flow solver”, International Journal of Multiphase Flow, 63 (2014) 52-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni M., Duke, J.D., Swantek, A.L., Tilocco, F.Z., Powell, C.F., Som, S., “The Effects of Non-Condensable Gas on Cavitating Nozzles”, Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 25 (2015) doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2015011076.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bilicki, Z., Kestin, J., “Physical aspects of the relaxation model in two-phase flow”, Proc. Roy. Soc. Lond. A., 428, 379-397, (1990), doi:10.1098/rspa.1990.0040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Downar-Zapolski, P., Bilicki, Z., Bolle, L., Franco, J., “The nonequilibrium relaxation model for one-dimensional flashing liquid flow”, Int. J. of Multiphase Flow, (1996), 22 (3), pp. 473-483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brennen, C.E., “Cavitation and Bubble Dynamics”, Oxford University Press (1995).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni M. Som, S., Longman, D.E., “Comparison of Mixture and Multifluid Models for In-Nozzle Cavitation Prediction”, J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power, (2014) 136(6):061506-061506-12, GTP-13-1436, doi:10.1115/1.4026369.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senecal, P.K., Richards, K., Pomraning, E., Yang, T. et al., “A New Parallel Cut-Cell Cartesian CFD Code for Rapid Grid Generation Applied to In-Cylinder Diesel Engine Simulations”, SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0159, (2007), doi:10.4271/2007-01-0159.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pomraning E., Rutland C.J., “A Dynamic One-Equation Non-Viscosity LES Model”, AIAA Journal (2002), vol. 40, No. 4, 659-701.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senecal, P.K., Pomraning, E., Richards, K., and Som, S., “An Investigation of Grid Convergence for Spray Simulations using an LES Turbulence Model”, SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1083, (2013), doi:10.4271/2013-01-1083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue Q., Som S., Senecal P.K., Pomraning E., “Large Eddy Simulation of Fuel Spray Under Non-Reacting IC Engine Conditions,” Atomization and Sprays (2013), 23(10), 925-955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rhie, C.M., Chow, W.L., “A numerical study of the turbulent flow past an isolated airfoil with trailing edge separation”. AIAA 21(11), 1525- 1532 (1983).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Issa, R.I. “Solution of the implicitly discretised fluid flow equations by operator-splitting”, J. Comput. Phys. 62, 40-65 (1986).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Quan, S., Dai, M., Pomraning, E., Senecal, P. et al., “Numerical Simulations of Supersonic Diesel Spray Injection and the Induced Shock Waves,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):1054-1060, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014- 01-1423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., Quan, S., Dai, M., Pomraning, E., Senecal, P.K., Xue, Q., Battistoni, M., Som, S., “Validation of Three-Dimensional Internal Nozzle Flow Including Automatic Mesh Generation and Cavitation Effects”, ASME J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power (2014); 136(9):092603- 092603-10, GTP-14-1111, doi:10.1115/1.4027193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue, Q., Battistoni, M., Som, S., Quan, S. et al., “Eulerian CFD Modeling of Coupled Nozzle Flow and Spray with Validation Against X-Ray Radiography Data,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):1061-1072, (2014), doi:10.4271/2014-01-1425.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni M., Xue Q., Som S., “LES of Spray Transients: Start and End of Injection Phenomena”, Oil &amp; Gas Science Technology, 2015, under review.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swantek A.B., Kastengren A.L., Duke D., Tilocco F.Z., Sovis N., Powell C.F., “A further examination of fuel dribble from single hole diesel nozzles”. ILASS - Europe 2014, 8-10 Sep. (2014), Bremen, Germany. 34. Werner H., and Wengle H., “Large Eddy Simulation of Turbulent Flow Over and Around a Cube in a Plane Channel,” Proceedings of Eighth Symposium Turbulent Shear Flows, (1991).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Werner H., and Wengle H., “Large Eddy Simulation of Turbulent Flow Over and Around a Cube in a Plane Channel,” Proceedings of Eighth Symposium Turbulent Shear Flows, (1991).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni, M.; Grimaldi, C.N.; “Numerical analysis of injector flow and spray characteristics from diesel injectors using fossil and biodiesel fuels”, Applied Energy, 97 (2012) 656-666, Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Som S., Longman D.E., Ramírez A.I., Aggarwal S.K., A comparison of injector flow and spray characteristics of biodiesel with petrodiesel, Fuel, Vol. 89, (12), 2010, 4014-4024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network web site, http://www.sandia.gov/ecn/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kastengren A.L., Tilocco F.Z., Duke D., Powell C.F., Zhang X., Moon S., “Time-resolved x-ray radiography of sprays from Engine Combustion Network spray A diesel injectors”, Atomization and Sprays, 24 (3): 251-272 (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bardi M., Payri R., Malbec L.M., Bruneaux G., Pikett L.M., Manin J., Bazin T., Genzale C., “Engine combustion network: comparison of spray development, vaporization, and combustion in different combustion vessels”, Atomization and Sprays 22(10):807-842, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett L., Genzale C., Manin J. “Uncertainty quantification for liquid penetration of evaporating sprays at diesel-like conditions”, Atomization and Sprays, vol. 25 (2015), doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2015010618.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
