<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277540</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Applying Design of Experiments to Determine the Effect of Gas Properties on In-Cylinder Heat Flux in a Motored SI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Demuynck</surname>
                  <given-names>Joachim</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ghent University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Paepe</surname>
                  <given-names>Michel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ghent University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sileghem</surname>
                  <given-names>Louis</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ghent University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vancoillie</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeroen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ghent University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Verhelst</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ghent University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chana</surname>
                  <given-names>Kam</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Oxford</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1286</fpage>
         <lpage>1299</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277540"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Models for the convective heat transfer from the combustion gases to the walls inside a spark ignition engine are an important keystone in the simulation tools which are being developed to aid engine optimization. The existing models have, however, been cited to be inaccurate for hydrogen, one of the alternative fuels currently investigated. One possible explanation for this inaccuracy is that the models do not adequately capture the effect of the gas properties. These have never been varied in a wide range because air and ‘classical’ fossil fuels have similar values, but they are significantly different in the case of hydrogen. As a first step towards a fuel independent heat transfer model, we have investigated the effect of the gas properties on the heat flux in a spark ignition engine. The effect of the gas properties was decoupled from that of combustion, by injecting different inert gases (helium, argon, carbon dioxide) into the intake air flow of the engine under motored operation. This paper presents the results of the experiment, which was designed with DoE techniques. The paper shows that the three investigated effects (throttle position, compression ratio and gas) and the interaction between the throttle and the compression ratio are significant with a significance level of 1%. Both the individual and combined effects of the gas properties are investigated. The most remarkable effect observed in the data was that the dynamic viscosity influences the heat flux in two contrasting ways. At the one hand, it increases the heat flux by increasing the gas temperature, at the other hand, it reduces the heat flux through the convection coefficient. A preliminary test shows that modeling under motored operation could be based on classical concepts. However, some scatter occurs in the data which needs further investigation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borman, G.L. and Nishiwaki, K., Internal-Combustion Engine Heat- Transfer. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 1987. 13(1): p. 1-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck, J., De Paepe, M., Sierens, R., Vancoillie, J. and Verhelst, S. Literature review on the convective heat transfer measurements in spark ignition engines. in 13th European Automotive Congress (EAEC 2011), paper EAEC2011_A46. 2011. Valencia, Spain.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Annand, W.J.D., Heat transfer in the cylinders of reciprocating internal combustion engines. Proc Instn Mech Engrs, 1963. 177(36): p. 973-996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Annand, W.J.D. and Ma, T.H., Instantaneous heat transfer rates to the cylinder head surface of a small compression-ignition engine. Proc Instn Mech Engrs, 1971. 185(72): p. 976-987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., “A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi: 10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., Beitrag zum Problem des Warmeuberganges im verbrenningsmotor. Motortechnische Zeitschrift, 1965. 26(4): p. 128-133.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sitkei, G. and Ramanaiah, G., “A Rational Approach for Calculation of Heat Transfer in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 720027, 1972, doi: 10.4271/720027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hohenberg, G., “Advanced Approaches for Heat Transfer Calculations,” SAE Technical Paper 790825, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, J., Güralp, O., Filipi, Z., Assanis, D. et al., “New Heat Transfer Correlation for an HCCI Engine Derived from Measurements of Instantaneous Surface Heat Flux,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2996, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck, J., De Paepe, M., Huisseune, H., Sierens, R., Vancoillie, J. and Verhelst, S., On the applicability of empirical heat transfer models for hydrogen combustion engines. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 2011. 36(1): p. 975-984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verhelst, S. and Wallner, T., Hydrogen-fueled internal combustion engines. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2009. 35(6): p. 490-527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piccini, E., Guo, S.M. and Jones, T.V., The development of a new directheat- flux gauge for heat-transfer facilities. Measurement Science and Technology, 2000. 11(4): p. 342-349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demuynck, J., Raes, N., Zuliani, M., De Paepe, M., Sierens, R. and Verhelst, S., Local heat flux measurements in a hydrogen and methane spark ignition engine with a thermopile sensor. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 2009. 34(24): p. 9857-9868.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oldfield, M.L.G., Jones, T.V. and Schultz, D.L., On-Line Computer for Transient Turbine Cascade Instrumentation. IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems, 1978. 14(5): p. 738-749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berger, P.D., Experimental Design with Applications in Management, Engineering, and the Sciences, ISBN: 0-534-35822-5. 2002, Belmont, USA: Duxbury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rowley, R.L., Wilding, W.V., Oscarson, J.L., Yang, Y., Zundel, N.A., Daubert, T.E. and Danner, R.P., DIPPR® Data Compilation of Pure Compound Properties. 2003, New York (NY): Design Institute for Physical Properties, AIChE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, J.R., An introduction to error analysis: the study of uncertainties in physical measurements, 0-935702-42-3. 1982: University Science Books.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T. and Keribar, R., “A Model for Predicting Spatially and Time Resolved Convective Heat Transfer in Bowl-in-Piston Combustion Chambers,” SAE Technical Paper 850204, 1985, doi: 10.4271/850204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraser, R., Felton, P., Bracco, F., and Santavicca, D., “Preliminary Turbulence Length Scale Measurements in a Motored IC Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 860021, 1986, doi: 10.4271/860021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verhelst, S. and Sierens, R., A quasi-dimensional model for the power cycle of a hydrogen-fuelled ICE. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy, 2007. 32(15): p. 3545-3554.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
