<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023240</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Accounting Research and Political Economy</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Political Economy of Corporate Tax Avoidance</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>46</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023240"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper employs a new empirical approach for identifying the impact of politicians’ opportunistic policy preferences on corporate tax avoidance. Our key innovation is to use turnovers of local politicians as a source of exogenous variation in tax enforcement efforts, which have strong implications for firms’ strategic tax avoidance decisions. Using data on turnovers of China’s municipal political leaders and industrial firms in their jurisdictions, we document cycles in corporate tax avoidance corresponding with the timing of local politician turnovers. The political cycle of tax avoidance is more pronounced in municipal cities with strong tax base and weaker governance. The cycle occurs when a local politician is younger and follows an upward career trajectory. The tax avoidance cycle is also more evident among firms that can potentially derive higher value from strategically engaging in tax avoidance activity. Our findings suggest that varying tax enforcement driven by local politicians’ policy preferences is an important channel – entirely different from the political uncertainty and political connection channels – through which the political process affects real economic activity.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>political turnovers</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>tax avoidance cycle</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>enforcement</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>political economy</kwd>
            <x>.</x>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Acemoglu, D., and J. A. Robinson, 2006. Economic Origins of Dictatorship and Democracy. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akhmedov, A., and E. Zhuravskaya, 2004. Opportunistic Political Cycles: Test in a Young Democracy Setting, Quarterly Journal of Economics 119: 1301-1338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, F., J. Qian, and M. Qian, 2005. Law, Finance and Economic Growth in China. Journal of Financial Economics 77: 57-116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bagchi, S., 2013. The Political Economy of Tax Enforcement: A Look at the IRS from 1978-2010. SSRN Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, T., C. Lin, and Y. Ma, 2014. Why do Firms Evade Taxes? The Role of Information Sharing and Financial Sector Outreach. The Journal of Finance 69 (2): 763-817.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Belo, F., V. D. Gala, and J. Li, 2013. Government Spending, Political Cycles, and the Cross Section of Stock Returns. Journal of Financial Economics 107(2): 305-324.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernanke, B. S.,1983. Irreversibility, uncertainty, and cyclical investment. Quarterly Journal of Economics 98: 85-106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bloom, N., S. Bond, and J. V. Reenen, 2007. Uncertainty and investment dynamics. Review of Economic Studies 74: 391-415.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boutchkova, M., H. Doshi, A. Durnev, and A. Molchanov, 2012. Precarious politics and return volatility. Review of Financial Studies 25 (4): 1111-1154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bradshaw, M. T., G. Liao, and M. S. Ma, 2013. Ownership Structure and Tax Avoidance: Evidence from Agency Costs of State Ownership in China. SSRN Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brender, A., and A. Drazen, 2008. How Do Budget Deficits and Economic Growth Affect Reelection Prospects? Evidence from a Large Panel of Countries, American Economic Review 98(5): 2203-2220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cai, H., and Liu, Q., 2009. Competition and Corporate Tax Avoidance: Evidence from Chinese Industrial Firms. Economic Journal 119: 764-795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colak, G., A. Durnev, and Y. Qian, 2013. Political Uncertainty and IPO Activity: Evidence from US Gubernatorial Elections. SSRN Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DeBacker, J., B. T. Heim, A. Tran, and A. Yuskavage, 2013. The Impact of Legal Enforcement: An Analysis of Corporate Tax Aggressiveness after an Audit, Indiana University Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, M., and D. Dharmapala. 2006. Corporate tax avoidance and high-powered incentives. Journal of Financial Economics 79 (1): 145-179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, M., A. Dyck, and L. Zingales. 2007. Theft and Taxes. Journal of Financial Economics 84 (3): 591–623.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, S., M. Hanlon, and E. Maydew. 2008. Long-run Corporate Tax Avoidance. The Accounting Review: 83(1): 61-82。</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, A., C. Schwab, and T. J. Shevlin, 2014. Financial Constraints and the Incentive for Tax Planning. Rotman School of Management Working Paper No. 2163766.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fan, G., Wang, X., and H. Zhu, 2010. Marketization Index in China. The Economic Science Press (in Chinese).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gupta, S., and D. Lynch, 2012. The effects of changes in state tax enforcement on corporate income tax collections. 2012 American Taxation Association Midyear Meeting: Research-In-Process Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoopes, J. L., D. Mescall, and J. A. Pittman, 2012. Do IRS Audits Deter Corporate Tax Avoidance? The Accounting Review 87 (5): 1603-1639.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, Y., 1996. Inflation and Investment Controls in China: The Political Economy of Central-Local Relations during the Reform Era. Cambridge; New York and Melbourne: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Julio, B., and Y. Yook, 2012. Political Uncertainty and Corporate Investment Cycles. Journal of Finance 67 (1): 45-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, C. F., C. Pantzalis, J. C. Park, 2012. Political geography and stock returns: The value and risk implications of proximity to political power. Journal of Financial Economics 106 (1): 196-228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Landry, P. F., 2008. Decentralized Authoritarianism in China: The Communist Party’s Control of Local Elites in the Post-Mao Era. Cambridge and New York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Landry, P. F., X. Lü, and H. Duan, 2014. Does Performance Matter? Evaluating the Institution of Political Selection along the Chinese Administrative Ladder. APSA 2014 Annual Meeting Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levitt, S. D., 1997. Using Electoral Cycles in Police Hiring to Estimate the Effect of Police on Crime. American Economic Review 87(3): 270-290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., and L. Zhou, 2005. Political Turnover and Economic Performance: The Incentive Role of Personnel Control in China. Journal of Public Economics 89(9-10): 1743-1762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, W., and P. T.H. Ngo, 2014. Elections, Political Competition and Bank Failure, Journal of Financial Economics 112(2): 251-268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maskin, E., Y. Qian, and C. Xu, 2000. Incentives, Information, and Organizational Form. Review of Economic Studies 67(2): 359-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McGuire, S. T., D. Wang, and R. J. Wilson, 2014. Dual Class Ownership and Tax Avoidance. The Accounting Review 89 (4): 1487-1516.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mills, L., M. Erickson, and E. Maydew, 1998. Investments in Tax Planning. Journal of the American Taxation Association 20(1): 1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nathan, A., and B. Gilley, 2002. China’s New Rulers: The Secret Files. New York: New York Review of Books.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nordhaus, W., 1975. The Political Business Cycle. Review of Economic Studies 42: 169-190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba, J., 1994. State Responses to Fiscal Crises: The Effects of Budgetary Institutions and Politics. The Journal of Political Economy 102 (4): 799-821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rogoff, K., 1990. Equilibrium Political Budget Cycles. American Economic Review 80(1): 21-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rogoff, K., and A. Sibert, 1988. Elections and Macroeconomic Policy Cycles, The Review of Economic Studies 55(1): 1-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scholz, J. T., and B. D. Wood, 1998. Controlling the IRS: Principals, Principles, and Public Administration. American Journal of Political Science 42(1): 141-162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shevlin, T., T. Y. H. Tang, and R. J. Wilson, 2012. Domestic Income Shifting by Chinese Listed Firms. The Journal of the American Taxation Association 34 (1): 1-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shih, V., C. Adolph, and M. Liu, 2012. Getting ahead in the Communist Party: Explaining the Advancement of Central Committee Members in China. American Political Science Review 106 (1): 166-187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shleifer, A. and R. W. Vishny, 1993. Corruption. Quarterly Journal of Economics 108: 599-617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slemrod, J., 2004. The economics of corporate tax selfishness. National Tax Journal 57: 877-899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, L., and H. Yue, 2009. Corporate Tax, Capital Structure and the Accessibility of Bank Loans: Evidence from China. Journal of Banking and Finance 33(1): 30-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, C., 2011. The Fundamental Institutions of China’s Reforms and Development. Journal of Economic Literature 49 (4): 1076-1151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, M., M. Reksulak, and W. F. Shughart II, 2001. The Political Economy of the IRS. Economics &amp; Politics 13(2): 201-220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
