<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>אגוד הבנקים בישראל</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">ג'</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</issue>
         <issue-id>i24010137</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24012142</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comments on the Report on the issue of and the Trade in Securities / הערות לדין וחשבון של הוועדה להנפקת ניירות-ערך והמסחר בהם</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>בנימין</given-names>
                  <surname>פרגאי</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
                  <surname>Pragay</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>1964</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>85</fpage>
         <lpage>87</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24012142"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Mr. Pragay claims that if the Report of the Committee on the Issue of and the Trade in Securities did not sufficiently stress the importance of the functions of a trustee in respect of securities issued. He maintains that the proposed legislation for a Securities Authority should define the rights and obligations of the trustee and the qualifications required of a person fulfilling this function. Such a definition is lacking in existing Israel commercial legislation. The writer is of the opinion that the trustee should be a juridical body rather than an individual. He suggests that any person or body promoting a debenture issue should be required to appoint a trustee and that every such contract of trusteeship should be authorized by the proposed Securities Authority. Furthermore, Mr. Pragay proposes that the trustee should be entirely independent of the issuer. Mr. Pragay stresses the need for the trustee to be held legally responsible for the results of his actions. The trustee should be required to present reports on his activities both to investors and the proposed Securities Authority. Finally, the writer emphasizes that any legislation in this field must respect the principle that all are equal in the eyes of the law. Hence each issue of Government Bonds must be specifically required to be under the supervision of an independent trutee just as is proposed for an issue of debentures by any legal entity.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>[הערות שוליים]</title>
        <ref id="d99e119a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d99e123" publication-type="other">
מר בנימין פרגאי הוא מנהל חברת נאמנות כללית בע"מ.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


