<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26840425</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Role of Piston Bowl Shape to Enhance Late-Cycle Soot Oxidation in Low-Swirl Diesel Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Eismark</surname>
                  <given-names>Jan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Mats</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Christensen</surname>
                  <given-names>Magnus</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Karlsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Anders</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Denbratt</surname>
                  <given-names>Ingemar</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26840424</issue-id>
         <fpage>233</fpage>
         <lpage>250</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26840425"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Late-cycle soot oxidation in heavy-duty (HD) diesel engine low-swirl combustion was investigated using single-cylinder engine and spray chamber experiments together with engine combustion simulations. The in-cylinder flow during interactions between adjacent flames (flame-flame events) was shown to have a large impact on late-cycle combustion. To modify the flame-flame, a new piston bowl shape with a protrusion (wave) was designed to guide the near-wall flow. This design significantly reduced soot emissions and increased engine thermodynamic efficiency. The wave’s main effect was to enhance late-cycle mixing, as demonstrated by apparent rate of heat release after the termination of fuel injection. Combustion simulations showed that the increased mixing is driven by enhanced flow re-circulation, which produces a radial mixing zone (RMZ). The leading edge of the RMZ extends toward the center of the piston bowl, where unused ambient gas is available, promoting oxidation. The wave also enhances mixing in the trailing edge of the RMZ when it detaches from the wall, accelerating the burn-out of the RMZ. This flame interaction effect was isolated and studied further using a new optical setup in a spray chamber with a 2-hole nozzle fuel injector. A conceptual model relating piston bowl geometry to soot oxidation efficiency was developed to explain late-cycle soot oxidation in low-swirl HD engines.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Engine Combustion Network (ECN), https://ecn.sandia.gov/ diesel-spray-combustion/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Dec, J.E., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging*,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Kosaka, H., Aizawa, T., and Kamimoto, T., “Two- Dimensional Imaging of Ignition and Soot Formation Processes in a Diesel Flame,” International Journal of Engine Research 6:21-42, 2005, doi:10.1243/146808705X7347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Eismark, J., Balthasar, M., Karlsson, A., Benham, T. et al., “Role of Late Soot Oxidation for Low Emission Combustion in a Diffusion-Controlled, High-EGR, Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2813, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Musculus, M. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Pickett, L. and Lopez, J., “Jet-Wall Interaction Effects on Diesel Combustion and Soot Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0921, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0921.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Genzale, C., Reitz, R., and Musculus, M., “Effects of Piston Bowl Geometry on Mixture Development and Late-Injection Low-Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):913-937, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Polonowski, C., Mueller, C., Gehrke, C., Bazyn, T. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-Cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):51-77, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Miles, P., “The Influence of Swirl on HSDI Diesel Combustion at Moderate Speed and Load,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1829, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1829.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Andersson, O., Somhorst, J., Lindgren, R., Blom, R. et al., “Development of the Euro 5 Combustion System for Volvo Cars’ 2.4L Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1450, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1450.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Dembinski, H. and Angstrom, H.-E., “Swirl and Injection Pressure Impact on After- Oxidation in Diesel Combustion, Examined with Simultaneous Combustion Image Velocimetry and Two Color Optical Method,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0913, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0913.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Lequien, G., Berrocal, E., Gallo, Y., Mello, A. et al., “Effect of Jet-Jet Interactions on the Liquid Fuel Penetration in an Optical Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1615, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Lequien, G., Andersson, O., Tunestal, P., and Lewander, M., “A Correlation Analysis of the Roles of Soot Formation and Oxidation in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2535, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Gallo, Y., Li, X., Richter, M., and Andersson, O., “Parameters Influencing Soot Oxidation Rates in an Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(4):2044-2055, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Solsjo, R., Jangi, M., Chartier, C., Andersson, O. et al., “Mixing in Wall-Jets in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine: A LES Study,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1127, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Ruth, D. and O'Connor, J., “Diesel Spray Penetration and Spreading during Wall Impingement,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0814, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Lee, J., Lee, S., Kim, J., and Kim, D., “Bowl Shape Design Optimization for Engine-Out PM Reduction in Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0789, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0789.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Pitsch, H., “Detailed Kinetic Reaction Mechanism for Ignition and Oxidation of α-Methylnaphthalene,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 26:721-728, 1996, doi:10.1016/S0082-0784(96)80280-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Pitsch, H., Barths, H., and Peters, N., “Three-Dimensional Modeling of NOx and Soot Formation in DI-Diesel Engines Using Detailed Chemistry Based on the Interactive Flamelet Approach,” SAE Technical Paper 962097, 1996, doi:10.4271/962057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Kosters, A. and Karlsson, A., “Validation of the VSB2 Spray Model against Spray A and Spray H,” Atomization and Sprays 26:775-798, 2016, doi:10.1615/ AtomizSpr.2015011670.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Balthasar, M., Magnusson, I., and Eismark, J., “Soot Modelling in HD Diesel Engine,” in Combustion Generated Fine Carbonaceous Particle: Proceedings of an International Workshop held in Villa Orlandi, Anacapri, May 13-16, 2007, 611-636.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Balthasar, M., “Detailed Soot Modelling in Laminar and Turbulent Reacting Flows,” Doctoral thesis, Lund University, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Eismark, J., Karlsson, A., Lindgren, R., Magnusson, A. et al., ”Role of Formation and Transportation of Hydroxyl Radicals for Enhanced Late Soot Oxidation in a Low Emissions Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” paper presented at in Thiesel 2010, Valencia, September 14-17, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Eismark, J., Hammas, M., Karlsson, A., Denbratt, I. et al., “Role of Turbulence for Mixing and Soot Oxidation for an Equivalent Diesel Gas Jet during Wall Interaction Studied with LES,” paper presented at in Thiesel 2012, Valencia, September 11-14, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Li, K., Ido, M., Ogata, Y., Nishida, K. et al., “Effect of Spray/ Wall Interaction on Diesel Combustion and Soot in Two- Dimensional Piston Cavity,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(4):2061-2071, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-32-9021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Volvo patent US8499735.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Siebers, D. and Higgins, B., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Sprays Under Quiescent Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0530, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Dempsey, A.B., Seiler, P., Svensson, K., and Qi, Y., “Evaluation of the Two-Step Hiroyasu Soot Model over a Broad Range of Diesel Combustion Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2018-01-0242, 2018, doi:10.4271/2018-01-0242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Wang, Z., Stamatoglou, P., Lundgren, M., Luise, L. et al., “Ultra-High Speed Fuel Tracer PLIF Imaging in a Heavy- Duty Optical PPC Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2018-01-0904, 2018, doi:10.4271/2018-01-0904.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Single-cylinder engine (SCE) hardware, instrumentation, and fuel specifications. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Normalized CFD RANS predictions of soot emissions with five different conventional piston bowl geometries [21]. The experimental results were obtained using a Volvo D12 SCE. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Schematic of the high-pressure/high-temperature spray chamber experimental setup. (a) Top view. (b) View through the spray chamber window as seen by the cameras. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Specification of the wall units and fuel injector used in the spray chamber. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Wall interaction units used with the 2-hole nozzle. The arrows indicate spray directions. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>SCE test results with conventional piston bowl shapes at 1500 rpm under partial load. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>SCE test results with conventional piston bowl shapes at 1500 rpm under full load. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>The O₂ field in the plane containing the two spray axes. The figure illustrates the formation of an RMZ during the 20 CAD period starting with the onset of the flame-flame event at 370 CAD. Red, blue/green, and yellow regions in the plots represent areas of pure ambient gas, rich mixtures, and stoichiometric mixtures, respectively. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Evolution of the fuel distribution (quantified in terms of the mixture fraction Z) in a double-sector simulation of rich pocket oxidation (i.e., the time between EOI+10 and EOI+60). Blue and red/green regions indicate volumes containing pure ambient gas and rich mixtures, respectively. The textured iso-surface shows where the mixture is stoichiometric. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Piston with wave-like protrusions [26]. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>RANS CFD velocity fields in the plane containing both spray-axes at 375 CAD during the initial flame-flame event. The dashed line indicates the system’s axis of symmetry. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Velocity flow fields formed with the conventional and wave-shaped bowls at EOI (380 CAD). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Development of the O₂ field in double-sector CFD simulations of combustion with the wave and conventional bowls. White dotted lines indicate possible oxygen-containing flow pathways. The color gradient has the same meaning as in Figure 6. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>The late-cycle (385 and 410 CAD) distribution of the mixture fraction Z in the conventional and wave bowls at high load based on double-sector CFD simulations. Blue and red/green regions indicate volumes containing pure ambient gas and rich mixtures, respectively. The textured iso-surface shows where the mixture is stoichiometric. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Evolution of the total mass of the rich mixture (a) and the soot mass (b) after SOI in engines fitted with conventional and wave bowls at high load according to double-sector CFD simulations. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Evolution of rates of soot formation and oxidation after SOI with the wave and conventional piston designs at high load based on double-sector CFD simulations. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>The effect of the wave shape on the aRoHR in SCE experiments at high load (1200 rpm). The ratio was calculated as Ratio = 100 ⋅ (aRoHR<sub>wave</sub> − aRoHR<sub>conv</sub>)/aRoHR<sub>conv</sub>. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Brake-specific soot and NOx emissions from the SCE when using the conventional and wave bowl shapes at 1200 rpm and loads of 25, 50, and 100%. The NOx level was controlled by varying the EGR rate. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Illustration of the coupling between initiation of the rich pocket oxidation phase and the change in the slope of the aRoHR curve at 390 CA. The change in slope is indicated with a green circle. The plotted results originate from CFD simulations of combustion at full load. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Results from the spray chamber setup with a two-hole nozzle (A) and the wave piston sector (profile B, see Figure 3d). Fuel injection with Prail = 1000 bar and 1 ms injection duration. The figure shows a time-series of instantaneous natural flame luminosity images acquired between 3.33 and 4.66 ms after EOI along the symmetry axis between the two sprays (C). The green dot and yellow arrows indicate the nozzle location and original spray axes, respectively. The letters D, E, F, and G indicate the RMZ, its leading and trailing edges, and an adjacent RMZ, respectively. Frame rate: 75000 frames per s (interval 13.31 ms). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Results from the spray chamber setup with a two-hole nozzle and 2D open wall setup. Fuel injection with Prail = 1000 bar and 1 ms injection duration. Mean OH chemilumiscence time series from 10 replicates. Upper row: conventional reference bowl (see Figure 3a); lower row: Wave piston shape (see Figure 3b). False color scale 0-255 relative light intensity. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Schematic of late-cycle mixing in low-swirl combustion. Left: conventional bowl; right: wave bowl. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>A typical high-load aRoHR curve with labels highlighting points corresponding to key events. Blue and green colors indicate events discussed in the introduction and events discussed in this article, respectively. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>SC results. Natural luminosity (false color scheme) showing a detached U-shaped RMZ above a wave-shaped protrusion. Dotted red line is the symmetry line. Blue dotted line is main jet trajectory. Injection pressure (500 bar). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE B.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Comparison of relative net soot emissions in B50 (1500 rpm, half load). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE B.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Comparison of relative net soot emissions in C100 (1800 rpm, full load). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
