<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465656</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465661</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Does Stock Liquidity Affect Incentives to Monitor? Evidence from Corporate Takeovers</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
                  <surname>Roosenboom</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Frederik P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Schlingemann</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Manuel</given-names>
                  <surname>Vasconcelos</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2392</fpage>
         <lpage>2433</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465661"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We test whether stock liquidity affects acquirer returns through its hypothesized effect on institutional monitoring. We find that firms with lower stock liquidity have higher acquirer gains for takeovers of private targets, but not for takeovers of public targets. The negative relation between liquidity and acquirer gains is stronger when the threat of disciplinary trading (exit) by institutions is weaker and acquirers have higher agency costs. Acquirers of private targets with lower stock liquidity are more likely to withdraw deals and experience higher involuntary CEO turnover following value-destroying acquisitions. Our results support the hypothesis that stock liquidity weakens institutions' incentives to monitor management decisions, except in those cases where the disciplining effect of the threat of exit may be particularly high.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d29e238a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e245" publication-type="other">
We do not view these results as consistent with a positive effect of stock liquidity on monitoring via voice (e.g.,
Faure-Grimaud and Gromb 2004), given that we find a negative relation between liquidity and announcement
returns for private acquisitions and that there is no theoretical prediction of the positive effect of liquidity on
voice being stronger in specific contexts, such as value-destroying acquisitions, as there is with the threat of exit
models.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e264a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e271" publication-type="other">
Note, though, that for a complete test of some of the other theories (e.g., Maug 1998) we would need an empirical
setup in which liquidity and institutional ownership are estimated jointly.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e281a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e288" publication-type="other">
Typically, this concern is addressed by employing an instrumental variable approach. Fang, Noe, and Tice
(2009), Fang, Tian, and Tice (2012), Bharath, Jayaraman, and Nager (2013), and Edmans, Fang, and Zur (2013)
use decimalization of stock prices as an instrument, but this is not feasible in our setting because ours is a
cross-sectional rather than a time-series analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e304a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e311" publication-type="other">
Fang, Tian, and Tice (2012) show that firm innovation diminishes with higher stock liquidity as ownership by
short-term oriented institutions increases. Note that their result is not inconsistent with exit models in which
blockholders are considered long-term institutions that have the option to exit in the short run, but will not exit
if managers maximize shareholder value.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e328a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e335" publication-type="other">
We follow the definition first introduced by Bushee (1998), and further developed in Bushee (2001), who uses
principal component analysis based on a large number of variables for this classification. An institution is labeled
transient if it belongs to the group with higher share turnover and less concentrated holdings. These data are
kindly made available by Brian Bushee on his website (http://acct3.wharton.upenn.edu/faculty/bushee/).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e351a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e358" publication-type="other">
A number of alternative measures of liquidity have been used in the literature. However, the theories on the effect
of liquidity on institutional monitoring imply that large shareholders are mostly concerned with the price impact
of their trades (e.g., Maug 1998), which is well captured by the Amihud (2002) measure (Goyenko, Holden,
and Trzcinka 2009). In addition, to the extent that the Amihud (2002) measure captures trading costs or price
informativeness, it can also be used to test the prediction in Admati and Pfleiderer (2009) of a negative relation
between trading costs and institutional monitoring, and the prediction in Faure-Grimaud and Gromb (2004) of a
positive relation between price informativeness and institutional monitoring.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e384a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e391" publication-type="other">
Given that, theoretically, illiquidity could be zero, the correct functional form is debatable. We therefore also
follow Chordia, Huh, and Subrahmanyam (2009) and Hasbrouck (1999, 2009) and employ a square root
transformation as a robustness check, and we find similar results. More details are provided in Section 4 of
the paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e407a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e414" publication-type="other">
We also consider a variable for the percentage of equity used in the transactions and an all-equity indicator
variable for pure equity deals and obtain similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e424a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e431" publication-type="other">
Execucomp collects as many as nine executives for a given year, with most firms reporting five. Hence, per
company, one could obtain several entries, depending on how many executives a company files in its proxy
statement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e444a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e451" publication-type="other">
When we estimate model (4) conditional on the availability of CEO Incentives, we find Stock Liquidity to be
insignificant, with a p-value similar to that in model (5). Adding CEO Incentives to the full sample regression
decreases the proportion of acquisitions of private targets. As shown in the next section, the coefficient on stock
liquidity remains significant at the 5% level when we add CEO Incentives to the specification for the sample of
acquisitions of private targets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e471a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e478" publication-type="other">
A private cost in this context may be the effort needed to screen out targets and negotiate better acquisition terms.
This private cost also exists in public acquisitions, but can be offset by the increased visibility and size (and
possibly compensation) that come with a public acquisition.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e491a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e498" publication-type="other">
Admati and Pfleiderer (2009) mention value-reducing mergers as an empirical example that corresponds to the
type of agency problem where the threat of exit is expected to be particularly effective.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e508a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e515" publication-type="other">
Ferreira, Ferreira, and Raposo (2011) measure price informativeness as the firm-specific stock return variation
calculated as the log (1 -R2/R2) where R2 is obtained from a regression regressing daily stock returns on the
daily returns of a value-weighted market index and asset-pricing factors. We use a period ending 46 days before
the announcement date with a minimum of 100 trading days and a maximum of 200 trading days. The three
asset-pricing factors we use are Fama and French's (1992) Small minus Big (SMB) and High minus Low (HML)
factors and the Carhart (1997) momentum factor.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e538a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e545" publication-type="other">
The mean (median) number of nontransient blockholders in the complete sample of acquisitions of private targets
is 1.66 (1.00) with 584 observations with zero blockholders.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e555a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e564" publication-type="other">
Alternatively, we use the magnitude of exit, measured as the number of shares sold by the largest blockholder
as a percentage of the total number of shares outstanding as the dependent variable. The coefficient on acquirer
stock liquidity for OLS specifications for the subsample of value-destroying deals is 0.024, but statistically
indistinguishable from zero (p-value = 0.268). The results for the OLS exit regressions are available upon
request. We thank the referee for suggesting the exit tests.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e583a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e590" publication-type="other">
We thank the referee for pointing this out.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e598a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e605" publication-type="other">
The empirical design in Parrino, Sias, and Starks (2003) is different from ours. They condition their sample on
CEO turnover and find that, prior to the forced CEO's departure, institutions on average sell shares. In our design,
we attempt to explain forced CEO departures through a shock (a value-destroying acquisition).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e618a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e625" publication-type="other">
We are very grateful to Dirk Jenter, Fadi Kanaan, Florian Peters, and Alexander Wagner for sharing with us their
hand-collected data on involuntary CEO turnover.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e635a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e642" publication-type="other">
We cannot run meaningful analyses of the partition based on the Number of Blockholders, as in previous
subsections, because of the far fewer observations for which we have CEO turnover information.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d29e661a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e665" publication-type="other">
Admati, A. R., and R Pfleiderer. 2009. The Wall Street walk and shareholder activism: Exit as a form of voice.
Review of Financial Studies 22:2645-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e679" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y. 2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: Cross-section and time-series effects. Journal of Financial Markets
5:31-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e689a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e693" publication-type="other">
Bharath, S. T., S. Jayaraman, and V. Nager. 2013. Exit as governance: An empirical analysis. Journal of Finance
68:2515^17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e703a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e707" publication-type="other">
Bhide, A. 1993. The hidden costs of stock market liquidity. Journal of Financial Economics 34:31-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e715a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e719" publication-type="other">
Bond, P., A. Edmans, and I. Goldstein. 2012. The real effects of financial markets. Annual Review of Financial
Economics 4:339-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e733" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M., S. Huh, and A. Subrahmanyam. Forthcoming. An analysis of the Amihud illiquidity premium.
Review of Asset Pricing Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e747" publication-type="other">
Burns, N., S. Kedia, and M. Lipson. 2010. Institutional ownership and monitoring: Evidence from financial
misreporting. Journal of Corporate Finance 16:443-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e761" publication-type="other">
Bushee, B. J. 1998. The influence of institutional investors on myopic R&amp;D investment behavior. Accounting
Review 73:305-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e771a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e775" publication-type="other">
. 2001. Do institutional investors prefer near-term earnings over long-run value? Contemporary
Accounting Review 18:207-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e785a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e789" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e797a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e801" publication-type="other">
Chang, S. 1998. Takeovers of privately held targets, methods of payment, and bidder returns. Journal of Finance
53:773-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e815" publication-type="other">
Chen, X., J. Harford, and K. Li. 2007. Monitoring: Which institutions matter? Journal of Financial Economics
86:279-305.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e829" publication-type="other">
Chordia, T., S. Huh, and A. Subrahmanyam. 2009. Theory-based illiquidity and asset pricing. Review of Financial
Studies 22:3629-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e843" publication-type="other">
Coffee, J. C. 1991. Liquidity versus control: The institutional investors as corporate monitor. Columbia Law
Review 91:1277-367.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e857" publication-type="other">
Core, J., and W. Guay. 2002. Estimating the value of employee stock option portfolios and their sensitivities to
price and volatility. Journal of Accounting Research 40:613-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e871" publication-type="other">
Demiralp, I., R. D'Mello, F. P. Schlingemann, and V. Subramaniam. 2011. Are there monitoring benefits
to institutional ownership? Evidence from seasoned equity offerings. Journal of Corporate Finance
17:1340-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e885a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e889" publication-type="other">
Duggal, R., and J. A. Millar. 1999. Institutional ownership and firm performance: The case of bidder returns.
Journal of Corporate Finance 5:103-17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e899a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e903" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A. 2009. Blockholder trading, market efficiency, and managerial myopia. Journal of Finance
64:2481-513.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e913a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e917" publication-type="other">
. 2013. Blockholders and corporate governance. Working Paper prepared for the Annual Review of
Financial Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e927a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e931" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., V. W. Fang, and E. Zur. 2013. The effect of liquidity on governance. Review of Financial Studies
26:1443-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e941a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e945" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., X. Gabaix, and A. Landier. 2009. A multiplicative model of optimal CEO Incentives in market
equilibrium. Review of Financial Studies 22:4881-917.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e955a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e959" publication-type="other">
Edmans, A., and G Manso. 2011. Governance through trading and intervention: A theory of multiple blockholders.
Review of Financial Studies 24:2396-428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e970a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e974" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1992. The cross-section of expected stock returns. Journal of Finance
47:427-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e984a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e988" publication-type="other">
. 1997. Industry costs of equity. Journal of Financial Economics 43:153-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e995a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e999" publication-type="other">
. 2002. Testing trade-off and pecking order predictions about dividends and debt. Review of Financial
Studies 15:1-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1009a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1013" publication-type="other">
Fang, V. W., T. H. Noe, and S. Tice. 2009. Stock market liquidity and firm value. Journal of Financial Economics
94:150-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1023a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1027" publication-type="other">
Fang, V. W., X. Tian, and S. Tice. 2012. Does stock liquidity enhance or impede firm innovation? Working Paper,
University of Minnesota.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1037a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1041" publication-type="other">
Faure-Grimaud, A., and D. Gromb. 2004. Public trading and private incentives. Review of Financial Studies
17:985-1014.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1052a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1056" publication-type="other">
Ferreira, D., M. A. Ferreira, and C. C. Raposo, 2011. Board structure and price informativeness. Journal of
Financial Economics 99:523-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1066a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1070" publication-type="other">
Fuller, K., J. Netter, and M. Stegemoller. 2002. What do returns to acquiring firms tell us? Evidence from firms
that make many acquisitions. Journal of Finance 57:1763-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1080a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1084" publication-type="other">
Gaspar, J.-M., M. Massa, and P. Matos. 2005. Shareholder investment horizons and the market for corporate
control. Journal of Financial Economics 76:135-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1094a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1098" publication-type="other">
Giroud, X., and H. M. Mueller. 2011. Corporate governance, product market competition, and equity prices.
Journal of Finance 66:563-600.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1108a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1112" publication-type="other">
Goyenko, R. Y., C. W. Holden, and C. A. Trzcinka. 2009. Do liquidity measures measure liquidity? Journal of
Financial Economics 92:153-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1122a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1126" publication-type="other">
Harford, J., D. Jenter, and K. Li. 2011. Institutional cross-holdings and their effect on acquisition decisions.
Journal of Financial Economics 99:27-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1137a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1141" publication-type="other">
Hasbrouck, J. 1999. The dynamics of discrete bid and ask quotes. Journal of Finance 54:2109—42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1148a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1152" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Trading cost and returns for U.S. equities: Estimating effective costs from daily data. Journal of
Finance 64:1479-512.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1162a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1166" publication-type="other">
Heiwege J., V. J. Intintoli, and A. Zhang, 2012. Voting with their feet or activism? Institutional investors' impact
on CEO turnover. Journal of Corporate Finance 18:22-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1176a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1180" publication-type="other">
Holmström, B., and J. Tirole. 1993. Market liquidity and performance monitoring. Journal of Political Economy
101:678-709.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1194" publication-type="other">
Jenter, D., and F. Kanaan. Forthcoming. CEO turnover and relative performance evaluation. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1201a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1205" publication-type="other">
Jenter, D., and K. Lewellen. 2012. Performance-induced CEO turnover. Working Paper, Stanford Graduate School
of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1216a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1220" publication-type="other">
Kahn, C., and A. Winton. 1998. Ownership structure, speculation, and shareholder intervention. Journal of
Finance 53:99-129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1230a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1234" publication-type="other">
Kau, J. B., J. S. Linck, and P. H. Rubin. 2008. Do managers listen to the market? Journal of Corporate Finance
14:347-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1244a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1248" publication-type="other">
Lehn, K. M., and M. Zhao. 2006. CEO turnover after acquisitions: Are bad bidders fired? Journal of Finance
61:1759-811.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1258a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1262" publication-type="other">
Luo, Y. 2005. Do insiders learn from outsiders? Evidence from mergers and acquisitions. Journal of Finance
60:1951-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1272a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1276" publication-type="other">
Masulis, R. W., C. Wang, and F. Xie. 2007. Corporate governance and acquirer returns. Journal of Finance
62:1851-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1290" publication-type="other">
Matvos, G, and M. Ostrovsky. 2008. Cross-ownership, returns and voting in mergers. Journal of Financial
Economics 89:391-403.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1305" publication-type="other">
Maug, E. 1998. Large shareholders as monitors: Is there a trade-off between liquidity and control? Journal of
Finance 53:65-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1319" publication-type="other">
McCahery, J. A., Z. Sautner, and L. T. Starks. 2010. Behind the scenes: The corporate governance preferences
of institutional investors. Working Paper, University of Texas.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1333" publication-type="other">
Moeller, S. B., F. P. Schlingemann, and R. M. Stulz. 2004. Firm size and the gains from acquisitions. Journal of
Financial Economics 73:201-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1343a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1347" publication-type="other">
. 2005. Wealth destruction on a massive scale? A study of acquiring-firm returns in the recent merger
wave. Journal of Finance 60:757-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1357a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1361" publication-type="other">
Morck, R., A. Shleifer, and R. W. Vishny. 1988. Management ownership and market valuation: An empirical
analysis. Journal of Financial Economics 20:293-315.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1375" publication-type="other">
. 1990. Do managerial objectives drive bad acquisitions? Journal of Finance 45:31-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1383a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1387" publication-type="other">
Netter, J., M. Stegemoller, and M.B. Wintoki. 2011. Implications of data screens on merger and acquisition
analysis: A large sample study of mergers and acquisitions from 1992 to 2009. Review of Financial Studies
24:2316-57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1404" publication-type="other">
Noe, T. H. 2002. Investor activism and financial market structure. Review of Financial Studies 15:289-318.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1411a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1415" publication-type="other">
Norli, O., C. Ostergaard, and I. Schindele. 2010. Liquidity and shareholder activism. Working Paper, Norwegian
School of Management.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1429" publication-type="other">
Parrino, R. 1997. CEO turnover and outside succession: A cross-sectional analysis. Journal of Financial
Economics 46:165-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1443" publication-type="other">
Parrino, R., R. W. Sias, and L. T. Starks. 2003. Voting with their feet: Institutional ownership changes around
forced CEO turnover. Journal of Financial Economics 68:3-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1457" publication-type="other">
Peters, F. S., and A. F. Wagner. 2012. The executive turnover premium. Working Paper, University of Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1465a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1469" publication-type="other">
Roll, R. 1986. The hubris hypothesis of corporate takeovers. Journal of Business 59:197-216.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e1476a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1480" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A., and R. W. Vishny. 1986. Large shareholders and corporate control. Journal of Political Economy
94:461-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


