<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278045</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Desulfation of Pd-based Oxidation Catalysts for Lean-burn Natural Gas and Dual-fuel Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ottinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Nathan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Veele</surname>
                  <given-names>Rebecca</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuanzhou</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Liu</surname>
                  <given-names>Z. Gerald</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Cummins Emission Solutions</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278043</issue-id>
         <fpage>1472</fpage>
         <lpage>1477</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278045"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Lean-burn natural gas (NG) engines are used world-wide for both stationary power generation and mobile applications ranging from passenger cars to Class 8 line-haul trucks. With the recent introduction of hydraulic fracturing gas extraction technology and increasing availability of natural gas, these engines are receiving more attention. However, the reduction of unburned hydrocarbon emissions from lean-burn NG and dual-fuel (diesel and natural gas) engines is particularly challenging due to the stability of the predominant shortchain alkane species released (e.g., methane, ethane, and propane). Supported Pd-based oxidation catalysts are generally considered the most active materials for the complete oxidation of low molecular weight alkanes at temperatures typical of lean-burn NG exhaust. However, these catalysts rapidly degrade under realistic exhaust conditions with high water vapor concentrations and traces of sulfur. The impact of sulfur poisoning and the regeneration of the degraded Pd-based oxidation catalyst by thermal and reductive regeneration were investigated. Thermal regenerations beginning at 500°C recover some catalyst performance when performed in the absence of sulfur. However, in an exhaust environment, where sulfur is always present at trace levels, thermal regeneration may prove impractical. Reductive regenerations successfully remove sulfur and recover catalyst activity, with sulfur removal occurring rapidly in the complete absence of O₂.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, R. B., Stein, K. C., Feenan, J. J., Hofer, L. E.,“Catalytic Oxidation of Methane,” Ind. Eng. Chem. 53(10):1961, 809-812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., Urbano, F. J., Loader, P. K., “Methane Combustion over Palladium Catalysts: The Effect of Carbon Dioxide and Water on Activity,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen. 123(1):1995, 173-184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwartz, W. R., Ciuparu, D., Pfefferle, L. D., “Combustion of Methane over Palladium-based Catalysts: Catalytic Deactivation and Role of the Support,” J. Phys. Chem. 116(15):2012, 8587-8593, doi:10.1021/jp212236e.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ribiero, F. H., Chow, M., Dallabetta, R. A., “Kinetics of the Complete Oxidation of Methane over Supported Palladium Catalysts,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen. 146(2):1994, 537-544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrauto, R. J., Hobson, M. C., Kennelly, T., Waterman, E. M., “Catalytic Chemistry of Supported Palladium for Combustion of Methane,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen. 81:1992, 227-237.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Castellazzi, P., Groppi, G., Forzatti, P., “Effect of Pt/Pd Ratio on Catalytic Activity and Redox Behavior of Bimetallic Pt-Pd/Al2O3 Catalysts for CH4 Combustion,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 95:2010, 303- 311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lampert, J. K., Kazi, M. S., Farrauto, R. J., “Palladium Catalyst Performance for Methane Emissions Abatement from Lean Burn Natural Gas Vehicles,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 14:1997, 211-223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corro, G., Cano, C., Fierro, J., “A Study of Pt-Pd/Al2O3 Catalysts for Methane Oxidation Resistant to Deactivation by Sulfur Poisoning,” J. Mol. Catal. A: Chem. 315:2010, 35-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jones, J. M., Dupont, V. A., Brydson, R., Fullerton, D. J., Nasri, N. S., Ross, A. B., Westwood, A., “Sulphur Poisoning and Regeneration of Precious Metal Catalyzed Methane Combustion,” Catal. Today 81:2003, 589-601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Z., Ottinger, N., and Cremeens, C., “Methods for Quantifying the Release of Vanadium from Engine Exhaust Aftertreatment Catalysts,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):663-671, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ottinger, N., Foley, B., Xi, Y., and Liu, Z., “Impact of Hydrocarbons on the Dual (Oxidation and SCR) Functions of Ammonia Oxidation Catalysts,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(3):1262-1268, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoyos, L. J., Praliaud, H., Primet, M., “Catalytic Combustion of Methane over Palladium Supported on Alumina and Silica in Presence of Hydrogen Sulfide,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen. 98:1993, 125-138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arosio, F., Colussi, S., Groppi, G., Trovarelli, A., “Regeneration of S-poisoned Pd/Al2O3 Catalysts for the Combustion of Methane,” Catal. Today 117:2006, 569-576.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ottinger, N. A., Toops, T. J., Pihl, J. A., Roop, J. T., Choi, J-S., Partridge, W. P., “Sulfate Storage and Stability on Representative Lean NOx Trap Components,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 117:2012, 167-176, doi:10.1016/j.apcatb.2011.12.044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, R. J., Crozier, P. A., Smith, C. M., Hucul, D. A., Blackson, J., Salaita, G., “Metal Sintering Mechanisms and Regenerations of Palladium/Alumina Hydrogenation Catalysts,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen. 282: 2005, 111-121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
