<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278375</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of the Load Limits and Emissions of a Naturally-Aspirated Direct-Injection Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Northrop</surname>
                  <given-names>William F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Minnesota (former GM Employee)</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Torres</surname>
                  <given-names>Alejandro Plazas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Szymkowicz</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Company</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>May 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278342</issue-id>
         <fpage>493</fpage>
         <lpage>503</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278375"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Cost and robustness are key factors in the design of diesel engines for low power density applications. Although compression ignition engines can produce very high power density output with turbocharging, naturally-aspirated (NA) engines have advantages in terms of reduced cost and avoidance of system complexity. This work explores the use of direct injection (DI) and exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) in NA engines using experimental data from a single-cylinder research diesel engine. The engine was operated with a fixed atmospheric intake manifold pressure over a map of speed, air to fuel ratio, EGR, fuel injection pressure and injection timing. Conventional gaseous engine-out emissions were measured along with high speed cylinder pressure data to show the load limits and resulting emissions of the NA-DI engine studied. Well known reductions in NO<sub>X</sub>with increasing levels of EGR were confirmed with a corresponding loss in peak power output. However, advancing fuel injection timing is shown to partially offset this disadvantage at the cost of higher engine noise. Partially premixed low temperature combustion (LTC) can be used over a portion of the operating range, further lowering the engine-out emissions of soot and NO<sub>X</sub>. Since aftertreatment catalysts to reduce tailpipe NO<sub>X</sub>and soot add cost and complexity to diesel engine-powered vehicles, the extensive use of EGR may have advantages for low power density NA diesel engines designed for low cost vehicle markets or for electrical power generation in range-extended electric vehicles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alkidas, A. and Cole, R., “Gaseous and Particulate Emissions from a ingle - Cylinder Divided-Chamber Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical aper 831288, 1983, doi:10.4271/831288.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carstens, U., Isik, T., Biaggini, G., and Cornetti, G., “Sofim Small igh-Speed Diesel Engines-D. I. Versus I. D. I.,” SAE Technical Paper 810481, 1981, doi:10.4271/810481.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Monaghan, M., “The High Speed Direct Injection Diesel for Passenger ars,” SAE Technical Paper 810477, 1981, doi:10.4271/810477</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, John iley and Sons, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, R. and Luo, Y., “Control System Development for the Diesel PU in Off-Road Hybrid Electric Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4209, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Syles, D., Ratowski, J., “Development of a Lightweight, Multi Fuel- apable, 30-kwe APU for Non-Primary Power,” Proceedings of the 2009 Ground Vehicle Systems Engineering and Technology Symposium (GVSETS), 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Celıkten, I., “An Experimental Investigation of the Effect of the njection Pressure on Engine Performance and Exhaust Emission in ndirect Injection Diesel Engines,” Applied Thermal Engineering 23, pp: 2051-2060, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T.V., “Review of diesel emission and control,” International ournal of Engine Research, 2009, Vol. 10, pg: 275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petkar, R., Chougule, N., Rakhesh, B., and Bakare, A., “Development of Naturally Aspirated 3L DI Engine Compliant to Bharat stage-III orms (A Low Cost Solution),” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0074, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta, M., Hernandez, J. J., Gimenez, F., “Evaluation of exhaust gas ecirculation as a technique for reducing diesel engine NOx emissions,” roceedings of the Institute of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of utomobile Engineering 2000 214:85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Li, T., Miyamoto, N., “Characteristics of low temperature nd low oxygen diesel combustion with ultra-high exhaust gas,” nternational Journal of Engine Research, 2007, Vol.8, pg:365</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Enomoto, T., Nagano, H., Hagihara, Y., Koyama, T., “Thermal load in .I. diesel engine under EGR operation-measurements of steady state emperature of combustion chamber wall surface and intake gas emperature,” JSAE Review, pp 225-231, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hillion, M., Chauvin, J., Grondin, O., and Petit, N., “Active Combustion ontrol of Diesel HCCI Engine: Combustion Timing,” SAE Technical aper 2008-01-0984, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedrich, I., Liu, C.S., Oehlerking, D., “Coordinated EGR-Rate Model- ased Controls of Turbocharged Diesel Engines via an Intake Throttle nd an EGR Valve”, IEEE Technical Paper 978-1-4244-2601-0/09, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., Advanced Compression-Ignition Engines - Understanding the n-Cylinder Processes”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 32, pp 2727-2742, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diwakar, R. and Singh, S., “Importance of Spray-Bowl Interaction in a I Diesel Engine Operating under PCCI Combustion Mode,” SAE echnical Paper 2009-01-0711, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0711.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kerekes, J., Ohoka, S., and Horada, O., “The Design Concept of the uramax 6600 Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-2703, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-2703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stivender, D., “Development of a Fuel-Based Mass Emission easurement Procedure,” SAE Technical Paper 710604, 1971, doi: 10.4271/710604.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Butterworth, S., “Theory of Filter Amplifiers,” Experimental Wireless nd the Wireless Engineer, October, 1930, pp. 536-541.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H. and Mirsky, W., “Schlieren-Streak Measurements of nstantaneous Exhaust Gas Velocities from a Spark-Ignition Engine,” AE Technical Paper 741015, 1974, doi:10.4271/741015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S. et al., “Mechanism of he Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” AE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Badami, M., Mallamo, F., Millo, F., and Rossi, E., “Influence of ultiple Injection Strategies on Emissions, Combustion Noise and SFC of a DI Common Rail Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0503, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, T.J., Assanis, D.N., “Attainment of Premixed Compression gnition Combustion in a Compression Ignition Direct Injection ngine”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 31, pp 2913-2920, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
