<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">reviespafinacont</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50009991</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administarción de Empresas</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02102412</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">34</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">126</issue>
         <issue-id>i40105588</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">42782414</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Análisis de los efectos de las correlaciones bursátiles en la composición de carteras óptimas / Analyzing the effects of stock markets correlations on the composition of the optimal portfolios</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>José Luís Miralles</given-names>
                  <surname>Marcelo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>José Luis Miralles</given-names>
                  <surname>Quirós</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2005</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2005</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>689</fpage>
         <lpage>708</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2001 Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administración de Empresas</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/42782414"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>El objetivo de este trabajo es analizar la evolución de las relaciones existentes entre ocho de los principales índices bursátiles, y sus efectos sobre la composición de las carteras óptimas de los inversores, en el período que transcurre entre los años 1995 y 2002. La división del trabajo en dos períodos (antes y durante la crisis de los mercados referentes de la Nueva Economía) y la utilización de diferentes contrastes econométricos que parten del análisis de las correlaciones entre los índices, permiten determinar los efectos de la globalization en los mercados bursátiles y en los inversores. Los resultados obtenidos evidencian un claro aumento de la correlación entre los mercados bursátiles europeos, del mismo modo que muestran cómo los índices Dow y Dax se convierten en las principales referencias a nivel mundial, sobre todo en el período de crisis, dadas sus condiciones de potencias económicas. The objective of this work is to analyze the evolution of the existing relations between eight of the main stock-exchange indices, and its effects on composition of the optimal portfolios of the investors, in the period that passes between years 1995 and 2002. The division of the work in two periods (before and during the crisis of the referring markets of the New Economy) and the use of different econometric techniques that begin from the analysis of the correlations between the indices, allow to determine the effects of the globalization in the stock markets and the investors. The obtained results demonstrate a clear increase of the correlation between the European stock markets, in the same way that show as the indices Dow and Dax become the main references to world-wide level, mainly in the period of crises, given their conditions of economic powers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>spa</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1359e257a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1359e264" publication-type="other">
Sander y Kleimeier [2003].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>BIBLIOGRAFÍA</title>
        <ref id="d1359e280a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e284" publication-type="other">
Arbelaez, H.; Urrutia, J., y Abbas, N. [2001]: «Short-term and Long-term Linkages among the Colombian
Capital Market Indexes», International Review of Financial Analysis, 10, pp. 237-273.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e298" publication-type="other">
Arshanapalu, B., y Doukas, J. [1993]: «International Stock Market Linkages: Evidence from the Pre and
Post-October 1987 Period», Journal of Banking and Finance, 17, pp. 193-203.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e312" publication-type="other">
Bae, K. H., y Karolyi, G. A. [1994]: «Good News, Bad News and International Spillovers of Stock Return
Volatility between Japan and the U.S.», Pacific Basin Finance Journal, 2, pp. 405-438.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e326" publication-type="other">
Bollerslev, T [1986]: «Generalized Autoregressive Conditional Heteroskedasticity», Journal of
Econometrics, 31, February, pp. 307-327.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e341" publication-type="other">
Booth, G. G.; Martikainen, T., y Tse, Y. [1997]: «Price and Volatility Spillovers in Scandinavian Stock
Markets», Journal of Banking and Finance, 21, pp. 811-823.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e355" publication-type="other">
Calvo, S., y Reinhart, C. M. [1996]: «Capital flows to Latin America: Is there evidence of contagion effects?»,
en Calvo, Guillermo A.; Goldstein, Morris, and Hochreiter, Eduard, eds.: Private Capital Flows to Emerging
Markets After the Mexican Crisis (Institute for International Economics, Washington, D.C.).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e372" publication-type="other">
Chen, G. M.; Firth, M., y Rui, O. M. [2002]: «Stock Markets Linkages: Evidence from Latin America»,
Journal of Banking and Finance, 26, pp. 1113-1141.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e386" publication-type="other">
Chowdhury, A. R. [1994]: «Stock Markets Interdependences: Evidence from the Asian NIEs», Journal
of Macroeconomics, 16, pp. 629-651.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e400" publication-type="other">
Christofi, A., y Pericli, A. [1999]: «Correlation in Prices Changes and Volatility of Major Latin American
Stock Markets», Journal of Multinational Financial Management, 9, pp. 79-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e410a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e414" publication-type="other">
Chun, P. J., y Liu, D. J. [1994]: «Common Stochastic Trends in Pacific Rim Stock Markets», Quarterly
Review of Economics and Finance, 34, pp. 241-259.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e429" publication-type="other">
Climent, F., y Meneu, V. [2002]: «Has 1997 Asian Crisis Increased Information Flows between
International Markets», International Review of Economics and Finance, 171, pp. 1-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e443" publication-type="other">
Corhay, A.; Tourani, A., y Urbain, J. P. [1993]: «Common Stochastic Trends in European Stock Markets»,
Economic Letters, 42, pp. 385-390.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e457" publication-type="other">
Dickey, D. A., y Fuller, W. A. [1979]: «Distribution of the Estimators for Autoregressive Time Series with
a Unit Root», Journal of the American Statistical Association, 74, pp. 427-431.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e471" publication-type="other">
Edwards, S. [1998]: Interest rate volatility, capital controls, and contagion, Working Paper 6756, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e482" publication-type="other">
Engle, R. F. [1982]: «Autoregressive Conditional Heteroskedasticity with Estimates of the variance of
U.K. Inflation», Econométrica, 50, pp. 987-1008.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e492a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e496" publication-type="other">
Engle, R. E., y Granger, C. W. J. [1987]: «Cointegration and Error-correction: Representation, Estimation
and Testing», Econometrica, 55, pp. 251-276.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e507a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e511" publication-type="other">
Eun, C., y Shim, S. [1989]: «International Transmission of Stock Markets Movements», Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 24, pp. 241-246.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e521a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e525" publication-type="other">
Ferruz, L.; Marco, I., y Rivas, F. J. [2000]: «Evolución y Comparación de la Volatilidad de los principales
índices bursátiles internacionales», Actualidad Financiera, agosto, pp. 15-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e535a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e539" publication-type="other">
Forbes, K. J., y Rigobon, R. [2002]: «No Contagion, Only Interdependence: Measuring Stock Markets
Comovements», The Journal of Finance, vol 57, n. 5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e549a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e553" publication-type="other">
García Pascual, A. [2002]: «Assesing European Stock Markets (Co)Integration», Economics Letters, 1,
pp. 1-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e563a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e567" publication-type="other">
Gonzalo, J. [1994]: «Five Alternative Methods of Estimating Long Run Equilibrium Relationships»,
Journal of Econometrics, 60, pp. 203-233.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e577a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e581" publication-type="other">
Granger, C. W. J. [1969]: «Investigating Causal Relations by Econometrics Models and Cross-spectral
Methods», Econometrica, 37, pp. 424-438.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e592a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e596" publication-type="other">
--- [1988]: «Some Recent Development in an Concept of Causality», Journal of Econometrics, 39,
pp. 199-211.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e606a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e610" publication-type="other">
Harvey, C. R. [1991]: «The World Price of Covariance Risk», Journal of Finance, 46, pp. 111-157.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e621" publication-type="other">
Hamao, Y.; Masulis, R. W., y Ng, V. [1990]: «Correlations in Price Changes and Volatility across
International Stock Markets», The Review of Financial Studies, vol. 3, n. 2, pp. 281-307.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e631a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e635" publication-type="other">
Hansen, H., y Johansen, S. [1998]: Some Tests for Parameter Constancy in Cointegrated VAR-Models
(Mimeo).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e645a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e649" publication-type="other">
Huang, B. N.; Yang, C. W., y Hu, J. W. S. [2000]: «Causality and Cointegration of Stock Markets among
the United States, Japan and the South China Growth Triangle», International Review of Financial
Analysis, vol. 9, n. 3, pp. 281-297.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e662a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e666" publication-type="other">
Johansen, S. [1991]: «Estimation and Hypothesis Testing of Cointegration Vectors in Gaussian Vector
Autorregression Models», Econometrica, 59, pp. 1551-1580.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e677a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e681" publication-type="other">
Johansen, S., y Joselius, K. [1990]: «Maximun Likelihood Estimation and Inference on Cointegration with
Applications to Money Demand», Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 52, pp. 169-210.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e691a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e695" publication-type="other">
Kasa, K. [1992]: «Common Stochastic Trends in International Stock Markets», Journal of Monetary
Economics, 29, pp. 95-124.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e705a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e709" publication-type="other">
King, M., Sentana, E., y Wadhwani, S. [1994]: «Volatility and Links between National Stock Markets»,
Econometrica, vol. 62, n. 4, pp. 901-933.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e719a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e723" publication-type="other">
Koutmos, G., y Booth, G. G. [1995]: «Asymetric Volatility Transmission in International Stock Markets»,
Journal of International Money and Finance, 14, pp. 747-762.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e733a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e737" publication-type="other">
Liljeblom, E.; Löflund, A., y Krokfors, S. [1997]: «The Benefits from International Diversification for
Nordic Investors», Journal of Banking and Finance, 21, pp. 469-490.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e747a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e751" publication-type="other">
Longin, F. M., y Solnik, B. [1995]: «Is the correlation in international equity returns constant: 1960-
1990?», Journal of International Money and Finance, 14, pp. 3-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e762a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e766" publication-type="other">
Malliaris, A. G., y Urrutia, J. L. [1992]: «The International Crash of October 1987: Causality Tests»,
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 27, pp. 353-364.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e776a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e780" publication-type="other">
Masih, R., y Masih, A. M. M. [2001]: «Long and Short Term Dynamic Causal Transmission Amongst
International Stock Markets», Journal of International Money and Finance, 20, pp. 563-587.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e790a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e794" publication-type="other">
--- [2002]: «Propagative Causal Price Transmission among International Stock Markets: Evidence from
the Pre- and Post Globalization Period», Global Finance Journal 13, pp. 63-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e804a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e808" publication-type="other">
Mackinnon, J. G. [1991]: «Critical Values for Cointegration Tests», Long-run Economic Relationships:
Readings in Cointegration, Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e818a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e822" publication-type="other">
Meric, G.; Leal, R.; Ratner, M., y Meric, I. [2001]: «Co-movements of U.S. and Latin American Equity
Markets Before and After the 1987 Crash», International Review of Financial Analysis, 10, pp. 219-
235.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e835a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e839" publication-type="other">
Nelson, D. [1991]: «Conditional Heteroskedasticity in Asset Returns: A New Approach», Econometrica,
59, pp. 347-370.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e850a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e854" publication-type="other">
Osterwald-Lenum, M. [1992]: «A Note with Quantiles of the Asymptotic Distribution of the Maximum
Likelihood Cointegration Rank Test Statistics», Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 54, 461-472.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e864a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e868" publication-type="other">
Peiró, A.; Quesada, J., y Uriel, E. [1998]: «Transmission of Movements in Stock Markets», The european
Journal of Finance, 4, pp. 331-343.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e878a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e882" publication-type="other">
Phillips, P. C. B., y Perron, P. [1988]: «Testing for a Unit Root in Time Series Regression», Biometrika,
75, pp. 335-346.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e892a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e896" publication-type="other">
Rangvid, J. [2001]: «Increasing Convergence among European Stock Markets? A Recursive Common
Stochastic Trend Analysis», Economics Letters, 71, pp. 383-389.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e906a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e910" publication-type="other">
Ratanapakorn, O., y Sharma, S. C. [2002]: «Interrelationships among Regional Stock Indices», Review of
Financial Economics, 11, pp. 91-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e924" publication-type="other">
Sander, H., y Kleimeier, S. [2003]: «Contagion and Causality: An Empirical Investigation of Four Asian
Crisis Episodes», International Financial Markets, Institutions and Money, 13, pp. 171-186.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e935a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e939" publication-type="other">
Shawky, H. A.; Kuenzel, R., y Mikhail, A. D. [1997]: «International Portfolio Diversification: A Synthesis
and an Update», Journal of International Financial Markets, Institutions and Money, 7, pp. 303-327.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e949a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e953" publication-type="other">
Sheng, H., y Tu, A. H. [2000]: «A Study of Cointegration and Variance Decomposition among Nationall
Equity Indices nefore and during the Period of the Asian Financial Crisis», Journal of Multinantional
Financial Management, 10, pp. 345-365.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1359e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1359e970" publication-type="other">
Solnik, B. H.; Boucrelle, C., y Fur, Y. Le [1996]: «International Market Correlation and Volatility»,
Financial Analyst Journal, 52, pp. 17-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


