<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440106</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tax and the Crisis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <surname>Keen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
                  <surname>Klemm</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Victoria</given-names>
                  <surname>Perry</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">31</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440103</issue-id>
         <fpage>43</fpage>
         <lpage>79</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2010</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440106"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Did taxation play any role in precipitating the financial crisis? Are there lessons to be drawn for future tax reform priorities? This paper reviews the main channels by which tax effects might have been felt and which may require forceful attention. These include in particular the large tax biases favouring debt finance and, in some countries, investment in housing. The complexities of national tax codes, and the international interaction between them, have, moreover, encouraged the use of complicated financial instruments and international tax planning, reducing transparency. Tax distortions did not cause the crisis – in the sense that there are no obvious tax changes likely to have triggered it – but they may well have contributed by leading to higher leverage and more complexity than would otherwise have been the case. Most of these distortions have long been a source of concern, but dealing with them may be more important than previously supposed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d36e183a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e190" publication-type="other">
Submitted July 2009.
This is a revised version of International Monetary Fund (2009a). We have benefited greatly from the
comments and advice of Alan Auerbach, Carlo Cottarelli, Geoffrey Lloyd, Gareth Myles, John
Norregaard, Jeffrey Owens, Joel Slemrod and Peter Birch Sorensen, as well as those of many colleagues
at the IMF and seminar audiences in Milan and Toronto. Views expressed are ours alone, and should not
be attributed to the International Monetary Fund, its Executive Board or its management.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e213a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e220" publication-type="other">
This paper is based on International Monetary Fund (2009a), which was prepared, in early 2009, for
the Executive Directors of the IMF. An account of their views is at http://www.imf.org/external/np/sec/
pn/2009/pn0976.htm. For other discussions of tax issues raised by the crisis, see Lloyd (2009) and
Slemrod (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e236a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e243" publication-type="other">
The terms 'tax haven' and 'low-tax jurisdiction' are not used here synonymously; the former having
come to be associated with illegal concealment of income, we use the latter term to highlight the perfectly
legal avoidance opportunities that low tax rates (and/or narrow bases) may create: see Section IV.2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e256a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e263" publication-type="other">
The original rationale for this was a legalistic one, the view being that the corporation is so entwined
with its shareholders that payments to them should not be deductible, whereas payments on debt are to
true third parties and so should be. In economic terms, of course, both kinds of payment represent a return
to capital, and it is their combined treatment at corporate and personal levels that matters. Shaviro (2009)
discusses further.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e283a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e290" publication-type="other">
Davis and Stone (2004), for example, report a ratio of debt to the market value of equity of 28 per cent
for the non-financial corporate sector in the US in 1999, relative to a G7 median of 59 per cent. Reflecting
the magnitude of corporate liabilities, however, the ratio of corporate debt to GDP in the US, at 46 per
cent, is close to the G7 median of 50 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e306a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e313" publication-type="other">
That is, taking multiple interest deductions - by, for instance, borrowing in a (high-tax) country to
acquire equity in a subsidiary located in a low-tax jurisdiction that then lends to another subsidiary in a
third country (see Mintz (2004)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e326a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e333" publication-type="other">
Private equity and hedge funds are partnerships, so are taxed not at entity level but by 'flow through'
to the partners (raising issues related to the tax treatment of the general managers, which are discussed in
Section IV.4). Hedge funds typically do not push debt down to corporations, so this leverage issue does
not arise.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e349a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e356" publication-type="other">
For a more complete treatment, see, for instance, Auerbach (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e363a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e370" publication-type="other">
In addition, capital gains are often charged at a lower statutory rate the longer assets are held (as in the
US, and until 2008 in the UK and Germany); and, in the US, CGT can be avoided by holding assets until
death,</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e383a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e390" publication-type="other">
These were common in Europe, but have become less so in recent years, partly because of
complexities in dealing with cross-border investments but also as decisions of the European Court of
Justice have suggested that the Community's non-discrimination rules require member states to provide
credit for CIT paid in other member states. Australia and New Zealand retain full imputation, and Canada
partial.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e410a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e417" publication-type="other">
While practice varies, sovereign wealth funds are generally exempted on their passive investments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e424a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e431" publication-type="other">
Source: Office for National Statistics, 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e438a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e445" publication-type="other">
Analyses of the kind above leave unclear how equilibrium is reached in financial markets since
incentives for tax arbitrage - borrowing infinitely large amounts to pay infinitely large dividends, for
example - will remain unless tax rates happen to meet particular 'knife-edge' conditions for all investors.
Elements of an answer (which also revolves around the nature of any equilibrium, given for instance the
likely non-unanimity of shareholders with different tax positions as to the best policy for the firm to
pursue) include non-linearities in marginal tax rates (for example, progressivity of the personal tax, as
stressed in Miller (1977), and the effective rate of corporate tax falling as more debt is issued),
heterogeneity of risk attitudes across investors, and legal and other constraints on short selling (analysed,
for example, in Auerbach and King (1982)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e477a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e484" publication-type="other">
Defined, more precisely, as the proportion by which the pre-tax return on a project that the investor
just finds worthwhile exceeds the post-tax return they require.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e494a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e501" publication-type="other">
The former give the holder the option to convert to equity (and sometimes the issuer the option to call
the bond); the latter pay distributions at a fixed rate but allow the issuer to defer payment.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e511a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e518" publication-type="other">
Devereux et al. (2006) report a survey of finance officers as indicating that anti-avoidance legislation
adopted in the UK in 2005 has substantially reduced the use of hybrid entities and instruments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e529a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e536" publication-type="other">
Shaviro (2009) notes, for instance, that the US Congress instructed the Treasury to issue
comprehensive regulations setting out the tax distinction between the two in 1969: but, not for want of
trying, it has been unable to do so.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e549a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e556" publication-type="other">
Preferred securities are treated as Tier 2 capital if issued directly by the bank. If issued, however, by
a trust in which the bank has an interest, which then makes a loan to the bank, the interest is deductible to
the bank while Basel guidelines allow inclusion of the bank's equity interest in Tier 1 capital.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e569a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e576" publication-type="other">
De Meza and Webb (1987) and Stiglitz and Weiss (1981), for instance, derive contrasting results
from different assumptions on the joint distribution of projects' probability of success and return if
successful.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e589a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e596" publication-type="other">
There are no data on corporate leverage in Latvia during this period, though the financial and real-
estate sectors did become highly leveraged.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e606a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e613" publication-type="other">
Davis and Stone (2004), for instance, find that higher debt-equity ratios are associated with larger
post-crisis output declines, and Lall, Cardarelli and Elekdag (2008) find that the cumulative output loss
following periods of financial stress tends to be larger the greater the run-up in non-financial corporate
debt before the onset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e629a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e636" publication-type="other">
This and other issues in implementing an ACE are discussed in Griffith, Hines and Sorensen (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e644a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e651" publication-type="other">
See Klemm (2007); for Croatia, Keen and King (2002); for Italy, Bordignon, Giannini and
Panteghini (2001) and Staderini (2001), the latter finding reduced debt-equity ratios consequent on
movement to the partial ACE.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e664a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e671" publication-type="other">
See Bond and Devereux (2003). The use of a single notional rate, rather than one varying by firm or
sector, clearly also has the merit of simplicity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e681a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e688" publication-type="other">
A 'uniform cost of capital allowance' of this kind is proposed and discussed further by Kleinbard
(2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e698a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e705" publication-type="other">
Simulation results in de Mooij and Devereux (2009) suggest that unilateral movement to an ACE by
EU members would reduce corporate tax revenues by an average of 44 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e715a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e722" publication-type="other">
If, on the other hand, the normal return is subsidised (which, as noted above, may well be the case for
debt-financed investments), eliminating the distortion would increase tax revenue by more than labour
income falls: taxes could be cut so as to leave labour better off and tax revenue ultimately no lower.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e735a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e742" publication-type="other">
Since, given the dividend tax, not doing so would amount to double taxation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e750a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e757" publication-type="other">
These are stressed and discussed in Cottarelli and Vinals (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e764a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e771" publication-type="other">
As Slemrod (2009) notes, this latter 'lock-out' effect may be of some importance at present.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e778a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e785" publication-type="other">
In this area, tax rules generally follow accounting treatment.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e792a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e799" publication-type="other">
One such scheme, developed in Auerbach (1991), effectively charges tax on the excess of the actual
sale value over not the acquisition price but what that price would have been had the asset earned the risk-
free rate, in effect taxing only the normal return while leaving the realisation decision undistorted;
Auerbach and Bradford (2004) describe a more general class of schemes achieving the same effect.
Alworth, Arachi and Hamaui (2003) describe experience in Italy with schemes intended to mimic the
effects of taxation on accrual.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e822a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e829" publication-type="other">
As in International Monetary Fund (2009b) and the Turner Review (2009), for instance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e836a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e843" publication-type="other">
An incidental advantage of an1 ACE, for instance, is that tax incentives to overstate specific
provisions would in principle be eliminated, since any increased deduction from doing so would be offset
in PV by a reduction in Tier 1 capital and hence in the future imputed tax allowance on equity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e857a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e864" publication-type="other">
Several countries charge VAT on first sales of residences, which - to the extent that house prices are
the present value of housing services - amounts to an implicit tax on imputed rents, though one that is not
tailored to household circumstances in the same way that the income tax is.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e877a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e884" publication-type="other">
Taxation also affects other features of the housing market, not considered here - including the share
of housing in the aggregate capital stock.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e894a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e901" publication-type="other">
See Box 2 later.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e908a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e915" publication-type="other">
The comparison is with an idealised personal income tax 6f the type described above.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e922a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e929" publication-type="other">
This provided that any gain on disposal of a house would not be taxed if the proceeds were reinvested
in another property; so no tax liability arose as long as taxpayers traded up with each move.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e939a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e946" publication-type="other">
The UK phased out mortgage interest relief gradually. From 1983, the upper limit (of £30,000) was
frozen and hence slowly eroded by inflation. In 1991, relief was restricted to the basic rate of income tax
(25 per cent), then reduced to 20 per cent (1994), 15 per cent (1995) and 10 per cent (1998), before finally
being abolished in 2000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e963a1310">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e970" publication-type="other">
Tax issues raised by securitisation include: whether any gains on assets placed in the special purpose
vehicle by the originator are taxable; whether the SPV itself is taxable; and whether payments to holders
of the securitised assets will be taxed as interest or dividends.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e983a1310">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e990" publication-type="other">
investors paying tax on interest income at a rate higher than that at which they can offset capital
losses benefit by pooling assets to pay interest at a rate that reflects the expected losses. Investors facing
the same rate on both, on the other hand, do not care about the mix of interest and gains. Bringing the two
types together creates scope for tax arbitrage from which both can benefit, with a role too for the use of
credit default swaps. Eddin (2009) develops this argument.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1009a1310">
            <label>42</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1016" publication-type="other">
Neutrality argues against taxing intermediation of this kind. A coherent approach is to treat the SPV
itself on a flow-through basis, taxing instead at the level of the originator and security-holder.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1026a1310">
            <label>43</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1033" publication-type="other">
Controlled foreign corporation (CFC) rules aim to preclude this by bringing passive income into tax
even if not repatriated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1043a1310">
            <label>44</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1050" publication-type="other">
These are entities treated as a corporation in one country but as a branch or partnership (rather than
subsidiary) in another. For instance, a parent company can then locate in a low-tax jurisdiction a hybrid
that the home country treats not as a corporation (and hence is not subject to its CFC rules) but as a
branch of a corporation located in some third, high-tax jurisdiction. The parent then injects equity into the
hybrid, which lends to the high-tax affiliate. This generates interest deductions in the high-tax country,
but the interest received by the affiliate is not taxed by the home country until repatriated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1073a1310">
            <label>45</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1080" publication-type="other">
Pros and cons of international tax competition are reviewed in Keen (2008) and Wilson (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1088a1310">
            <label>46</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1095" publication-type="other">
See Janeba and Smart (2003) and Keen (2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1102a1310">
            <label>47</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1109" publication-type="other">
This is the case, for instance, with the potential inconsistencies that make possible the hybrid entity
(explained in footnote 44).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1119a1310">
            <label>48</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1126" publication-type="other">
As argued forcefully by Sinn (2008), for example.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1133a1310">
            <label>49</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1140" publication-type="other">
In the simplest case, the investor ends up bearing the same after-tax risk, with increased holding of
the asset offset by the reduced riskiness of its post-tax return.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1150a1310">
            <label>50</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1157" publication-type="other">
If denial of loss offset is used to finance a reduction in the tax rate, the increased after-tax return in
good states makes the effect ambiguous.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1167a1310">
            <label>51</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1174" publication-type="other">
Leasing, for instance, can be a way for companies to effectively trade in tax losses, with tax-paying
firms taking investment-related deductions that are then shared by leasing to tax-exhausted companies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1185a1310">
            <label>52</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1192" publication-type="other">
Subsequently reversed, though not retroactively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1199a1310">
            <label>53</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1206" publication-type="other">
The tax treatment described here is not universal, but is quite common.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1213a1310">
            <label>54</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1220" publication-type="other">
This is the case, for instance, in Belgium, Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy, Spain,
Sweden, the UK and the US.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1230a1310">
            <label>55</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1237" publication-type="other">
See Bond, Hawkins and Klemm (2005), who examine the effects on share prices of reductions in
stamp duty announced in 1984, 1986 and (though ultimately not implemented) 1990.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1247a1310">
            <label>56</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1254" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, Westerholm (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e1261a1310">
            <label>57</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e1268" publication-type="other">
The marginal cost of any form of finance today typically depends on the marginal source in the
future; the latter is assumed throughout this analysis to be retentions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d36e1287a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1291" publication-type="other">
Alworth, J., Arachi, G. and Hamaui, R. (2003), 'What's come to perfection perishes: adjusting
capital gains taxation in Italy', National Tax Journal, vol. 56, pp. 197-219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1305" publication-type="other">
Amromin, G., Harrison, P. and Sharpe, S. (2006), 'How did the 2003 dividend tax cut affect
stock prices?', Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago, Working Paper no. 2006-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1319" publication-type="other">
Arulampalam, W., Devereux, M. P. and Maffini, G. (2008), 'The direct incidence of corporate
income tax on wages', Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1329a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1333" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. J. (1991), 'Retrospective capital gains taxation', American Economic Review,
Papers and Proceedings, vol. 92, pp. 167-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1344a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1348" publication-type="other">
— (2002), 'Taxation and corporate financial policy', in A. J. Auerbach and M. Feldstein
(eds), Handbook of Public Economics, vol. 4, Amsterdam: North Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1358a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1362" publication-type="other">
— and Bradford, D. F. (2004), 'Generalized cash-flow taxation', Journal of Public
Economics, vol. 88, pp. 957-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1372a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1376" publication-type="other">
— and King, M. A. (1982), 'Corporate financial policy with personal and institutional
investors', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 17, pp. 259-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1386a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1390" publication-type="other">
Bank of England (2007), Financial Stability Review, issue 21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1397a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1401" publication-type="other">
— (2008), Financial Stability Review, issue 24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1408a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1412" publication-type="other">
Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (2008), Flow of Funds Accounts of the
United States, 11 December, at http://www.federalreserve.gov/releases/zl/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1423a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1427" publication-type="other">
Bond, S. R. and Devereux, M. P. (2003), 'Generalised R-based and S-based taxes under
uncertainty \ Journal of Public Economics, vol. 87, pp. 1291-311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1437a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1441" publication-type="other">
—, Hawkins, M. and Klemm, A. (2005), 'Stamp duty on shares and its effect on share prices',
FinanzArchiv, vol. 61, pp. 275-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1451a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1455" publication-type="other">
Bordignon, M., Giannini, S. and Panteghini, P. (2001), 'Reforming business taxation: lessons
from Italy?', International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 8, pp. 191-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1465a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1469" publication-type="other">
Büttner, T., Overesch, M., Schreiber, U. and Wamser, G. (2006), 'Taxation and capital
structure choice: evidence from a panel of German multinationals', CESifo, Working
Paper no. 1841.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1482a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1486" publication-type="other">
Cardarelli, R., Igan, D. and Rebucci, A. (2008), 'The changing housing cycle and the
implications for monetary policy', in World Economic Outlook, April, Washington, DC:
International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1499a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1503" publication-type="other">
Cheng, Y. and Green, C. J. (2008), 'Taxes and capital structure: a study of European
companies', The Manchester School, vol. 76, no. SI, pp. 85-115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1514a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1518" publication-type="other">
Cottarelli, C. and Vinals, J. (2009), 'A strategy for renormalizing fiscal and monetary policies
in advanced economies', International Monetary Fund, Staff Position Note SPN/09/22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1528a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1532" publication-type="other">
Davis, P. E. and Stone, M. R. (2004), 'Corporate financial structure and financial stability',
Journal of Financial Stability, vol. 1, pp. 65-91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1542a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1546" publication-type="other">
de Meza, D. and Webb, D. (1987), 'Too much investment: a problem of asymmetric
information', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 102, pp. 281-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1556a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1560" publication-type="other">
de Mooij, R. and Devereux, M. P. (2009), 'Alternative systems of business tax in Europe: an
applied analysis of ACE and CBIT reforms', European Commission Directorate General
for Taxation and Customs Union, Working Paper no. 17-2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1573a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1577" publication-type="other">
Desai, M. A., Foley, C. F. and Hines, J. R. (2004), 'A multinational perspective on capital
structure choice and internal capital markets', Journal of Finance, vol. 59, pp. 2451-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1587a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1591" publication-type="other">
Devereux, M. P., Griffith, R. and Klemm, A. (2002), 'Corporate income tax reforms and
international tax competition', Economic Policy, vol. 17, pp. 451-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1602a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1606" publication-type="other">
—, Mokkas, S., Pennock, J. and Wharrad, P. (2006), 'Interest deductibility for UK
corporation tax', Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1616a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1620" publication-type="other">
Dunsky, R. M. and Follain, J. R. (2000), 'Tax-induced portfolio reshuffling: the case of the
mortgage interest deduction', Real Estate Economics, vol. 28, pp. 683-718.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1630a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1634" publication-type="other">
Eddin, S. T. (2009), 'Tax arbitrage feedback theory', IronBridge Capital Management LP,
mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1644a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1648" publication-type="other">
European Central Bank (2006), Financial Stability Review, December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1655a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1659" publication-type="other">
Glaeser, E. L. and Shapiro, J. M. (2002), 'The benefits of the home mortgage interest
deduction', National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 9284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1669a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1673" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R. (2003), 'Taxes and corporate finance: a review', Review of Financial Studies,
vol. 16, pp. 1075-129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1684a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1688" publication-type="other">
Griffith, R., Hines, J. R. and Sorensen, P. B. (2008), 'International capital taxation', paper
prepared for the Report of a Commission on Reforming the Tax System for the 21st
Century, chaired by Sir James Mirrlees, http://www.ifs.org.uk/mirrleesreview/press_docs/
international.pdf; forthcoming in J. Mirrlees, S. Adam, T. Besley, R. Blundell, S. Bond,
R. Chote, M. Gammie, P. Johnson, G. Myles and J. Poterba (eds), Dimensions of Tax
Design: The Mirrlees Review, Oxford: Oxford University Press for Institute for Fiscal
Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1714a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1718" publication-type="other">
Hall, B. and Liebman, J. (2000), 'The taxation of executive options', Tax Policy and the
Economy, vol. 20, pp. 1—44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1728a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1732" publication-type="other">
Hassett, K. A. and Mathur, A. (2008), 'Taxes and wages', American Enterprise Institute,
mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1742a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1746" publication-type="other">
Hendershott, P., Price, G. and White, M. (2003), 'Household leverage and the deductibility of
home mortgage interest: evidence from UK house purchases', Journal of Housing
Research, vol. 14, pp. 49-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1759a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1763" publication-type="other">
Huizinga, H., Laeven, L. and Nicodeme, G. (2008), 'Capital structure and international debt
shifting', Journal of Financial Economics, vol. 88, pp. 80-118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1773a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1777" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund (2009a), 'Debt bias and other distortions: crisis-related issues in
tax policy', prepared by the Fiscal Affairs Department, 12 June, available at
http://www.imf.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1791a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1795" publication-type="other">
— (2009b), 'Lessons of the financial crisis for future regulation of financial institutions and
markets and for liquidity management', prepared by the Monetary and Capital Markets
Department, 4 February, available at http://www.imf.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1808a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1812" publication-type="other">
Janeba, E. and Smart, M. (2003), 'Is targeted tax competition less harmful than its remedies?',
International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 10, pp. 259-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1822a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1826" publication-type="other">
Johansson, A., Heady, C., Arnold, J., Brys, B. and Varita, L. (2008), 'Taxation and economic
growth', OECD Economics Department, Working Paper no. 620.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1836a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1840" publication-type="other">
Keen, M. (2001), 'Preferential regimes can make tax competition less harmful', National Tax
Journal, vol. 54, pp. 757-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1850a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1854" publication-type="other">
— (2008), 'Tax competition', in S. N. Durlauf and L. E. Blume (eds), The New Palgrave
Dictionary of Economics, second edition, London: Palgrave Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1864a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1868" publication-type="other">
— and King, J. (2002), 'The Croatian profit tax: an ACE in practice', Fiscal Studies, vol. 23,
pp. 401-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1879a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1883" publication-type="other">
— and Syed, M. (2006), 'Domestic taxes and international trade: some evidence',
International Monetary Fund, Working Paper no. 06/47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1893a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1897" publication-type="other">
Kleinbard, E. (2007), 'Designing an income tax on capital', in H. J. Aaron, L. Burman and E.
Steuerle (eds), Taxing Capital Income, Washington, DC: Urban Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1907a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1911" publication-type="other">
Klemm, A. (2007), 'Allowances for corporate equity in practice', CESifo Economic Studies,
vol. 53, pp. 229-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1921a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1925" publication-type="other">
Lall, S., Cardarelli, R. and Elekdag, S. (2008), 'Financial stress and economic downturns', in
World Economic Outlook, October, Washington, DC: International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1935a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1939" publication-type="other">
Lloyd, G. (2009), 'Moving beyond the crisis: using tax policy to support financial stability',
OECD, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1949a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1953" publication-type="other">
MacKie-Mason, J. (1990), 'Do taxes affect corporate financing decisions?', Journal of
Finance, vol. 45, pp. 1471-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1964a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1968" publication-type="other">
Meade, J. E. (1978), The Structure and Reform of Direct Taxation, Report of a Committee
chaired by Professor J. E. Meade, London: George Allen &amp; Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1978a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1982" publication-type="other">
Miller, M. H. (1977), 'Debt and taxes', Journal of Finance, vol. 32, pp. 261-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1989a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1993" publication-type="other">
Mintz, J. (2004), 'Conduit entities: implications of indirect tax-efficient financing structures
for real investment', International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 11, pp. 419-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2003a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2007" publication-type="other">
— and Weichenrieder, A. (2005), 'Taxation and the financial structure of German outbound
FDI', CESifo, Working Paper no. 1612.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2017a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2021" publication-type="other">
Morinobu, S. (2006), 'The rise and fall of the land myth in Japan: some implication to the
Chinese land taxation', Japanese Ministry of Finance, Research Department Policy
Research Institute, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2034a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2038" publication-type="other">
Mullins, P. (2006), 'Moving to territoriality? Implications for the US and the rest of the
world', Tax Notes International, 4 September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2049a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2053" publication-type="other">
OECD (1998), Harmful Tax Competition: An Emerging Global Issue, Paris: Organisation for
Economic Cooperation and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2063a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2067" publication-type="other">
Office for National Statistics (2007), Share Ownership: A Report on Ownership of UK Shares
as at 31s' December 2006, Norwich: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2077a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2081" publication-type="other">
Poterba, J. M. (2004), 'Taxation and corporate payout policy', American Economic Review,
vol. 94, pp. 171-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2091a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2095" publication-type="other">
— and Sinai, T. M. (2008), 'Income tax provisions affecting owner-occupied housing:
revenue costs and incentive effects', National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER),
Working Paper no. 14253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2108a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2112" publication-type="other">
Shaviro, D. (2009), Decoding the Corporate Tax, Washington, DC: Urban Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2119a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2123" publication-type="other">
Sinn, H.-W. (2008), 'The end of the wheeling and dealing', CESifo Forum, vol. 9, no. 4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2131a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2135" publication-type="other">
Slemrod, J. (2009), 'Lessons for tax policy in the great recession', National Tax Journal, vol.
62, pp. 387-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2145a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2149" publication-type="other">
Staderini, A. (2001), 'Tax reforms to influence corporate financial policy: the case of the
Italian business tax reform of 1997-98', Banca d'ltalia, Working Paper no. 423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2159a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2163" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J. and Weiss, A. (1981), 'Credit rationing in markets with imperfect information',
American Economic Review, vol. 71, pp. 393—410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2173a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2177" publication-type="other">
Turner Review (2009), A Regulatory Response to the Global Banking Crisis, London:
Financial Services Authority.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2187a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2191" publication-type="other">
UK House of Commons Treasury Committee (2007), Private Equity: Tenth Report of Session
2006-07, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2201a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2205" publication-type="other">
US Department of the Treasury (1992), Integration of the Individual and Corporate Tax
Systems: Taxing Business Income Once, Washington, DC: US Government Printing
Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2219a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2223" publication-type="other">
US Government Accountability Office (2008), Private Equity: Recent Growth in Leveraged
Buyouts Exposed Risks that Warrant Continued Attention, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2233a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2237" publication-type="other">
van den Noord, P. (2005), 'Tax incentives and house price volatility in the euro area: theory
and evidence', Economie internationale, vol. 101, pp. 29—45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2247a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2251" publication-type="other">
Weichenrieder, A. and Klautke, T. (2008), 'Taxes and the efficiency costs of capital
distortions', CESifo, Working Paper no. 2431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2261a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2265" publication-type="other">
Westerholm, J. (2003), 'The impact of transaction costs on turnover, asset prices and
volatility: the case of Sweden's and Finland's security transaction tax reductions', Finnish
Journal of Business Economics, vol. 2, pp. 213—41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e2278a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e2282" publication-type="other">
Wilson, J. D. (1999), 'Theories of tax competition', National Tax Journal, vol. 52, pp. 269-
304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
