<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278223</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Backward-Looking Simulation of the Toyota Prius and General Motors Two-Mode Power-Split HEV Powertrains</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Arata</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Leamy</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Meisel</surname>
                  <given-names>Jerome</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cunefare</surname>
                  <given-names>Kenneth</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Taylor</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Georgia Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1281</fpage>
         <lpage>1297</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278223"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a comparative analysis of two different power-split hybrid-electric vehicle (HEV) powertrains using backward-looking simulations. Compared are the front-wheel drive (FWD) Toyota Hybrid System II (THS-II) and the FWD General Motors Allison Hybrid System II (GM AHS-II). The Toyota system employs a one-mode electrically variable transmission (EVT), while the GM system employs a two-mode EVT. Both powertrains are modeled with the same assumed mid-size sedan chassis parameters. Each design employs their native internal combustion (IC) engine because the transmission’s characteristic ratios are designed for the respective brake specific fuel consumption (BSFC) maps. Due to the similarities (<italic>e.g.</italic>, power, torque, displacement, and thermal efficiency) between the two IC engines, their fuel consumption and performance differences are neglected in this comparison. The road-load parameters defining each system are used to calculate the required mechanical power at the driven wheels necessary to follow a given drive-cycle. Admissible engine operating states are sought based on component performance limitations and the required mechanical power at the driven wheels. Each IC engine operating point defines an accompanying battery power consistent with the constraints of the electric machines. The design approach is to exhaustively search all admissible states and minimize an instantaneous cost function based on engine power and battery power, at each time instant of the drive-cycle. Two cost functions are considered which weight battery power usage using either a linear, or an inverse-tangent, function of the current battery state-of-charge (SOC). Selected operational states are then compared against each other based on the flexibility and power delivery capabilities of the powertrains. Fuel minimizing cost functions are determined with the assistance of a charge sustaining index introduced by this paper. Finally, the most fuel efficient choices are used to determine the expected efficiency of both powertrains considered.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gelb, G.H., Richardson, N.A., Wang, T.C., and Berman, B., “An Electromechanical Transmission for Hybrid Vehicle Powertrains - Design and Dynamometer Testing,” SAE Technical Paper 710235, 1971, doi: 10.4271/710235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, J., “Comparative assessment of hybrid vehicle power split transmissions,” Fourth VI Winter Workshop Series, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olszewski, M., “Evaluation of 2004 Toyota Prius Hybrid Electric Drive System,” Oak Ridge National Laboratory Report FY2006, 1-95, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meisel, J., “An Analytic Foundation for the Toyota Prius THS-II Powertrain with a Comparison to a Strong Parallel Hybrid-Electric Powertrain,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0666, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0666.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cho, S., Ahn, K., and Lee, J., “Efficiency of the planetary gear hybrid powertrain,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2006, 220(10), 1445-1454.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahn, K., Cho, S., Cha, S., and Lee, J., “Engine operation for the planetary gear hybrid powertrain,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2006, 220(12), 1727-1735.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahn, K., Cho, S., Cha, S.W., “Optimal operation of the power-split hybrid electric vehicle powertrain,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2008, 222(5), 789-800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahn, K., Papalambros, P.Y., “Engine optimal operation lines for power-split hybrid electric vehicles,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2009, 223(9), 1149-1162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahn, K., Cho, S., Lim, W., Park, Y., Lee, J.M., “Performance analysis and parametric design of the dualmode planetary gear hybrid powertrain,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2006, 220(11), 1601-1614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Conlon, B., “Comparative Analysis of Single and Combined Hybrid Electrically Variable Transmission Operating Modes,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1162, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grewe, T.M., Conlon, B.M., and Holmes, A.G., “Defining the General Motors 2-Mode Hybrid Transmission,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0273, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0273.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meisel, J., “An Analytic Foundation for the Two-Mode Hybrid-Electric Powertrain with a Comparison to the Single- Mode Toyota Prius THS-II Powertrain,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1321, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1321.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roos, F. and Spiegelberg, C., “Relations Between Size and Gear Ratio in Spur and Planetary Gear Trains,” Royal Institute of Technology Technical report, 2004, http://www.md.kth.se/∼fredrikr/AM2D/gearReport.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Litvin, F., Fuentes, A., Vecchiatto, D., and Gonzales- Perez, I., “New design and improvement of planetary gear trains,” Project report to NASA, University of Illinois at Chicago, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">General Motors, ‘1.6L Fam 1 for Teams.xls’, EcoCAR resource, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
