<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3/4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24440119</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24440127</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Methodological Innovations in Collecting Spending Data: The HRS Consumption and Activities Mail Survey</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <surname>Hurd</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Susann</given-names>
                  <surname>Rohwedder</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>435</fpage>
         <lpage>459</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2009</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440127"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>It has traditionally been believed that collecting survey measures of total spending necessarily involved asking a large number of questions, too many for inclusion of a comprehensive spending measure in a general-purpose survey. In this paper, we report on a supplemental survey to the Health and Retirement Study that took up this challenge. We discuss issues that arise when designing a survey module to collect spending data with strict time constraints, describe how the implementation in the Consumption and Activities Mail Survey (CAMS) played out, and elicit anomalies that more detailed analysis of data quality revealed. We report how we addressed some of these anomalies in subsequent waves of CAMS. Other anomalies required conducting some randomised experiments to find what explains the observed patterns. The results highlight the tension between asking about spending using a long time frame, which exacerbates recall bias, versus using a short time frame, which risks relying on an unrepresentative snapshot of a household's spending to proxy the total for the last 12 months. An important complicating factor in deciding which goods should be put into which time frames is that there is substantial heterogeneity in the frequency of spending across households even for the same category of spending.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d78e229a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e236" publication-type="other">
Submitted November 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e243a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e250" publication-type="other">
Economic theory models consumption, not spending. However, it is spending that is measured in
household surveys. This difference is not a matter of great concern provided we have good methods of
finding the flow of consumption services from consumer durables. Thus in surveys of household
consumption such as the US Consumer Expenditure Survey (CEX), no distinction is made between
consumption and spending. That is the point of view in this paper and we will use consumption and
spending interchangeably.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e273a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e280" publication-type="other">
See, among others, Hall and Mischkin (1982), Zeldes (1989), Altug and Miller (1990) and Shea
(1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e290a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e297" publication-type="other">
Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1978.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e305a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e312" publication-type="other">
See Browning, Crossley and Weber (2003) for additional discussion of this single-question approach.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e319a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e326" publication-type="other">
See http://hrsonline.isr.umich.edu/ for a description of HRS and AHEAD and links to the
questionnaire.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e336a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e343" publication-type="other">
Browning and Madsen, 2005, p. 318.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e350a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e357" publication-type="other">
Browning and Madsen, 2005, p. 319.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e364a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e371" publication-type="other">
Bonke and Browning (this issue) look in more detail at the allocation of expenditures within
households.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e381a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e388" publication-type="other">
We are not aware of any experiments that provide empirical evidence to support this view.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e396a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e403" publication-type="other">
A copy of the paper-and-pencil questionnaire for wave 1 is available online at
http://hrsonline.isr.umich.edu/modules/meta/2001/cams/qnaire/cams01abc.pdf. The questionnaire for
wave 2 can be found at http://hrsonline.isr.umich.edu/modules/meta/2003/cams/qnaire/cams2003.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e416a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e423" publication-type="other">
Comparisons with the CEX are based on Consumer Expenditures Annual Reports (various years)
published by the US Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics. We focus on the population aged
55 and older and exclude from the CEX total some few categories that were not covered in CAMS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e436a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e443" publication-type="other">
Total spending in the first two waves of CAMS exceeded CEX totals for 2001 and 2003 by 16 per
cent and 15 per cent respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e453a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e460" publication-type="other">
The 'age' of the CEX household is the age of the reference person, who is the owner or renter of the
dwelling. Thus, an 80-year-old living with her 54-year-old son in his house would be classified as aged 54
in the CEX. In the HRS, each person is a sample member, so we can study consumption by the household
in which the 80-year-old lives. For classification by age, we assign in the HRS the age of the husband to
be the age of the household, to make the comparison as relevant as possible with the CEX. The HRS does
not elicit ownership of assets, so we cannot match the CEX classification exactly.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d78e483a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d78e490" publication-type="other">
HRS income measures have been shown to be closely comparable to incomes as measured in the
Current Population Survey (CPS). For details, see table 4 in Hurd and Rohwedder (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d78e509a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e513" publication-type="other">
Altug, S. and Miller, R. (1990), 'Household choices in equilibrium', Econometrica, vol. 58,
pp. 543-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e523a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e527" publication-type="other">
Bonke, J. and Browning, M. (2009), 'The allocation of expenditures within the household: a
new survey', Fiscal Studies, vol. 30, pp. 461-81 (this issue).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e537a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e541" publication-type="other">
Browning, M., Crossley, T. F. and Weber, G. (2003), 'Asking consumption questions in
general purpose surveys', Economic Journal, vol. 113, pp. F540-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e551a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e555" publication-type="other">
— and Madsen, E. (2005), 'Consumption', in A. Börsch-Supan, A. Brugiavini, H. Jürges, J.
Mackenbach, J. Siegrist and G. Weber (eds), Health, Ageing and Retirement in Europe:
First Results from the Survey of Health, Ageing and Retirement in Europe, Mannheim:
Mannheim Research Institute for the Economics of Aging (MEA).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e572a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e576" publication-type="other">
Bureau of Labor Statistics (1978), Consumer Expenditure Survey: Interview Survey, 1972-73,
Bulletin 1997, Washington, DC: US Department of Labor.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e590" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. E. and Mischkin, F. S. (1982), 'The sensitivity of consumption to transitory income:
estimates from panel data on households', Econometrica, vol. 50, pp. 461-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e604" publication-type="other">
Hurd, M. D., McFadden, D., Chand, H., Gan, L., Merrill, A. and Roberts, M. (1998),
'Consumption and saving balances of the elderly: experimental evidence on survey
response bias', in D. Wise (ed.), Frontiers in the Economics of Aging, Chicago:
University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e620a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e624" publication-type="other">
— and Rohwedder, S. (2006), 'Economic well-being at older ages: income- and consumption-
based poverty measures in the HRS', RAND, Working Paper no. WR-410.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e634a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e638" publication-type="other">
— and — (2008), 'Wealth change and active saving at older ages', RAND, manuscript.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e645a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e649" publication-type="other">
Shea, J. (1995), 'Union contracts and the life-cycle hypothesis', Economic Inquiry, vol. 26,
pp. 609-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d78e660a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d78e664" publication-type="other">
Zeldes, S. P. (1989), 'Consumption and liquidity constraints: an empirical investigation',
Journal of Political Economics, vol. 97, pp. 305—46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


