<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Military Operations Research Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26853192</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Advancing Campaign Analysis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hanley</surname>
                  <given-names>John T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>December 2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">52</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26853180</issue-id>
         <fpage>34</fpage>
         <lpage>40</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26853192"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Baker, G. L., and Gollub, J. P. 1996. Chaotic Dynamics: An Introduction, second edition.Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Comptroller General of the United States. 1973. Report to Congress: Advantages and Limitations of Computer Simulation in Decisonmaking. Comptroller General of the United States, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Duke, Richard D., and Geurts, Jac L. A. 2004. Policy Games for Strategic Management: Pathways into the Unknown. Dutch University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Enthoven, Alain C., and Smith, K. Wayne. 1971. How Much Is Enough? Shaping the Defense Program 1961–1969. Harper &amp; Row.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Hanley, John T. Jr. 2017. Changing DoD's Analysis Paradigm: The Science of War Gaming and Combat/Campaign Simulation, Naval War College Review, Vol 70, No 1, 64–103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Haywood, O. G., Jr. 1954. Military Decision and Game Theory, Journal of the Operations Research Society of America, Vol 2, No 4, 365–385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Hofmann, Rudolph M. 1952. War Games. Historical Division, Headquarters, US Army, Europe.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Hornfischer, James D. 2011.Neptune's Inferno: The U.S. Navy at Guadalcanal. Bantam.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Hughes, Wayne P. CAPT USN (Ret.), and Girrier, Robert P. 2018. Fleet Tactics and Naval Operations, third edition. Naval Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Hughes, Wayne P. Jr. 2012.Prediction. Address to Military Applications section of INFORMS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Kent, Glenn A. 2008. Thinking About America's Defense: An Analytical Memoir. RAND Project Air Force.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Kimball, George E., and Morse, Philip M. 1951. Methods of Operations Research, first edition revised. Peninsula Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Kline, J, Hughes, W., and Otte, D. 2010. Campaign Analysis: An Introductory Review. volume 1. Wylie Encyclopedia of Operations Research and Management Science, J. Cochran, ed. John Wiley &amp; Sons, 558–566.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Koopman, Bernard O. 1970. A Study of the Logical Basis of Combat Simulation, Journal of Operations Research, Vol 18, No 5, 761-960. https://doi.org/10.1287/opre.18.5.855.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Koopman, Bernard Osgood. 1980. Search and Screening: General Principles with Historical Applications. Pergamn Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Leonard, Robert. 2010. Von Neumann, Morgenstern, and the Creation of Game Theory: From Chess to Social Science, 1900-1960. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Mullin, Tom, ed. 1993. The Nature of Chaos. Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine. 2019. Reproducibility and Replicability in Science. National Academies Press. https://doi.org/10.17266/25303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Operations Research Society of America. 1971. Guidelines for the Practice of Operations Research, Journal of the Operations Research Society of America, Vol 19, No 5, 1123–1258.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Perla, Peter P. 1990. The Art of Wargaming: A Guide for Professionals and Hobbyists.Naval Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Stewart, Ian. 2002. Does God Play Dice: The New Mathematics of Chaos, second edition. Blackwell Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Submarine Development Squadron TWELVE. 1999. A Look—Past, Present and Future, Proceedings of the Submarine Development Group TWO &amp; Submarine Development Squadron TWELVE 50th Anniversary Symposium 1949–1999. Submarine Development Squadron TWELVE, Groton, CT.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Watts, Barry D. 1996. Doctrine, Technology, and War. Maxwell Air Force Base, Montgomery, AL. Accessed June 28, 2019, https://www.airuniversity.af.edu/Portals/10/ASPJ/journals/Chronicles/watts.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Wylie, J. C. 1989. Military Strategy: A General Theory of Power Control. Naval Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Uncertainty versus number of variables. The figure uses an order of magnitude of 10 percent error in each variable, which is exceedingly generous considering errors typical in combat models for own much less enemy performance, and 1/n as the increase in accuracy by adding more detail by adding variables to the model.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
