<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308344</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CFD-Based Optimization of a Diesel-fueled Free Piston Engine Prototype for Conventional and HCCI Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bergman</surname>
                  <given-names>Miriam</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fredriksson</surname>
                  <given-names>Jakob</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Golovitchev</surname>
                  <given-names>Valeri I.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Chalmers University of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>1118</fpage>
         <lpage>1143</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308344"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents results of a parametric CFD modeling study of a prototype Free Piston Engine (FPE), designed for application in a series hybrid electric vehicle. Since the piston motion is governed by Newton’s second law, accounting for the forces acting on the piston/translator, i.e. friction forces, electrical forces, and in-cylinder gas forces, having a high-level control system is vital. The control system changes the electrical force applied during the stroke, thus obtaining the desired compression ratio. Identical control algorithms were implemented in a MATLAB/SIMULINK model to those applied in the prototype engine. The ignition delay and heat release data used in the MATLAB/SIMULINK model are predicted by the KIVA-3V CFD code which incorporates detailed chemical kinetics (305 reactions among 70 species).</p>
            <p>Since the piston motion and frequency, the rate of heat release and the initial in-cylinder conditions all affect each other, while predicted using different modelling tools with no direct coupling between them, an iterative procedure was used among models describing:</p>
            <p>1. Piston dynamics governed by Newton’s second law including a high-level control system (using MATLAB/SIMULINK)</p>
            <p>2. Combustion processes (using KIVA-3V)</p>
            <p>3. Intake and exhaust system dynamics (using the GT-POWER module of the GT-SUITE™)</p>
            <p>Effects of varying parameters such as compression ratios, power supplied to the compressor, fuel injection timings and injection pressures have been studied in both conventional diesel and HCCI modes, the target being to identify optimal conditions for the combustion process in which the engine can be operated highly efficiently with very low-emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goldsborough, S., Van Blarigan, P., Optimizing the cavenging System for a Two-Stroke Cycle, Free iston Engine for High Efficiency and Low Emissions: Computational Approach, SAE Paper 2003-01- 0001 (2003)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carter, D., Wechner, E., The Free Piston Power ack: Sustainable Power for Hybrid Electric Vehicles, AE Paper 2003-01-3277 (2003)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caresana, F., Comodi G., Pelagalli, L., Design pproach for a Two-Stroke Free Piston Engine for lectric Power Generation, SAE Paper 2004-32-0037 (2004)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Max, E., FPEC, Free Piston Energy Converter, roceedings of the 21st Worldwide International attery, Hybrid and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicle ymposium &amp; Exhibition (EVS21 Monaco), Monaco 2-6 April (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleemann, A.P., Dabadie, J.C., Henriot, S., omputational Design Studies for a High-Efficiency nd Low-Emissions Free Piston Engine Prototype, AE Paper 2004-01-2928 (2004)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fredriksson, J., Bergman, M., Golovitchev, V.I., enbratt, I., Modeling the Effect of Injection Schedule hange on Free Piston Engine Operation, SAE Paper 2006-01-0449 (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergman, M., Fredriksson, J., Golovitchev, V.I., erformance and Emission Formation Evaluation of a iesel-Fueled Free Piston Engine using CFD, JSAE aper 20065454 (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden A.A., KIVA-3V: A Block-structured KIVA rogram for Engines with Vertical or Canted Valves, A-13313-MS, July (1997)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergman, M., Golovitchev, V.I., Application of ransient Temperature vs. Equivalence Ratio mission Maps to Engine Simulations, SAE paper 2007-01-1086, (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guibet, J.C., Fuels and Engines, Editions Technip, aris (1999)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrell, J.T., Chernavsky, N.P, Dryer, F.L. et al, evelopment of an Experimental Database and inetic Models for Surrogate Diesel Fuels, SAE Paper 2007-01-0201 (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergman, M., Golovitchev, V.I., Chemical echanisms for Modeling HCCI with Gasoline and iesel Oil Surrogates, Proceedings of the VII. ongress on Engine Combustion Processes, pp. 323- 334, Munchen, 15-16 March (2005) ttp://web.student.chalmers.se/~miriam78/first.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gustavsson*, J., Golovitchev, V. I., Helmantel, A., 3-D odelling of Conventional and HCCI Combustion iesel Engines, SAE paper 2004-01-2964 (2004) *This author’s current last name is Edman</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergman, M., Golovitchev, V.I., Modification of a iesel Oil Surrogate Model for 3D CFD Applied to onventional and HCCI Combustion, SAE Paper 2008-01-2410 (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagle, J., Strickland-Constable, R.F., Proc. 5th arbon Conf., vol. 1, p.154 (1962)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J., B., Internal Combustion Engine undamentals, page 638, McGraw-Hill Book ompany (1988)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stiesch, G., Modeling Engine Spray and Combustion rocesses, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg (2003)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S.M., Flowers, D.L., Espinoza-Loza, F., abajimopoulos, A., Assanis, D.N., Analysis of remixed Charge Compression Ignition Combustion ith a Sequential Fluid Mechanics-Multizone hemical Kinetics Model, SAE Paper 2005-01-0115 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Assanis, D., Flowers, D., ceves, S., Hessel, R., A Fully Coupled omputational Fluid Dynamics and Multi-Zone Model ith Detailed Chemical Kinetics for the Simulation of remixed Charge Compression Ignition Engines, nternational Journal of Engine Research, Volume 6, umber 5, pp. 497-512 (16) (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., Reitz, R.D., Musculus, M.P.B., omparison of the Characteristic Time (CTC), epresentative Interactive Flamelet (RIF), and Direct ntegration with Detailed Chemistry Combustion odels against Optical Diagnostic Data for Multi- ode Combustion in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine, AE Paper 2006-01-0055 (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kong, S.C., Reitz, R.D., Application of Detailed hemistry and CFD for Predicting Direct Injection CCI Engine Combustion and Emissions, roceedings of the Combustion Institute, Volume 29, p. 663-669 (2002)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patterson, M. A., Reitz, R., D., Modeling the Effects of uel Spray Characteristics on Diesel Engine ombustion and Emission, SAE Paper 980131 (1998)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dr. Tao Feng, Chalmers University, personal ommunication (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, F., Foster, D. E., Reitz, R. D., Soot Structure in Conventional Non-Premixed Diesel Flame, SAE aper 2006-01-0196 (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., L., Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in iesel Sprays, SAE Paper 980809 (1998)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fredriksson, J., Denbratt, I. Simulation of a Two- troke Free Piston Engine, SAE Paper 2004-01-1871 (2004)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin West, Volvo Technology, personal ommunication (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amneus, P., Mauss, F., Kraft, M., Vressner, A., ohansson, B., NOx and N2O Formation in HCCI ngines, SAE Paper 2005-01-0126 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Professor Ingemar Denbratt, Chalmers University, ersonal communication (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helmantel, A., Low Emission Concepts for Diesel ngines, PhD thesis, Department of Applied echanics, Chalmers University of Technology, öteborg, Sweden (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryan, T., South West Research Institute, USA, Slides rom the lecture: Advanced Combustion for Low missions and High Efficiency, given at the 7:th nternational Conference on Engines for Automobile, CE 2005 (SAE Naples section), Italy, September (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
