<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830142</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830145</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE IMPACTS OF FISCAL VARIABLES, FINANCIAL VARIABLES AND COMPOSITION OF FINANCIAL AGGREGATES ON NIGERIAN ECONOMY / L'IMPACT DES VARIABLES FISCALES, DES VARIABLES FINANCIÈRES ET DE LA STRUCTURE DES AGRÉGATS FINANCIERS SUR L'ÉCONOMIE DU NIGÉRIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>M.O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Odedokun</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1988</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>127</fpage>
         <lpage>144</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830145"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The paper examines the effectiveness of fiscal policy vis-a-vis monetary and credit policy on the various states of the economy in Nigeria. The effectiveness of monetary policy vis-a-vis credit policy is also examined as well as the influence of bank portfolio composition on the economy. Our states of the economy are the GDP, the price level, industrial production, and imports. To do this, we estimated reduced-form single-equation models with Nigerian data over the 50-quarterly period from 1970(I) to 1983 (II). Our findings suggest that monetary and credit policies are more potent on the economy than the fiscal policy; monetary policy is more potent on the GDP and imports but less potent on industrial activity than the credit policy; and bank portfolio composition has no influence on the economic activity. All these demand management policies are found not to be strong in an absolute sense. Cet article examine l'efficacité comparée de la politique fiscale, de la politique monétaire et du crédit sur les différents aspects de l'économie du Nigéria. On analyse aussi deux autres aspects: (1) l'efficacité relative de la politique monétaire et de la politique du crédit et 2) l'influence de la structure des activités des banques sur l'économie. Les différentes variables examinées de l'économie prise en considération sont le produit national brut, le niveau des prix, la production industrielle et les importations. Pour cette analyse, on a estimé des modèles économétriques formés par une équation à forme réduite utilisant les données du Nigéria pendant 50 trimestres de la période 1970 (I) — 1983 (II). Les données montrent que les politiques monétaires et du crédit sont plus efficaces que la politique fiscale sur les variables de l'économie. La politique monétaire a une influence plus forte sur le produit national brut et sur les importations. En ce qui concerne l'activité industrielle la politique monétaire est moins efficace que la politique du crédit. La composition des activités financières des banques n'a pas d'influence sur les principales variables macroéconomiques. Toutes ces méthodes de régulation de la demande globale ne semblent pas avoir d'effets particulièrement remarquables sur l'économie du Nigéria.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e181a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e185" publication-type="other">
Ajayi, S.I, «An Econometric Case Study of the Relative Importance of Monetary and Fiscal Policy in Nigeria*,
Bangladesh Economic Review, Vol. 2, April 1974.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e195a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e199" publication-type="other">
Anderson, L. and K.M. Carlson, «A Monetarist Model of Economic Stabilization*, Federal Reserve Bank of St.
Louis, Monthly Review, April 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e209a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e213" publication-type="other">
Anderson, L. and J. Jordan, «Monetary and Fiscal Actions: A Test of their Relative Importance in Economic
Stabilization*, Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis Review, Vol. 50, Nov. 1968 p. 11-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e223a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e227" publication-type="other">
Batavia, B. and N.A. Lash, «The Impact of Bank Portfolio Composition on GNP», Journal of Money, Credit and
Banking, Vol. 14, No. 4, Part I, Nov. 1982 p. 517-524.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e238a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e242" publication-type="other">
Campell, T.S., «Monetary Policy and Bank Portfolio Composition: An Analysis of their Impact on GNP», Journal
of Money, Credit and Banking, Vol.10, No. 2, May 1978, p. 239-251.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e252a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e256" publication-type="other">
de Leeuw, F. and M. Gramlich, «The Channels of Monetary Policy*, Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis Review,
June 1969.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e266a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e270" publication-type="other">
Elliot, J.W., «The Influence of Monetary and Fiscal Actions in Total Spending: The St. Louis Spending Equation
Revisited*, Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, Vol. 7, May 1975, p. 181-192.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e280a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e284" publication-type="other">
Friedman, M., «The Monetary Studies of the National Bureau*, The Optimum Quantity of Money and Other Essays,
Chicago, 1969.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e298" publication-type="other">
Liu, Ta-Chung, «A Monthly Recursive Econometric Model of United States: A Test of Feasibility*, Review of
Economics and Statistics, Vol. 51, No. 1, Feb. 1969, p. 1-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e312" publication-type="other">
Silber, W., «Monetary Channels and the Relative Importance of Money Supply in Bank Portfolios*, Journal of
Finance, Vol. 24, March 1969a p. 81-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e323a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e327" publication-type="other">
Silber, W., «Velocity and Bank Portfolio Composition*, Southern Economic Journal, Vol. 36, Oct. 1969b, p. 147-152.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e334a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e338" publication-type="other">
Smith, W., «On the Effectiveness of Monetary Policy*, American Economic Review, Vol. 46, Sept. 1956 p. 588-606.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e345a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e349" publication-type="other">
Ubogu, R.E., «Potency of Monetary and Fiscal Policy Instruments on Economic Activities of African Countries*,
Savings and Development, No. 4 1985, p. 441 - 457.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


