<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816515</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>The Effects of State and Local Tax Incentives (State and Local)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Stadium Subsidies, Public Choice, and Property Values</article-title>
            <subtitle>A Test of the Homevoter Hypothesis in King County, Washington</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miner</surname>
                  <given-names>Kimberly A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Downes</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>41</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816515"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper examines whether the “homevoter hypothesis” helps explain popular support for public subsidies in a 1997 referendum on a new stadium for the National Football League’s Seattle Seahawks. According to the hypothesis, homeowners vote for proposals that will increase their property’s value and against those that will decrease their property’s value. If the homevoter hypothesis explains voter behavior in this instance, then voters who perceive that their home value will increase – via “noisy signals” from sales in their local neighborhood – will be more likely to support the proposal. This paper has two empirical steps: a hedonic analysis to quantify the stadium’s impact on property values and an analysis that connects these price effects to voting results in King County, Washington. The results indicate a very small negative stadium price effect. Measures of anticipated, stadium-induced changes in property values created by analyzing changes in property values following critical information revelations about the new stadium are associated with the extent of support for public subsidies in specifications that fail to account for past voting behavior. But that association disappears when past support is taken into account. The results suggest the need to account for unobserved attitudes towards public subsidies when assessing potential explanations for voter support of such subsidies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Ahlfeldt, Gabriel M., and Georgios Kavetsos. 2010. “Form or function? The impact of new football stadia on property prices in London.” MPRA: Munich Personal RePEc Archive MPRA Paper No. 25003 (Accessed September 14, 2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Almond, Elliott. 1997. “Legislators ready to punt on Hawks' stadium.” The Seattle Times, January 10, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Almond, Elliott. 1997. “S.F. voters approving stadium.” The Seattle Times, June 5, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Almond, Elliott, and David Schaefer. 1996. “Allen would help with new stadium, not dome fixup.” The Seattle Times, December 10, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Anderson, Paul M., editor. 2016. Sports Facility Reports 17. Milwaukee: Marquette University Law School, National Sports Law Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Baade, Robert A. 1996. “Professional sports as catalysts for metropolitan economic development.” Journal of Urban Affairs 18 (1): 1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Brunner, E., and J. Sonstelie. 2003. “Homeowners, property values, and the political economy of the school voucher.” Journal of Urban Economics 54: 239-257.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Brunner, E., J. Sonstelie, and M. Thayer. 2001. “Capitalization and the voucher: An analysis of precinct returns from California's Proposition 174.” Journal of Urban Economics 50: 517- 536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Carlino, Gerald, and N. Edward Coulson. 2004. “Compensating differentials and the social benefits of the NFL.” Journal of Urban Economics 56 (May 19): 25-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Carpenter, Les, and David Schaefer. 1997. “Seahawk stadium.” The Seattle Times, April 27, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Chema, Thomas V. 1996. “When professional sports justify the subsidy, a reply to Robert A. Baade.” Journal of Urban Affairs 18 (1): 19-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Coates, Dennis R., and Brad R. Humphreys. 2008. “Do economists reach a conclusion on subsidies for sports franchises, stadiums, and mega-events?” Econ Journal Watch 5 (3) (September): 294-315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Coates, Dennis, Brad R. Humphreys, and Andrew Zimbalist. 2006. “Compensating differentials and the social benefits of the NFL: A comment.” Journal of Urban Economics 60 (February 17): 124-131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dehring, Carolyn A., Craig A. Depken II, and Michael R. Ward. 2008. “A direct test of the homevoter hypothesis.” Journal of Urban Economics 64 (January 10): 155-170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Eigsti, Roger, and Bob Watt. 1997. “Stands on stadiums: Touchdown: Allen's vision deserves vote.” The Seattle Times, March 19, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Fischel, William. 2001. The Homevoter Hypothesis. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Goldberg, Carey. 1997. “A decision on the Seattle Seahawks' home.” The New York Times, May 24, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Hilber, C., and C. Mayer. 2006. “Why do households without children support local public schools? Linking house price capitalization to school spending.” Working Paper, Columbia Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Georgios Kavetsos and Stefan Szymanski, "National Wellbeing and International Sports Events." North American Association of Sports Economists, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Kiel, Katherine A., Victor A. Matheson, and Christopher Sullivan, "The Effect of Sports Franchises on Property Values: The Role of Owners Versus Renters." Working Papers, College of the Holy Cross, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Marwaha, Amitoj. 1997. “Voters don't need another referendum on stadiums.” The Online Daily of the University of Washington (February 28, 1997), http://dailyuw.com/1997/2/28/voters022897/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Pappas, Doug. 2000. “New stadia: Atlanta, Arizona, Seattle.” Boston Baseball. http://roadsidephotos.sabr.org/baseball/bb00sta-4.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Plutzer, Eric. 2001. “Becoming a Habitual Voter: Inertia, Resources, and Growth in Young Adulthood.” American Political Science Review 96 (March): 41-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Portney, P. R., and J. C. Sonstelie. 1980. “Take the money and run: A theory of voting in local referenda.” Journal of Urban Economics 8: 187-195.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Rosentraub, Mark S. 1996. “Does the emperor have new clothes?: A reply to Robert A. Baade.” Journal of Urban Affairs 18 (1): 23-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Rosentraub, Mark S., and David Swindell. 1998. “Who benefits from the presence of professional sports teams? The implications for public funding of stadiums and arenas.” Public Administration Review 58 (1): 11-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Schaefer, David. 1997. “Allen showed them the money -- The big winners in state's most expensive campaign.” The Seattle Times, August 12, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Schaefer, David. 1997. “Opposition counts pennies as stadium campaign opens.” The Seattle Times, May 9, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Schaefer, David. 1997. “Referendum 48 -- from backer to ballots, stadium vote is unique -- returns now arriving in mostly-mail poll on billionaire's plan to keep the Seahawks.” The Seattle Times, June 8, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Schaefer, David. 1997. “Stadium foes chide Allen for not voting -- campaign to set spending record.” The Seattle Times, May 28, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Schaefer, David. 1997. “Voters begin casting stadium ballots -- two-thirds may use mail instead of polling place.” The Seattle Times, May 27, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">“The stadium: Safeco Field timeline.” 1999. The Seattle Post-Intelligencer. http://www.seattlepi.com/safeco/stadium/timesafe.shtml</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Stewart, Tom. 1997. “Referendum 48 -- Eastern Washington is tired.” The Seattle Times, June 21, 1997. Letters to the Editor.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Tu, Charles C. 2005. “How does a new sports stadium affect housing values? The case of FedEx Field.” Land Economics 81 (3) (August): 379-395.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Timeline of Events Related to Referendum 48 and the Seahawks’ New Stadium</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Variable Definitions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Summary Statistics – Base Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Summary Statistics – Parcel Attributes</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Summary Statistics – Precinct Demographics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Summary Statistics – Vote Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Regression Results – Hedonic Analysis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Distance and Announcement Effects on Sale Price</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Regression Results – Voting Analysis: Percent Yes</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Regression Results – Voting Analysis: Percent Turnout</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
