<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">jfinance</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100221</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00221082</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15406261</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25094455</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Capital Gains Taxes and Asset Prices: Capitalization or Lock-In?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Zhonglan</given-names>
                  <surname>Dai</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Edward</given-names>
                  <surname>Maydew</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Douglas A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Shackelford</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Harold H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">63</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25094447</issue-id>
         <fpage>709</fpage>
         <lpage>742</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 The American Finance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25094455"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper demonstrates that the equilibrium impact of capital gains taxes reflects both the capitalization effect (i.e., capital gains taxes decrease demand) and the lock-in effect (i.e., capital gains taxes decrease supply). Depending on time periods and stock characteristics, either effect may dominate. Using the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 as our event, we find evidence supporting a dominant capitalization effect in the week following news that sharply increased the probability of a reduction in the capital gains tax rate and a dominant lock-in effect in the week after the rate reduction became effective.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group>
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d28e152a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e159" publication-type="other">
Sinai and Gyourko (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d28e166a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e173" publication-type="other">
Graham and Kumar (2006)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e179" publication-type="other">
Ivkovic, Poterba, and Weisbenner (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d28e186a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e193" publication-type="other">
Ayers et al.
(2003)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e202" publication-type="other">
Dhaliwal and Li (2006)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e208" publication-type="other">
Dhaliwal et al. (2005)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d28e215a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e222" publication-type="other">
Shackelford (2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d28e238a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e242" publication-type="other">
Ayers, Benjamin, Craig Lefanowicz, and John Robinson, 2003, Shareholder taxes in acquisition
premiums: The effect of capital gains taxation, Journal of Finance 58, 2785-2803.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e252a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e256" publication-type="other">
Ayers, Benjamin, Oliver Li, and John Robinson, 2006, Tax induced trading around the Taxpayer
Relief Act of 1997, Working paper, University of Georgia, University of Notre Dame, and
University of Texas at Austin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e269a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e273" publication-type="other">
Blouin, Jennifer, Luzi Hail, and Michelle Yetman, 2006, Capital gains taxes, pricing spreads and
arbitrage: Evidence from cross-listed firms in the U.S., Working paper, The Wharton School
and University of California at Davis.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e286a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e290" publication-type="other">
Blouin, Jennifer, Jana Raedy, and Douglas Shackelford, 2003, Capital gains taxes and equity
trading: Empirical evidence, Journal of Accounting Research 41, 611-651.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e305" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, George, 1983, Capital market equilibrium with personal tax, Econometrica 51,
611-636.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e319" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, George, 1984, Optimal stock trading with personal taxes: Implications for prices
and abnormal January returns, Journal of Financial Economics 13, 65-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e329a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e333" publication-type="other">
Dammon, Robert, Chester Spatt, and Harold H. Zhang, 2001, Optimal consumption and investment
with capital gains taxes, Review of Financial Studies 14, 583-616.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e343a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e347" publication-type="other">
Dhaliwal, Daniel, Linda Krull, Oliver Li, and William Moser, 2005, Dividend taxes and implied
cost of equity capital, Journal of Accounting Research 43, 675-708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e357a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e361" publication-type="other">
Dhaliwal, Daniel, and Oliver Li, 2006, Investor tax heterogeneity and ex-dividend day trading
volume, Journal of Finance 61, 463-490.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e371a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e375" publication-type="other">
Ellis, Katrina, Oliver Li, and John Robinson, 2006, Capital gains taxes and IPO under-pricing,
Working paper, University of California, Davis, University of Notre Dame, and University of
Texas at Austin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e389a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e393" publication-type="other">
Feldstein, Martin, Joel Slemrod, and Shlomo Yitzhaki, 1980, The effects of taxation on the selling
of corporate stock and the realization of capital gains, Quarterly Journal of Economics 94,
777-791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e406a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e410" publication-type="other">
George, Thomas, and Chuan-Yan Hwang, 2007, Long-term reversals: Overreaction or taxes?
Journal of Finance 62, 2865-2896.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e420a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e424" publication-type="other">
Goolsbee, Austan, 1998, Investment tax incentives, prices, and the supply of capital goods, Quar-
terly Journal of Economics 113, 121-148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e434a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e438" publication-type="other">
Graham, John, 2003, Taxes and corporate finance: A review, Review of Financial Studies 16,1075-
1129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e448a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e452" publication-type="other">
Graham, John, and Alok Kumar, 2006, Do dividend clienteles exist? Evidence on dividend prefer-
ences of retail investors, Journal of Finance 61, 1305-1336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e462a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e466" publication-type="other">
Guenther, David, and Michele Willenborg, 1999, Capital gains tax rates and the cost of capital for
small business: Evidence from the IPO market, Journal of Financial Economics 53, 385-408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e477a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e481" publication-type="other">
Ivkovic, Zoran, James Poterba, and Scott Weisbenner, 2005, Tax-motivated trading by individual
investors, American Economic Review 95, 1605-1630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e491a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e495" publication-type="other">
Jin, Li, 2006, Capital gain tax overhang and price pressure, Journal of Finance 61, 1399-1431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e502a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e506" publication-type="other">
Klein, Peter, 1999, The capital gain lock-in effect and equilibrium returns, Journal of Public
Economics 71, 355-378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e516a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e520" publication-type="other">
Klein, Peter, 2001, The capital gain lock-in effect and long horizon return reversal, Journal of
Financial Economics 59, 33-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e530a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e534" publication-type="other">
Landsman, Wayne, and Douglas Shackelford, 1995, The lock-in effect of capital gains taxes: Evi-
dence from the RJR Nabisco leverage buyout, National Tax Journal 48, 245-259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e544a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e548" publication-type="other">
Lang, Mark, and Douglas Shackelford, 2000, Capitalization of capital gains taxes: Evidence from
stock price reactions to the 1997 rate reduction, Journal of Public Economics 76, 69-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e559a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e563" publication-type="other">
Michaely, Roni, and Jean-Luc Vila, 1996, Trading volume with private valuation: Evidence from
the ex-dividend day, Review of Financial Studies 9, 471-509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e573a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e577" publication-type="other">
Peterson, Mitchell, 2005, Estimating standard error in finance panel data sets: Comparing ap-
proaches, Review of Financial Studies, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e587a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e591" publication-type="other">
Poterba, James, 2001, Estate and gift taxes and incentives for inter vivos giving in the United
States, Journal of Public Economics 79, 237-264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e601a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e605" publication-type="other">
Poterba, James, and Scott Weisbenner, 2001, Capital gains tax rules, tax-loss trading, and turn-
of-the-year returns, Journal of Finance 56, 353-368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e615a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e619" publication-type="other">
Reese, William, 1998, Capital gains taxation and stock market activity: Evidence from IPOs,
Journal of Finance 53, 1799-1820.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e629a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e633" publication-type="other">
Shackelford, Douglas, 2000, Stock market reaction to the capital gains tax changes: Empirical
evidence from the 1997 and 1998 Tax Acts, in James M. Poterba, ed. Tax Policy and the Economy
14 (National Bureau of Economics Research and MIT Press, Cambridge, MA).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e647a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e651" publication-type="other">
Shackelford, Douglas, and Ro Verrecchia, 2002, Intertemporal tax discontinuities, Journal of
Accounting Research 40, 205-222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e661a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e665" publication-type="other">
Sinai, Todd, and Joseph Gyourko, 2004, The asset price incidence of capital gains taxes: Evidence
from the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 and publicly-traded real estate firms, Journal of Public
Economics 88, 1543-1560.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d28e678a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d28e682" publication-type="other">
Viard, Alan, 2000, Dynamic asset pricing effects and incidence of realization-based capital gains
taxes, Journal of Monetary Economics 46, 465-488.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
