<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">77</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">262</issue>
         <issue-id>i40008730</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40234547</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Double-Base Number System and Its Application to Elliptic Curve Cryptography</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Vassil</given-names>
                  <surname>Dimitrov</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Laurent</given-names>
                  <surname>Imbert</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Pradeep K.</given-names>
                  <surname>Mishra</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1075</fpage>
         <lpage>1104</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40234547"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We describe an algorithm for point multiplication on generic elliptic curves, based on a representation of the scalar as a sum of mixed powers of 2 and 3. The sparseness of this so-called double-base number system, combined with some efficient point tripling formulae, lead to efficient point multiplication algorithms for curves defined over both prime and binary fields. Side-channel resistance is provided thanks to side-channel atomicity.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Primary 14H52</kwd>
            <kwd>Secondary 14G50</kwd>
            <kwd>Secondary 68R99</kwd>
            <kwd>ECC</kwd>
            <kwd>point multiplication</kwd>
            <kwd>double-base number system</kwd>
            <kwd>side-channel atomicity</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d4832459e165a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e172" publication-type="other">
J.-P. Allouche and J. Shallit, Automatic sequences, Cambridge University Press, 2003.
MR1997038 (2004k: 11028)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e182a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e189" publication-type="other">
R. Avanzi, H. Cohen, C. Doche, G. Prey, T. Lange, K. Nguyen, and F. Vercauteren, Handbook
of elliptic and hyperelliptic curve cryptography, CRC Press, 2005. MR2162716 (2007f:14020)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e199a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e206" publication-type="other">
R. Avanzi, V. Dimitrov, C. Doche, and F. Sica, Extending scalar multiplication using double
bases, Advances in Cryptology, ASIACRYPT'06, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol.
4284, Springer, 2006, pp. 130-144.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e219a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e226" publication-type="other">
R. Avanzi and F. Sica, Scalar multiplication on Koblitz curves using double bases, Cryptology
ePrint Archive, Report 2006/067, 2006, http://eprint.iacr.org/2006/067.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e237a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e244" publication-type="other">
J.-C. Bajard, L. Imbert, and T. Plantard, Modular number systems: Beyond the Mersenne
family, Proceedings of the 11th International Workshop on Selected Areas in Cryptogra-
phy, SAC'04, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 3357, Springer, 2005, pp. 159-169.
MR2181315 (2006h:94071)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e260a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e267" publication-type="other">
V. Berthé, Autour du système de numération d'Ostrowski, Bulletin of the Belgian Mathe-
matical Society 8 (2001), 209-239. MR1838931 (2002k:68147)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e277a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e284" publication-type="other">
V. Berthé and L. Imbert, On converting numbers to the double-base number system, Advanced
Signal Processing Algorithms, Architecture and Implementations XIV, Proceedings of SPIE,
vol. 5559, SPIE, 2004, pp. 70-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e297a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e304" publication-type="other">
I. F. Blake, G. Seroussi, and N. P. Smart, Advances in elliptic curve cryptography, Lon-
don Mathematical Society Lecture Note Series, no. 317, Cambridge University Press, 2005.
MR2166105</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e317a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e324" publication-type="other">
É. Brier and M. Joye, Fast point multiplication on elliptic curves through isogenies, Applied
Algebra, Algebraic Algorithms and Error-Correcting Codes, AAECC 2003, Lecture Notes in
Computer Science, vol. 2643, Springer, 2003, pp. 43-50. MR2042411 (2005a:14029)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e337a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e344" publication-type="other">
B. Chevalier-Mames, M. Ciet, and M. Joye, Low-cost solutions for preventing simple side-
channel analysis: Side-channel atomicity, IEEE Transactions on Computers 53 (2004), no. 6,
760-768.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e358a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e365" publication-type="other">
J. Chung and A. Hasan, More generalized Mersenne numbers, Selected Areas in Cryptog-
raphy, SAC'03, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 3006, Springer, 2004, pp. 335-347.
MR2094740 (2005f:94089)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e378a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e385" publication-type="other">
M. Ciet, M. Joye, K. Lauter, and P. L. Montgomery, Trading inversions for multiplications
in elliptic curve cryptography, Designs, Codes and Cryptography 39 (2006), no. 2, 189-206.
MR2209936 (2006j:94057)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e398a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e405" publication-type="other">
M. Ciet and F. Sica, An analysis of double base number systems and a sublinear scalar
multiplication algorithm, Progress of Cryptology, Mycrypt 2005, Lecture Notes in Computer
Science, vol. 3715, Springer, 2005, pp. 171-182.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e418a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e425" publication-type="other">
H. Cohen, A. Miyaji, and T. Ono, Efficient elliptic curve exponentiation using mixed coor-
dinates, Advances in Cryptology, ASIACRYPT'98, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol.
1514, Springer, 1998, pp. 51-65. MR1726152</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e438a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e445" publication-type="other">
E. De Win, S. Bosselaers, S. Vandenberghe, P. De Gersem, and J. Vandewalle, A fast soft-

              ware implementation for arithmetic operations in
              
              , Advances in Cryptology, ASI-
            
ACRYPT'96, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 1163, Springer, 1996, pp. 65-76.
MR1486049</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e464a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e471" publication-type="other">
V. Dimitrov, L. Imbert, and P. K. Mishra, Efficient and secure elliptic curve point multipli-
cation using double-base chains, Advances in Cryptology, ASIACRYPT'05, Lecture Notes in
Computer Science, vol. 3788, Springer, 2005. dd. 59-78. MR2236727</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e485a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e492" publication-type="other">
V. S Dimitrov, K. Järvinen, M. J. Jacobson, Jr., W. F. Chan, and Z. Huang, FPGA imple-
mentation of point multiplication on Koblitz curves using Kleinian integers, Cryptographic
Hardware and Embedded Systems, CHES'06, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 4249,
Springer, 2006, pp. 445-459.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e508a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e515" publication-type="other">
V. S. Dimitrov, G. A. Jullien, and W. C. Miller, An algorithm for modular exponentiation,
Information Processing Letters 66 (1998), no. 3, 155-159. MR1627991 (99d:94023)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e525a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e532" publication-type="other">
C. Doche, T. Icart, and D. R. Kohel, Efficient scalar multiplication by isogeny decompositions,
Public Key Cryptography, PKC'06, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 3958, Springer,
2006, pp. 191-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e545a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e552" publication-type="other">
C. Doche and L. Imbert, Extended double-base number system with applications to elliptic
curve cryptography, Progress in Cryptology, INDOCRYPT'06, Lecture Notes in Computer
Science, vol. 4329, Springer, 2006, pp. 335-348</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e565a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e572" publication-type="other">
K. Eisenträger, K. Lauter, and P. L. Montgomery, Fast elliptic curve arithmetic and improved
Weil pairing evaluation, Topics in Cryptology - CT-RSA 2003, Lecture Notes in Computer
Science, vol. 2612, Springer, 2003, pp. 343-354. MR2080147</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e585a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e592" publication-type="other">
K. Fong, D. Hankerson, J. Lòpez, and A. Menezes, Field inversion and point halving revisited,
IEEE Transactions on Computers 53 (2004), no. 8, 1047-1059.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e603a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e610" publication-type="other">
D. M. Gordon, A survey of fast exponentiation methods, Journal of Algorithms 27 (1998),
no. 1, 129-146. MR1613189 (99g:94014)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e620a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e627" publication-type="other">
T. Granlund, GMP, the GNU multiple precision arithmetic library, see: http://www.
swox.com/gmp/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e637a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e644" publication-type="other">
J. Guajardo and C. Paar, Efficient algorithms for elliptic curve cryptosystems, Advances
in Cryptology, CRYPTO'97, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 1294, Springer, 1997,
pp. 342-356. MR1630403 (99b:94033)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e657a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e664" publication-type="other">
D. Hankerson, J. Lòez Hernandez, and A. Menezes, Software implementation of elliptic
curve cryptography over binary fields, Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems,
CHES'00, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 1965, Springer, 2000, pp. 1-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e677a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e684" publication-type="other">
D. Hankerson, A. Menezes, and S. Vanstone, Guide to elliptic curve cryptography, Springer,
2004. MR2054891 (2005c:94049)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e694a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e701" publication-type="other">
K. Itoh, M. Takenaka, N. Torii, S. Temma, and Y. Kurihara, Fast implementation of public-
key cryptography on a DSP TMS320C6201, Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Sys-
tems, CHES'99, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 1717, Springer, 1999, pp. 61 -
72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e718a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e725" publication-type="other">
T. Izu, B. Möller, and T. Takagi, Improved elliptic curve multiplication methods resistant
against side channel attacks, Progress in Cryptology, INDOCRYPT'02, Lecture Notes in
Computer Science, vol. 2551, Springer, 2002, pp. 269-313.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e738a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e745" publication-type="other">
T. Izu and T. Takagi, A fast parallel elliptic curve multiplication resistant against side chan-
nel attacks, Public Key Cryptography, PKC'02, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol.
2274, Springer, 2002, pp. 280-296.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e758a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e765" publication-type="other">
---, Fast elliptic curve multiplications resistant against side channel attacks, IEICE
Transactions Fundamentals E88-A (2005), no. 1, 161-171.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e775a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e782" publication-type="other">
M. Joye and C. Tymen, Protections against differential analysis for elliptic curve cryptog-
raphy - an algebraic approach, Cryptographic Hardware and Embedded Systems, CHES'01,
Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 2162, Springer, 2001, pp. 377 - 390. MR1946618
(2003k:94031)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e798a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e805" publication-type="other">
N. Koblitz, Elliptic curve cryptosystems, Mathematics of Computation 48 (1987), no. 177,
203-209. MR866109 (88b:94017)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e815a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e822" publication-type="other">
P. Kocher, J. Jaffe, and B. Jun, Differential power analysis, Advances in Cryptology,
CRYPTO'99, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 1666, Springer, 1999, pp. 388-397.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e833a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e840" publication-type="other">
P. C. Kocher, Timing attacks on implementations of Diffie-Hellman, RSA, DSS, and other
systems, Advances in Cryptology, CRYPTO'96, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol.
1109, Springer, 1996, pp. 104-113.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e853a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e860" publication-type="other">
J. Lopez and R. Dahab, An improvement of the Guajardo- Paar method for multiplication on
non-supersingular elliptic curves, Proceedings of the XVIII International Conference of the
Chilean Society of Computer Science, SCCC'98, 1998, pp. 91-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e873a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e880" publication-type="other">
K. Mahler, On a special functional equation, Journal of the London Mathematical Society
s1-15 (1940), no. 2, 115-123. MR0002921 (2:133e)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e890a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e897" publication-type="other">
V. S. Miller, Uses of elliptic curves in cryptography, Advances in Cryptology, CRYPTO'85,
Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol. 218, Springer, 1986, pp. 417-428. MR851432
(88b:68040)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e910a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e917" publication-type="other">
National Institute of Standards and Technology, FIPS PUB 186-2: Digital signature standard
(DSS), National Institute of Standards and Technology, January 2000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e927a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e934" publication-type="other">
W. B. Pennington, On Mahler's partition problem, Annals of Mathematics 57 (1953), no. 3,
531-546. MR0053959 (14:846m)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e945a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e952" publication-type="other">

              C. M. Skinner, On the diophantine equation
              
              , Journal of Number
            
Theory 35 (1990), 194-207. MR1057322 (91h:11021)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e965a1310">
            <label>42</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e972" publication-type="other">
J. Solinas, Generalized mersenne numbers, Research Report CORR-99-39, Center for Applied
Cryptographic Research, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e982a1310">
            <label>43</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e989" publication-type="other">
Certicom Research The SECG group, SEC 2: Recommended elliptic curve domain parame-
ters, Standard for Efficient Cryptography, September 2000, http://www.secg.org/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e999a1310">
            <label>44</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e1006" publication-type="other">
R. Tijdeman, On the maximal distance between integers composed of small primes, Compo-
sitio Mathematica 28 (1974), 159-162. MR0345917 (49:10646)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4832459e1016a1310">
            <label>45</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4832459e1023" publication-type="other">
H. S. Wilf, Generatingfunctionology, 2nd ed., Academic Press Inc., 1994. MR1277813
(95a:05002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


