<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465710</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465718</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Predictable Corporate Distributions and Stock Returns</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hendrik</given-names>
                  <surname>Bessembinder</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Feng</given-names>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1199</fpage>
         <lpage>1241</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465718"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Corporate managers frequently announce corporate distributions, including stock splits, stock dividends, special dividends, and increases in regular dividends, on the anniversary of a like announcement at the same firm. The market appears to not fully appreciate the implications of current distributions for future distributions and stock returns, as a simple strategy that involves purchasing firms with high predicted probabilities of distribution announcements earns significant abnormal monthly returns. These results are distinct from previously documented return regularities related to regular earnings and dividend announcements and return seasonality.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1240248e263a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e270" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Fama et al. (1969), Grinblatt, Masulis, and Titman (1984), and McNichols and Dravid (1990)
regarding announcement returns for stock dividends and stock splits, Brickley (1983) and DeAngelo, DeAngelo,
and Skinner (2000) for returns associated with special dividend announcements, and Lie (2000) and Grullon,
Michaely, and Swaminathan (2002) regarding returns at dividend increase announcements.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e286a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e293" publication-type="other">
Including share repurchases in a study of distribution events is also natural. However, Banyi, Dyl, and Kahle
(2008) document significant errors in share repurchase announcement dates. Despite these errors, we document
(Figure Al of the Internet Appendix) a degree of calendar-based recurrence in the repurchase announcement
dates in the SDC Platinum database for the 1980 to 2012 period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e309a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e316" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Lo and MacKinlay (1990), White (2000), and Harvey, Liu, and Zhu (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e323a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e330" publication-type="other">
The sample period starts in 1963 because we require accounting data from Compustat that are not available for
earlier years for most firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e341a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e348" publication-type="other">
We impose the minimum dividend increase requirement to focus on events that should be informative and relevant
to valuation. However, our central results are robust to either not imposing a minimum rate of increase or to
raising the minimum increase to 10%.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e361a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e368" publication-type="other">
We extend the window to 20-180 trading days for semiannual cash dividends and 20-360 trading days for annual
dividends.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e378a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e385" publication-type="other">
About two-thirds of sample firms have a fiscal year that ends in December.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e392a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e399" publication-type="other">
Cukurova (2013) reports that annual corporate meetings are most frequently held in April and May. We obtain
annual meeting dates from the RiskMetrics database.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e409a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e416" publication-type="other">
Explanatory variables are winsorized at the upper and lower 1% boundaries to mitigate the effect of outliers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e423a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e430" publication-type="other">
To ensure that we rely on accounting data that would have been available to investors, we use ROA and cash
holdings data from the fiscal year that ends in calendar year Y-l as the explanatory variables in the hazard model
from July of year Y to June of year Y +1. To increase the usable sample size, we replace missing ROA and cash
holding data with the market median in the fiscal year when estimating the probability of a follow-on dividend
increase or a follow-on special dividend. In unreported results (available upon request), we find that excluding
the observations with missing ROA and cash balance does not alter our results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e454a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e461" publication-type="other">
To estimate the probability of a follow-on event during the first ten years of our sample period (1963-1972),
we rely on distribution data prior to 1963. In light of the evidence that the predictability mainly stems from
calendar-related recurrence, we replace missing ROA and cash-holding data with the market median in the fiscal
year to increase the usable data points.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e477a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e484" publication-type="other">
Asparouhova, Bessembinder, and Kalcheva (2013) show that noise in transaction prices leads to upward bias in
equal-weighted portfolio returns. We implement their correction, which simply involves weighting each return
by the prior-period gross return on the same security.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e497a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e504" publication-type="other">
For example, Bessembinder and Zhang (2013) document that the apparent abnormal long-run returns to firms
issuing equity can be attributed to differences in firm characteristics, including illiquidity and idiosyncratic
volatility, that are related to average returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e517a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e524" publication-type="other">
This evidence parallels that presented by La Porta et al. ( 1997), who show that returns in the days around earnings
surprises can substantially explain the value premium in returns, a result that is also difficult to reconcile with
risk-based explanations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e537a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e544" publication-type="other">
We also assess the effect of selecting stocks on the basis of high absolute predicted event probabilities, rather
than of high relative (K = 1 % and K=5%) probabilities. In particular, we form portfolios of stocks with estimated
probabilities of a follow-on corporate event above the cutoffs of X = (5%, 10%, 20%, or 40%). The resulting
alpha estimates are reported in Table A3 of the Internet Appendix and are uniformly positive and significant at
the 1% level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e563a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e572" publication-type="other">
An alternative would be to exclude stocks that announced earnings rather than those expected to announce
earnings. An effect would be that stocks that unexpectedly did not announce earnings, that is, that were late
in announcing earnings, would then be retained. However, this event would be informative if it occurred. This
analysis is restricted to the post-January 1973 period (following Frazzini and Lamont 2006), because of the poor
coverage of earnings announcement dates in the Compustat database before 1973.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e592a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e599" publication-type="other">
The rate of coincidence for our sample of dividend increase announcements and Hartzmark and Solomon's
(2013) sample of regular dividend ex-dates simply captures the proportion of dividend increase events in which
the announcement and the ex-dividend date occur in the same month.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e612a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e619" publication-type="other">
In particular, we identify a company as having a predicted ex-dividend date in month s if it had an ex-dividend
date for a quarterly dividend in months s-3, s-6, 5-9, or 5-12, a semiannual dividend in months 5-6 or 5-12, an
annual dividend in months 5-12, or a dividend of unknown frequency in months 5-3, 5-6, 5-9, or 5-12.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1240248e632a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1240248e639" publication-type="other">
We also assess whether Heston and Sadka's (2008) results survive the exclusion of stocks with high predicted
probabilities of distribution events and find that they do.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1240248e658a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e662" publication-type="other">
Asparouhova, E., H. Bessembinder, and I. Kalcheva. 2013. Noisy prices and inference regarding returns. Journal
of Finance 68:665-714.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e676" publication-type="other">
Banyi, M. L., E. A. Dyl, and K. M. Kahle. 2008. Errors in estimating share repurchases. Journal of Corporate
Finance 14:460-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e686a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e690" publication-type="other">
Beaver, W. H. 1968. The information content of annual earnings announcements. Journal of Accounting Research
6:67-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e700a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e704" publication-type="other">
Bernard, V. L., and J. K. Thomas. 1990. Evidence that stock prices do not fully reflect the implications of current
earnings for future earnings. Journal of Accounting and Economics 13:305-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e715a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e719" publication-type="other">
Bessembinder, H., and F. Zhang. 2013. Firm characteristics and long-run stock returns after corporate events.
Journal of Financial Economics 109:83-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e729a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e733" publication-type="other">
Brickley, J. A. 1983. Shareholder wealth, information signaling and the specially designated dividend: An
empirical study. Journal of Financial Economics 12:187-209.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e747" publication-type="other">
Brown, S. J., and J. B. Warner. 1980. Measuring security price performance. Journal of Financial Economics
8:205-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e761" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e772" publication-type="other">
Chordia, T., R. Roll, and A. Subrahmanyam. 2011. Recent trends in trading activity and market quality. Journal
of Financial Economics 101:243-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e786" publication-type="other">
Cox, D. R. 1972. Regression models and life-tables (with discussion). Journal of the Royal Statistical Society,
Series B 34:187-220.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e797a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e801" publication-type="other">
Cukurova, S. 2013. What do outside directors learn around annual meetings? Evidence from insider trading.
Working Paper, Aalto University School of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e815" publication-type="other">
DeAngelo, H., L. DeAngelo, and D. J. Skinner. 2000. Special dividends and the evolution of dividend signaling.
Journal of Financial Economics 57:309-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e829" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Corporate payout policy. Foundations and Trends in Finance 3:95-287.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e836a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e840" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., L. Fisher, M. C. Jensen, and R. Roll. 1969. The adjustment of stock prices to new information.
International Economic Review 10:1-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e850a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e854" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 1993. Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial
Economics 33:3-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e864a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e868" publication-type="other">
Frazzini, A., and O. Lamont. 2006. The earnings announcement premium and trading volume. Working Paper,
NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e879a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e883" publication-type="other">
Grinblatt, M., R. Masulis, and S. Titman. 1984. The valuation effects of stock splits and stock dividends. Journal
of Financial Economics 4:461-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e893a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e897" publication-type="other">
Grullon, G, R. Michaely, and B. Swaminathan. 2002. Are dividend changes a sign of firm maturity? Journal of
Business 75:387-424.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e911" publication-type="other">
Hartzmark, S. M., and D. H. Solomon. 2013. The dividend month premium. Journal of Financial Economics
109:640-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e921a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e925" publication-type="other">
Harvey, C. R., Y. Liu, and H. Zhu. 2014.... and the cross-section of stock returns. Working Paper, Duke University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e932a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e936" publication-type="other">
Heston, S. L., and R. Sadka. 2008. Seasonality in the cross-section of stock returns. Journal of Financial
Economics 87:418^45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e946a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e950" publication-type="other">
Kalay, A., and U. Loewenstein. 1985. Predictable events and excess returns: The case of dividend announcements.
Journal of Financial Economics 14:423-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e961a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e965" publication-type="other">
La Porta, R., J. Lakonishok, A. Shleifer, and R. Vishny. 1997. Good news for value stocks: Further evidence on
market efficiency. Journal of Finance 52:859-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e975a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e979" publication-type="other">
Lakonishok, J., and B. Lev. 1987. Stock splits and stock dividends: Why, who, and when. Journal of Finance
42:913-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e989a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e993" publication-type="other">
Lie, E. 2000. Excess funds and agency problems: An empirical study of incremental cash distributions. Review
of Financial Studies 13:219-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1003a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1007" publication-type="other">
Lo, A., and C. MacKinlay. 1990. Data snooping biases in tests of financial asset pricing models. Review of
Financial Studies 3:431-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1017a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1021" publication-type="other">
McNichols, M., and A. Dravid. 1990. Stock dividends, stock splits, and signaling. Journal of Finance 45:857-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1028a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1032" publication-type="other">
Muscarella, C. J., and M. R. Vetsuypens. 1996. Stock splits: Signaling or liquidity? The case of ADR 'solo-splits'.
Journal of Financial Economics 42:3-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1043a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1047" publication-type="other">
Pontiff, J. 2006. Costly arbitrage and the myth of idiosyncratic risk. Journal of Accounting and Economics
42:35-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1057a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1061" publication-type="other">
Pontiff, J., and D. McLean. 2013. Does academic research destroy stock return predictability? Working Paper,
Boston College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1071a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1075" publication-type="other">
Royston, P. 2006. Explained variation for survival models. Stata Journal 6:83-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1082a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1086" publication-type="other">
Sias, R., and L. Starks. 1997. Return autocorrelations and institutional investors. Journal of Financial Economics
46:103-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1096a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1100" publication-type="other">
Stambaugh, R. F., J. Yu, and Y. Yuan. 2012. The short of it: Investor sentiment and anomalies. Journal of Financial
Economics 104:288-302.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1240248e1110a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1240248e1114" publication-type="other">
White, H. 2000. A reality check for data snooping. Econometrica 68:1097-126.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


