<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830275</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830282</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE DETERMINATION OF THE EXTERNAL DEBT OF HONDURAS / LA DETERMINATION DE LA DETTE EXTERNE D'HONDURAS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Luis René</given-names>
                  <surname>Cáceres</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1991</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>385</fpage>
         <lpage>407</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830282"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper examines the feasibility of undertaking efforts to overcome the debt problems of developing countries by means of accelerating their economic growth. This approach consists in that a country will increase its saving ratio to such magnitude that it surpasses the requirement of investment and interest payments, whereby the resulting saving surplus leads to a reduction in its external debt. Computations carried out for the case of Honduras indicate that if consumption was limited to grow at 2% annually while the economy grows at 5%, it would have to wait 10 years for its debt to begin decreasing. Besides, its external debt would be twice as large within this period, which seems very difficult to attain given to scarcity of funds available to developing countries. Given this result, an alternative approach to the determination of external debt is developed wherein the annual demand for external resources depends on domestic income and on the international interest rate. This latter variable explains much of Honduras' debt growth in the 1981-1987 period, given the significant increase in the cost of capital during the past decade. Since the interest rate increase has resulted from the fiscal deficit of developed countries an analysis is made of the asimetric relationship between the economic growth of developed and developing countries. Finally, a series of compensating measures are examined, that could be used to provide compensation to the developing countries by the developed ones on account of the latter's economic mismanagement. Ce papier examine la possibilité d'entreprendre des efforts pour surmonter les problêmes des pays sous-développés par moyen d'accélérer leur croissance économique. Cette approche consiste d'un pays qui augment sa proportion d'épargne jusqu'au niveau où il surpasse la condition requise d'investissements et paiements des intérêts, lorsque le resultat de surplus épargne entraîne à reduire la dette externe. Les calculations fait dans le cas d'Honduras indiquent que quand la consommation étais limitée à augmenter 2 pour cent par an pendant que l'économie augmentait à 5 pour cent, il faudra attendre 10 ans avant que la dette commence à diminuer. D'ailleurs, sa dette externe sera deux fois si grande dans cette période, laquelle semble très difficile d'atteindre gràce à la rareté des fonds disponible pour les pays en traîn de développer. Donné ce résultat, un approche alternatif à la détermination de la dette externe est développée où la demande annuelle pour ressources externes depende sur le revenu domestique et sur les impôts internationaux des intérêts. La seconde variable explique beaucoup sur la croissance de la dette Hondurienne dans la période 1981-1987, donnée l'augmentation significative du prix des fonds pendant la dernière décade. Puisque l'augmentation des intérêts des impôts est un résultat du déficit fiscal des pays sous-développés, une analyse est faite de la rélation (asimetric?) entre la croissance économique des pays développés et sous-développés. En fin, une succession de mesures compensateurs est examinée, qui peut être utilisée pour fournir compensation aux pays sous-développés par les pays développés à cause de cette dernière mauvaise administration économique.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e199a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e206" publication-type="other">
Marcelo Selowsky and Herman G. Van der Tak, "The Debt Problem and Growth", World Development, vol.
14, No. 1, Septiembre, 1986, pp. 1107-1124.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e216a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e223" publication-type="other">
M. Selowsky and H. van der Tak, op. cit., p. 1123</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e230a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e237" publication-type="other">
World Bank, World Debt Tables, 1989</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e243" publication-type="other">
IMF, International Financial Statistics</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e250a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e257" publication-type="other">
Luis Rene Caceres, et. al, "Consideraciones sobre el Endeudamiento Externo de Central America", Boletin
de Ciencias Econdmicas, IX, No. 3, May-June, 1986, p. 130-146.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e268a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e275" publication-type="other">
William Loehr, "Balance en Cuenta Corriente en Central America (1969-1984): Influencias Locales y Ex-
ternas", Revista de la Integracion y el Desarrollo de Centroamerica, No. 36, 1987, p. 21-61.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e285a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e292" publication-type="other">
Luis
Rene Caceres and Salvador Quintanilla, "Sector Externo y Ahorro Domestico: El Papel de las Exportaciones
Intrarregionales en Centroamerica", BCIE, Cuadernos de Economia y Finanzas, No. 11, april 1990.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e305a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e314" publication-type="other">
Rudiger Dornbusch, "La Situacion Economica Mundial y los Paises Deudores", in Ana Maria
Martinela-Martel, Deuda Externa, Ahorro y Crecimiento en America Latina, Washington, D.C., International
Monetary Fund, 1988, p. 57.89.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e327a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e334" publication-type="other">
Economic Report of the President, Washington, D.C, 1988.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e340" publication-type="other">
Richard J. Cebula, "Federal Government Budget Deficits and Interest Rates: An Emprical Analysis for the
United States, 1985-1988", Public Finance, vol. 43, No. 3, 1988, pp. 337-347</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e349" publication-type="other">
"Federal
Government Budget Deficits and Interest Rates in the United States: An Empirical Analysis", Economia
Internazionale, vol. 41, No. 1-2, February-March 1988, pp. 1-7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e362a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e371" publication-type="other">
Norman S. Fieleke, The International Economy Under Stress, New York Ballinger Publishing Company,
1988, page 137.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e380" publication-type="other">
Eduardo Conesa, "El Deficit Fiscal Estadounidense y la Crisis de le Deuda Externa Latinoamericana",
Integracion Latinoamericana, 13, No. 139, October 1988, pp. 21.35</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e390" publication-type="other">
V.R. Errunza and J.P. Ghalbouni, "Interest
Rates and International Debt Crisis", Banca Nazionale del Lavoro Quarterly Review, No. 157, pp. 225-245.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e400a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e407" publication-type="other">
Sweder van Wijnbergen, "Interdependence Revisited: a Developing Countries Perspective on
Macroeconomic Management and Trade Policy in the Industrial World", Economic Policy, November 1985, pp.
82-137.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e419" publication-type="other">
Paul Atkinson and Jean-Calude Chouraqui, "The Origins of High Real Interest Rates", OECD Economic
Studies, No. 5, Fall 1985, pp. 7-56.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e430a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e437" publication-type="other">
Rob Vos, "Savings, Investment and Foreign Capital Flows: Have Capital Markets Become
More Integrated?, Journal of Development Studies, vol. 24, No. 3, April 1988, pp. 370-334.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e447a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e456" publication-type="other">
Aksav H. Mansur and David J. Robinson, "Transmission of Effects of the Fiscal Deficit in Industrial
Countries", in Mario I. Blejer and Ke-Joung Chu, eds., Fiscal Policy, Stabilization and Growth in Developing
Countries, Washington, D.C., International Monetary Fund, 1989.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e469a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e476" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund, World Economic Outlook, October, 1989.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e483a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e490" publication-type="other">
Morris Goldstein and Mohsin Kahn, "Effects of a Slowdown in Industrial Countries on
Growth in non-oil Developing Countries", Occasional Papers, No. 12, International Monetary Fund, August 1982</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e499" publication-type="other">
J. Michael Finger and Patrick A. Masser-Lin, "The Effects of Slowdown in Industrial Countries Policies on Develop-
ing Countries", World Bank, Policy Planning and Research Series, No. 3, 1989</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e508" publication-type="other">
Philippe Collier, "Growth of
Developing Countries and the World Interest Rates", Journal of Macroeconomics, vol. 6, No. 4, Fall, 1984, pp.
465-471.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e521a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e528" publication-type="other">
Paul Sounder and Andrew Dean, "The International Debt Situation and Linkages between Developing
Countries and the OECD", OECD Economic Studies, No. 7, Fall 1986, pp. 155-203</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e537" publication-type="other">
F. Landis Mackellar, "Modell-
ing the Developing Regions in a Linked International Context", Papers of the Regional Science Association,
Vol. 65, 1988, pp. 79-100.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e550a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e557" publication-type="other">
Ralph E, Bryant, John F. Helliwell and Peter Hooper, "Domestic and Cross-Border Consequences
of U.S. Macroeconomic Policies", in Macroeconomic Policies in an Interdependent World, R. C, Bryant, D.A.
Currie, J. A. Frenkel, P. R. Masson and R. Portes, ed., Washington, D.C., The Brookings Institution, 1989, pp.
150-122.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e572" publication-type="other">
Anton Muscatelli and David Vines,
"Macroeconomic Interaction Between the North and South", in R. C. Bryant, D.A. Currie, J. A. Frenkel, P.R.
Masson and R. Portes, eds., op. cit. pp. 384-416.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e586a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e593" publication-type="other">
L. R. Caceres, "Ahorro, Inversion, Deuda Externa y Catastrofe", El Trimestre
Econdmico, vol. 52, No. 207, July-September 1986, pp. 683-704.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e603a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e610" publication-type="other">
W. M. Buiter and R.C. Marston, eds., International Economic Policy Coordination, Cam-
bridge, Cambridge University Press, 1985.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e620a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e627" publication-type="other">
Michael Artis and Silvia Astry, International Economic Policy Coordination, London, Routledge and Kegan
Paul, 1986, p. 13.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e637a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e644" publication-type="other">
Michael Beenstock, "An Econometric Investigation of North-South Interdependence",
in David Currie and David Vines, ed., Macroeconomic Interactions Between North and South, Cambridge, Cam-
bridge University Press, 1988, pp. 32-64.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e657a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e664" publication-type="other">
James M. Buchanan, "Joint Supply, Externality and Optimality", Journal of Political Economy, November
1966, pp. 404-415.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e674a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e681" publication-type="other">
J. Buchanan, "An Economic Theory of Clubs", Economics, Vol. 32, February 1965, pp. 1-14.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e689a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e696" publication-type="other">
Jose Luis Martin Simon, "La Influencia de las
Externalidades en la Economia del Bienestar", Cuadernos de Economfa, vol. 17, No. 48, January-April 1989,
pp. 95-134.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e709a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e716" publication-type="other">
Report on Trade and Development of UNCTAD, 1985</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e722" publication-type="other">
M. Marcel and G. Palma,
"Third World Debt and its Effects on the British Economy: A Southern View of Economic Mismanagement in
the North", Cambridge Journal of Economics, Vol. 12, 1988, pp. 361-400.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e735a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e742" publication-type="other">
M. Marcel and G. Palma, op. cit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e749a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e756" publication-type="other">
Peter F. Drucker, "Latin America Economically Crucial to U.S.", The Wall Street Journal, April 1990</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e762" publication-type="other">
Tegucigalpa This Week, vol. 3, No. 15, April 28 1990. pp. 19-20.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


