<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278273</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of Post-Injection Strategies on Near-Injector Over-Lean Mixtures and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emission in a Heavy-Duty Optical Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chartier</surname>
                  <given-names>Clément</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Oivind</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Bengt</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Musculus</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bobba</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1978</fpage>
         <lpage>1992</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278273"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Post-injection strategies aimed at reducing engine-out emissions of unburned hydrocarbons (UHC) were investigated in an optical heavy-duty diesel engine operating at a low-load, low-temperature combustion (LTC) condition with high dilution (12.7% intake oxygen) where UHC emissions are problematic. Exhaust gas measurements showed that a carefully selected post injection reduced engine-out load-specific UHC emissions by 20% compared to operation with a single injection in the same load range. High-speed in-cylinder chemiluminescence imaging revealed that without a post injection, most of the chemiluminescence emission occurs close to the bowl wall, with no significant chemiluminescence signal within 27 mm of the injector. Previous studies have shown that over-leaning in this near-injector region after the end of injection causes the local equivalence ratio to fall below the ignitability limit. With a carefully selected post-injection, mixtures close to the injector show significant chemiluminescence emission, indicating more complete combustion of those regions, likely due to increased local equivalence ratios.</p>
            <p>Simultaneous planar laser-induced fluorescence (PLIF) of OH with 284-nm excitation and PLIF of combined formaldehyde and poly aromatic hydrocarbons (PAH) with 355-nm excitation were employed to identify the regions of first- and second-stage ignition, as well as providing some indication of local equivalence ratios. The laser diagnostics show that without a post injection, regions close to the injector show formaldehyde fluorescence late in the cycle without detectable OH fluorescence, indicating that these regions do not achieve second-stage ignition, and therefore likely contribute to UHC emissions. Persistence of formaldehyde fluorescence late in the cycle is also consistent with fuel-lean mixtures. With a carefully selected post injection, strong OH fluorescence appears in the near-injector regions, indicating that they are likely enriched by the post-injection such that they reach second-stage ignition and more complete oxidation. The reduction observed in the exhaust UHC emission is therefore attributed to the enrichment mechanism of the near-injector regions by the close-coupled post-injection.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Bae, C., Miles, P.C., Choi, D., and Pickett, L.M, “The Influence of Charge Dilution and Injection Timing on Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3837, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., “A Conceptual Model of D.I. Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L.M., and Idicheria, C.A., “End-of-Injection Over-Mixing and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions in Low-Temperature- Combustion Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007- 01-0907, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lachaux, T. and Musculus, M.P.B., “In-cylinder Unburned Hydrocarbon Visualization during Low- Temperature Compression-Ignition Engine Combustion Using Formaldehyde PLIF,” Proc.Combustion.Inst.,2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Ekoto, I., Colban, W.F. and Miles, P.C., “In-cylinder CO and UHC Imaging in a Light-Duty Engine Diesel Engine during PPCI Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):933-956, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, M. Assanis, D.N. and Bohac, S.V., “Sources of Hydrocarbon Emissions from Low-Temperature Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion from a Common Rail Direct Injection Diesel Engine”, Combustion Science and Technology, 181: 3, pp. 496-517, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Genzale, C.L., Reitz, R.D., and Musculus, M.P.B., “Effects of Jet-Bowl and Jet-Jet Interactions on Late- Injection Low-Temperature Heavy-Duty Diesel Combustion”, Proceedings Thiesel 2008, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C.P., Ra, Y., Krieger, R., Andrie, M., et al., “Detailed Unburned Hydrocarbon Investigations in a Highly-Dilute Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):858-879, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collin, R., Nygren, J., Richter, M., Aldén, M., Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., “Simultaneous OH- and Formaldehyde- LIF Measurements in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3218, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-3218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., Musculus, M.P.B and Reitz, R.D, “Mixing and flame structures inferred from OH-PLIF for conventional and low-temperature diesel engine combustion,” Combustion and Flame 156 (2009), pp. 1898-1908, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Dec, J.E. and Tree, D.R., “Effects of Fuel Parameters and Diffusion Flame Lift- Off on Soot Formation in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0889, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0889.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Espey, C. and Dec, J.E., “Diesel Engine Combustion Studies in a Newly Designed Optical Access Engine Using High-Speed Visualization and 2-D Laser Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 930971, 1993, doi:10.4271/930971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ojeda, W., Zoldak, P., Espinosa, R., and Kumar, R., “Development of a Fuel Injection Strategy for Partially Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1473-1488, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, Inc., 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bobba, M.K, Chartier, C., Andersson, Ö., Johansson, B., Musculus, M.P.B, “Planar Laser-Diagnostics of Soot and OH with Post-Injections in a Heavy-Duty LTC Diesel Engine”, Proceedings Thiesel 2010, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., “On the Correlation between NOx Emissions and the Diesel Premixed Burn,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1401, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1401.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klein-Douwel, R. J. H., Frijters, P. J. M., Seykens, X. L. J., Somers, L. M. T. and Baert, R. S. G. “Gas Density and Rail Pressure Effects on Diesel Spray Growth from a Heavy-Duty Common Rail Injector,” Energy &amp; Fuels 2009, 23, pp. 1832-1842, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kohse-Höinghaus, K. “Laser techniques for the quantitative detection of reactive intermediates in combustion systems”. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 20, 203-279, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Genzale, C.L., Reitz, R.D. and Musculus, M.P.B. “Effects of Piston Bowl Geometry on Mixture Development and Late- Injection Low-Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1): 913- 937, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S.A., Flowers, D.L., Espinosa-Loza, F., Martinez-Frias, J., Dibble, R.W., Christenson, M., Bengt, J., and Hessel, R.P., “Piston-Liner Crevice Geometry Effect on HCCI Combustion by Multi-Zone Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2869, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01- 2869.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greeves, G., Khan, I.M., Wang, C.H.T., and Fenne, I., “Origins of Hydrocarbon Emissions from Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 770259, 1977, doi:10.4271/770259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
