<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186480</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44437103</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PART I</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject>Engines, Fuels, Lubricants, Supercharging</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Methods of Measuring Detonation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Neil</given-names>
                  <surname>Mac Coull</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1928</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>63</fpage>
         <lpage>73</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44437103"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>AREPORT is made herein of an attempt to correlate measurements of the antiknock values of gasolines as determined by various laboratories. Six samples of gasoline were sent to each of 10 laboratories that agreed to cooperate, the principal object being to learn whether volatility affects the antiknock values obtained from multi-cylinder engines more than it affects the values obtained from singlecylinder engines. The results of the tests are shown in numerous tables and charts. The conclusions reached are that (1) Further development of antiknock measurements is needed (2) Certain elements of technique, such as the mixture-ratio and the spark-setting should be standardized at once (3) Intensive study should be made of the fundamental methods in use for the direct control of detonation in test engines, such as the compression ratio and the manifold vacuum (4) Measurement of antiknock values in terms of the mixtures of a reference fuel with benzol or tetraethyl lead is likely to be very misleading if the peculiarities of such scales are not thoroughly understood by the investigator (5) The data obtained indicate that probably no great difference in the results exists whether the detonation point is determined by audibility, the maximum power, or the bouncing-pin (6) The size and type of engine used does not seem to affect the results (7) Eventually, a reference fuel of low antiknock value and one of high antiknock value should be standardized</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


