<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">32</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186520</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44438074</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Determination of Ratings for Transport Aircraft Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>R. F.</given-names>
                  <surname>Gagg</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1937</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>400</fpage>
         <lpage>427</lpage>
         <page-range>400-404, 427</page-range>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44438074"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>THE objective in determining an engine rating is to establish the limiting values for the variables in operating procedure which permit a maximum of utility in power output and economy of fuel consistent with requirements for safety and durability in the class of service for which the engine in intended. The obvious safety requirement is that no interruptions to service shall occur due to engine trouble when operations are conducted in the manner established by the rating tests. This paper consists of a discussion of testing methods to be used for the determination of engine ratings, and some suggestions for the adoption of a uniform procedure. Standardization of engine-rating procedure is thoroughly in accord with the established policy of the American aircraft industry as a means of insuring a maximum of safety to air-transport passengers. American aircraft and engine-testing requirements are more rigorous than those of many of our foreign competitors, and it is for this reason that American products have established a worldwide reputation for safety and durability. If this leadership is to be maintained, technical standardization and advancement must be synchronized and coordinated so that each activity supplements the other.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


