<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437419</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Dynamics of Household Wealth Accumulation in Italy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>TULLIO</given-names>
                  <surname>JAPPELLI</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>LUIGI</given-names>
                  <surname>PISTAFERRI</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437413</issue-id>
         <fpage>269</fpage>
         <lpage>295</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2000</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437419"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>We examine the dynamics of wealth accumulation distribution in Italy using data drawn from the Survey of Household Income and Wealth, a representative survey of the Italian population conducted by the Bank of Italy. We compare survey data with National Accounts data and discuss sample representativeness, attrition and measurement issues. We then look at wealth inequality (the cross-sectional dispersion of wealth) and wealth mobility (individual transitions across the wealth distribution) and examine the age profile of wealth using repeated cross-sectional data. Finally, we consider various explanations for the pattern of wealth accumulation in Italy, focusing on retirement, bequests, income risk, health shocks and credit market imperfections.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d8e254a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e261" publication-type="other">
Another explanation for the increase in response rates in 1993 is the change in the firm responsible for
collecting the data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e271a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e278" publication-type="other">
The problem of bracketing can be handled either by assuming that all households own the mid-point of the
interval or by applying more sophisticated imputation procedures, such as that suggested by Stewart (1983).
The advantage of the second procedure falls with the number of brackets. Since we have a relatively high
number of brackets, we proceed with the first alternative.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e294a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e301" publication-type="other">
Financial wealth in 1995 is measured in 27 categories: checking accounts, three types of saving accounts, two
types of certificates of deposit, postal accounts, postal bonds, short-term government bonds, Treasury bonds
indexed to short-term bonds, long-term government bonds, zero-coupon government bonds, other government
bonds, corporate bonds, mutual funds, five types of equities, two types of management investment accounts,
trust funds, foreign bonds, foreign equities, other foreign assets and loans to co-operative firms. Wealth
brackets are: 0, up to 2 million lire, 2-4, 4-8, 8-12, 12-16. 16-24, 24-36, 36-70, 70-140, 140-300, 300-600.
600 million to 1 billion lire, 1-2 billion lire and over 2 billion lire.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e327a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e334" publication-type="other">
Note that the increase in the response rate highlighted in Table 1 might be, at least in part, responsible for the
increase in the wealth-income ratio and for the saving rate after 1993.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e345a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e352" publication-type="other">
Net worth and financial wealth inequalities increase slightly from 1989 to 1995.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e359a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e366" publication-type="other">
The pattern for financial wealth inequality is similar.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e373a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e380" publication-type="other">
Checchi, Ichino and Rustichini (1999) report data on intergenerational mobility for Italy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e387a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e394" publication-type="other">
Systematic changes in life-cycle wealth accumulation may affect our results. To counter this criticism, we
have analysed wealth mobility conditioning on the year of birth of the head of the household. In particular, we
allocate the panel households in our sample to six different cohorts. Cohort 1 includes those bom between 1905
and 1914, cohort 2 those bom between 1915 and 1924, and so forth; the youngest cohort includes those bom
between 1955 and 1964. We exclude those bom before 1904 or after 1964 because of small cell sizes. We find
that wealth mobility is much higher for the young than for the elderly, a fact that tallies with the evidence
presented in Deaton and Paxson (1993) and discussed further in Section IV. The reason for this is that the
retired no longer face income shocks, which are most responsible for movements up and down in the transition
matrix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e426a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e433" publication-type="other">
Clearly, the empirical relevance of this source of bias depends on the correlation between wealth and the
probability of death. Ando, Guiso and Terlizzese (1994) use Italian Census data and find that, while there is a
clear correlation between affluence and the probability of death at younger ages, there is little or no correlation
at ages above retirement (p. 193).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e449a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e456" publication-type="other">
The graph could also be used to detect breaks in cohort effects similar to the ones observed in the US for pre-
war generations compared with post-war generations (i.e. the baby boomers). In Italy, starting in the early
1970s, there has been a dramatic demographic transition, with the birth rate dropping from approximately 2 per
cent to just over 1 per cent in the past few years. This has been accompanied by a decline in the marriage rate
and an increase in the mean age at marriage and at childbearing. Since our youngest cohort was born between
1965 and 1969, these changes are too recent to produce detectable effects in our graphs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e480a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e487" publication-type="other">
The age-cohort profile for mean wealth can be interpreted as the total wealth of a cohort divided by the
number of individuals in that cohort. For the percentiles of the wealth distribution, however, the interpretation
is not straightforward. For instance, the age profile for median wealth is not the median per capita total wealth
in that cohort, because the 'median' individual changes across the wealth distribution.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e503a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e510" publication-type="other">
The assumptions used to compute pension wealth capture fairly well the characteristics of the social security
system before the 1992 reform, but tend to overstate pension wealth after the pension reforms, since the latter
increased retirement age and reduced the replacement rate. Using a replacement rate of 60 or 50 per cent
would, of course, affect the dynamics of pension wealth during retirement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e526a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e533" publication-type="other">
Neither method is obviously superior to the other. Kessler and Masson (1989) argue that what matters is the
propensity to save out of transfers, which is generally greater than zero (as in Modigliani (1988)) but less than
one (as in Kotlikoff and Summers (1981)). Thus the 'true' share of inherited wealth in Italy lies between 25 per
cent and 36 per cent, a sufficiently small range, at least relative to the figures reported for the US by Kotlikoff
and Summers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e552a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e559" publication-type="other">
In contrast to other OECD countries, where there is either an estate tax (where the tax base and rate depend
on the amount transferred by the deceased) or an inheritance tax (where base and rate depend on the amount
received by the beneficiary), Italy features both, inheritance taxes being levied only on legacies outside the
immediate family. These taxes were first introduced in 1972, replacing earlier legislation. Tax brackets and tax
rates for both types of taxes have been changed frequently in the past 20 years. The general principle is that of
progressive taxation. The spouse and direct descendants are subject only to the estate tax. More distant relatives
and other recipients are also subject to the inheritance tax, at rates that vary according to class of beneficiary.
Life insurance policies and social security benefits are not subject to inheritance taxes. Gifts are taxed in a way
similar to bequests.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e591a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e598" publication-type="other">
Only the currently employed receive an explicit compensation in case of temporary lay-off. The compensation
depends on gross earnings at the time of lay-off and on firm size. Its duration also varies by firm size. The
current legislation implies the following rules: for those working in firms with at least 50 employees and
earning a gross monthly salary above 1,250 Euros, unemployment benefits are set at 750 Euros a month and are
received for 12 months following the lay-off; for those working in firms with at least 50 employees and earning
a gross monthly salary below 1,250 Euros, benefits are set at either 625 Euros monthly or 80 per cent of gross
salary, whichever is the lower (duration is again 12 months); for those working in small firms (under 50
employees), benefits are set at 30 per cent of gross monthly income and are received for six months.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e627a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e634" publication-type="other">
The data used in this comparative study are the 1993 SEE for the US, the 1995 VSB panel for the
Netherlands and the 1995 SHIW for Italy. The measure of income uncertainty considered is the coefficient of
variation and is based on questions about income prospects that are similar across surveys but with two
important differences. First, Dutch and American households are asked to report the probabilities of income
falling below four thresholds (a given sequence in the SEE; equally spaced in the VSB), while in the SHIW
there is only one threshold (the average between the reported minimum and the reported maximum of expected
income). The SEE and the VSB both refer to household income, while the SHIW refers to individual earnings.
The coefficient of variation is then obtained assuming that the distribution of future income follows a multi-
step uniform distribution; this provides an upper bound to the true measure of uncertainty and is, of course,
subject to the criticism that the distribution of future income may differ across countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e670a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e677" publication-type="other">
Since the subjective conditional variance of income growth is a proxy for the conditional variance of
consumption growth, the coefficient they estimate has no structural interpretation. Yet, with isoelastic
preferences, the coefficient of prudence equals 1+jt where ^is the coefficient of relative risk aversion; since
credible values of the latter range from 1 to 10, the estimated coefficient (5.67) is consistent with the theoretical
restrictions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e696a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e703" publication-type="other">
In some cases, however, quality is not a relevant issue (for example, in the case of subsidies for drug
purchases).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e713a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e720" publication-type="other">
The 1993 SHIW contains a self-reported indicator of the quality of the services of the national health system.
The index ranges from 1 (lowest) to 10 (highest), and averages 4.1 in the South and 5.8 in the North.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e730a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e737" publication-type="other">
An increasing body of recent literature has characterised the joint distribution of health status, income and
wealth, and the connection between health and income inequality. Smith (1999) calculates median net worth by
self-reported health status and age in the Survey of Consumer Finances and finds that net worth is strongly
correlated with health status: poor health is associated with low wealth at all ages. The 1995 SHIW shows that
health status correlates with wealth in Italy as well. Note that the direction of causality between health and
wealth can go both ways. On the one hand, poor health affects labour market performance; on the other, the
wealthy can afford better health care.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e763a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e770" publication-type="other">
Starting in 1994, Italian banks offer mortgages with a lower down-payment requirement (about 20 per cent).
Such contracts are the results of a higher exposure to both domestic and international competition.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e780a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e787" publication-type="other">
Controlling for the growth rate of GDP, public sector saving and demographics does not change the positive
association between down payments and saving (the regression coefficient indicates that a 10 per cent increase
in the down-payment ratio raises saving by 2 percentage points).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e801a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e808" publication-type="other">
The other exception is large medical expenses. This might act as a buffer for unforeseen expenses and thus
reduce precautionary saving to face health hazards. However, withdrawal is allowed only once during the
employment contract and only for a small fraction of each company's work-force at any point in time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d8e830a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e834" publication-type="other">
Ando, A., Guiso, L. and Terlizzese, D. (1994), 'Dissaving by the elderly, transfer motives and
liquidity constraints', in A. Ando, L. Guiso and I. Visco (eds), Saving and the Accumulation of
Wealth: Essays on Italian Households and Government Behavior, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e850a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e854" publication-type="other">
Attanasio, O. and Brugiavini, A. (1996), 'L'effetto della riforma Amato sul risparmio delle famiglie
Italiane', University of Venice, Note di Lavoro no. 96-05.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e864a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e868" publication-type="other">
Barca, F., Cannari, L. and Guiso, L. (1994), 'Bequests and saving for retirement. What impels the
accumulation of wealth?', in A. Ando, L. Guiso and 1. Visco (eds), Saving and the
Accumulation of Wealth: Essays on Italian Households and Government Behavior, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e884a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e888" publication-type="other">
Brandolini, A. (1999), 'The personal distribution of income in post-war Italy: source description,
data quality, and the time pattern of income inequality', Bank of Italy, Temi di Discussione no.
350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e902a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e906" publication-type="other">
— and Cannari, L. (1994), 'Methodological appendix: the Bank of Italy's Survey of Household
Income and Wealth', in A. Ando, L. Guiso and I. Visco (eds), Saving and the Accumulation of
Wealth: Essays on Italian Households and Government Behavior, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e922a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e926" publication-type="other">
Brugiavini, A. (1997), 'Social security and retirement in Italy', in D. Wise (ed.), Frontiers in the
Economics of Aging, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e936a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e940" publication-type="other">
Caballero, R. J. (1990), 'Consumption puzzles and precautionary savings', Journal of Monetary
Economics, vol. 25, pp. 113-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e950a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e954" publication-type="other">
Carroll, C. D. and Samwick, A. (1997), 'The nature of precautionary saving', Journal of Monetary
Economics, vol. 40, pp. 41-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e964a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e968" publication-type="other">
Checchi, D., Ichino, A. and Rustichini, A. (1999), 'More equal but less mobile?', Journal of Public
Economics, vol. 74, pp. 351-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e978a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e982" publication-type="other">
Das, M. and Donkers, B. (1997), 'How certain are Dutch households about future income? An
empirical analysis', CentER, Discussion Paper no. 9738.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e993a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e997" publication-type="other">
Deaton, A. and Paxson, C. H. (1993), 'Intertemporal choice and inequality', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 102, pp. 384-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1007a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1011" publication-type="other">
Dominitz, J. and Manski, C. (1997), 'Using expectations data to study subjective income
expectations', Journal of the American Statistical Association, vol. 92, pp. 855-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1021a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1025" publication-type="other">
Feldstein, M. S. (1974), 'Social security, induced retirement, and aggregate capital accumulation'.
Journal of Political Economy, vol. 82, pp. 905-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1035a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1039" publication-type="other">
Guiso, L. and Jappelli, T. (1991), 'Do intergenerational transfers offset capital market
imperfections? Evidence from a cross-section of Italian households', European Economic
Review, vol. 35, pp. 103-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1052a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1056" publication-type="other">
— and — (1999), 'Private transfers, borrowing constraints and the timing of homeownership',
Centre for Economic Policy Research, Discussion Paper no. 2050 / Université di Salerno,
Center for Studies in Economics and Finance, Working Paper no. 17, mandata.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1069a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1073" publication-type="other">
—, — and Pistaferri, L. (1999), 'What determines earnings and employment uncertainty?', Centre
for Economic Policy Research, Discussion Paper no. 2043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1084a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1088" publication-type="other">
—, — and Terlizzese, D. (1992), 'Earnings uncertainty and precautionary saving', Journal of
Monetary Economics, vol. 30, pp. 307-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1098a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1102" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. E. (1978), 'Stochastic implications of the life-cycle permanent income hypothesis: theory
and evidence', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 86, pp. 971-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1112a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1116" publication-type="other">
Jappelli, T. (1999), 'The age-wealth profile and the life-cycle hypothesis: a cohort analysis with a
time series of cross-sections of Italian households', Review of Income and Wealth, vol. 45, pp.
57-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1129a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1133" publication-type="other">
— and Modigliani, F. (1998), 'The age-saving profile and the life-cycle hypothesis', Université di
Salerno, Center for Studies in Economics and Finance, Working Paper no. 9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1143a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1147" publication-type="other">
— and Pagano, M. (1994a), 'Personal saving in Italy', in J. M. Poterba (ed.), International
Comparisons of Household Saving, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1157a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1161" publication-type="other">
— and — (1994b), 'Saving, growth and liquidity constraints', Quarterly Journal of Economics,
vol. 106, pp. 83-109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1176" publication-type="other">
— and Pistaferri, L. (2000), 'Using subjective income expectations to test the excess sensitivity of
consumption to predicted income changes', European Economic Review, vol. 44, pp. 337-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1190" publication-type="other">
Kessler, D. and Masson, A. (1989), 'Bequest and wealth accumulation: are some pieces of the
puzzle missing?', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 3, pp. 141-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1200a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1204" publication-type="other">
Kotlikoff, L. J. and Summers, L. (1981), 'The role of intergenerational transfers in aggregate
capital accumulation', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 89, pp. 706-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1218" publication-type="other">
Lusardi, A. (1997), 'Precautionary saving and subjective earnings variance', Economic Letters, vol.
57, pp. 353-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1228a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1232" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F. (1986), 'Life cycle, individual thrift, and the wealth of nations', American Economic
Review, vol. 76, pp. 297-312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1242a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1246" publication-type="other">
— (1988), 'The role of intergenerational transfers and life cycle saving in the accumulation of
wealth', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 2, pp. 15-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1257a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1261" publication-type="other">
Palumbo, M. G. (1999), 'Uncertain medical expenses and precautionary saving near the end of the
life cycle', Review of Economic Studies, vol. 66, pp. 395-421.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1271a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1275" publication-type="other">
Peracchi, F. and Rossi, N. (1996), 'Nonostante tutto è una riforma', in Le nuove frontière della
politico economica, U. Galimberti, F. Giavazzi, A. Penati and G. Tabellini (eds), Milano: Sole
24 Ore.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1288a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1292" publication-type="other">
Smith, J. P. (1999), 'Healthy bodies and thick wallets: the dual relation between health and
economic status', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 13, pp. 145-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1302a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1306" publication-type="other">
Stewart, M. B. (1983), 'On least squares estimation when the dependent variable is grouped',
Review of Economic Studies, vol. 50, pp. 737-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
