<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909443</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>THE PRESIDENTIAL PLATFORMS</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>President-Elect Platform</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>McKenna</surname>
                  <given-names>Pat</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mr Pat McKenna is currently the chief of the Capabilities Analysis Branch, Analysis Management Division, Resource and Requirements Directorate United States Strategic Command. Mr McKenna holds a Bachelors of Science degree in Industrial and Management Systems Engineering from North Dakota State University and a Masters of Science in Industrial and Systems Engineering from the University of Nebraska, Lincoln. Mr McKenna has received numerous awards during his career to include Air Force Civilian Analyst of the Year (1998) and most recently the Joint Meritorious Civilian Service Award (2004). Mr McKenna has been serving the military operations research community and MORS in a variety of capacities starting in 1994 as a working group co-chair. He has served as a working group chair, composite group chair, working group and composite group coordinator, symposium chair, special meeting co-chair, and as a member of the board of directors since 2000. Pat began his service to the Executive Council in 2003 as the Vice President for Professional Affairs and is currently serving as the Vice President for Meeting Operations.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2005</year>
            <string-date>June 2005</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>38</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909423</issue-id>
         <fpage>23</fpage>
         <lpage>24</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2005 Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909443"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
