<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422620</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Combustion Indexes for Innovative Combustion Control</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ravaglioli</surname>
                  <given-names>Vittorio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ponti</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabrizio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>De Cesare</surname>
                  <given-names>Matteo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magneti Marelli SpA - Powertrain</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Stola</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magneti Marelli SpA - Powertrain</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Carra</surname>
                  <given-names>Filippo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Corti</surname>
                  <given-names>Enrico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422609</issue-id>
         <fpage>2371</fpage>
         <lpage>2381</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422620"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The continuous development of modern Internal Combustion Engine (ICE) management systems is mainly aimed at combustion control improvement. Nowadays, performing an efficient combustion control is crucial for drivability improvement, efficiency increase and pollutant emissions reduction. These aspects are even more crucial when innovative combustions (such as LTC or RCCI) are performed, due to the high instability and the high sensitivity with respect to the injection parameters that are associated to this kind of combustion. Aging of all the components involved in the mixture preparation and combustion processes is another aspect particularly challenging, since not all the calibrations developed in the setup phase of a combustion control system may still be valid during engine life.</p>
            <p>The most important quantities used for combustion control are engine load (Indicated Mean Effective Pressure or Torque delivered by the engine) and center of combustion (CA50), i.e. the angular position in which 50% of fuel burned within the engine cycle is reached. All these quantities can be directly evaluated starting from in-cylinder pressure measurement; however, the use of in-cylinder pressure sensors would significantly increase the cost of the whole engine management system. Due to these reasons, over the past years, many methodologies have been developed by the authors of this paper in order to evaluate combustion characteristics using low-cost sensors or sensors that are already present on-board. The approaches considered in this paper are based on engine speed fluctuations and engine block vibration. These measurements are performed through the magnetic pick-up facing the toothed wheel already present on-board and a low-cost accelerometer mounted on engine block. Each of these measurements allows estimating a combustion characteristic that can be used for combustion control, such as IMEP, pressure peak position, CA50. The paper presents how the combination of the information that can be extracted from the low or zero cost sensors employed enables the control of innovative combustions, as for example dual-fuel RCCI combustion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, S., Hanson, R., Wagner, R., and Reitz, R., "Efficiency and Emissions Mapping of RCCI in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0289, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., "Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gross, C. and Reitz, R., "Investigation of Steady-State RCCI Operation in a Light-Duty Multi-Cylinder Engine Using “Dieseline”," SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0761, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0761.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., "Partially Pre-Mixed Auto-Ignition of Gasoline to Attain Low Smoke and Low NOx at High Load in a Compression Ignition Engine and Comparison with a Diesel Fuel," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0006, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wissink, M. and Reitz, R., "Direct Dual Fuel Stratification, a Path to Combine the Benefits of RCCI and PPC," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):878-889, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0856.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bakker, P., De Abreu Goes, J., Somers, L., and Johansson, B., "Characterization of Low Load PPC Operation using RON70 Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1304, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pizzonia, F., Castiglione, T., Bova, S., “A Robust Model Predictive Control for efficient thermal management of internal combustion engines”, 2016, Applied Energy, Volume 169, 1 May 2016, pp. 555-566, DOI: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.02.063.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran Scott J, Hanson Reed M, Wagner Robert M, “Reactivity controlled compression ignition combustion on a multi-cylinder lightduty diesel engine”, International Journal of Engine Research, Vol 13, Issue 3, pp. 216 - 225, First published date: April-26-2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn S L, Hanson R M, ASplitter D, Reitz R D , “Fuel reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI): a pathway to controlled highefficiency clean combustion”, International Journal of Engine Research, Vol 12, Issue 3, pp. 209 - 226, First published date: June-22-2011, 10.1177/1468087411401548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DelVescovo, D., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., "The Effects of Charge Preparation, Fuel Stratification, and Premixed Fuel Chemistry on Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion," SAE Int. J. Engines 10(4):2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0773.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu Y, Hanson R, Reitz RD., “Investigation of Combustion Phasing Control Strategy During Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Multicylinder Engine Load Transitions”. ASME. J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power. 2014;136(9):091511-091511-10. doi:10.1115/1.4027190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cavina, N., Poggio, L., and Sartoni, G., "Misfire and Partial Burn Detection based on Ion Current Measurement," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2451-2460, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Azzoni, P., Moro, D., Porceddu-Cilione, C., and Rizzoni, G., "Misfire Detection in a High-Performance Engine by the Principal Component Analysis Approach," SAE Technical Paper 960622, 1996, doi:10.4271/960622.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gerhardt, J., Hönninger, H., and Bischof, H., "A New Approach to Functional and Software Structure for Engine Management Systems - BOSCH ME7," SAE Technical Paper 980801, 1998, doi:10.4271/980801.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ravaglioli, V., Ponti, F., and Stola, F., "Torsional Analysis of Different Powertrain Configurations for Torque and Combustion Phase Evaluation," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1544, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ponti, F., Ravaglioli V., Cavina, N., De Cesare, M., “Diesel Engine Combustion Sensing Methodology Based on Vibration Analysis”. ASME. J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power. 2014;136(11): 111503-111503-7. doi:10.1115/1.4027363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">European Patent EP2431595 (A1), “Method of estimating a combustion index and/or the indicated torque in a cylinder of a four stroke internal combustion engine with spontaneous mixture ignition”.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ponti, F., Ravaglioli, V., Serra, G., and Stola, F., "Instantaneous Engine Speed Measurement and Processing for MFB50 Evaluation," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):235-244, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2747.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polonowski, C., Mathur, V., Naber, J., and Blough, J., "Accelerometer Based Sensing of Combustion in a High Speed HPCR Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0972, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnone, L., Boni, M., Manelli, S., Chiavola, O. et al., "Block Vibration Measurements for Combustion Diagnosis in Multi-Cylinder Common Rail Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0646, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
