<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3/4</issue>
         <issue-id>i40172066</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44113792</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Correlations of perceived post-editing effort with measurements of actual effort</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Joss</given-names>
                  <surname>Moorkens</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Sharon</given-names>
                  <surname>O'Brien</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Igor A. L.</given-names>
                  <surname>da Silva</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Norma B.</given-names>
                  <surname>de Lima Fonseca</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Fabio</given-names>
                  <surname>Alves</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>267</fpage>
         <lpage>284</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Springer Science+Business Media 2015</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44113792"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Human rating of predicted post-editing effort is a common activity and has been used to train confidence estimation models. However, the correlation between human ratings and actual post-editing effort is under-measured. Moreover, the impact of presenting effort indicators in a post-editing user interface on actual post-editing effort has hardly been researched. In this study, ratings of perceived post-editing effort are tested for correlations with actual temporal, technical and cognitive post-editing effort. In addition, the impact on post-editing effort of the presentation of post-editing effort indicators in the user interface is also tested. The language pair involved in this study is English-Brazilian Portuguese. Our findings, based on a small sample, suggest that there is little agreement between raters for predicted post-editing effort and that the correlations between actual post-editing effort and predicted effort are only moderate, and thus an inefficient basis for MT confidence estimation. Moreover, the presentation of post-editing effort indicators in the user interface appears not to impact on actual post-editing effort.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1126388e299a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1126388e306" publication-type="other">
http://www.statmt.org/wmtl4/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1126388e313a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1126388e320" publication-type="other">
Hokamp and Liu 2015</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1126388e327a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1126388e334" publication-type="other">
esurv.org</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1126388e341a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1126388e348" publication-type="other">
Available from www.cs.umd.edu/~snover/tercom.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d1126388e364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e368" publication-type="other">
Alves F, Koglin A, Mesa-Lao B, Garcia MM, Fonseca NBL, Sá AM, Gonçalves JL, Szpak KS, Sekino
K, Aquino M (2015) Analysing the impact of interactive machine translation on post-editing effort.
In: Carl M, Bangalore S, Schaeffer M (eds) New directions in empirical translation process research.
Springer, New York, pp 77-95</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e384a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e388" publication-type="other">
Biçici E, Way A (2014) Referential translation machines for predicting translation quality. WMT 2014:
ACL 2014 Ninth Workshop On Statistical Machine Translation, Baltimore</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e398a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e402" publication-type="other">
Blain F, Senellart J, Schwenk H, Plitt M, Roturier J (20 1 1 ) Qualitative analysis of post-editing for high quality
machine translation. In: Machine Translation Summit XIII, Asia-Pacific Association for Machine
Translation (AAMT), Xiamen</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e415a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e419" publication-type="other">
Blatz J, Fitzgerald E, Foster G, Gandrabur S, Goutte C, Kulesza A, Sanchis A, Ueffing N (2004) Confidence
estimation for machine translation. Proceedings of the 20th international conference on computational
linguistics, 23-27 Aug 2004, Geneva, pp 315-321</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e433a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e437" publication-type="other">
Carl M, Dragsted B, Elming J, Hardt D, Jakobsen AL (2011) The process of post-editing: a pilot study.
In: Proceedings of the 8th international natural language processing and cognitive science workshop,
Frederiksberg, pp 131-142</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e454" publication-type="other">
Cooper A (2004) The inmates are running the asylum: why hi-tech products drive us crazy and how to
restore the sanity. Sams Publishing, Indianapolis</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e464a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e468" publication-type="other">
Da Silva IAL, Schmaltz M, Alves F, Pagano A, Wong D, Chao L, Leal ALV, Quaresma P, Garcia C (2015)
Translating and post-editing in the Chinese-Portuguese Language pair: insights from an exploratory
study of key logging and eye tracking. Translation Spaces 4(1): 145-169</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e481a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e485" publication-type="other">
De Almeida G, O'Brien S (2010) Analysing post-editing performance: Correlations with years of translation
experience. In: Proceedings of the 14th annual conference of the European Association for Machine
Translation, St. Raphaël</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e502" publication-type="other">
DePalma DA, Hegde V, Pielmeier H, Stewart RG (2013) The language services market. Common Sense
Advisory, Boston</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e516" publication-type="other">
Doherty S (2012) Investigating the effects of controlled language on the reading and comprehension of
machine translated texts: a mixed-methods approach. Dissertation, Dublin City University</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e531" publication-type="other">
Gaspari F, Toral A, Kumar NS, Groves D, Way A (2014) Perception vs. reality: measuring machine trans-
lation post-editing productivity. In: O'Brien S, Simard M, Specia L (eds) Proceedings of the 11th
conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas: workshop on post-editing
technology and practice (WPTP3), Vancouver, pp 60-72</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e551" publication-type="other">
Guerberof A (2009) Productivity and quality in the post-editing of outputs from translation memories and
machine translation. Localisation Focus 7(1): 11-21</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e561a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e565" publication-type="other">
Hokamp C, Liu C (2015) HandyCAT. In: Durgar El-Kahlout Í, Özkan M, Sánchez-Martínez F, Ramírez-
Sánchez G, Hollowood F, Way A (eds) Proceedings of European Association for Machine Translation
(EAMT) 2015, Antalya, p 216</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e582" publication-type="other">
Koponen M (2012) Comparing human perceptions of post-editing effort with post-editing operations. In:
Proceedings of the 7th workshop on statistical machine translation, Montreal, pp 181-190</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e592a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e596" publication-type="other">
Krings HP (2001) Repairing texts. Kent State University Press, Kent</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e603a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e607" publication-type="other">
Lacruz I, Shreve GM (2014) Pauses and cognitive effort in post-editing. In: O'Brien S, Balling LW, Carl M,
Simard M, Specia L (eds) Post-editing of machine translation: processes and applications. Cambridge
Scholars Publishing, Newcastle-Upon-Tyne, pp 246-272</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e625" publication-type="other">
Läubli S, Fishel M, Massey G, Ehrensberger-Dow M, Volk M (2013) Assessing post-editing efficiency in a
realistic translation environment. In: Simard M, Specia L (eds) O'Brien S. Proceedings of MT Summit
XIV workshop on post-editing technology and practice, Nice, pp 83-91</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e638a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e642" publication-type="other">
Moorkens J, O'Brien S (2013) User attitudes to the post-editing interface. In: Simard M, Specia L (eds)
O'Brien S. Proceedings of MT Summit XIV workshop on post-editing technology and practice, Nice,
pp 19-25</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e655a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e659" publication-type="other">
Moorkens J, O'Brien S (2015) Post-editing evaluations: Trade-offs between novice and professional par-
ticipants. In: Durgar El-Kahlout Í, Özkan M, Sánchez-Martínez F, Ramírez-Sánchez G, Hollowood F,
Way A (eds) Proceedings of European Association for Machine Translation (EAMT) 2015, Antalya,
pp 75-81</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e679" publication-type="other">
O'Brien S (2005) Methodologies for measuring the correlations between post-editing effort and machine
translatability. Machine Translation 19(1): 37-5 8</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e689a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e693" publication-type="other">
O'Brien S (2010) Introduction to Post-Editing: Who, What, How and Where to Next? In: Proceedings of
AMTA 2010, the 9th conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas (online),
Denver</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e706a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e710" publication-type="other">
O'Brien S (2011) Towards predicting post-editing productivity. Machine Translation 25:197-215</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e718a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e722" publication-type="other">
Plitt M, Masselot F (2010) A productivity test of statistical machine translation post-editing in a typical
localization context. Prague Bull Math Linguist 93:7-16</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e732a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e736" publication-type="other">
Quirk C (2004) Training a sentence-level machine translation confidence measure. In: Proceedings of the
4th conference on language resources and evaluation, Lisbon, pp 825-828</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e746a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e750" publication-type="other">
Rayner K (1998) Eye movements in reading and information processing: 20 years of research. Psychological
Bulletin 124(3): 372-422</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e760a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e764" publication-type="other">
Shah K, Specia L (2014) Quality estimation for translation selection. In: Tadic M, Koehn P, Roturier J,
Way A (eds) Proceedings of the 17th annual conference of the European Association for Machine
Translation (EAMT 2014), Dubrovnik, pp 109-116</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e777a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e781" publication-type="other">
Snover M, Dorr B, Schwartz R, Micciulla L, Makhoul J (2006) A study of translation edit rate with targeted
human annotation. In: Proceedings of the 7th conference of the Association for Machine Translation in
the Americas (AMTA2006), "Visions for the Future of Machine Translation', Cambridge, pp 223-231</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e794a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e798" publication-type="other">
Soricut R, Narsale S (2012) Combining quality prediction and system selection for improved automatic
translation output. In: Proceedings of the ACL 7th workshop on statistical machine translation (WMT-
2012), Montreal, pp 163-170</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e812a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e816" publication-type="other">
Specia L (2011) Exploiting objective annotations for measuring translation post-editing effort. In: Proceed-
ings of the 15th conference of EAMT, Leuven, pp 73-80</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e826a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e830" publication-type="other">
Specia L, Cancedda N, Dymetman M, Turchi M, Cristianini N (2009) Estimating the sentence-level quality
of machine translation systems. In: Proceedings of the 13th annual conference of the EAMT, Barcelona,
pp 28-35</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e847" publication-type="other">
Sperber D, Wilson D (1986) Relevance: communication and cognition. Blackwell, Oxford</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e854a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e858" publication-type="other">
Tatsumi M (2009) Correlation between automatic evaluation scores, post-editing speed and some other
factors. In: Proceedings of MT Summit XII, Ottawa, pp 332-339</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e868a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e872" publication-type="other">
Tatsumi M, Roturier J (2010) Source text characteristics and technical and temporal post-editing effort:
what is their relationship? In: Zhechev V (ed) Proceedings of the 2nd joint EM+/CNGL workshop
"Bringing MT to the User: Research on Integrating MT in the Translation Industry" (JEC ' 10). Denver,
pp 43-51</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e888a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e892" publication-type="other">
Teixeira CSC (2014) Perceived vs. measured performance in the post-editing of suggestions from machine
translation and translation memories. In: O'Brien S, Simard M, Specia L (eds) Proceedings of the
11th conference of the association for machine translation in the Americas: workshop on post-editing
technology and practice (WPTP3), Vancouver, pp 45-59</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e909a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e913" publication-type="other">
Temnikova I (2010) Cognitive evaluation approach for a controlled language post-editing experiment. In:
Proceedings of the 7th international conference on language resources and evaluation, LREC 2010,
Valletta, pp 3485-3490</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e930" publication-type="other">
Türian J, Shen L, Melamed D (2003) Evaluation of machine translation and its evaluation. In: Proceedings
of the MT Summit IX, New Orleans, pp 386-393</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e940a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e944" publication-type="other">
Vieira L, Specia L (201 1) A review of translation tools from a post-editing perspective. In: Proceedings of
the 3rd joint EM+/CNGL workshop bringing MT to the users: research meets translators" (JEC 'li),
Luxembourg, pp 33-42</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1126388e957a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1126388e961" publication-type="other">
Vieira LN (2014) Indices of cognitive effort in machine translation post-editing. Machine Translation
28(3): 187-216</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


