<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909588</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MORS Special Meeting:</article-title>
            <subtitle>Analyzing the Value of Infrastructure</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Trainor</surname>
                  <given-names>Tim</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Colonel Tim Trainor received his MBA from Duke University and his PhD in Industrial Engineering from North Carolina State University. He received his undergraduate degree from the United States Military Academy in 1983. He is currently the Head of the Systems Engineering Department at the United States Military Academy. He has served in various command and staff positions in the Engineer branch of the US Army during a 24-year Army career.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lehmkuhl</surname>
                  <given-names>Lee</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr Lee Lehmkuhl is a Principal Modeling and Simulation Engineer with The MITRE Corporation in Colorado Springs, providing analysis support for system acquisition and strategic planning at Air Force Space Command. He joined MITRE upon retirement from the Air Force after a 20 year career as a Scientific Analyst. Dr Lehmkuhl taught Operations Research at the Air Force Institute of Technology and the United States Air Force Academy. He currently serves on the MORS Board of Directors.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Dell</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr Robert F. Dell is an Associate Professor of Operations Research at the Naval Postgraduate School. Since 1990, he has taught and applied optimization to a variety of military problems and received continuous support for Army Base Realignment and Closure. He has received additional research support from every uniformed service for topics ranging from naval capital planning to Coast guard cutter scheduling. He has also applied optimization in the private sector in areas ranging from production scheduling to supply chain design. His research appears in many open literature publications. He recently received a Special Army Payne Award for excellence in operations research for his contributions to the 2005 Army BRAC Analysis.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Huo</surname>
                  <given-names>Chien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr Chien Huo is the Chief of Future Infrastructure Analysis in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army (Installations &amp; Environment). His previous experiences include the 2005 base realignment and closure (BRAC) analysis, development of several six-year resource projections for Army installations and resources decision support tools for the Headquarters Army Staff, policy analyst, project manager, and data administrator for the office of the Under Secretary of Defense (AT&amp;L). Dr Huo brings with him 33 years of experience in government, academia, and the private sector. He received his M.S. and Ph. D. in Applied Mathematics from Brown University, and his undergraduate engineering degree from the National Taiwan University</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wallshein</surname>
                  <given-names>Corinne</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Ms Corinne Wallshein is currently in an Air Force career broadening position, working in the Force and Infrastructure Cost Analysis Division in OSD/PA&amp;E. Previous experiences include 2005 BRAC analysis, studies of Air Force infrastructure, and studies on national strategic and tactical command, control, and communications. She is currently pursuing a doctorate in Information Technology at George Mason University, with software cost estimating as her research topic. An ardent supporter of MORS, she serves on the Board of Directors.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2007</year>
            <string-date>March 2007</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>40</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909586</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>35</lpage>
         <page-range>1, 31-35</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909588"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barker, Dan and Dr Daniel Nussbaum. DoD Infrastructure: Why It Is &amp; What Does It Cost? MORS Mini-Symposium Report, Williamsburg, Virginia, January 1998. Available at http://www.mors.org/reports.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
