<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277572</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Air-Entrainment in Wall-Jets Using SLIPI in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chartier</surname>
                  <given-names>Clement</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sjoholm</surname>
                  <given-names>Johan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kristensson</surname>
                  <given-names>Elias</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Oivind</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Richter</surname>
                  <given-names>Mattias</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Bengt</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Alden</surname>
                  <given-names>Marcus</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Lund University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1684</fpage>
         <lpage>1692</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277572"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Mixing in wall-jets was investigated in an optical heavy-duty diesel engine with several injector configurations and injection pressures. Laser induced fluorescence (LIF) was employed in non-reacting conditions in order to quantitatively measure local equivalence ratios in colliding wall-jets. A novel laser diagnostic technique, Structured Laser Illumination Planar Imaging (SLIPI), was successfully implemented in an optical engine and permits to differentiate LIF signal from multiply scattered light. It was used to quantitatively measure local equivalence ratio in colliding wall-jets under non-reacting conditions. Mixing phenomena in wall-jets were analyzed by comparing the equivalence ratio in the free part of the jet with that in the recirculation zone where two wall-jets collide. These results were then compared to ϕ predictions for free-jets. It was found that under the conditions tested, increased injection pressure did not increase mixing in the wall-jets. Comparisons with free-jet predictions further indicated that mixing in wall-jets is less effective than in free-jets for identical conditions and downstream distances. The confined nature of the wall-jet in the optical engine is suspected to be the reason for these observations. A rapid leaning-out of the jet after end of injection was observed for all cases, but this enhanced mixing was not transmitted to the wall-jet.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L. “Soot formation in diesel fuel jets near the lift-off region.” Proceedings of IMechE JER03505 vol.7: pp 103-129, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., and Idicheria, C., “Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. and Siebers, D., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi:10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., “Scaling Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays Based on Mixing-Limited Vaporization,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0528, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronsson, U., Chartier, C., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R. et al., “Analysis of the Correlation Between Engine-Out Particulates and Local Φ in the Lift-Off Region of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Using Raman Spectroscopy,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):645-660, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eismark, J., Balthasar, M., Karlsson, A., Benham, T. et al., “Role of Late Soot Oxidation for Low Emission Combustion in a Diffusioncontrolled, High-EGR, Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2813, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Mixing Process in High Pressure Diesel Jets by Normalized Laser Induced Exciplex Fluorescence Part II: Wall Impinging Versus Free Jet,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2097, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2097.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berrocal, E., Kristensson, E., Richter, M., Linne, M. and Aldén, M., “Application of structured illumination for multiple scattering suppression in planar laser imaging of dense sprays,” Opt. Express, 16, 17870-17881, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kristensson, E., “Structured Laser Illumination Planar Imaging, SLIPI, Applications for spray diagnostics”, doctoral thesis, Lund University 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöholm, J., Chartier, C., Kristenson, E., Berrocal, E., Gallo, Y., Richter, M., Andersson, Ö., Aldén, M., Johansson, B., “Quantitative in-cylinder fuel measurements in a heavy duty diesel engine using Structured Laser Illumination Planar Imaging (SLIPI)”, COMODIA 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fansler, T., French, D., and Drake, M., “Fuel Distributions in a Firing Direct-Injection Spark-Ignition Engine Using Laser-Induced Fluorescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 950110, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, C. and Sick, V., “Tracer-LIF diagnostics: quantitative measurement of fuel concentration, temperature and fuel/air ratio in practical combustion systems”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 31, (1), 75-121 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yip, B., Miller, M. F, Lozano, A., Hanson, R. K, “A combined OH/acetone planar laser-induced fluorescence imaging technique for visualizing combusting flows”, Experiments in Fluids, Vol. 17, 1994, pp 330-336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neil, M. A. A., Juskaitis, R. and Wilson, T., “Method of obtaining optical sectioning by using structured light in a conventional microscope” Opt. Lett., 22, 1905-1907 (1997).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kristensson, E., Berrocal, E., Richter, M. and Aldén, M., “Nanosecond structured laser illumination planar imaging for single-shot imaging of dense sprays,” Atomization Sprays, 20, 337-343, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and López, J., “Jet-Wall Interaction Effects on Diesel Combustion and Soot Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0921, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0921.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L., and Idicheria, C., “End-of- Injection Over-Mixing and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions in Low- Temperature-Combustion Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0907, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
