<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278246</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Challenges for In-Cylinder High-Speed Two-Dimensional Laser-Induced Incandescence Measurements of Soot</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sjöholm</surname>
                  <given-names>Johan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Physics, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wellander</surname>
                  <given-names>Rikard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Physics, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bladh</surname>
                  <given-names>Henrik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Physics, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Richter</surname>
                  <given-names>Mattias</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Physics, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bengtsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Per-Erik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Physics, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Alden</surname>
                  <given-names>Marcus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Physics, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aronsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Ulf</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Engines, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chartier</surname>
                  <given-names>Clement</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Engines, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Oivind</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Engines, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Bengt</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Combustion Engines, Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1607</fpage>
         <lpage>1622</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278246"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Laser-Induced Incandescence (LII) has traditionally been considered a straightforward and reliable optical diagnostic technique for in-cylinder soot measurements. As a result, it is nowadays even possible to buy turn-key LII measurement systems. During recent years, however, attention has been drawn to a number of unresolved challenges with LII. Many of these are relevant mostly for particle sizing using time-resolved LII, but also two dimensional soot volume fraction measurements are affected, especially in regions with high soot concentrations typically found in combustion engines. In this work the focus is on the specific challenges involved in performing high-repetition rate measurements with LII in diesel engines. All the mentioned issues might not be possible to overcome but they should nevertheless be known and their potential impact should be considered. The measurements, which, to the authors’ knowledge, are the first in-cylinder high-speed LII published to date, were made using a Multi-YAG laser system, capable of producing a burst of eight high-power laser pulses during one combustion event. A high-speed framing camera was used as detector in order to match the high repetition rate of the laser. In an initial feasibility study, high-speed LII measurements were made in a laminar ethylene/air flame to test the characteristic features of high-speed LII. Excessive influence of soot sublimation was observed in the LII signals induced by later pulses in the pulse sequence for typical pulse separations of interest in the engine (139 μs). This is a result of that each laser pulse partly sublimates soot particles in the measurement volume, resulting in a lower signal yield. Analysis on the data from the in-cylinder measurements does not show signs of the same behavior. This is believed to be due to high mixing and/or very fast soot formation/oxidation in the measurement volume. This implies that time-resolved LII is a suitable technique to qualitatively follow the evolution of the soot distribution inside a reacting diesel jet.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., “Advanced compression-ignition engines - understanding the in-cylinder processes”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 32 (2):2727-2742, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santoro, R. J. and Shaddix, C.R., “Laser-Induced Incandescence”, Applied Combustion Diagnostics 252-286,2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, C., Kock, B.F., Hofmann, M., Michelsen, H., Will, S., Bougie, B., Suntz, R. and Smallwood, G., “Laserinduced incandescence: recent trends and current questions”, Appl. Phys. B 83 (3):333-354, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bladh, H., Johnsson, J. and Bengtsson, P.-E., “On the dependence of the laser-induced incandescence (LII) signal on soot volume fraction for variations in particle size”, Appl. Phys. B 90 (1):109-125, 2008, 10.1007/s00340-007-2826-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Melton, L.A., “Soot Diagnostics Based on Laser-Heating”, Appl. Opt. 23 (13):2201-2208, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bladh, H., Johnsson, J. and Bengtsson, P.E., “Influence of spatial laser energy distribution on evaluated soot particle sizes using two-colour laser-induced incandescence in a flat premixed ethylene/air flame”, Appl. Phys. B 96 (4):645-656, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snelling, D.R., Smallwood, G.J., Liu, F., Gülder, Ö.L. and Bachalo, W.D., “A calibration-independent laser-induced incandescence technique for soot measurement by detecting absolute light intensity”, Appl. Opt. 44 (31):6773-6785, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Will, S., Schraml, S. and Leipertz, A., “2-Dimensional Soot-Particle Sizing by Time-Resolved Laser-Induced Incandescence”, Opt. Lett. 20 (22):2342-2344, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Omrane, A., Särner, G. and Aldén, M., “2D-temperature imaging of single droplets and sprays using thermographic phosphors”, Applied Physics B: Lasers and Optics 79 (4): 431-434, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “Soot Distribution in a D.I. Diesel Engine Using 2-D Imaging of Laser-induced Incandescence, Elastic Scattering, and Flame Luminosity,” SAE Technical Paper 920115, 1992, doi: 10.4271/920115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Espey, C., “Soot and Fuel Distributions in a D.I. Diesel Engine via 2-D Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 922307, 1992, doi: 10.4271/922307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H. and Ladommatos, N., “Optical diagnostics for soot and temperature measurement in diesel engines”, Prog. Energy Combust. 24 221-255, 1998</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bougie, B., Ganippa, L.C., Dam, N.J. and Ter Meulen, J.J., “On particulate characterization in a heavy-duty Diesel engine by time-resolved laser-induced incandescence”, Appl. Phys. B 83 (3):477-485, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kock, B.F., Tribalet, B., Schulz, C. and Roth, P., “Twocolor time-resolved LII applied to soot particle sizing in the cylinder of a Diesel engine”, Combust. Flame 147 (1-2): 79-92, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., zur Loye, A., and Siebers, D., “Soot Distribution in a D.I. Diesel Engine Using 2-D Laser-Induced Incandescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 910224, 1991, doi: 10.4271/910224.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Espey, C. and Dec, J., “Diesel Engine Combustion Studies in a Newly Designed Optical-Access Engine Using High-Speed Visualization and 2-D Laser Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 930971, 1993, doi: 10.4271/930971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Espey, C., “Ignition and Early Soot Formation in a DI Diesel Engine Using Multiple 2-D Imaging Diagnostics,” SAE Technical Paper 950456, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950456.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Tree, D., “Diffusion-Flame/ Wall Interactions in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1295, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-1295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Takasu, S., and Nakakita, K., “In-cylinder Quantitative Soot Concentration Measurement By Laser- Induced Incandescence,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0508, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Takasu, S., Nakakita, K., and Watanabe, S., “Quantitative Analysis of Soot Formation and Oxidation Process using Laser-Induced Incandescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1795, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Miura, S., Nakakita, K. and Watanabe, S., “Quantitative soot concentration measurement with the correction of attenuated signal intensity using laser-induced incandescence”, The Fourth international Symposium COMODIA 98 371-378, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bladh, H., Hildingsson, L., Gross, V., Hultqvist, A. and Bengtsson, P.-E., “Quantitative soot measurements in an HSDI Diesel engine”, Proceedings of the 13th International Symposium on Applications of Laser Techniques to Fluid Mechanics, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Francqueville, L., Bruneaux, G., and Thirouard, B., “Soot Volume Fraction Measurements in a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine by Combined Laser Induced Incandescence and Laser Extinction Method,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 163-182, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pastor, J., García, J., Pastor, J., and Buitrago, J., “Analysis Methodology of Diesel Combustion by Using Flame Luminosity, Two-Colour Method and Laser-Induced Incandescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-24-012, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-24-012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, X., Ma, X., Wu, F., Wang, J. et al., “Investigation of Soot Formation in Laminar Diesel Diffusion Flame by Two- Color Laser Induced Incandescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1064, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bougie, B., Ganippa, L.C., Van Vliet, A.P., Meerts, W.L., Dam, N.J. and Ter Meulen, J. J., “Soot particulate size characterization in a heavy-duty diesel engine for different engine loads by laser-induced incandescence”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 31 (1):685-691, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Michelsen, H.A., “Understanding and predicting the temporal response of laser-induced incandescence from carbonaceous particles”, J. Chem. Phys. 118 (15):7012-7045, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bladh, H. and Bengtsson, P.-E., “Characteristics of laserinduced incandescence from soot in studies of a timedependent heat-and mass-transfer model”, Appl. Phys. B 78 (2):241-248, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hofmann, M., Bessler, W.G., Schulz, C. and Jander, H., “Laser-induced incandescence for soot diagnostics at high pressures”, Appl. Opt. 42 (12):2052-2062, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B. and Pickett, L. A., “Diagnostic considerations for optical laser-extinction measurements of soot in high-pressure transient combustion environments”, Combust. Flame 141 (4):371-391, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zerbs, J., Geigle, K., Lammel, O., Hader, J., Stirn, R., Hadef, R. and Meier, W., “The influence of wavelength in extinction measurements and beam steering in laser-induced incandescence measurements in sooting flames”, Appl. Phys. B 96 (4):683-694, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “A Study of Soot Cloud Structure In High Pressure Single Hole Common Rail Diesel Injection Using Multi-Layered Laser-Induced Incandescence”, presented at COMODIA 2001, July 1-4, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Talley, D.G., “Optical patternation method”, US 6,734,965 B2, May 11, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goulay, F., Schrader, P.E., Nemes, L., Dansson, M.A. and Michelsen, H.A., “Photochemical interferences for laserinduced incandescence of flame-generated soot”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 32 (1):963-970, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dasch, C.J., “New Soot Diagnostics in Flames Based on Laser Vaporization of Soot”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 20 1231-1237, 1984,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vander Wal, R.L. and Choi, M.Y., “Pulsed laser heating of soot: Morphological changes”, Carbon 37 231-239, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vander Wal, R.L., Ticich, T.M. and Stephens, A.B., “Optical and Microscopy Investigations of Soot Structure Alterations by Laser-Induced Incandescence”, Appl. Phys. B 67 115-123, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoder, G.D., Diwakar, P.K. and Hahn, D.W., “Assessment of soot particle vaporization effects during laser-induced incandescence with time-resolved light scattering”, Appl. Opt. 44 (20):4211-4219, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hult, J., Richter, M., Nygren, J., Aldén, M., Hultqvist, A., Christensen, M. and Johansson, B., “Application of a high-repetition-rate laser diagnostic system for single-cycleresolved imaging in internal combustion engines”, Applied Optics 41 (24):5002-5014, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronsson, U., Chartier, C., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R. et al., “Analysis of the Correlation Between Engine-Out Particulates and Local Φ in the Lift-Off Region of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Using Raman Spectroscopy,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):645-660, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bowditch, F., “A New Tool for Combustion Research A Quartz Piston Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 610002, 1961, doi: 10.4271/610002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, J.H., Mallard, W.G. and Smyth, K.C., “The observation of laser-induced visible fluorescence in sooting diffusion flames”, Combustion and Flame 47 205-214, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
