<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278386</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reduction of Transient Particulate Matter Spikes with Decision Tree Based Control</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brahma</surname>
                  <given-names>Indranil</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Bucknell Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>May 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278342</issue-id>
         <fpage>608</fpage>
         <lpage>621</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278386"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Decision trees have been proposed as a basis for modifying table based injection to reduce transient particulate spikes during the turbocharger lag period. It has been shown that decision trees can detect particulate spikes in real time. In well calibrated electronically controlled diesel engines these spikes are narrow and are encompassed by a wider NOₓ spike. Decision trees have been shown to pinpoint the exact location of measured opacity spikes in real time thus enabling targeted PM reduction with near zero NOₓ penalty. A calibrated dimensional model has been used to demonstrate the possible reduction of particulate matter with targeted injection pressure pulses. Post injection strategy optimized for near stoichiometric combustion has been shown to provide additional benefits. Empirical models have been used to calculate emission tradeoffs over the entire FTP cycle. An empirical model based transient calibration has been used to demonstrate that such targeted transient modifiers are more beneficial at lower engine-out NOₓ levels.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oberdörster, G., Utell, M. J., 2002, Ultrafine Particles in the Urban Air: o the Respiratory Track and Beyond, Environmental Health erspectives, 110, A440-A441</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope, C.A., Dockery, D.W., 2006, Health Effects of Fine Particulate Air ollution: Lines That Connect, Journal of the Air &amp; Waste Management ssociation, 56, 709-742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Air Quality Management District (AQMD), (2006), “Ultrafine particles- he Science, Technology and Policy Issues”, Conference held in Los ngeles, United States. http://www.amqd.gov/TAO/ltrafineParticleConf.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S., Vaglieco, B., and Di Iorio, S., “Nanoparticles at Internal ombustion Engines Exhaust: Effect on Urban Area,” SAE Technical aper 2006-01-3006, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goto, Y., Lee, J., Kawai, T., and Odaka, M., “Trapping Performance of ine Particles from a Diesel Engine by Various DPFs with Different urface Structures,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0598, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0598.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Vezza, D., Vlachos, T., Fino, D. et al., “Particle Number and ize Distribution from a Small Displacement Automotive Diesel Engine uring DPF Regeneration,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):404-413, 2010, oi:10.4271/2010-01-1552.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Di Iorio, S., Beatrice, C., Guido, C., Del Giacomo, N. et al., “Analysis f Particle Mass and Size Emissions from a Catalyzed Diesel Particulate ilter during Regeneration by Means of Actual Injection Strategies in ight Duty Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2510-2518, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-24-0210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Filippo, A., “Particle Size and Number Emissions from Modern ight-Duty Diesel Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0632, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">COMMISSION REGULATION (EC) No 692/2008 of 18 July 2008 mplementing and amending Regulation (EC) No 715/2007 of the uropean Parliament and of the Council on type-approval of motor ehicles with respect to emissions from light passenger and commercial ehicles (Euro 5 and Euro 6) and on access to vehicle repair and aintenance information, Official Journal of the European Union, 28/7/2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagena, J., Filipi, Z., and Assanis, D., “Transient Diesel Emissions: nalysis of Engine Operation During a Tip-In,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1151, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I. and Chi, J., “Development of Model Based Transient alibration Process: Part 1: Data Requirements, Processing and nalysis”, accepted for publication by the International Journal of ngine research, accepted on Aug 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I. and Chi, J., “Development of Model Based Transient alibration Process: Part 2: Modeling and Optimization”, accepted for ublication by the International Journal of Engine research, accepted on ug 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., Sharp, M., and Frazier, T., “Empirical Modeling of ransient Emissions and Transient Response for Transient ptimization”, SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1433-1443, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., “Development of Dynamic Constraint Models for a Model ased Transient Calibration Process,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):828-836, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0691.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, C., Allain, M., and Zhang, H., “Using Model-Based Rapid ransient Calibration to Reduce Fuel Consumption and Emissions in iesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1365, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1365.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, C. and Mott, G., “Dynamic Model-Based Calibration ptimization: An Introduction and Application to Diesel Engines,” SAE echnical Paper 2005-01-0026, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giakoumis, E.G., and Alafouzos, A.I., “Study of diesel engine erformance and emissions during a transient cycle applying an engine apping-based methodology”, Applied Energy 87(2010) 1358-1365, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Castagna, E., Cottrell, J., Fino, D., and Saracco, G., “Combined steady tate and transient optimization for dynamic smoke reduction on Heavy uty engine (TIER3 Applications),” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0055, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Filipi, Z., Wang, Y., and Assanis, D., “Effect of Variable Geometry urbine (VGT) on Diesel Engine and Vehicle System Transient esponse,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1247, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-1247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Filipi, Z., Hagena, J., and Fathy, H., “Investigating the Impact of In- ehicle Transients on Diesel Soot Emissions”, Thermal Science, Vol. 12 (2008), No.1, pp, 53-72, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagena, J.R., Assanis, D.N., and Filipi, Z.S., “Cycle-resolved easurements of in-cylinder constituents during diesel engine transients nd insight into their impact on emissions”, Proceedings of the nstitution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile ngineering 2011, pp 225: 1103, DOI: 10.1177/0954407011414997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C.D., Dimaratos, A.M., Giakoumis, E.G., and Rakopoulos, .C., “Evaluation of the effect of engine, load and turbocharger arameters on transient emissions of diesel engine”, Energy Conversion nd Management 50 (2009) pp 2381-2393</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C.D., and Giakoumis, E.G., “Sensitivity analysis of ransient diesel engine simulation”, Proceedings of the Institution of echanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 2006 220: 89, DOI: 10.1243/095440705X69641.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C.D., Dimaratos, A.M., and Giakoumis, E.G., “Investigation of turbocharged diesel engine operation, exhaust missions, and combustion noise radiation during starting under cold, arm, and hot conditions”, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical ngineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 2011 225: 1118, OI: 10.1177/0954407011400155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nuszkowski, J., Thompson, G., and Ursic, M., “The Influence of ccelerator Pedal Position Control during Transient Laboratory Testing n Heavy Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):398-413, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0619.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nuszkowski, J. and Thompson, G., “Application and Repeatability of ransient Heat Release Analysis for Heavy Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE echnical Paper 2009-01-1125, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1125.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galindo, J., Bermúdez, V., Serrano, J., and López, J., “Cycle to Cycle iesel Combustion Characterisation During Engine Transient peration,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3262, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-3262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galindo, J., Lujan, J.M., Serrano, J.R., Dolz, V., and Guilain, S., (2004) “Design of an exhaust manifold to improve transient performance of an igh speed turbocharged diesel engine”, Experimental Thermal and luid Science, Vol. 28, No. 8, pp. 863-875</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galindo, J., Serrano, J.R., Vera, F., and Cervello, C., (2006) “Relevance f valve overlap for meeting Euro 5 soot emissions requirements during oad transient process in heavy duty diesel engines”, Int. J. Vehicle esign, Vol. 41, Nos. 1/2/3/4 2006, pp343-367</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reifarth, S. and Angstrom, H., “Transient EGR in a High-Speed DI iesel Engine for a set of different EGR-routings,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):1071-1078, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Darlington, A., Glover, K., and Collings, N., “A Simple Diesel Engine ir-Path Model to Predict Cylinder Charge During Transients: trategies for Reducing Transient Emission Spikes”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bai, L. and Yang, M., “Coordinated Control of EGR and VNT in urbocharged Diesel Engine Based on Intake Air Mass Observer,” SAE echnical Paper 2002-01-1292, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ammann, M., Fekete, N., Guzzella, L., and Glattfelder, A., "Model- ased Control of the VGT and EGR in a Turbocharged Common-Rail iesel Engine: Theory and Passenger Car Implementation," SAE echnical Paper 2003-01-0357, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolmanovsky, I., Morall, P., van Nieuwstadt, M., &amp; Stefanopoulou, A. 1997. Issues in modelling and control of intake flow in variable eometry turbocharged engines. Proceedings of the 18th IFIP TC7 onference on Systems Modelling and Optimization, pp. 436-445.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stefanolpoulou, A. 1998 (June). Control of Variable Geometry urbocharged Diesel Engines for Reduced Emissions. In: Proceedings f the IEEE American Control Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Nieuwstadt, M., Kolmanovsky, I., and Moraal, P., “Coordinated GR-VGT Control for Diesel Engines: an Experimental Comparison,” AE Technical Paper 2000-01-0266, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yilmaz, H., &amp; Stefanopoulou, A. 2003 (June). Control of Charge ilution in Turbocharged Diesel Engines via Exhaust Valve Timing. ages pp. 761-766 of: Proceedings of the IEEE American Control onference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Z., Thurow, E., Lincoln, J., Chen, D. et al., “Transient Analysis of ngine Nano-Particles Using a Fast-Scanning Differential Mobility article Analyzer,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0971, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Z., Thurow, E., Caldow, R., and Johnson, T., “Transient erformance of Diesel Particulate Filters as Measured by an Engine xhaust Particle Size Spectrometer,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0185, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, G.Z., Ford, D.C., Vasys, V.N., Chen, D., and Johnson, T.R., “Influence of Engine Operating Conditions on Diesel Particulate Matter missions in Relation to Transient and Steady-State Conditions”, nviron. Sci. Technol. 2007, 41, 4593-4599</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kass, M., Domingo, N., Storey, J., and Lewis, S., “Influence of High uel Rail Pressure and Urea Selective Catalytic Reduction on PM ormation in an Off-Highway Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. uels Lubr. 1(1):1560-1570, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2497.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pagán, J., “Study of Particle Size Distributions Emitted by a Diesel ngine,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1141, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-1141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertola, A., Schubiger, R., Kasper, A., Matter, U. et al., “Characterization of Diesel Particulate Emissions in Heavy-Duty DIDiesel ngines with Common Rail Fuel Injection Influence of Injection arameters and Fuel Composition,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3573, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3573.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J., Bermudez, V., Garcia, A., Linares, W. et al., “An nvestigation of Particle Size Distributions with Post Injection in DI iesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1379, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, J., Zhang, F., Tian, G., Xu, H. et al., “The Particle Emission haracteristics of a Light Duty Diesel Engine by Using Different Pilot njections,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1959, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scafati, F., Cesario, N., Lavorgna, M., Merola, S. et al., “Soft omputing Model for Prediction of EGR Effects on Particle Sizing at R Diesel Engine Exhaust,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0104, 2007, oi:10.4271/2007-24-0104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhu, J. and Lee, K., “Effects of Exhaust Gas Recirculation on articulate Morphology for a Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE echnical Paper 2005-01-0195, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0195.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, D., Lou, D., Hu, Z., and Tan, P., “Experimental Investigation on article Number and Size Distribution of a Common Rail Diesel Engine ueling with Alternative Blended Diesel Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0620, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0620.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farron, C., Matthias, N., Foster, D., Andrie, M. et al., “Particulate haracteristics for Varying Engine Operation in a Gasoline Spark gnited, Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1220, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., “An investigation Into the Causes of Transient Particulate atter Spikes in Production Diesel Engines”, Proceedings of the ASME 2011 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference CEF2011, October 2-5, 2011, Morgantown, West Virginia, USA</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Breiman, L., Friedman, J., Olshen, R., and Stone, C.. Classification and egression Trees. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press, 1984</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Kadota, T., “Models for Combustion and Formation of itric Oxide and Soot in Direct Injection Diesel Engines,” SAE echnical Paper 760129, 1976, doi: 10.4271/760129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I. “Analysis of air flow and EGR flow their effect on articulate formation during the turbocharger lag period”, manuscript in reparation</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
