<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437446</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Proposed State Second Pension</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>PHIL</given-names>
                  <surname>AGULNIK</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1999</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">20</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437441</issue-id>
         <fpage>409</fpage>
         <lpage>421</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1999</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437446"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The UK government has recently proposed radical changes in second-tier pension provision, with the existing State Earnings-Related Pension Scheme (SERPS) being replaced by a new State Second Pension (SSP). This paper sets out how the proposed scheme differs from its predecessor and describes the distributional effects of this reform. It shows that the SSP greatly increases the pension entitlements of low earners while maintaining existing benefit levels for higher earners. However, the higher contributions needed to pay for the new scheme mean that, after taking financing into account, people earning more than around £12,000 a year will lose out. Because of the upper limit to National Insurance contributions for employees, these losses will be greatest for people earning at the contribution ceiling.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d43e169a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e176" publication-type="other">
These earnings limits similarly apply to the contribution side of National Insurance. In keeping with the spirit
of social insurance, SERPS benefits directly reflect contributions to the scheme (via NICs) and, therefore, the
same upper and lower limits are used to calculate both benefits and contributions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e189a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e196" publication-type="other">
Note, however, that the Green Paper assumes that the NIC limits will remain tied to prices, and hence the
illustrations of the effects of the SSP and SERPS provided here are not directly comparable to the government1 s
estimates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e209a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e216" publication-type="other">
The government now refers to income support for pensioners as a 'minimum income guarantee', though no
changes to the structure of the benefit, or indeed its name, have yet been proposed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e226a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e233" publication-type="other">
The equivalence between SERPS and the second-tier pension entitlements earned by people in private pension
schemes relies on the Government Actuary accurately assessing likely investment returns, charges and annuity
rates. If assumptions about these turn out to be too optimistic, then people in private schemes will, in
retrospect, have been better off remaining in SERPS. Conversely, if investment and annuity rates exceed
assumed levels, people who chose to opt out will end up with higher pension benefits than those who stayed in
SERPS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e257a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e264" publication-type="other">
A little arithmetic shows that someone on £9,000 a year for the whole of a (49-year) working life would get a
SERPS pension of £22 a week (in terms of today's earnings), assuming that the earnings limits are increased in
line with earnings in the future. The SSP will provide a pension for all its members (including those earning
less than £9,000 and non-earners) of twice this level, i.e. £44 a week for someone who remains in the scheme
throughout their working life. Uncoincidentally, £44 a week is fractionally more than 10 per cent of MAE, the
gap between the basic pension and income support in 2050.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e287a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e294" publication-type="other">
Note that, for this incentive to hold for everyone, the level of rebates will need to vary with the age of the
recipient: as older people are closer to retirement, and hence benefit from fewer years of investment growth
than younger workers, they require higher rebates to be persuaded to opt out (see Government Actuary
(1995a)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e310a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e317" publication-type="other">
Presumably, the point of this structure is to ensure that no one sees their pension benefits reduced relative to
their position under SERPS (ignoring the better benefits that some women would have been entitled to under
home responsibilities protection — see written parliamentary answer 1,3,99). Note, though, that the point at
which people would start losing from the reduction in rebates on the tranche of earnings beyond £9,000 a year
is in fact £20,000, not £18,500. Everyone will therefore enjoy higher benefits as a result of the Green Paper's
proposals, albeit only very marginally so for people earning more than £18,500. This discrepancy within the
scheme is recognised by the DSS and is likely to be corrected in the government's final proposals. Therefore, to
simplify analysis, it is effectively assumed here that the benefits received by people on earnings above £18,500
are the same as they would get under SERPS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e349a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e356" publication-type="other">
it should, however, be borne in mind that the figure refers to the first- and second-tier pension entitlements
that individuals will accumulate in their own right and, similarly, the level of income support for a single
pensioner (aged 65-74) is shown. As the level of income support for couples is significantly less than twice
that for single people, the combined first- and second-tier pension entitlements of couples should lift them
substantially above the minimum income standard even beyond 2050. Note also that, under the government's
proposed 'shadow' lower NIC limit (see the 1999 Budget), an element of 'dynamisation' will be built into the
scheme, as the £9,000 figure will be increased in line with earnings while (presumably) the entry-point for the
SSP will be tied to prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e385a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e392" publication-type="other">
The SSP is therefore rather different from the minimum pension guarantee systems outlined by Atkinson
(1995), Hills (unpublished) and Falkingham and Johnson (1995), which, in effect, all act as a lifetime means
test.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e405a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e412" publication-type="other">
In the normal course of events, NIC rates are set so that they yield sufficient revenue to meet expected
expenditure from the National Insurance Fund. Administratively, this operates through the Government
Actuary estimating (on a five-year basis) the NIC rate needed to keep the Fund in balance (see, for instance.
Government Actuary (1995b)). A zero Treasury grant is assumed and, at least in recent years, payments to the
Fund from this source have been negligible.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e432a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e439" publication-type="other">
To simplify the analysis, the following assumes that employee NICs bear the full adjustment needed to keep
the NI Fund in balance (i.e. employer and self-employed NICs are ignored). It should also be borne in mind that
the projected fall of 4.25 percentage points is based on the assumption that the contribution limits will increase
in line with prices, not earnings. As it was assumed earlier that these limits will be linked to earnings in the
future, the analysis here should really be based on the NIC rate that would apply under earnings indexation of
the contribution base. However, for ease of exposition, the following looks only at the change in NICs caused
by the SSP relative to the 4.25 percentage point reduction expected under a price-linked contribution base.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e465a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e472" publication-type="other">
12Under the SSP, there will be a clear incentive to opt in below £9,000 and to opt out above this level of
earnings (see Section III). The number of people contracted out is therefore likely to increase, reflecting the fact
that there are more moderate and high earners (on over £9,000 a year) currently in SERPS than there are low
earners who have opted out.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e488a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e495" publication-type="other">
Assuming that employer and self-employed contribution rates do not change. Note that the £4.1 billion
estimate is in real price terms and hence, if one allows for the increase in the tax base for NICs resulting from
earnings growth, the necessary increase in the NIC rate is half that which would be required today.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e508a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e515" publication-type="other">
This figure is relative to the level of expenditure expected under a policy of increasing the minimum income
standard with earnings but retaining SERPS in its existing form (i.e. as in Figure 1). Note again that this
estimate is in real price terms, and hence in relation to today's tax base is half as large as indicated. Also note
that there are good reasons for thinking that income tax rates may be higher in the future than they are today, as
the ageing of the population is likely to have a very significant impact on NHS spending (Cardarelli, Sefton and
Kotlikoff, 1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d43e547a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e551" publication-type="other">
Agulnik, P. and Le Grand, J. (1998), 'Partnership versus compulsion', New Economy, vol. 5, pp.
147-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e561a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e565" publication-type="other">
ASD (1999), The Abstract of Statistics for Social Security Benefits and Contributions and Indices
of Prices and Earnings, Newcastle: Analytical Services Division.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e579" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. B. (1995), 'State pensions for today and tomorrow', in A. B. Atkinson, Incomes and
the Welfare State, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e589a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e593" publication-type="other">
Cardarelli, R., Sefton, J. and Kotlikoff, L. (1998), Generational Accounting in the UK, London:
National Institute of Economic and Social Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e604a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e608" publication-type="other">
Creedy, J., Disney, R. and Whitehouse, E. (1993), 'The earnings-related state pension, indexation
and lifetime redistribution in the UK', Review of Income and Wealth, vol. 39, pp. 257-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e618a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e622" publication-type="other">
Curry, C. (1996), PENSIM: A Dynamic Simulation Model of Pensioners' Incomes, London:
Department of Social Security / Government Economic Service.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e632a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e636" publication-type="other">
DSS (1998), A New Contract for Welfare: Partnership in Pensions, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e643a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e647" publication-type="other">
Falkingham, J. and Johnson, P. (1995), 'Funding pensions over the life cycle', in J. Falkingham
and J. Hills (eds), The Dynamic of Welfare: The Welfare State and the Life Cycle, Hemel
Hempstead: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e660a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e664" publication-type="other">
Gardiner, K. and Hills, J. (1999), 'Policy implications for new data on income mobility', Economic
Journal, vol. 109, pp. F91-111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e674a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e678" publication-type="other">
Government Actuary (1995a), Memorandum on the Reduction in Class 1 Rates of Contribution for
Those Contracted-Out, London: Government Actuary's Department.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e689a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e693" publication-type="other">
— (1995b), National Insurance Fund Long Term Financial Estimates: Report by the Government
Actuary, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e703a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e707" publication-type="other">
Gregg, P. (1997), Jobs, Wages and Poverty, London: Centre for Economic Performance.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e714a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e718" publication-type="other">
Hills, J. (unpublished), submission to the Pensions Review.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e725a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e729" publication-type="other">
Johnson, P. and Stears, G. (1996), 'Should the basic state pension be a contributory benefit?',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 17, no. 1, pp. 105-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e739a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e743" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A. and Ward, D. (1999), PENSIM: Developing Dynamic Simulation, London: Department
of Social Security / Government Economic Service.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e753a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e757" publication-type="other">
Rake, K., Falkingham, J. and Evans, M. (1999), Tightropes and Tripwires: New Labour's
Proposals and Means-Testing in Old Age, London: Centre for Analysis of Social Exclusion.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
