<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816592</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>School Funding (Education)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Is There A School Finance Channel? Effects of Ambient Air Pollution on K-12 Education in USA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Datta</surname>
                  <given-names>Biplab</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>91</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816592"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>How pollution affects education is typically studied through the health aspects of pollution exposure, and its subsequent effects on academic performance. Other than the health channel, this paper proposes a financing channel of pollution’s impact on education outcome. Financing of K-12 public education in USA is fairly decentralized, where local property tax is a major source of school revenue. Literature has shown that preference for air quality is capitalized in housing prices. School districts with better air quality are, therefore, endowed with higher tax base, and can generate more resources for K-12 education. Hence, public school funding across jurisdictions could be affected by pollution as well. This financing aspect of pollution and education nexus is generally not emphasized in literature. I analyze property tax revenue per pupil across school districts, and examine how that varies with pollution level. Panel fixed effect analysis for around 1000 metropolitan school districts from 1996 to 2008 academic years suggests that pollution has negative impact on per pupil property tax revenue.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Anderson, Nathan B, et al. 2006. Property Tax Limitations: An Interpretative Re- view. National Tax Journal, 59(3), 685–94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Anderson, Robert J, &amp; Crocker, Thomas D. 1971. Air Pollution and Residential Property Values. Urban Studies, 8(3), 171–180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Baker, Bruce D. 2012. Revisiting the Age-Old Question: Does Money Matter in Education?. Albert Shanker Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Banzhaf, H Spencer, &amp; Walsh, Randall P. 2008. Do People Vote with Their Feet? An Empirical Test of Tiebout. The American Economic Review, 98(3), 843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bayer, Patrick, Ferreira, Fernando, &amp; McMillan, Robert. 2007. A Unified Framework for Measuring Preferences for Schools and Neighborhoods. Journal of Political Economy, 115(4), 588–638.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bayer, Patrick, Keohane, Nathaniel, &amp; Timmins, Christopher. 2009. Migration and hedonic valuation: The case of air quality. Journal of Environmental Economics and Management, 58(1), 1–14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Ceballo, Rosario, McLoyd, Vonnie C, &amp; Toyokawa, Teru. 2004. The influence of neighborhood quality on adolescents educational values and school effort. Journal of Adolescent Research, 19(6), 716–739.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Cellini, Stephanie Riegg, Ferreira, Fernando, &amp; Rothstein, Jesse. 2010. The value of school facility investments: Evidence from a dynamic regression discontinuity design. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 125(1).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Champaloux, Steven W, &amp; Young, Deborah R. 2015. Childhood chronic health con- ditions and educational attainment: a social ecological approach. Journal of Ado- lescent Health, 56(1), 98–105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Chay, Kenneth Y, &amp; Greenstone, Michael. 2003. The Impact of Air Pollution on Infant Mortality: Evidence from Geographic Variation in Pollution Shocks Induced by a Recession. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 118(3), 1121–1167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Chay, Kenneth Y, &amp; Greenstone, Michael. 2005. Does air quality matter? Evidence from the housing market. Journal of political economy, 113(2), 376–424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Chen, Lei, Jennison, Brian L, Yang, Wei, &amp; Omaye, Stanley T. 2000. Elementary school absenteeism and air pollution. Inhalation Toxicology, 12(11), 997–1016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Clotfelter, Charles, Ladd, Helen F, Vigdor, Jacob, &amp; Wheeler, Justin. 2006. High- poverty schools and the distribution of teachers and principals. North Carolina Law Review, 85, 1345.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Clotfelter, Charles T, Ladd, Helen F, &amp; Vigdor, Jacob L. 2011. Teacher mobility, school segregation, and pay-based policies to level the playing field. Education, 6(3), 399–438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Crosnoe, Robert. 2006. Health and the education of children from racial/ethnic mi- nority and immigrant families. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, 47(1), 77–93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Crump, Casey, Rivera, Diana, London, Rebecca, Landau, Melinda, Erlendson, Bill, &amp;Rodriguez, Eunice. 2013. Chronic health conditions and school performance among children and youth. Annals of epidemiology, 23(4), 179–184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Currie, Janet, &amp; Almond, Douglas. 2011. Human capital development before age five.Handbook of labor economics, 4, 1315–1486.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Currie, Janet, Neidell, Matthew, &amp; Schmieder, Johannes F. 2009a. Air pollution and infant health: Lessons from New Jersey. Journal of health economics, 28(3), 688–703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Currie, Janet, Hanushek, Eric A, Kahn, E Megan, Neidell, Matthew, &amp; Rivkin, Steven G. 2009b. Does pollution increase school absences? The Review of Eco- nomics and Statistics, 91(4), 682–694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Currie, Janet, Davis, Lucas, Greenstone, Michael, &amp; Walker, Reed. 2015. Environ- mental health risks and housing values: evidence from 1,600 toxic plant openings and closings. The American Economic Review, 105(2), 678–709.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Dewey, James, Husted, Thomas A, &amp; Kenny, Lawrence W. 2000. The ineffectiveness of school inputs: a product of misspecification? Economics of Education Review, 19(1), 27–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Eide, Eric, &amp; Showalter, Mark H. 1998. The effect of school quality on student performance: A quantile regression approach. Economics letters, 58(3), 345–350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Gilliland, Frank D, Berhane, Kiros, Rappaport, Edward B, Thomas, Duncan C, Avol, Edward, Gauderman, W James, London, Stephanie J, Margolis, Helene G, Mc-Connell, Rob, Islam, K Talat, et al. 2001. The effects of ambient air pollution on school absenteeism due to respiratory illnesses. Epidemiology, 12(1), 43–54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Haas, Steven A, &amp; Fosse, Nathan Edward. 2008. Health and the educational attain- ment of adolescents: Evidence from the NLSY97. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, 49(2), 178–192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Ham, J. C., Zweig, J. S., &amp; Avol, E. 2014. Pollution, Test Scores and the Distribution of Academic Achievement: Evidence from California Schools 2002-2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Hanushek, Eric A. 1979. Conceptual and empirical issues in the estimation of educa- tional production functions. The Journal of Human Resources, 14(3), 351–388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Hanushek, Eric A. 1986. The economics of schooling: Production and efficiency in public schools. Journal of economic literature, 24(3), 1141–1177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Hanushek, Eric A. 1997. Assessing the effects of school resources on student perfor- mance: An update. Educational evaluation and policy analysis, 19(2), 141–164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Hanushek, Eric A, Kain, John F, &amp; Rivkin, Steven G. 2004. Why public schools lose teachers. Journal of human resources, 39(2), 326–354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Harrison, David, &amp; Rubinfeld, Daniel L. 1978. Hedonic housing prices and the demand for clean air. Journal of environmental economics and management, 5(1), 81–102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Haverinen-Shaughnessy, Ulla, Moschandreas, DJ, &amp; Shaughnessy, RJ. 2011. Asso- ciation between substandard classroom ventilation rates and students academic achievement. Indoor air, 21(2), 121–131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Hedges, Larry V, Laine, Richard D, &amp; Greenwald, Rob. 1994. An exchange: Part I: Does money matter? A meta-analysis of studies of the effects of differential school inputs on student outcomes. Educational researcher, 23(3), 5–14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Isen, Adam, Rossin-Slater, Maya, &amp; Walker, W Reed. 2015. Every Breath You TakeEvery Dollar Youll Make: The Long-Term Consequences of the Clean Air Act of 1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Kenyon, Daphne A. 2007. The Property Tax - School Funding Dilemma. Lincoln Institute of Land Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Koedel, Cory. 2008. Teacher quality and dropout outcomes in a large, urban school district. Journal of urban economics, 64(3), 560–572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Ladd, Helen, &amp; Loeb, Susanna. 2013. The Challenges of Measuring School Quality: Implications for Educational Equity. Pages 22–55 of: Allen, D, &amp; Reich, R (eds), Education, Justice, and Democracy. University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Lankford, Hamilton, Loeb, Susanna, &amp; Wyckoff, James. 2002. Teacher sorting and the plight of urban schools: A descriptive analysis. Educational evaluation and policy analysis, 24(1), 37–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Lavy, Victor, Ebenstein, Avraham, &amp; Roth, Sefi. 2014. The Impact of Short Term Exposure to Ambient Air Pollution on Cognitive Performance and Human Capital Formation. Tech. rept. National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Ludwig, Jens, &amp; Bassi, Laurie J. 1999. The puzzling case of school resources and student achievement. Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, 21(4), 385–403.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Lutz, Byron F. 2008. The Connection Between House Price Appreciation and Prop- erty Tax Revenues*. National Tax Journal, 61(3), 555.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Miller, Sebasti´an J, &amp; Vela, Mauricio A. 2013. The Effects of Air Pollution on Ed- ucational Outcomes: Evidence from Chile. IDB Working Paper (Department of Research and Chief Economist); IDB-WP-468.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Mohai, Paul, Kweon, Byoung-Suk, Lee, Sangyun, &amp; Ard, Kerry. 2011. Air pollution around schools is linked to poorer student health and academic performance. Health Affairs, 30(5), 852–862.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Murray, Sheila E, Evans, William N, Schwab, Robert M, et al. 1998. Education-Finance Reform and the Distribution of Education Resources. American Economic Review, 88(4), 789–812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Papke, Leslie E. 2005. The effects of spending on test pass rates: evidence from Michigan. Journal of Public Economics, 89(5), 821–839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Pastor, Manuel, Sadd, James L, &amp; Morello-Frosch, Rachel. 2004. Reading, writing, and toxics: children’s health, academic performance, and environmental justice in Los Angeles. Environment and Planning C, 22(2), 271–290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Ransom, M. R., &amp; Pope, I. C. 2013. Air Pollution and School Absenteeism: Results from a Natural Experiment. Tech. rept. IZA Workshop of Labor Market Effects of Environmental Policies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Ransom, Michael R, &amp; Pope, C Arden. 1992. Elementary school absences and PM 10 pollution in Utah Valley. Environmental research, 58(1), 204–219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Ridker, Ronald G, &amp; Henning, John A. 1967. The determinants of residential prop- erty values with special reference to air pollution. The Review of Economics and Statistics, 246–257.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Rivkin, Steven G, Hanushek, Eric A, &amp; Kain, John F. 2005. Teachers, schools, and academic achievement. Econometrica, 417–458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Rockoff, Jonah E. 2004. The impact of individual teachers on student achievement: Evidence from panel data. American Economic Review, 247–252.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Ross, Justin M, &amp; Nguyen-Hoang, Phuong. 2013. School District Income Taxes: New Revenue or a Property Tax Substitute? Public Budgeting &amp; Finance, 33(2), 19–40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Sander, William. 1993. Expenditures and student achievement in Illinois: New evi- dence. Journal of Public Economics, 52(3), 403–416.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Sander, William. 1999. Endogenous expenditures and student achievement. Eco- nomics letters, 64(2), 223–231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Sanders, Nicholas J. 2012. What doesnt kill you makes you weaker prenatal pollution exposure and educational outcomes. Journal of Human Resources, 47(3), 826–850.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Schwartz, J. 2004. Air pollution and children’s health. Pediatrics, 113(Supplement 3), 1037–1043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Sieg, Holger, Smith, V Kerry, Banzhaf, H Spencer, &amp;Walsh, Randy. 2004. Estimating the general equilibrium benefits of large policy changes: the Clean Air Act revisited.International Economic Review, 45(4), 1047–1077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Smith, V, &amp; Huang, Ju-Chin. 1995. Can Markets Value Air Quality? A Meta-analysis of Hedonic Property Value Models. Journal of Political Economy, 103(1), 209–27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Snyder, Thomas D, Brey, Cristobal de, &amp; Dillow, Sally A. 2016. Digest of education statistics 2014. National Center for Education Statistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Stafford, Tess M. 2015. Indoor air quality and academic performance. Journal of Environmental Economics and Management, 70, 34–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Sutton, Alice, &amp; Soderstrom, Irina. 1999. Predicting elementary and secondary school achievement with school-related and demographic factors. The Journal of Educa- tional Research, 92(6), 330–338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Taylor, Corrine. 1998. Does money matter? An empirical study introducing resource costs and student needs to educational production function analysis. W. Fowler (ed.), 75–97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Taylor, Lori L, &amp; Glander, Mark C. 2006. Documentation for the NCES Comparable Wage Index Files. EFSC 2006-865. National Center for Education Statistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Thompson, Franklin T. 2002. Student achievement, selected environmental charac- teristics, and neighborhood type. The Urban Review, 34(3), 277–292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Weimer, David L, &amp; Wolkoff, Michael J. 2001. School performance and housing val- ues: Using non-contiguous district and incorporation boundaries to identify school effects. National Tax Journal, 231–253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Wenglinsky, Harold. 1997. How Money Matters: The Effect of School District Spend- ing on Academic Achievement. Sociology of Education, 70(3), 221–37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Wilson, Kathryn. 2000. Using the PSID to study the effects of school spending. Public Finance Review, 28(5), 428–451.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Policy Offsetting Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Shift in State K-12 Financing Policy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>No Shift in State K-12 Financing Policy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Trend in Average School District Revenue per Pupil</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Trend in Average Pollution Level</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Compound Growth Rate of Pollution - 1992 to 2004 and Initial Pollution Level</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Current Expenditure per Pupil -Linear Model</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - Linear Model</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Current Expenditure per Pupil Specification - Wald F-statistic</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil Specification - Wald F-statistic</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Current Expenditure per Pupil Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Current Expenditure per Pupil</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Current Expenditure per Pupil With Control for Property Tax Revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Current Expenditure per Pupil After Controlling for Property Tax Revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Current Expenditure per Pupil With Control for State Revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Current Expenditure per Pupil After Controlling for State Revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 13:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Property Tax Revenue per Pupil</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 14:</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil Regression With State-Year Fixed Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 15:</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - State Year Fixed Effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 16:</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - State Specific Time Trend</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 17:</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - State Specific Time Trend</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 18:</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - Dynamic Panel Specification</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 19:</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - Dynamic Panel</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 20:</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil Regression Results - Weighted by Pupils</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 21:</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - Weighted by Pupils</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 22:</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil Regression Results - Weighted by Property Tax Share</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 23:</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - Weighted by Property Tax Share</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 24:</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil Regression - Excluded Sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 25:</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - Excluded Sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 26:</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>Spurious Regression Check - State Revenue</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 27:</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - All Pollutant Regression - Ozone</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 28:</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - All Pollutant Regression - NO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 29:</label>
         <caption id="ca-35">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - All Pollutant Regression - PM<sub>10</sub>
            </p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 30:</label>
         <caption id="ca-36">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - All Pollutant Regression - SO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 31:</label>
         <caption id="ca-37">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - All Pollutant Regression</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 32:</label>
         <caption id="ca-38">
            <p>Minimum Monitor Distance Robustness Check - Ozone</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 33:</label>
         <caption id="ca-39">
            <p>Minimum Monitor Distance Robustness Check - NO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 34:</label>
         <caption id="ca-40">
            <p>Minimum Monitor Distance Robustness Check - PM<sub>10</sub>
            </p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 35:</label>
         <caption id="ca-41">
            <p>Minimum Monitor Distance Robustness Check - SO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 36:</label>
         <caption id="ca-42">
            <p>Monitor Distance Robustness Check Marginal Effects - Ozone</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 37:</label>
         <caption id="ca-43">
            <p>Monitor Distance Robustness Check Marginal Effects - NO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 38:</label>
         <caption id="ca-44">
            <p>Monitor Distance Robustness Check Marginal Effects - PM<sub>10</sub>
            </p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 39:</label>
         <caption id="ca-45">
            <p>Monitor Distance Robustness Check Marginal Effects - SO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 40:</label>
         <caption id="ca-46">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Time Sample - Ozone</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 41:</label>
         <caption id="ca-47">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Time Sample - NO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 42:</label>
         <caption id="ca-48">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Time Sample - PM<sub>10</sub>
            </p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 43:</label>
         <caption id="ca-49">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Time Sample - SO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 44:</label>
         <caption id="ca-50">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Lag Period - Ozone</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 45:</label>
         <caption id="ca-51">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Lag Period - NO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 46:</label>
         <caption id="ca-52">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Lag Period - PM<sub>10</sub>
            </p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 47:</label>
         <caption id="ca-53">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue - Different Lag Period - SO₂</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 48:</label>
         <caption id="ca-54">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - Unbalanced Panel</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 49:</label>
         <caption id="ca-55">
            <p>Property Tax Revenue per Pupil - CBSA Relative Pollution Level</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 50:</label>
         <caption id="ca-56">
            <p>Adjusted Current Expenditure per Pupil Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 51:</label>
         <caption id="ca-57">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Adjusted Current Expenditure per Pupil</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 52:</label>
         <caption id="ca-58">
            <p>Pupil Teacher Ratio Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 53:</label>
         <caption id="ca-59">
            <p>Marginal Effects for Pupil Teacher Ratio</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-60">
            <p>Pollution Measures</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
