<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">18</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830362</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830367</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>PRICES, MONEY AND SUPPLY SHOCKS IN THE SUB-SAHARAN AFRICA: THE CASE OF GHANA / PRIX, MONNAIE ET CHOC DU CÔTE DE L'OFFRE DANS L'AFRIQUE SUB-SAHARIENNE: LE CAS DU GHANA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Riccardo</given-names>
                  <surname>Florentini</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mohamed Abdisalam</given-names>
                  <surname>Hassan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>65</fpage>
         <lpage>80</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830367"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The paper analyses the relation between prices, money and supply shocks in Ghana, a classic case of economic stagnation and decline in contemporary sub-Saharan Africa. The hypothesis of the paper is that inflation in Ghana during the seventies and the eighties was mainly caused by supply shocks in food production and excessive money creation by the monetary authorities. The high rate of money growth, in turn, was a consequence of the large budget deficits run by the government. In the paper the relations between money, prices and supply shock is tested by means of the VAR technique, while the link between money and fiscal deficits is tested by means of ordinary regression analysis (OLS). Because of lack of data about supply shocks, in the paper a specific form of structural VAR is employed to obtain a supply shock series that can be used in the testing procedure. We found the available real GDP data to be a very good proxy for supply shocks. The results of the VAR and impuls response analysis are very interesting. On the one hand, they confirm the hypothesis that inflation in Ghana depends both on money and supply shocks. On the other hand, they show that the dynamics of prices is consistent with the predictions of the aggregate demand-supply textbook model. In other words, monetary shocks have a permanent long run effect on prices, while temporary supply shocks have only a short run impact on prices. The long run equilibrium level is not affected. Finally, the results of the OLS analysis support the idea that in Ghana money growth is closely linked to government expenditure policies. L'article analyse la relation entre prix, monnaie et choc du côté de l'offre en Ghana, un cas classique de stagnation économique et de déclin dans l'Afrique sub-saharienne contemporaine. Dans ce travail on soutient l'hypothèse que l'inflation en Ghana, dans les années 70 et 80, fut provoquée par des chocs negatifs dans le secteur agricole et par une croissance excessive de l'offre de monnaie. La forte expansion monétaire, à sa fois, fut provoquée directement par des remarquables déficits publiques. La relation entre prix, monnaie et choc du côté de l'offre est verifié par la technique VAR, pendant que le rapport entre la monnaie et les déficits est verifié en employant l'analyse de régression simple (OLS). Faute de données explicites sur la série temporelle des chocs du côté de l'offre, on emploie dans l'article une forme particulière de VAR structural, afin d'obtenir un'estimation des chocs du côté de l'offre employable dans le procédé de vérification des hypothèses. Un des premiers résultats est que la série du produit national brut réel est une bonne approximation de la série des chocs du côté de l'offre. L'analyse économétrique confirme l'hypothèse que en Ghana l'inflation depend soit de l'offre de la monnaie que des chocs du côté de l'offre. En outre les résultats montrent que la dynamique des prix s'accorde avec les prévisions du modèle de l'offre et de la demande agrégée traditionnelle. En d'autres mots, les chocs monétaires ont un effet permanent de long période sur les prix, tandis que des chocs temporaires du côté de l'offre ont seulement un impact de bref période sur les prix. L'équilibre de long période n'en est point modifié. Enfin, les résultats de l'analyse de régression soutiennent l'idée que l'offre de monnaie en Ghana est strictement en corrélation avec les politiques des dépenses publiques du gouvernement.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d22e202a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e209" publication-type="other">
Lewis (1953) p. 8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e216a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e223" publication-type="other">
Judge, et al. (1988), chapter 18.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e230a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e237" publication-type="other">
Dornbusch and Fischer (1990), chapter XIII.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e244a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e251" publication-type="other">
Aghevli and Khan (1987).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d22e267a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e271" publication-type="other">
Aghevli B.B. and M.S. Khan, "Government deficit and the inflationary process in developing countries", in Coats
W.L.J. and D.R. Khatkhate (eds), Government deficit and the inflationary process in developing countries,
Pergamon Press, Washington DC, 1980.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e288" publication-type="other">
Bayoumi T. and B. Eichengreen, "Macroeconomic adjustment under Bretton Woods and the post-Bretton-Woods
float: an impulse response analysis", CEPR Discussion Paper Series, n. 729, 1992a.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e298a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e302" publication-type="other">
Bayoumi T. and B. Eichengreen, "Shocking aspects of European monetary unification", CEPR Discussion Paper
Series, n. 715, 1992b.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e312a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e316" publication-type="other">
Bayoumi T. and M. Taylor P., "Macroeconomic Shocks, the ERM and tripolarity", CEPR Discussion Paper Series,
n. 711, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e327a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e331" publication-type="other">
Blanchard O. Jean and D. Quah, "The dynamic effects of aggregate demand and supply disturbances", American
Economic Review, n. 79, 1989, pp. 655-673.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e341a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e345" publication-type="other">
Cline W.R. and Associates, World inflation and the developing countries, The Brooking Institute, Washington
D.C., 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e355a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e359" publication-type="other">
Dornbusch R. and S. Fischer, Macroeconomics, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e370" publication-type="other">
Frimpong A. J.H., The vampire state in Africa, Africa World Press Inc., Trenton N.Y., 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e377a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e381" publication-type="other">
Giannini C, "Topics in structural VAR econometrics", Quaderni di Ricerca, Dipartimento di Economia, Univer-
sita di Ancona, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e391a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e395" publication-type="other">
Goldsmith R.W., Financial structure and development, Yale University Press, Yale, 1969.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e403a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e407" publication-type="other">
Judge G.G., R.C Hill, W.E. Griffiths, H. Lutkepohl and T. - C Lee, Introduction to the theory and practice of
econometrics (2nd edition), Wiley, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e417a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e421" publication-type="other">
Lewis W.A., Report on industrialization and the Gold Coast, Government Printer, Accra, 1953.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e428a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e432" publication-type="other">
Lewis W.A., The theory of economic growth, Allen and Unwin, London, 1955.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e443" publication-type="other">
Sims C.A., "Macroeconomic and reality", Econometrica, n. 48, 1980, pp. 1-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


