<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">106</volume>
         <issue-id>i40199176</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44730727</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Review of Mixture Preparation and Combustion Control Strategies for Spark-Ignited Direct-Injection Gasoline Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Fu-Quan</given-names>
                  <surname>Zhao</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ming-Chia</given-names>
                  <surname>Lai</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Harrington</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>861</fpage>
         <lpage>904</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1998 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44730727"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The current extensive revisitation of the application of gasoline direct-injection to automotive, four-stroke, sparkignition engines has been prompted by the availability of technological capabilities that did not exist in the late 1970s, and that can now be utilized in the engine development process. The availability of new engine hardware that permits an enhanced level of computer control and dynamic optimization has alleviated many of the system limitations that were encountered in the time period from 1976 to 1984, when the capabilities of direct-injection, stratified-charge, spark-ignition engines were thoroughly researched. This paper incorporates a critical review of the current worldwide research and development activities in the gasoline directinjection field, and provides insight into new areas of technology that are being applied to the development of both production and prototype engines. The advantages and disadvantages of the emerging technologies that are being utilized to develop gasoline direct-injection combustion systems, such as electronic common-rail injection, variable swirl and tumble control, computational fluid dynamics, and laser diagnostics of fuel sprays and combustion are discussed in detail within the context of the total industry effort to enhance the attainable brake specific fuel consumption and emissions. Significant emphasis is placed upon extracting the key findings of each investigation and discussing the relative potential of the technique for meeting the major requirements of the gasoline direct-injection engine. Areas of general consensus that are evident among the hundreds of researchers who are currently investigating this field are noted, as are apparent conflicts that must be resolved in the near future by obtaining additional data. Also noted and discussed are a number of critical research areas for which it is obvious that insufficient effort and resources are being devoted. One example of such an area is the development of a proven laboratory test for quantifying the deposit formation tendencies of direct-injection gasoline injectors. Based upon the review of all available technical publications, the trends and directions of the current effort on gasoline direct-injection engine are noted, and the remaining difficult developmental areas are discussed. For planning purposes, the totality of the literature is used to formulate likely engine scenarios regarding the development of specific engine configurations, and to outline technological path options and trends that may be expected in the displacement of the port fuel injection engine by the gasoline direct-injection engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d353447e486a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e493" publication-type="other">
Alperstein, M., Schafer, G. H., and Villforth, III, F. J., Texaco's
stratified charge engine -multifuel, efficient, clean, and practical,
SAE Technical Paper, No. 740563 (1974).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e506a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e513" publication-type="other">
Anderson, R. W., Brehob, D. D., Yang, J., vaiiance, J. ?., ana
Whiteaker, R. M., A new direct injection spark Ignition (DISI)
combustion system for low emissions, FISITA-96 Technical
Paper, No. P0201 (1996a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e529a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e536" publication-type="other">
Anderson, R. W., Yang, J., Brehob, D. D., vaiiance, J. *., ana
Whiteaker, R. M., Understanding the thermodynamics of direct
injection spark ignition (DISI) combustion systems: an analytical
and experimental investigation, SAE Technical Paper, No.
962018 (1996b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e555a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e562" publication-type="other">
Ando, H., Combustion control technologies for direcwnjecuon
gasoline engines, Proceedings of the 73rd JSME Annual Meeting
(V) (in Japanese), No. WS 1 1-(4), pp.31 9-320 (1996a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e576a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e583" publication-type="other">
Ando, H., Combustion control technologies for gasoline engines,
I.MechE. Seminar of Lean Bum Combustion Engines, S433,
December 3-4, 1996 (1996b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e596a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e603" publication-type="other">
Arcoumanis, C., Gold, M. R., Whitelaw, J. h., ana au, m. m.,
Local charge stratification In spark-ignition engines, I.MechE.
Seminar of Lean Bum Combustion Engines, S433, December
3-4,1996(1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e619a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e626" publication-type="other">
Balles, ?. ?., Ekchian, J. ?., and Heywood, J. ?., Fuel injection
characteristics and combustion behavior of a direct-injection
stratified-charge engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 841379
(1984).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e642a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e649" publication-type="other">
Baranescu, G. S., Some characteristics of sparx assistea airea
injection engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 830589 (1983).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e659a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e666" publication-type="other">
Buchheim, R. and Quissek, F., Ecological ana economical
aspects of future passenger car powertrains, FISITA Technical
Paper, No. P1 404 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e679a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e686" publication-type="other">
Caracciolo, F. and Stebar, R. F., An engine aynamometer tesi rar
evaluating port fuel injector plugging, SAE Technical Paper, No.
872111 (1987).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e700a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e707" publication-type="other">
Daisho, Y., Shimizu, A., Saito, T., and Choi, K. H., A fundamentai
study on charge stratification, Proceedings of COMODIA-85,
pp.423-432 (1985).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e720a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e727" publication-type="other">
Das, S. and Dent, J. C., A stuay of air-assisted fuel injection into
a cylinder, SAE Technical Paper, No. 941876 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e737a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e744" publication-type="other">
Diwakar, R., Fansler, T. D., French, D. T., Ghandhi, J. B., Dasch,
C. J., and Heffelfinger, D. M., Liquid and vapor fuel distributions
from an air-assist injector - an experimental and computational
study, SAE Technical Paper, No. 920422 (1992).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e760a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e767" publication-type="other">
Dodge, L. G., Fuel preparation requirements tor direct-injected
spark ignition engines, Proceedings of ILASS-America, pp.120-
124 (1996a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e780a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e787" publication-type="other">
Dodge, L. G., Fuel preparation requirements for direct-injected
spark ignition engines, SAE Technical Paper, No. 962015
(1996b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e800a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e807" publication-type="other">
Douaud, A., Tomorrow's efficient and clean engines and fuels,
FISITA Technical Paper, No. K0006 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e818a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e825" publication-type="other">
Drake, M. C., Fansler, T. D., and French, D. T., Crevice flow and
combustion visualization in a direct-injection spark-ignition engine
using laser imaging techniques, SAE Technical Paper, No.
952454(1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e841a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e848" publication-type="other">
Duggal, V. K., Kuo, T.-W., and Lux, F. B., Review of multi-fuel
engine concepts and numerical modeling of in-cylinder now
processes in direct injection engines, SAE Technical Paper, No.
840005(1984).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e864a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e871" publication-type="other">
Emerson, J., Felton, P. G., and Bracco, F. V., Structure of sprays
from fuel injectors part III: the Ford air-assisted fuel injector, SAE
Technical Paper, No. 900478 (1990).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e884a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e891" publication-type="other">
Enright, B., Borman, G. L., and Myers, P. P., A Critical review of
spark ignited diesel combustion, SAE Technical Paper, No.
881317 (1988).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e904a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e911" publication-type="other">
Evers, L. W., Characterization of the transient spray from a high
pressure swirl injector, SAE Technical Paper, No. 940188 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e921a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e928" publication-type="other">
Fansler, T. D., French, D. T., and Drake, M. C., Fuel distribution
in a firing direct-Injection spark-ignition engine using laser-
induced fluorescence imaging, SAE Technical Paper, No. 950110
(1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e945a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e952" publication-type="other">
Felton, P. G., Laser diagnostics for direct-injection gasoline
engines, I.MechE. Seminar of Lean Bum Combustion Engines,
S433, December 3-4, 1996 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e965a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e972" publication-type="other">
Fraidl, G. K., Piock, W. F., and Wirth, M., Gasoline direct
injection: actual trends and future strategies for injection and
combustion systems, SAE Technical Paper, No.960465 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e985a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e992" publication-type="other">
Frank, R. M. and Heywood, J. B., Combustion characterization in
a direct-injection stratified-charge engine and implications on
hydrocarbon emissions, SAE Technical Paper, No. 892058
(1989).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1008a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1015" publication-type="other">
Frank, R. M. and Heywood, J. B., The importance of injection
system characteristics on hydrocarbon emissions from a direct-
injection stratified-charge engine, SAE Technical Paper, No.
900609 (1990a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1031a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1038" publication-type="other">
Frank, R. M. and Heywood, J. B., The effect of fuel
characteristics on combustion in a spark-ignited direct-injection
engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 902063 (1990b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1051a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1058" publication-type="other">
Frank, R. M. and Heywood, J. B., The effect of piston temperature
on hydrocarbon emissions from a spark-ignited direct-injection
engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 910558 (1991).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1072a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1079" publication-type="other">
Fujieda, M., Siraisi, T., and Oosuga, M., Influence or the spray
pattern on combustion characteristics of the direct injection SI
engine, Proceedings of ILASS-Japan (in Japanese), pp. 173-1 77
(1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1095a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1102" publication-type="other">
Furuno, S. et al., The effects of inclination angle of swirl axis on
turbulence characteristics in a 4-valve lean bum engine with SCV,
SAE Technical Paper, No. 902139 (1990).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1115a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1122" publication-type="other">
Ghandhi, J. B. and Bracco, F. v., Fuel distnbution eneas on tne
combustion of a direct-injection stratified-charge engine, SAE
Technical Paper, No. 950460 (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1135a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1142" publication-type="other">
Giovanetti, A. J., Ekchian, J. A., and Heywood, J. B., Analysis of
hydrocarbon emission mechanisms in a direct injection spark-
ignition engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 830587 (1983).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1155a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1162" publication-type="other">
Gualtieri, J. and Sawyer, C. A., Toyota, Mitsubishi Dl gas engines
debut, Automotive Industries, p.30 August, 1995 (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1172a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1179" publication-type="other">
Han, Z., Reitz, R. D., Claybaker, P. J., Rutland, C., Yang, J., and
Anderson, R. W., Modeling the effects of intake flow structures
on fuel/air mixing in a direct-injected spark ignition engine, SAE
Technical Paper, No. 961 1 92 (1 996a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1196a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1203" publication-type="other">
Han, Z., Parrish, S. E., Farrell, v., and Reitz, R. D., Moaeiing
atomization processes of pressure-swirl hollow-cone fuel sprays,
Paper Submitted to Atomization and Sprays, (1996b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1216a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1223" publication-type="other">
Han, Z., Reitz, R. D., Yang, J., and Anderson, R. W., Effects of
injection timing on air/fuel mixing in a direct-injection spark-ignition
engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 970625 (1997a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1236a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1243" publication-type="other">
Han, Z., Fan, L., and Reitz, R. D., Multi-dimensional modeling of
spray atomization and air/fuel mixing in a direct-injection spark-
ignition engine characteristics, SAE Technical Paper, No. 970625
(1997b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1259a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1266" publication-type="other">
Harada, J., Tornita, T., Mizuno, H., Mashikí, Z., and Ito, Y.,
Development of a direct injection gasoline engine, SAE Technical
Paper, No. 970540 (1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1279a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1286" publication-type="other">
Harrington, D. L., Interactions of direct injection fuel sprays with
in-cylinder air motions, SAE Transition, Vol. 93, (1984a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1296a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1303" publication-type="other">
Harrington, D. L., Analysis of spray penetration and velocity
dissipation for non-steady fuel injection, ASME Technical Paper
04-DGP-13 (1984b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1317a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1324" publication-type="other">
Harrington, D. L., Stebar, R. F., and Caracciolo, F., Deposit-
induced fuel flow reduction in multiport fuel injectors, SAE
Technical Paper, No. 892123 (1989).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1337a1310">
            <label>42</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1344" publication-type="other">
Hauser, G., Heitland, H., and Wislocki, K., Can the no man's land
between diesel-and otto-engines be bridged?, SAE Technical
Paper, No. 951962 (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1357a1310">
            <label>43</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1364" publication-type="other">
Hattori, H., Ota, M., Sato, E., and Kadota, T., Fundamental study
on DISC engine with two-stage fuel injection, JSME International
J., Series B., Vol. 38, No. 1, pp.1 29-1 35 (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1377a1310">
            <label>44</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1384" publication-type="other">
Heisler, H., Advanced engine technology, SAE (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1391a1310">
            <label>45</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1398" publication-type="other">
Hiroyasu, H., Experimental and theoretical studies on the
structure of fuel sprays in diesel engines, Proceedings of
ICLASS-91, Keynote Lecture, pp.17-32 (1991).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1411a1310">
            <label>46</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1418" publication-type="other">
Hoffman, J., Martin, J. K., and Coates, S. W., Spray photographs
and preliminary spray mass flux distribution measurements of a
pulsed pressure atomizer, Proceedings of ILASS-America,
pp.288-291 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1435a1310">
            <label>47</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1442" publication-type="other">
Hoffman, J., Eberhardt, E., and Martin, J. K., companson
between air-assisted and single-fluid pressure atomizers for
direct-injection SI engines via spatial and temporal mass flux
measurements, SAE Technical Paper, No. 970630 (1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1458a1310">
            <label>48</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1465" publication-type="other">
lida, Y., The current status and future trend of DISC engines,
Preprint of JSME Seminar (in Japanese), No. 920-48, pp.72-76
(1992).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1478a1310">
            <label>49</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1485" publication-type="other">
liyama, A. And Muranaka, S., Current status and future
perspective of DISC engine, Proceedings of JSAE (in Japanese),
No. 9431030, pp.23-29 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1498a1310">
            <label>50</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1505" publication-type="other">
liyama, A., Direct Injection gasoline engines, Technical Seminar
at Wayne State University, February 26, 1996 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1515a1310">
            <label>51</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1522" publication-type="other">
Ikeda, Y., Nakajima, T., and Kurihara, N., Spray formation of air-
assist injection for two-stroke engine, SAE Technical Paper, No.
950271(1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1535a1310">
            <label>52</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1542" publication-type="other">
Iwamoto, Y., Noma, K, Yamauchi, T., and Nakayama, O.,
Development of gasoline direct injection engine, SAE Technical
Paper, No. 970541 (1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1556a1310">
            <label>53</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1563" publication-type="other">
Iwata, M., Furuhashi, M., and Ujihashi, M., The spray
characteristics and engine performance of EFI injector,
Proceedings of the Technical Conference of JSAE (in Japanese),
No. 861, pp.29-32 (1986).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1579a1310">
            <label>54</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1586" publication-type="other">
Jackson, N. S., Stokes, J., Whitaker, P. ?., and Lake, T. H., A
direct injection stratified charge gasoline combustion system for
future European passenger cars, I.MechE. Seminar of Lean Bum
Combustion Engines, S433, December 3-4, 1996 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1602a1310">
            <label>55</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1609" publication-type="other">
Jackson, N. S., Stokes, J., and Lake, T. H., Stratified and
homogeneous charge operation for the direct injection gasoline
engine -high power with low fuel consumption and emissions,
SAE Technical Paper, No. 970543 (1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1625a1310">
            <label>56</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1632" publication-type="other">
Kagawa, L., Okazaki, S., Somyo, N., and Akagi, Y., A study of a
direct-injection stratified charge rotary engine for motor vehicle
application, SAE Technical Paper, No. 930677 (1993).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1645a1310">
            <label>57</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1652" publication-type="other">
Karl, G., Kemmler, R., and Bargende, M., Analysis of a direct
injected gasoline engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 970624
(1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1665a1310">
            <label>58</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1672" publication-type="other">
Kato, S. and Onishi, S., New mixture formation technology of
direct fuel injection stratified combustion SI engine (OSKA), SAE
Technical Paper, No. 871689 (1987).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1686a1310">
            <label>59</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1693" publication-type="other">
Kato, S. and Onishi, S., Direct fuel Injection stratified charge
engine by impingement of fuel jet (OSKA) -performance and
combustion characteristics, SAE Technical Paper, No. 900608
(1990).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1709a1310">
            <label>60</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1716" publication-type="other">
Kim, C. and Foster, D. E., Aldehyde and unbumed fuel emission
measurements from a methanol-fueled Texaco stratified charge
engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 852120 (1985).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1729a1310">
            <label>61</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1736" publication-type="other">
Kim, K. S. and Kim, S. S., Spray characteristics of an air-assisted
fuel injector for two-stroke direct-injection gasoline engines,
Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 4, pp.501 -521 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1749a1310">
            <label>62</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1756" publication-type="other">
Kono, S., Kudo, H., and Terashita, A Study of spray Direction
Against Swirl in D.I. Engines, Proceedings of COMODIA-90,
pp.269-274 (1 990).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1769a1310">
            <label>63</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1776" publication-type="other">
Kono, S., Study of the stratified charge and stable combustion in
DI gasoline engines, SAE Technical Paper, No. 950688 (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1786a1310">
            <label>64</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1793" publication-type="other">
Kume, T., Iwamoto, Y., lida, K., Murakami, M., Aklshino, K., and
Ando, H., Combustion control technologies for direct injection SI
engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 960600 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1807a1310">
            <label>65</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1814" publication-type="other">
Kuwahara, K., Watanabe, T., Shudo, T., and Ando, H., A study of
combustion characteristics in a direct injection gasoline engine by
high-speed spectroscopic measurement, Proceedings of the
internal Combustion Engine Symposium -Japan (in Japanese),
pp.145-150 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1833a1310">
            <label>66</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1840" publication-type="other">
Laforgia, D., Chehroudi, B., and Bracco, F. V., Structure of
sprays from fuel injectors - part II, the Ford DFI - 3 fuel injector,
SAE Technical Paper, No. 890313 (1989).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1853a1310">
            <label>67</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1860" publication-type="other">
Lake, T. H., Christie, M. J., Stokes, J., Horada, O., and
Shimotani, K., Preliminary investigation of solenoid activated in-
cylinder injection in stoichiometric S.I. engine, SAE Technical
Paper, No. 940483 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1876a1310">
            <label>68</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1883" publication-type="other">
Lake, T. H., Sapsford, S. M., Stokes, J., and Jackson, N. S.,
Simulation and development experience of a stratified charge
gasoline direct injection engine, SAE Technical Paper, No.
962014(1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1899a1310">
            <label>69</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1906" publication-type="other">
Lee, C. F. and Bracco, F. V., Initial comparisons of computed and
measured hollow-cone sprays in an engine, SAE Technical
Paper, No. 940398 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1919a1310">
            <label>70</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1926" publication-type="other">
Lewis, J. M., UPS multifuel stratified charge engine development
program - field test, SAE Technical Paper, No. 860067 (1986).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1937a1310">
            <label>71</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1944" publication-type="other">
Maclnnes, J. M. and Bracco, F. V., Computation of the Spray
from an Air-Assisted Fuel Injector," SAE Technical Paper, No.
902079 (1990).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1957a1310">
            <label>72</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1964" publication-type="other">
Matsushita, S., Nakanishi, K., Gohno, T., and Sawada, D.,
Mixture formation process and combustion process of direct
injection S.I. engine, Proceedings of JSAE (in Japanese), No.
965, Oct. 10, 1996, pp. 101-104 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e1980a1310">
            <label>73</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e1987" publication-type="other">
Mccann, K. A., MMC ready with first DI gasoline engine, WARD'S
Engne and Vehicle Technology Update, Vol. 21, No. 11, June 1,
1995, pp.1 -2 (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2000a1310">
            <label>74</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2007" publication-type="other">
Meyer, J., Kiefer, K., Von Issendorff, F., Thiemann, J., Haug, M.,
Schreiber, M., and Klein, R., Spray visualization of air-assisted
fuel injection nozzles for direct injection Si-engines, SAE
Technical Paper, No. 970623 (1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2023a1310">
            <label>75</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2030" publication-type="other">
Meurer, S. and Urlaub, A., Development and operational results of
the MAN FM combustion system, SAE Technical Paper, No.
690255 (1969).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2043a1310">
            <label>76</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2050" publication-type="other">
Miok, J., Huh, K. Y., and Noh, S. H., Numerical prediction of
charge distribution in a lean burn direct-injection spark-ignition
engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 970626 (1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2064a1310">
            <label>77</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2071" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, E., Alperstein, M., Cobb, J. M., and Faist, C. H., A
stratified charge multifuel military engine -a progress report, SAE
Technical Paper, No. 720051 (1972).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2084a1310">
            <label>78</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2091" publication-type="other">
Miyamoto, N., Ogawa, H., Shudo, T., and Takeyama, F.,
Combustion and emissions in a new concept DI stratified charge
engine with two-stage fuel injection, SAE Technical Paper, No.
940675 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2107a1310">
            <label>79</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2114" publication-type="other">
Miyamoto, T., Kobayashi, T., and Matsumoto, Y., Structure of
sprays from an air-assist hollow-cone injector, SAE Technical
Paper, No. 960771 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2127a1310">
            <label>80</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2134" publication-type="other">
Naitoh, K. and Takagi, Y., Synthesized spheroid particle (SSP)
method for calculating spray phenomena in direct-injection SI
engines, SAE Technical Paper, No. 962017 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2147a1310">
            <label>81</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2154" publication-type="other">
Ohyama, Y., Nogi, T., and Ohsuga, M., Effects of fuel/air mixture
preparation on fuel consumption and exhaust emission in a spark
ignition engine, IMechE Paper, No. 925023, C389/232, pp.59-64
(1992).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2170a1310">
            <label>82</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2177" publication-type="other">
Parrish, S. and Farrel, P. V., Transient spray characteristics of a
direct-injection spark-ignited fuel injector, SAE Technical Paper,
No. 970629 (1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2191a1310">
            <label>83</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2198" publication-type="other">
Pischinger, F. and Walzer, P., Future trends in automotive engine
technology, FISITA Technical Paper, No. P1303 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2208a1310">
            <label>84</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2215" publication-type="other">
Pontoppidan, M., Gaviani, G., and Marelli, M., Direct fuel-injection
- a study of injector requirements for different mixture preparation
concepts, SAE Technical Paper, No. 970628 (1 997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2228a1310">
            <label>85</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2235" publication-type="other">
Ronald, B., Helmut, T., and Hans, ?., Direct fuel Injection - a
necessary step of development of the Si engine, Fl SITA Technical
Paper, No. P1613 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2248a1310">
            <label>86</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2255" publication-type="other">
Saito, A., Kawamura, K. and Tanasawa, Y., Improvement of fuel
atomizatlon electronic fuel injector by air flow, Proceedings of
ICLASS-88, pp.263-270 (1988).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2268a1310">
            <label>87</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2275" publication-type="other">
Salters, D., Williams, P., and Greig, A., Fuel spray
characterization within an optically accessed gasoline direct
injection engine using a CCD imaging system, SAE Technical
Paper, No. 961149 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2291a1310">
            <label>88</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2298" publication-type="other">
Schapertons, H., Emmenthal, K.-D., Grabe, H.-J., and
Oppermann, W., VW's gasoline direct injection (GDI) research
engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 91 0054 (1991).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2312a1310">
            <label>89</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2319" publication-type="other">
Schechter, M. M. and Levin, M. B., Air-forced fuel injection
system for 2-stroke D.I. gasoline engine, SAE Technical Paper,
No. 910664(1991).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2332a1310">
            <label>90</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2339" publication-type="other">
Scussei, A. J., Simko, A. O., and Wade, W. R., The Ford
PROCO engine update, SAE Technical Paper, No. 780699
(1978).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2352a1310">
            <label>91</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2359" publication-type="other">
Seiffert, U., The automobile in the next century, FISITA Technical
Paper, No. K0011 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2369a1310">
            <label>92</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2376" publication-type="other">
Shimotani, K., Oikawa, K., Horada, O., and Kagawa, Y.,
Characteristics of gasoline in-cylinder direct injection engine,
Proceedings of the Internal Combustion Engine Symposium -
Japan (in Japanese), pp.289-294 (1 995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2392a1310">
            <label>93</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2399" publication-type="other">
Shimotani, K., Oikawa, K., Tashiro, Y., and Horada, O.,
Characteristics of exhaust emission on gasoline in-cylinder direct
injection engine, Proceedings of the Internal Combustion Engine
Symposium -Japan (in Japanese), pp.1 1 5-1 20 (1 996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2415a1310">
            <label>94</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2422" publication-type="other">
Simko, A., Choma, M. A., and Repko, L. L., Exhaust emissions
control by the Ford Programmed combustion process -PROCO,
SAE Technical Paper, No. 720052 (1972).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2436a1310">
            <label>95</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2443" publication-type="other">
Spiegel, L. and Spicher, U., Mixture Formation and Combustion in
a Spark Ignition Engine with Direct Fuel Injection, SAE Technical
Paper, No.920521(1992).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2456a1310">
            <label>96</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2463" publication-type="other">
Sugimoto, T., Takeda, K., and Yoshizaki, H., Toyota air-mix type
two-hole injector for 4-valve engines, SAE Technical Paper, No.
912351 (1991).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2476a1310">
            <label>97</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2483" publication-type="other">
Takagi, Y., The role of mixture formation in improving fuel
economy and reducing emissions of automotive S.I. engines,
FISITA Technical Paper, No. P0109 (1996a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2496a1310">
            <label>98</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2503" publication-type="other">
Takagi, Y., Combustion characteristics and research topics of in-
cylinder direct-injection gasoline engines, Proceedings of the 73rd
JSME Annual Meeting (V) (in Japanese), No. WS 1 1-(3), pp.31 7-
318 (1996b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2519a1310">
            <label>99</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2526" publication-type="other">
Tomoda, T., Sasaki, S., Sawada, D., Saito, A., and Sami, H.,
Development of direct injection gasoline engine - study of
stratified mixture formation, SAE Technical Paper, No. 970539
(1997).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2542a1310">
            <label>100</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2549" publication-type="other">
Toyota, Direct-injection 4-stroke gasoline engine, TOYOTA Press
Information 96, August 1996 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2560a1310">
            <label>101</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2567" publication-type="other">
Urlaub, A. G. and Chmela, F. G., High-speed, multifuel engine:
L9204 FMV, SAE Technical Paper, No. 740122 (1974).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2577a1310">
            <label>102</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2584" publication-type="other">
Wirth, M., Piock, W. F., and Fraidl, Actual trends and future
strategies for gasoline direct injection, I.MechE. Seminar of Lean
Bum Combustion Engines, S433, December 3-4, 1996 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2597a1310">
            <label>103</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2604" publication-type="other">
Wojik, K. and Fraidl, G. K., Engine and vehicle concepts for low
consumption and low-emission passenger cars, FISITA Technical
Paper, No. P1302 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2617a1310">
            <label>104</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2624" publication-type="other">
Wood, C. D., Unthrottled open-chamber stratified charge engines,
SAE Technical Paper, No. 780341(1978).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2634a1310">
            <label>105</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2641" publication-type="other">
Yamada, T., Trends of S.I. engine technologies in Japan, FISITA -
96 Technical Paper, No. P0204 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2651a1310">
            <label>106</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2658" publication-type="other">
Yamaguchi, J., Mitsubishi DI gasoline engine prototype,
Automotive Engineering, pp.25-29, September, 1995 (1995).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2669a1310">
            <label>107</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2676" publication-type="other">
Yamaguchi, J., Toyota readies direct-injection gasoline engine for
production, Automotive Engineering, pp.74-76, November, 1996
(1996a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2689a1310">
            <label>108</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2696" publication-type="other">
Yamaguchi, J., Mitsubishi Galant sedan and Legnum wagon,
Automotive Engneering, pp.26-29, November, 1996 (1996b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2706a1310">
            <label>109</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2713" publication-type="other">
Yamauchi, T. and Wakisaka, T., Computation of the hollow-cone
sprays from high-pressure swirl injector from a gasoline direct-
injection SI engine, SAE Technical Paper, No. 962016 (1996).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2726a1310">
            <label>110</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2733" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Taketomi, M., Nishida, K. and Hiroyasu, H.,
Quantitative imaging of the fuel concentration in a SI engine with
laser Rayleigh scattering, SAE Technical Paper, No.932641
(1993).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2749a1310">
            <label>111</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2756" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Taketomi, M., Nishida, K. and Hiroyasu, H., PUF
measurements of the cyclic variation of mixture concentration in a
SI engine, SAE Technical Paper, No.940988 (1994).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2769a1310">
            <label>112</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2776" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Lai, M.-C., and Harrington, D. L., The spray
characteristics of automotive port fuel injection -a critical review,
SAE Technical Paper, No. 950506 (1995a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2790a1310">
            <label>113</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2797" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Yoo, J.-H., and Lai, M.-C., The spray charactenstics
of dual-stream port fuel injectors for applications to 4-valve
gasoline engines, SAE Technical Paper, No. 952487 (1995b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2810a1310">
            <label>114</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2817" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Lai, M.-C., Liu, Y., Yoo, J.-H., Zhang, L., and
Yoshida, Y., Spray characteristics of direct-injection gasoline
engines, Proceedings of ILASS-America, pp.150-154 (1996a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2830a1310">
            <label>115</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2837" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Yoo, J.-H., Liu, Y., and Lai, M.-C., Spray dynamics of
high pressure fuel injectors for DI gasoline engines, SAE
Technical Paper, No. 961925 (1996b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2850a1310">
            <label>116</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2857" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Yoo, J.-H. and Lai, M.-C., The spray structure of air-
shrouded dual-stream port fuel injectors with different air mixing
mechanisms, Proceedings of the 1996 Spring Technical
Conference of the ASME Internal Combustion Engne Division,
ICE-Vol. 26-2, pp.21 -29 (1996c).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2876a1310">
            <label>117</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2883" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Yoo, J.-H., and Lai, M.-C., Mixture formation and
combustion characteristics of a direct-injection gasoline engine,
Paper submitted to ILASS-America (1997a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2896a1310">
            <label>118</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2903" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Yoo, J.-H., and Lai, M.-C., Mixture formation process
of a direct-injection gasoline engine, Paper submitted to 1997
SAE Spring Fuels and Lubricants meeting, (1997b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d353447e2917a1310">
            <label>119</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d353447e2924" publication-type="other">
Zhao, F.-Q., Yoo, J.-H., Liu, Y., and Lai, M.-C., Characterization
of direct-injection gasoline sprays under different ambient and fuel
injection conditions, Paper submitted to ICLASS-97 (1997c).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


