<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">39</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24459263</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24459268</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Supplemental Educational Services and Student Test Score Gains: Evidence from a Large, Urban School District</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Matthew G.</given-names>
                  <surname>Springer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Matthew J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Pepper</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Bonnie</given-names>
                  <surname>Ghosh-Dastidar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>370</fpage>
         <lpage>403</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 Board of Directors of the Journal of Education Finance, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24459268"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This study examines the effect of supplemental education services (SES) on student test score gains and whether particular subgroups of students benefit more from NCLB tutoring services. Our sample includes information on students enrolled in third through eighth grades nested in 121 elementary and middle schools over a five-year period comprising the 2003–04 to 2007–08 school years. A total of 17 elementary and middle schools were required to offer SES at some point during the period under study, and 9,861 student-year pairings in the sample were eligible to receive SES. Although our preferred analytic approach takes advantage of panel data to implement an analysis strategy with student fixed effect regression methods, we also test the robustness of these estimates to a number of alternative approaches, including a comparison of student test score gains between current and future SES participants. We find consistently significant and positive average effects of SES on test score gains in mathematics. Results in reading tend to be insignificant. SES tutoring does not appear to disproportionately benefit a particular racial/ethnic group or ability level. Female students and students with disabilities appear to benefit more from participating in SES. SES has a significant, cumulative effect on students in both mathematics and reading. We also demonstrate that not accounting for content area of tutoring can cause downward bias in estimates of the SES treatment effect. Our findings are qualified on a couple of dimensions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e257a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e264" publication-type="other">
In 1994, Congress authorized the 21st Century Community Learning Center to open schools
for broader use in their communities. The program became more narrowly focused on school-based
academic and enrichment activities in 1998, growing from an appropriation of $40 million per year in
1998 to more than $1 billion in 2002 (Dynarski et al. 2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e280a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e287" publication-type="other">
In this article, the acronym SES refers to supplemental education services, which should not be
confused with socioeconomic status.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e297a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e304" publication-type="other">
The U.S. Department of Education has entered into flexibility agreements with 5 districts and 11
states for the 2008-09 school year to offer SES to eligible students after only two years of failing AYP.
Locations include Boston Public Schools; Chicago Public Schools; and the states of Arkansas, Florida,
and Utah.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e320a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e327" publication-type="other">
Chappell and colleagues (2010) synthesize research on provider effects of SES.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e335a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e342" publication-type="other">
Two randomized, controlled trials compare the impact of students participating in a typical after-
school program to those students participating in an after-school tutoring program with a specific
curriculum (Black et al. 2008; Fitzgerald 8c Hartry, 2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e355a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e362" publication-type="other">
Researchers have examined whether non-experimental methods replicate estimates on the
experimental impact of a program or policy intervention. Agodini and Dynarski (2004) concluded that
propensity score analysis performed poorly when measuring the experimental impacts of 16 dropout
prevention programs. Wilde and Hollister (2007) reached a similar conclusion using data from the
Tennessee STAR study. Diaz and Handa (2006) suggest that propensity score analysis can adequately
address selection bias if researchers have "an extremely rich set of covariates, detailed knowledge of the
beneficiary selection process, and the outcomes of interest [are] measured as comparably as possible"
(p. 341).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e391a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e398" publication-type="other">
Provider-specific models were run by the authors. Although variation did exist in the efficacy of
provider, it was not the case that a small subset of providers drove the results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e408a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e415" publication-type="other">
Steinberg (2011) examines the extent to which Chicago public school students most in need of, and
who could potentially benefit from, SES actually participate in SES. He finds that students with higher
achievement are less likely to engage in SES, whereas students with better noncognitive outcomes are
more likely to participate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e431a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e438" publication-type="other">
Good and colleagues (2014) report qualitative findings from a mixed-method study of SES in five
urban school districts. They conclude that the lack of effects reported in quantitative studies is largely
due to treatment exposure problem and the instructional capacity and practice of the instructional core.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e451a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e458" publication-type="other">
The two lowest strata contained only two student observations that enrolled in SES.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e466a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e473" publication-type="other">
"Continuously enrolled" is defined using the states definition under NCLB; that is, a student must
be enrolled within the same school from the 20th day of school through mid-April when the states high-
stakes assessments are administered.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e486a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e495" publication-type="other">
An investigation into subject area data by SES providers reveals that providers generally offered
services either focused on both subjects or focused on one subject only. For example, the provider
that tutored the most students focused only on mathematics for 133 students, only on reading for 151
students, and both or unknown for 8 students. The third largest provider focused on both subjects for
199 students, and a single subject only for 15 students.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e514a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e521" publication-type="other">
Students who enrolled in but did not attend SES may have received out-of-school remedial services
from another venue, although this explanation is less likely given the social and economic conditions
of the district and the group of students under study. For example, 92.7% of students who enrolled
with a SES provider but did not attend a single tutoring session qualified for the free lunch program
(7.3% quality for the reduced-price lunch program). And, as reported by the United States Department
of Agriculture (2008), children from families with incomes at or below 130% of the poverty level are
eligible for free meals. Those with incomes between 130% and 185% of the poverty level are eligible for
reduced-price meals, for which students can be charged no more than 40 cents. For the 2008-09 school
year, 130% of the poverty level is $27,560 for a family of four (185% is $39,220) (USDA, 2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e553a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e560" publication-type="other">
We also ran regressions investigating the effect of a quadratic form of total hours attended to
determine whether the positive impact of attendance decreased with its growth, but the quadratic
expression was statistically insignificant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e573a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e580" publication-type="other">
We do not investigate differential effects by socioeconomic status because a student must be
eligible for free lunch or reduced-price lunch to enroll with a provider, and more than 90% of students
enrolled in SES qualified for free lunch.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e593a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e600" publication-type="other">
This approach is described in Hanushek et al. (2005) and has been used by Springer (2007, 2008)
and others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e611a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e618" publication-type="other">
Barley and Wegner (2010) examine underlying issues with student participation in SES in nine
rural schools.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e628a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e635" publication-type="other">
The upper and lower 95% confidence interval bounds are .56 and .21 in mathematics and .68 and
.28 in reading.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e658" publication-type="other">
Agodini, R., &amp; Dynarski, M. (2004). Are experiments the only option? A look at dropout prevention
programs. Review of Economics and Statistics, 86(1), 180-194.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e672" publication-type="other">
Aronson, J., Zimmerman, J., 8t Carlos, L. (2002). Improving student achievement by extending
school: Is it just a matter of time? Washington, DC: WestEd.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e686" publication-type="other">
Barley, Z. A., &amp; Wegner, S. (2010). An examination of the provision of supplemental educational
services in nine rural schools. Journal of Research in Rural Education,25(4), 1-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e700" publication-type="other">
Blau, D., &amp; Robins, R (1988). Child-care costs and family labor supply. Review of Economics and
Statistics, 70(3), 374.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e715" publication-type="other">
Borman, G. D., Rachuba, L. T., Fairchild, R., &amp; Kaplan, J. (2002). Randomized evaluation of a multi-
year summer program: Teach Baltimore: Year 3 report. Retrieved from www.childcareresearch.
org/location/3333</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e728a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e732" publication-type="other">
Burch, P., Steinberg, M., &amp; Donovan, J. (2007). Supplemental educational services under NCLB:
Policy assumptions, market practices, emerging policy issues. Educational Evaluation and
Policy Analysis, 29(2), 115-133.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e745a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e749" publication-type="other">
Catalano, R., Berglund, M. L., Ryan, J., Lonczak, H. S., &amp; Hawkins, J. D. (1999). Positive youth and
development in the United States: Research findings on evaluations of Positive Youth Program.
Social Development Research Group. University of Washington.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e762a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e766" publication-type="other">
Center on Education Policy. (2006). From the capital to the classroom: Year 4 of the No Child Left
Behind Act. Washington, DC: Center on Education Policy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e776a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e780" publication-type="other">
Center on Education Policy. (2007). State implementation of supplemental educational services
under the No Child Left Behind Act. Washington, DC.: Center on Education Policy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e790a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e794" publication-type="other">
Chappell, S., Nunnery, J., Pribesh, S., 8c Hager, J. (2010). Research brief: Supplemental educational
services (SES) provision of No Child Left Behind: A synthesis of provider effects. The Center
for Educational Partnership at Old Dominion University. Retrieved from http://files.eric.
ed.gov/fulltext/ED530860.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e815" publication-type="other">
Chicago Public Schools: Office of Research, Evaluation, and Accountability. (2005). SES tutoring
programs: An evaluation of the second year. Chicago, IL: Chicago Public Schools.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e829" publication-type="other">
Chicago Public Schools: Office of Research, Evaluation, and Accountability. (2007). SES tutoring
programs: An evaluation of year 3 in the Chicago Public Schools. Chicago, IL: Chicago Public
Schools.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e842a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e846" publication-type="other">
Clotfelter, C. T„ Ladd, H. F., &amp; Vigdor, J. L. (2009). The academic achievement gap in grades 3
through 8. Review of Economics and Statistics, 91(2), 398-419.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e856a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e860" publication-type="other">
Connelly, R. (1992). The effect of child care costs on married women's labor force participation.
Review of Economics and Statistics, 74(1), 83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e870a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e874" publication-type="other">
Deke, J., Dragoset, L., Bogen, K., 8c Gill, B. (2012). Impacts of Title I supplemental educational
services on student achievement (NCEE 2012-4053). Washington, DC: National Center
for Education Evaluation and Regional Assistance, Institute of Education Sciences, U.S.
Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e890a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e894" publication-type="other">
Diaz, J. J,. 8c Handa, S. (2006). An assessment of propensity score matching as a nonexperimental
impact estimator. Journal of Human Resources, XLI(2), 319-345.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e905a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e909" publication-type="other">
Dynarski, M„ James-Burdumy, S„ Moore, M., Rosenberg, L., Deke, J., 8c Mansfield, W. (2004).
When schools stay open late: The national evaluation of the 21st Century Community Learning
Centers Program: New findings. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Education, National
Center for Education Evaluation and Regional Assistance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e925a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e929" publication-type="other">
Gelbach, J. (2002). Public schooling for young children and maternal labor supply. American
Economic Review, 92(1), 321.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e943" publication-type="other">
Good, A., Burch, P., Stewart, M, Acosta, R., Heinrich, C., Jones, K., 8c Herrera, A. (2014).
Instruction matters: Lessons from a mixed methods evaluation of Supplemental Educational
Services under No Child Left Behind. Teachers College Record, 116(3).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e960" publication-type="other">
Hanushek, E. A., 8c Rivkin, S. G. (2006). School quality and the black-white achievement gap. NBER
Working Paper No. W12651. Cambridge, MA: National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e970a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e974" publication-type="other">
Heinrich, C. J., Meyer, R. H., 8c Whitten, G. (2010). Supplemental education service under No
Child Left Behind: Who signs up, and what do they gain? Educational Evaluation and Policy
Analysis, 32, 273-298.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e987a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e991" publication-type="other">
Heistad, D. (2005). Analysis of2005 supplemental education services in Minneapolis public schools:
An application of matched sample statistical design. Minneapolis, MN: Minneapolis Public
Schools.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1005a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1009" publication-type="other">
Hollister, R. (2003). The growth in after-school programs and their impact. Washington, DC:
Children's Roundtable.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1019a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1023" publication-type="other">
Kane, T. (2004). The impact of after-school programs: Interpreting the results of four recent
evaluations. New York, NY: William T. Grant Foundation.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1033a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1037" publication-type="other">
Karweit, N. (1985). Should we lengthen the school term? Educational Resesearcher, 14(6), 9-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1044a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1048" publication-type="other">
Lunceford, J. K., 8c Davidian, M. (2004). Stratification and weighting via the propensity score in
estimation of causal treatment effects: A comparative study. Statistics in Medicine, 23(19),
2937-2960.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1061a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1065" publication-type="other">
Potter, A., Ross, S. M., Paek, J„ McKay, D., Ashton, J., 8c Sanders, W. L. (2007). Supplemental
educational services in the State of Tennessee: 2005-2006. Memphis, TN: Center for Research
in Educational Policy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1078a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1082" publication-type="other">
Reisner, E. R„ White, R. N., Brimingham, J„ &amp; Welsch, M. (2002). Building quality and supporting
expansion of after-school projects: Evaluation results from the TASC after-school program.
Washington, DC: Policy Studies Associates.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1096a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1100" publication-type="other">
Rosenbaum, P. R., &amp; Rubin, D. B. (1983). The central role of the propensity score in observational
studies for causal effects. Biometrika, 70(1), 41-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1110a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1114" publication-type="other">
Springer, M. G., Pepper, M. J., Gardner, C., &amp; Bower, C. B. (2009). Supplemental educational
services under No Child Left Behind. In M. Berends, M. G. Springer, D. Ballou, &amp; H. J.
Walberg (Eds.), Handbook of Research on School Choice. New York, NY: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1127a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1131" publication-type="other">
Shaul, M. S. (2006). No Child Left Behind Act: Education actions needed to improve local
implementation and state evaluation of supplemental educational services. Report to
congressional requesters. Washington, DC: Government Accountability Office.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1144a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1148" publication-type="other">
Stiefel, L., Schwartz, A. E., &amp; Ellen, I. G. (2007). Disentangling the racial test score gap: Probing the
evidence in a large urban school district. Journal of Policy Analysis and Management, 26(1),
7-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1165" publication-type="other">
Steinberg, M. (2011). Educational choice and student participation: The case of the supplemental
educational services provision in Chicago Public Schools. Educational Evaluation and Policy
Analysis, 33(2), 159-182.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1178a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1182" publication-type="other">
Wilde, E. T., &amp; Hollister, R. (2007). How close is close enough? Testing nonexperimental estimates of
impact against experimental estimates of impact with education test score as outcomes. Madison,
WI: Institute for Research on Poverty. Retrieved from www.irp.wisc.edu/publications/dps/
pdfs/dp 124202.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1203" publication-type="other">
Zimmer, R., Gill, B., Razquin, P., Booker, K., Lockwood, J. R., Vernez, G., Birman, B. F., Garet,
M. S., &amp; O'Day, J. (2007). State and local implementation of the No Child Left Behind Act:
Volume I—Title I school choice, supplemental educational services, and student achievement.
Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Education. Retrieved from www.rand.org/pubs/
reprints/2007/RAND_RP 1265.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1222a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1226" publication-type="other">
Zimmer, R., Hamilton, L. S., &amp; Christina, R. (2010). After-school tutoring in the context of No
Child Left Behind: Effectiveness of two programs in Pittsburgh Public Schools. Economics of
Education Review, 29(1), 18-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


