<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440192</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tax Biases to Debt Finance: Assessing the Problem, Finding Solutions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Ruud A.</given-names>
                  <surname>De Mooij</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">33</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440186</issue-id>
         <fpage>489</fpage>
         <lpage>512</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2012 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440192"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Legal, administrative and economic considerations offer no compelling reason for the current tax advantage of debt finance in many countries. Instead, this 'debt bias' creates significant inequities, complexities and economic distortions. These are likely to be larger than previously thought, especially in the financial sector. To tackle debt bias, the most promising reform is to introduce an allowance for corporate equity, as some countries have successfully done. Its main obstacle is a budgetary cost, estimated at around 15 per cent of current revenue, on average for a selection of advanced economies. This cost can be reduced by granting the allowance only to new investment. The allowance could also be targeted to the financial sector and financed by special bank levies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d22e150a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e157" publication-type="other">
Submitted April 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e164a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e171" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Auerbach (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e178a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e185" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Slemrod (2009), Keen, Klemm and Perry (2010) and Hemmelgarn and Nicodème
(2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e195a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e202" publication-type="other">
Claessens, Keen and Pazarbasioglu, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e210a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e217" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees et al., 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e224a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e231" publication-type="other">
Other aspects of the tax code matter too for the bias towards debt. For instance, non-debt tax shields,
such as fiscal depreciation allowances and loss-offset rules, can reduce the value of the interest deduction
as firms may run into taxable losses. Moreover, imputation systems (applied in Canada and Australia, for
example) mitigate the double taxation of dividends by providing a credit in the PIT for the CIT already
paid.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e250a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e257" publication-type="other">
Keen and De Mooij, 2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e264a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e271" publication-type="other">
Incentives are especially strong in countries that exempt foreign dividends from domestic tax. They
may be smaller under credit systems (applied in the US, for example) as the tax rate of the parent country
then ultimately applies also to foreign income. However, credit systems generally allow deferral until
repatriation and do not provide credits for taxes that exceed the home-country tax. This brings credit
regimes closer to exemption and makes debt shifting important for credit countries too. Japan and the UK
have recently moved from credit to exemption systems.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e294a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e301" publication-type="other">
ZEW and Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e308a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e315" publication-type="other">
Existing studies have established these results only for CIT. The impact of PIT on corporate finance
depends on who is the marginal investor (PIT-exempt or PIT-taxed), which has been difficult to identify.
The impact of PIT is therefore largely an open empirical issue (Graham, 2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e329a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e336" publication-type="other">
Broad leverage includes non-debt liabilities, such as accounts payable to creditors, reserves,
insurance and non-interest-bearing liabilities. The difference from debt is large; see, for example, Rajan
and Zingales (1995). For instance, the average debt-asset ratio is 0.26 while the average leverage-asset
ratio is 0.57 in the studies reviewed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e352a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e359" publication-type="other">
Some caution is required here, since data and estimation techniques may have improved over time,
leading to more precise and perhaps larger estimates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e369a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e376" publication-type="other">
In light of the non-linear increase in the probability of default in response to lower capitalisation,
even small changes in leverage by large banks can have significant welfare losses.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e386a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e393" publication-type="other">
See also Devereux and Gerritsen (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e400a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e407" publication-type="other">
Shaviro, 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e414a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e421" publication-type="other">
Schön et al., 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e429a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e436" publication-type="other">
Modigliani and Miller, 1958.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e443a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e450" publication-type="other">
According to Myers and Majluf (1984), debt is favoured over new equity as a source of external
finance. The reason is that management will not issue new shares if the firm is undervalued, so issuance
of new shares is a signal of overvaluation. This gives rise to adverse selection. It leads to the pecking
order in corporate finance: (1) internal finance, (2) debt and (3) external equity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e466a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e473" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz and Weiss, 1981.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e480a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e487" publication-type="other">
For instance, empirical studies report significant positive effects of a firm's cash flow on investment
(Hubbard, 1997), which is consistent with credit rationing of firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e497a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e504" publication-type="other">
Keuschnigg and Ribi, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e511a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e518" publication-type="other">
Gordon and Bovenberg, 1996.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e526a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e533" publication-type="other">
Fidora, Fratzscher and Thimann, 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e540a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e547" publication-type="other">
To the extent that debt bias creates larger welfare cost in the banking sector than in other sectors, this
warrants attention for special banking taxes (Claessens, Keen and Pazarbasioglu, 2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e557a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e564" publication-type="other">
Banks and Diamond (2010) offer a comprehensive analysis of the arguments for taxing the normal
return on capital, concluding that a positive tax is likely desirable. After weighing the pros and cons of
taxing the normal return, Mirrlees et al. (2011) in Tax by Design argue that a consumption-based tax
system is preferable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e580a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e587" publication-type="other">
Weichenrieder and Windischbauer, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e594a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e601" publication-type="other">
Buettner et al., 2006.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e608a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e615" publication-type="other">
Bond, 2000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e623a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e630" publication-type="other">
Institute for Fiscal Studies, 1991; Devereux and Freeman, 1991.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e637a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e644" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees et al., 2011; Griffith, Hines and Sorensen, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e651a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e658" publication-type="other">
This subtraction is necessary to avoid double tax relief. Indeed, an ACE frees the normal return on
equity participations from tax. If the parent were granted an ACE on all equity, including that used to
finance participations in related entities, it would receive an allowance for returns that are untaxed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e671a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e678" publication-type="other">
Bond and Devereux, 1995.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e685a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e692" publication-type="other">
This rule for the ACE rate is derived under specific assumptions - for example, it would not apply in
the presence of imperfect loss offset - but carries the advantage of simplicity as risks do not have to be
differentiated across companies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e705a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e714" publication-type="other">
In present-value terms (not year by year), the revenue impact is equivalent to that of a cash-flow tax,
which allows investment to be deducted immediately instead of depreciated. The Meade Report in 1978
discussed two versions of the cash-flow tax. The R-base would eliminate interest deductions and the
taxation of interest income (as under CBIT), while the R+F-base would preserve these and add net
borrowing to them. The main difference between the two is the treatment of banks (which would go
untaxed under the former). In Tax by Design, Mirrlees et al. (2011) arrive at a preference for the ACE
over a cash-flow tax, which would involve large transitional difficulties. In his commentary, however,
Gordon (2011) seems not entirely convinced and points to the benefits of an expenditure tax system with
a business cash-flow tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e747a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e754" publication-type="other">
Recent papers take into account agency problems, created by the conflict of interest between
managers and firm owners. This may alter the efficiency properties of the ACE. For instance,
Koethenbuerger and Stimmelmayr (2009) argue that eliminating the tax on the normal return to
investment stimulates not only productive investment, but also unproductive pet-projects that aggravate
the conflict of interest between the shareholders and managers. Keuschnigg and Ribi (2009) emphasise
the distortions of ACE and cash-flow tax systems when firms are credit constrained.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e777a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e784" publication-type="other">
Boadway and Bruce, 1984.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e791a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e798" publication-type="other">
The ACC raises a question, however, about the tax treatment of interest income received, similar to
the taxation of banks under CBIT. Indeed, taxes on banks may need to be modified to avoid double
taxation of interest.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e811a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e818" publication-type="other">
Keen and King, 2002.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e825a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e832" publication-type="other">
Klemm, 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d22e839a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e846" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Gravelle (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d22e862a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e866" publication-type="other">
Altshuler, R. and Auerbach, A. J. (1990), 'The significance of tax law asymmetries: an
empirical investigation', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 105, pp. 61-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e876a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e880" publication-type="other">
Arulampalam, W., Devereux, M. P. and Maffini, G. (2010), 'The direct incidence of corporate
income tax on wages', Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 5293.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e890a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e894" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. J. (2002), 'Taxation and corporate financial policy', in A. J. Auerbach and M.
Feldstein (eds), Handbook of Public Economics, Volume 3, Amsterdam: Elsevier North-
Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e907a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e911" publication-type="other">
Banks, J. and Diamond, P. (2010), 'The base for direct taxation', in J. Mirrlees, S. Adam, T.
Besley, R. Blundell, S. Bond, R. Chote, M. Gammie, P. Johnson, G. Myles and J. Poterba
(eds), Dimensions of Tax Design: The Mirrlees Review, Oxford: Oxford University Press
for the Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e928a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e932" publication-type="other">
Bianchi, J. (2010), 'Overborrowing and systemic externalities in the business cycle',
University of Maryland, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e942a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e946" publication-type="other">
Boadway, R. and Bruce, N. (1984), 'A general proposition on the design of a neutral business
tax', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 24, pp. 231-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e956a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e960" publication-type="other">
Bond, S. R. (2000), 'Levelling up or levelling down? Some reflections on the ACE and CBIT
proposals, and the future of the corporate tax base', in S. Cnossen (ed.), Taxing Capital
Income in the European Union: Issues and Options for Reform, Oxford: Oxford
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e976a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e980" publication-type="other">
— and Devereux, M. P. (1995), 'On the design of a neutral business tax under uncertainty',
Journal of Public Economics, vol. 58, pp. 57-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e994" publication-type="other">
Buettner, T., Overesch, M., Schreiber, U. and Wamser, G. (2006), 'The impact of thin-
capitalization rules of multinationals' financing and investment decisions', CESifo,
Working Paper no. 1817.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1007a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1011" publication-type="other">
Ciaessens, S., Keen, M. and Pazarbasioglu, C. (2010), Financial Sector Taxation: The IMF's
Report to the G-20 and Background Material, Washington DC: International Monetary
Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1025a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1029" publication-type="other">
De Meza, D. and Webb, D. (1987), 'Too much investment: a problem of asymmetric
information', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 102, pp. 281-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1039a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1043" publication-type="other">
De Mooij, R. A. (2011), 'The tax elasticity of corporate debt: a synthesis of size and
variations', International Monetary Fund, Working Paper no. 11/95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1053a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1057" publication-type="other">
— and Devereux, M. P. (2011), 'An applied analysis of ACE and CBIT reforms in the EU',
International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 18, pp. 93-120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1067a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1071" publication-type="other">
Devereux, M. P. and Freeman, H. (1991), 'A general neutral profits tax', Fiscal Studies, vol.
12, no. 3, pp. 1-15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1081a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1085" publication-type="other">
— and Gerritsen, A. (2010), 'The tax treatment of debt and equity', in D. A. Albregtse and P.
Kavelaars (eds), Towards a European Profits Tax, Deventer: Kluwer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1095a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1099" publication-type="other">
Fidora, M., Fratzscher, M. and Thimann, C. (2007), 'Home bias in global bond and equity
markets: the role of real exchange rate volatility', Journal of International Money and
Finance, vol. 26, pp. 631-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1113a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1117" publication-type="other">
Gordon, R. H. (2010), 'Taxation and corporate use of debt: implications for tax policy',
National Tax Journal, vol. 63, pp. 151-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1127a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1131" publication-type="other">
— (2011), 'Commentary on Tax by Design: The Mirrlees Review', Fiscal Studies, vol. 32, pp.
395—414.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1141a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1145" publication-type="other">
— and Bovenberg, A. L. (1996), 'Why is capital so immobile internationally? Possible
explanations and implications for capital income taxation', American Economic Review,
vol. 86, pp. 1057-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1158a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1162" publication-type="other">
Graham, J. R. (2008), 'Taxes and corporate finance', in B. E. Eckbo (ed.), Handbook of
Empirical Corporate Finance, Volume 2, Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1176" publication-type="other">
Gravelle, J. C. (2010), 'Corporate tax incidence: review of general equilibrium estimates and
analysis', Congressional Budget Office, Working Paper no. 2010-03.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1190" publication-type="other">
Griffith, R., Hines, J. and Sorensen, P. B. (2010), 'International capital taxation', in J.
Mirrlees, S. Adam, T. Besley, R. Blundell, S. Bond, R. Chote, M. Gammie, P. Johnson,
G. Myles and J. Poterba (eds), Dimensions of Tax Design: The Mirrlees Review, Oxford:
Oxford University Press for the Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1207a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1211" publication-type="other">
Hemmelgarn, T. and Nicodème, G. (2010), 'The 2008 financial crisis and tax policy',
European Commission Directorate-General for Taxation and Customs Union, Working
Paper no. 20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1224a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1228" publication-type="other">
Hubbard, R. G. (1997), 'Capital-market imperfections and investment', National Bureau of
Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 5996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1238a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1242" publication-type="other">
Institute for Fiscal Studies (1991), Equity for Companies: A Corporation Tax for the 1990s,
London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1252a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1256" publication-type="other">
Keen, M. and De Mooij, R. (2012), 'Debt, taxes and banks', International Monetary Fund
(IMF), Working Paper no. 12/48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1266a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1270" publication-type="other">
— and King, J. (2002), 'The Croatian profit tax: an ACE in practice', Fiscal Studies, vol. 23,
pp. 401-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1280a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1284" publication-type="other">
—, Klemm, A. and Perry, V. (2010), 'Tax and the crisis', Fiscal Studies, vol. 31, pp. 43-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1292a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1296" publication-type="other">
Keuschnigg, C. (2011), 'The design of capital income taxation: reflections on the Mirrlees
Review', Fiscal Studies, vol. 32, pp. 437-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1306a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1310" publication-type="other">
— and Dietz, M. D. (2007), 'A growth oriented dual income tax', International Tax and
Public Finance, vol. 14, pp. 191-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1320a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1324" publication-type="other">
— and Ribi, E. (2009), 'Profit taxation and finance constraints', Centre for Economic Policy
Research (CEPR), Discussion Paper no. 7433.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1334a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1338" publication-type="other">
— and — (2010), 'Business taxation, corporate finance and economic performance',
University of St. Gallen, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1348a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1352" publication-type="other">
Kleinbard, E. (2007), 'Designing an income tax on capital', in H. J. Aaron, L. Burman and E.
Steuerle (eds), Taxing Capital Income, Washington DC: Urban Institute Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1362a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1366" publication-type="other">
Klemm, A. (2007), 'Allowances for corporate equity in practice', CESifo Economic Studies,
vol. 53, pp. 229-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1377a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1381" publication-type="other">
Koethenbuerger, M. and Stimmelmayr, M. (2009), 'Corporate taxation and corporate
governance', CESifo, Working Paper no. 2881.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1391a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1395" publication-type="other">
Meade, J. (1978), The Structure and Reform of Direct Taxation, London: George Allen and
Unwin for the Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1405a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1409" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees, J., Adam, S., Besley, T., Blundell, R., Bond, S., Chote, R., Gammie, M., Johnson,
P., Myles, G. and Poterba, J. (2011), Tax by Design: The Mirrlees Review, Oxford:
Oxford University Press for the Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1422a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1426" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F. and Miller, M. (1958), 'The cost of capital, corporation finance and the theory
of investment', American Economic Review, vol. 48, pp. 261-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1436a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1440" publication-type="other">
Myers, S. C. and Majluf, N. S. (1984), 'Corporate financing and investment decisions when
firms have information that investors do not have', Journal of Financial Economics, vol.
13, pp. 187-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1453a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1457" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R. G. and Zingales, L. (1995), 'What do we know about capital structure? Some
evidence from international data Journal of Finance, vol. 50, pp. 1421-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1468a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1474" publication-type="other">
Schön, W., Beuchert, T., Erker, A., Gerten, A., Haag, M., Heidenbauer, S., Hohmann, C.,
Kornack, D., Lagdali, N., Müller, L., Osterloh-Konrad, C., Polhausen, C., Redeker, P. and
Röder, E. (2009), 'Debt and equity: what's the difference? A comparative view', Max
Planck Institute for Intellectual Property, Competition and Tax Law, Research Paper no.
09-09.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1493a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1497" publication-type="other">
Shaviro, D. N. (2009), Decoding the U.S. Corporate Tax, Washington DC: Urban Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1504a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1508" publication-type="other">
Slemrod, J. (2009), 'Lessons for tax policy in the Great Recession', National Tax Journal,
vol. 62, pp. 387-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1518a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1522" publication-type="other">
Smith, C. W. (1986), 'Investment banking and the capital acquisition process', Journal of
Financial Economics, vol. 15, pp. 3-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1532a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1536" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J. and Weiss, A. (1981), 'Credit rationing in markets with imperfect information',
American Economic Review, vol. 71, pp. 393—410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1546a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1550" publication-type="other">
US Department of the Treasury (1992), Integration of the Individual and Corporate Tax
System: Taxing Business Income Once, Washington DC: US Government Printing Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1561a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1565" publication-type="other">
Weichenrieder, A. and Klautke, T. (2008), 'Taxes and the efficiency costs of capital
distortions', CESifo, Working Paper no. 2431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1579" publication-type="other">
— and Windischbauer, H. (2008), 'Thin-capitalization rules and company responses:
experience from German legislation', CESifo, Working Paper no. 2456.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e1589a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1593" publication-type="other">
ZEW and Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation (2008), Effective Tax Rates on
Investments in the EU, 1998-2007, Report for the European Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
