<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910740</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>LAST WORD</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Last Word</article-title>
            <subtitle>Operations Research Critical for Missile Defense Critical</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Syring</surname>
                  <given-names>J.D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Vice Adm. Syring is the director of the Missile Defense Agency (MDA), Office of the Secretary of Defense, Pentagon, Washington, DC. In this capacity, he oversees the MDA’s worldwide mission to develop a capability to defend deployed forces, the United States, allies, and friends against ballistic missile attacks. VADM Syring is a 1985 graduate of the United States Naval Academy and has an MS in mechanical engineering from the Naval Postgraduate School. Syring served as the technical director for the US Navy’s DDG 1000 Shipbuilding Program and followed that tour as the DDG 1000 major program manager. Upon selection to flag rank in 2010, Syring served as the program executive officer for Integrated Warfare Systems. His personal awards include the Distinguished Service medal, Legion of Merit (two awards), the Meritorious Service medal (four awards), Navy and Marine Corps Commendation medal, and Navy and the Marine Corps Achievement medal.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>48</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910718</issue-id>
         <fpage>62</fpage>
         <lpage>63</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910740"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
