<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812212</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Analyzing Corporate Tax Issues Using Administrative Data</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>"Perception of Gasoline Taxes and Driver Cost: Implications for Highway Finance"</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fisher</surname>
                  <given-names>Ronald C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wassmer</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>23</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812212"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This research compares the actual magnitude of fuel taxes to the perceptions of these amounts. The issue is whether misperceptions about fuel taxes are contributing to voter perspectives about transportation finance and investment issues. A survey of likely Michigan voters shows that taxpayers greatly overestimate the amount they pay in fuel taxes. Half of the respondents (voters) overestimate the magnitude by at least a factor of five, and three-quarters overestimate the magnitude by at least a factor of three. Logistic regression analysis shows that voter (mis)perceptions regarding the magnitude of state fuel taxes do affect their views regarding highway revenue and investment proposals.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Agrawal, Asha, Jennifer Dill, and Hilary Nixon. “’Green’ Transportation Taxes and Fees: ASurvey of Californians.” Mineta Transportation Institute, San Jose State University, June 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Boyer, Kenneth D. “Using Survey Data to Measure the Demand for Road Quality.” Working Paper, Michigan State University Department of Economics, May 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Brown, Alyssa.“In U.S., Most Oppose State Gas Tax Hike to Fund Repairs.” April 22, 2013.Available 10/4/2014 at http://www.gallup.com/poll/161990/oppose-state-gas-tax-hike-fundrepairs. aspx .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Center for Economic Analysis. Gasoline Tax: How Does Michigan Compare to Surrounding States? Department of Agriculture, Food, and Resource Economics; Michigan State University.Available 11/4/2014 at http://news.msu.edu/media/documents/2014/02/ab633576-c65f-4a80- 9ef8-d3366f42815a.pdf .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chetty, Raj, Adam Looney, and Kory Kroft. “Salience and Taxation: Theory and Evidence.”American Economic Review 99:4, September 2009, pp. 1145-1177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">County Road Association. Michigan’s County Road Agencies: Driving Our Economy Forward. 2013. Available 11/4/2014 at http://www.micountyroads.org/PDF/econ_broch_13.pdf .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Duncan, Denvil and John Graham. “Road User Fees Instead of Fuel Taxes: The Quest for Political Acceptability.” Public Administration Review 72, no. 3, May/June 2013, pp. 415–426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Duncan, Denvil, Venkata Nadella, Ashley Bowers, Stacey Giroux, and John D. Graham.“Bumby Designs: Impact of Privacy and Technology Costs on Support for Road Mileage User Fees.” 67 National Tax Journal 67, September 2014, pp. 505–530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Federal Highway Administration. Highway Statistics. 2012. Available 11/4/2014 at https://www.fhwa.dot.gov/policyinformation/statistics/2012 .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Federal Highway Administration. Status of the Nation’s Highways, Bridges, and Transit: Conditions and Performance, 2010. Available 11/4/2014 at http://www.fhwa.dot.gov/policy/2010cpr/execsum.htm#c7h .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Fisher, Ronald C. "Taxes and Expenditures in the U.S.: Public Opinion Surveys and Incidence Analysis Compared." Economic Inquiry (July 1985), pp. 525-550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Friedman, Matt. “Idea to Raise NJ Gas Tax Gets Little Mileage with Voters, Poll Shows.” The Star-Ledger, March 10, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Goldin, Jacob and Tatiana Homonoff. “Smoke Gets in Your Eyes: Cigarette Tax Salience and Regressivity.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 5, 1, 2013, pp. 302-336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Marion and Muehlegger (2011) on “Fuel Tax Incidence and Supply Conditions” (available 11/4/2014 at http://www.nber.org/papers/w16863 )</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Reason-Rupe Public Opinion Survey. Topline Results. Winter 201. Available 11/4/2014 at http://reason.com/poll .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Report Card for America’s Infrastructure, 2013. American Society of Civil Engineers. Available 11/4/2014 at http://www.infrastructurereportcard.org/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">“Report of Minnesota’s Mileage-Based User Fee Policy Task Force.” December 201. Available 11/4/2014 at https://angel.msu.edu/section/default.asp?id=SS14-PPL-891-001-97CS9X-EL-38- 676</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Schmoelders, G. “Fiscal Psychology: A New Branch of Public Finance.” National Tax Journal 12, December 1959, pp. 340-345.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Sheffrin, Steven. “Perceptions of Fairness in the Crucible of Tax Policy.” In Tax Progressivity and Income Inequality, J. Slemrod, ed. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Slemrod, Joel. “The Role of Misconceptions in Support of Regressive Tax Reform.” National Tax Journal 59 (March 2006), pp. 57-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Transportation Solutions: A Report on Michigan’s Transportation Needs and Funding Alternatives. Available 11/4/2014 at http://www.michigan.gov/documents/mdot/MDOT_TF2_Entire_Report_255609_7.pdf .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">“What if Michigan had Enacted a Price Based Gasoline Tax in 1997?,” Citizens Research Council of Michigan, November 2011. Available 11/4/2014 at http://www.crcmich.org/PUBLICAT/2010s/2011/note201102.html .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Whitty, James. “Oregon’s Mileage Fee Concept and Road User Fee Pilot Program, Final Report.” Oregon Department of Transportation, November 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Road Expenditure Preferences (Michigan Epic-MRA Poll, August 2014)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Michigan Gasoline Tax Perceptions (Epic-MRA Poll, August 2014)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Variable Description and Descriptive Statistics (231 Observations, Most Dummy Variables)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Logistic Regression Results (231 Observations, Odds Ratio Reported)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Relative Influence of Explanatory Variables on Poll Respondents Choice of Paying Nothing for Road Improvement (Relative to all Other Options)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Relative Influence of Explanatory Variables on Poll Respondents Choice of Paying More than $20 More per Month for Road Improvement (Relative to all Other Options)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
