<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278309</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Cfd Diagnostic Methodology for the Assessment of Mixture Formation Quality in GDI Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Millo</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Badami</surname>
                  <given-names>Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bianco</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Delogu</surname>
                  <given-names>Enrico</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278288</issue-id>
         <fpage>2461</fpage>
         <lpage>2476</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278309"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The fuel injection plays a crucial role in determining the mixture formation process in Gasoline Direct Injection (GDI) engines.</p>
            <p>Pollutant emissions, and soot emissions in particular, as well as phenomena affecting engine reliability, such as oil dilution and injector coking, are deeply influenced by the injection system features, such as injector geometric characteristics (such as injector type, injector position and targeting within the combustion chamber) and operating characteristics (such as injection pressure, injection phasing, etc.).</p>
            <p>In this paper, a new CFD methodology is presented, allowing a preliminary assessment of the mixture formation quality in terms of expected soot emissions, oil dilution and injector coking risks for different injection systems (such as for instance multihole or swirl injectors) and different injection strategies, from the early stages of a new engine design.</p>
            <p>The proposed methodology, after a number of validation steps with experimental data gathered from different injection systems, has then been applied to guide the choice of the injector type, injection targeting and injection pressure and phasing for a GDI engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Star-CD Methodology Manual, CD-Adapco</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FIRE User Manual, AVL</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Badami, M., Bevilacqua, V., Millo, F., Chiodi, M., Bargende, M., “GDI Swirl Injector Spray Simulation: a Combined Phenomenological-CFD Approach,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3005, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-3005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, D. P., Nouar, I., Senecal, P. K., Hoffmann, J., Martin, J., Rutland, C. J., Reitz, R. D., “Pressure-Swirl Atomization in the Near Field,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0496, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lefebvre, A.H., “Atomizations and Spray”, 1989, Taylor &amp; Francis</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, X. F. and Lefebvre, A. H. “Mean drop sizes from pressure swirl nozzles.” Am. Inst. Aeronaut. Astronaut. J. Propulsion Power, Vol. 3, pages 11-18, 1987</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lefebvre, A. H. “Atomization and Spray”, Taylor &amp; Francis, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allocca, L., Bella, G., De Vita, A. and Di Angelo, L., “Experimental Validation of a GDI Spray Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1137, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-1137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Danieli, A., “Simulazione numerica dello spray in motori ad accensione comandata ad iniezione diretta”, Graduation Thesis Dipartimento di Energetica, Politecnico di Torino, Italy, 2002 (In italian).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Arai, M., “Fuel Spray Penetration and Spray Angle of Diesel Engines”, Trans, of JSAE, Vol. 21, pp. 5-11, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. D. and Bracco, F. B., “On the Dependence of Spray Angle and Other Spray Parameters on Nozzle Design and Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 790494, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790494.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, S., Trattner, A., Schogl, O., Kirchberger, R., Eichlseder, H., Joyce, M., Wall, J., “Combustion System Concept for Low Pressure Gasoline Direct Injection”, Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug und Motorentechnik, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abart, A., Schmidt, S., Schoegl, O., Trattner, A., Kirchberger, R., Eichlseder, H., Jajcevic, D., “Basic Investigations on the Prediction of Spray-Wall and Spray- Fluid Interaction for a GDI Combustion Process,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-32-0030, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-32-0030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stevens, E., Steeper, R., “Piston Wetting in an Optical DISI Engine: Fuel Films, Pool Fires, and Soot Generation,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1203, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-1203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warey, A., Huang, Y., Matthews, R., Hall, M., Ng, H., “Effects of Piston Wetting on Size and Mass of Particulate Matter Emissions in a DISI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1140, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1140.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Di Iorio, S., Lazzaro, M., Sementa, P., Vaglieco, B. M., Catapano, F., “Use of Renewable Oxygenated Fuels in Order to Reduce Particle Emissions from a GDI High Performance Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0628, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0628.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andriesse, D., Comignaghi, E., Lucignano, G., Oreggioni, A., Quinto, S., Sacco, D., “The New 1.8 ltr DI Turbo-Jet Gasoline Engine from Fiat Powertrain Technologies”, 17° Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug und Motorentechnik, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Perazzo, A. and Pautasso, E., “Optimizing the Calibration of a Turbocharged GDI Engine through Numerical Simulation and Direct Optimization,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):556-570, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0780.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
