<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23026343</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>REGIONAL INTEGRATION OF STOCK EXCHANGES IN AFRICA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Samuel O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Onyuma</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2006</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23026337</issue-id>
         <fpage>97</fpage>
         <lpage>122</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23026343"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Although stock markets contribute to economic development, the advances in technology, globalisation, stiff competition, institutionalisation of capital markets, and their traditional nature as self-regulatory, controlled and governed by members or governments threaten their well-being. Elsewhere, exchanges are demutualizing and integrating with others domestically or across borders. African stock exchanges cannot ignore these developments. This article discusses the implications of globalisation to stock markets, benefits and impediments to stock market integration, and suggests how to promote integration of stock markets. It argues that becoming cost-efficient, transparent, widely accountable, and contributively to regional integration, African exchanges must first adapt to global standards, improve their governance practices before thinking of regional integration. Harmonizing listing, trading and settlement systems and rules, and adopting a single currency are crucial as developing mutual commitment and other ties bonding cooperating exchanges. Successful integration requires meticulous planning and execution, political determination and economic rationale. Further progress in developing domestic exchanges must precede any move to integrate. Creating a single African stock market is a complex undertaking thus domestic exchanges should consider forming closer cooperation through cross-border listing and information and technology sharing. From these regional alliances, continental integration could then be considered.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d29e107a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e111" publication-type="other">
ACMF. (2003) Stock Market Development in Africa. African Capital Market Forum Quarterly Newsletter,
Issue No. 6, January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e121a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e125" publication-type="other">
ACC, 2000. Exporting to COMESA and South Africa. American Chamber of Commerce.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e132a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e136" publication-type="other">
Alverez, A. M., and K. Kalman, 2004. "Emerging Stock Markets and the Scope for Regional Coopera-
tion", UNCTAD Discussion Paper No. 79 (Geneva: UNCTAD).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e146a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e150" publication-type="other">
AIIAfrica, 2000. Stock Exchanges Adopt Common Listing Requirements, www.allAfrica.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e158a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e162" publication-type="other">
Alonso-Gamo, P and Fedelino, A and Horvitz, S, 1997. "Globalisation and Growth Prospects in African
Countries", IMF Working Paper No. 97/125.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e176" publication-type="other">
Arnold, T., Hersch, R, Mulherin, J. H. and Netter, J. 1999. "Merging Markets." Journal of Finance 54, (3): 1083-1107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e183a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e187" publication-type="other">
Benimadhu, S. 2002. Speech by S. Benimadhu, Chairman, SADC Committee of Stock Exchanges, the
web site of Johannesburg Stock Exchange, at http://www.jse.co.za.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e197a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e201" publication-type="other">
Bissember, E. E. 2000. Towards A Regional Stock Exchange Volume 3 The Importance Of The Regional
Stock Exchange. Economic Intelligence and Policy Unit, Regional Capital Market Education and Awareness
Programme, Georgetown, Guyana.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e218" publication-type="other">
Bolkestein, F. 2001. The integration of the European Financial Markets and its Importance for Growth
and Economic Development in Europe, The EU Online web site, http://europa.eu.int.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e228a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e232" publication-type="other">
Cybo-Ottone, A., Di Noia, C and Murgia, M. 2000. Recent Development in the Structure of Securities
Markets, Brookings Wharton Papers on Financial Services.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e243a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e247" publication-type="other">
Domowitz, I., Glen, J. and Madhavan, A. 1998. "International Cross-Listing, Foreign Ownership Restric-
tions, and Order Flow Migration: Evidence from Mexico." Journal of Finance, 53 (6): 2001-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e257a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e261" publication-type="other">
Domowitz, I. and Steil, B. 2000. Automation, Trading Costs, and the Structure of the Securities Trading
Industry. LSE conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e271a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e275" publication-type="other">
Di Noia, C. 1999. The Stock-Exchange Industry: Network Effects, Implicit Mergers and Corporate Gov-
ernance, Commissione Nazionale Per Le Societa E La Borsa (CONSOB).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e285a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e289" publication-type="other">
El Serafie, H. and Shahid, S. F. 2002. World Stock Exchanges are Integrating Consolidating/ Merging:
What Could be Done by Arab Exchanges?. CASE Working Paper Series No. 2, Oct.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e299a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e303" publication-type="other">
EAC, 2001. EAC Secretariat Press Release, May 25. http://www.eachq.org/News/PressR 25May2001.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e310a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e314" publication-type="other">
FEAS, 2001. Best Practices for the Development of Stock Exchanges in Transition Economies. Federa-
tion of Euro Asian Stock Exchanges/OECD/lstanbul Stock Exchange.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e325a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e329" publication-type="other">
Hillcapital, 2004. Inventory of World.Exchanges, www.hillscapital/sitemapjinks.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e336a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e340" publication-type="other">
Hooper, V. 2001. "Integration of Stock Exchanges in Regions", G-15 Conference on Capital Markets:
Challenges and Opportunities in the New World, Cairo, Egypt, 25-26th March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e350a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e354" publication-type="other">
Irving, J. 2005. "Regional Integration of Stock Exchanges in East and Southern Africa: Progress and
Prospect", IMF Working Paper No. 05/122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e364a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e368" publication-type="other">
IOSCO, 2001. Issues Paper on Exchange Demutualization. Report of the Technical Committee of the
International Organization of Securities Commissions, June, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e378a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e382" publication-type="other">
Johnson, C. C. and T. Mims. 2003. "Recommendations on Creating Greater Access to African Capital
Markets," Paper presented at the 2003 African Capital Markets Development Forum, New York, April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e392a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e396" publication-type="other">
Kapumpa, M. S. 2000. Strategies for Financial Market Integration: Special Reference to SADC and East
African Regions. Second Annual African Investment Conference and Exhibition, 4-5 October, Cape Town, SA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e407a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e411" publication-type="other">
Kempf, A. and Korn, O. 1996. "Trading System and Market Integration." Working Paper 96-2. University
of Mannheim, Lehrstuhle fur Finanzwirtschaft.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e421a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e425" publication-type="other">
Licht, A. 1998. Regional Stock Market Integration in Europe, CAER II Discussion Paper No. 15, Harvard
Institute of International Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e435a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e439" publication-type="other">
Lee, R. 2000. What is an Exchange? The Automation, Management, and Regulation of Financial Markets.
Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e449a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e453" publication-type="other">
Loubser, R. 2002. "Developments at the JSE and Implications for African Markets," presentation at the
seventh ASEA annual conference, Dar es Salaam, November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e463a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e467" publication-type="other">
Mbendi, 1998. Trade blocs and agreements, Mbendi web site at http://www.mbendi.co.za.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e474a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e478" publication-type="other">
Michael, H. 1998. The Middle East Dilemma: The Politics and Economics of Arab Integration, Columbia
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e489a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e493" publication-type="other">
Mwenda, K. K., 2000. The Dynamics of Market Integration: African Stock Exchanges in the New Millenni-
um, Brown Walker Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e503a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e507" publication-type="other">
Mwenda, K. K. 2001. Zambia's Stock Exchange and Privatization Programme: Studies in African Eco-
nomic and Social Development, Lewiston, N.Y.: Edwin Mellen Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e517a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e521" publication-type="other">
Murray, A. 2002. Key Issues Facing European Securities Exchanges, Sponsored by the Federation of
European Securities Exchanges, July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e531a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e535" publication-type="other">
Njau, J. A. 2004. Regional Integration: The case for East African capital markets. The 8th ASEA Confer-
ence. Nairobi, 23-26 November, Presentation by Chief Executive, DSE.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e545a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e549" publication-type="other">
NYSE, 2000. The Formation of a Global Equity Market, NYSE web site, at www.nyse.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e556a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e560" publication-type="other">
Okeahalam, C. C. 2001. Strategic Alliances and Mergers of Financial Exchanges: The Case of the
SADC," Paper presented at the 4th annual conference of the Centre for the Study of African Economies,
Oxford University, March 29-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e574a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e578" publication-type="other">
Onyuma, S. O. 2006. New Paradigm in Stock Exchanges: The Automation, Governance, Integration and
Regulation of Stock Markets in Africa (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e588a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e592" publication-type="other">
Pieper, P. and Vogel, R. 1997. The Stock Market Integration In Latin America, CAER II Discussion Paper
No. 21, Harvard Institute for International Development, October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e602a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e606" publication-type="other">
Ramos, S. B. and von Thadden, E. L. 2002. Stock Exchanges Competition in a Simple Model of Capital
Market Equilibrium. Unpublished Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e616a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e620" publication-type="other">
Ramanlal, P., Hargis, K. and McDonald, C. G. 1997. "When Do Markets Consolidate? An Analysis of
Market Maker Incentives and Market Characteristics." Working Paper, Finance Department, University of
South Carolina, Columbia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e633a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e637" publication-type="other">
Rothschild, G. 2003. African Capital Markets Development Forum, Paper presented at the SADC mem-
ber committee of stock exchange meeting, JSE Securities Exchange, 14-15 April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e647a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e651" publication-type="other">
Sandu, N. 2004. Zambia Stock Exchange shelves secondary listing plans. Business Digest, October 29th.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e659a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e663" publication-type="other">
Shah, A., and Thomas, S. 1996. "How Competition and Automation Have Changed the Bombay Stock
Exchange." Technical Report. Centre for Monitoring the Indian Economy, Bombay.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e673a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e677" publication-type="other">
Shafik, N. 1994. Learning From Doers: lessons on Regional Integration for the Middle East. Economic
Research Forum For the African Countries: Iran &amp; Turkey, Forum 1(4) December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e687a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e691" publication-type="other">
Steil, B. 2002. Changes in the Ownership and Governance of Securities Exchanges: Causes and Conse-
quences, Brookings Wharton Papers on Financial Services.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e701a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e705" publication-type="other">
Wellons, P. 1998. Integration of Stock Exchanges in Regions in Europe, Asia and Canada and the US,
CAER II Discussion Paper No. 14, Harvard Institute for International Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e715a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e719" publication-type="other">
World Bank, 2002. Capital Market Integration in the East African Community. Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e726a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e730" publication-type="other">
Zenina, Z. 2001. Case Study: Merger of the London and Frankfurt Stock Exchanges, Harvard Law
School, International Finance Seminar, 14th May.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
