<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277769</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>On the Accuracy of Dissipation Scale Measurements in IC Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tess</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ghandhi</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaal</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>323</fpage>
         <lpage>338</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277769"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The effects of imaging system resolution and laser sheet thickness on the measurement of the Batchelor scale were investigated in a single-cylinder optical engine. The Batchelor scale was determined by fitting a model spectrum to the dissipation spectrum that was obtained from fuel tracer planar laser-induced fluorescence (PLIF) images of the in-cylinder scalar field. The imaging system resolution was quantified by measuring the step-response function; the scanning knife edge technique was used to measure the 10-90% clip width of the laser sheet. In these experiments, the spatial resolution varied from a native resolution of 32.0 μm to 137.4 μm, and the laser sheet thickness ranged from 108 μm to 707 μm. Thus, the overall resolution of the imaging system was made to vary by approximately a factor of four in the in-plane dimension and a factor of six in the out-of-plane dimension. The Batchelor scale was found to increase linearly with the laser sheet thickness; a beam half-width of less than six times the effective in-plane resolution was required for 10% accuracy. The in-plane spatial resolution of the imaging system does not need to conform to the Nyquist condition, where at least two pixels are required to measure a given turbulence length scale, when using a spectral analysis method to calculate the Batchelor scale. Rather, the turbulence length scales can be estimated with 10% accuracy at an effective resolution equal to 1.4 times the Batchelor scale. The major developments of this work are two methods to correct the measured Batchelor scale for finite resolution effects. Based on these results and guidelines, researchers can estimate the error of existing measurements in the literature and design experiments to faithfully resolve the turbulence in engine flows.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buch, K.A., and Dahm, W.J.A., “Experimental study of the finescale structure of conserved scalar mixing in turbulent shear flows. Part 2. Sc ≈ 1,” J. Fluid Mech. 364:1-29, 1998, doi:10.1017/S0022112098008726.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, L.K., and Clemens, N.T., “The structure of fine-scale mixing in gas-phase planar turbulent jets,” J. Fluid Mech. 488:1-29, 2003, doi:10.1017/S002211200300466X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G., Karpetis, A.N., and Barlow, R.S., “Dissipation length scales in turbulent nonpremixed jet flames,” Combust. Flame 148(1-2):62-75, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2006.09.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiser, S.A., and Frank, J.H., “Imaging of dissipative structures in the near field of a turbulent non-premixed jet flame,” P. Combust. Inst. 31(1):1515-1523, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2006.08.043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., and Ghandhi, J., “High-resolution turbulent scalar field measurements in an optically accessible internal combustion engine,” Exp. Fluids 51(6):1695-1708, 2011, doi:10.1007/s00348- 011-1178-z.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y., Jesch, D., Oakley, J., and Ghandhi, J., “High Resolution In-Cylinder Scalar Field Measurements during the Compression and Expansion Strokes,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0567, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0567.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope, S.B., “Turbulent Flows,” Cambridge University Press, New York, ISBN 978-0-521-59125-6, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Batchelor, G.K., “Small-scale variation of convected quantities like temperature in turbulent fluid, Part 1,” J. Fluid Mech. 5(1):113-133, 1959, doi:10.1017/S002211205900009X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurikov, M.S., and Clemens, N.T., “The structure of dissipative scales in axisymmetric turbulent gas-phase jets,” AIAA Paper 2002-0164, 2002, doi:10.2514/6.2002-164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frank, J.H., and Kaiser, J.H., “High-resolution imaging of the dissipative structures in a turbulent jet flame with laser Rayleigh scattering,” Exp. Fluids 44(2):221-233, 2008, doi:10.1007/s00348- 007-0396-x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G.H., and Clemens, N.T., “Effects of imaging system blur on measurements of flow scalars and scalar gradients,” Exp. Fluids 37(2):194-205, 2004, doi:10.1007/S00348-004-0801-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clemens, N.T., “Flow Imaging,” in Hornak, J.P. (ed.) Encyclopedia of Imaging Science and Technology, John Wiley and Sons, 2002, doi:10.1002/0471443395.img022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G.H., Clemens, N.T., Barlow, R.S., and Varghese, P.L., “A system model for assessing scalar dissipation measurement accuracy in turbulent flows,” Meas. Sci. Technol. 18(5):1287-1303, 2007, doi:10.1088/0957-0233/18/5/015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buch, K.A., and Dahm, W.J.A., “Experimental study of the finescale structure of conserved scalar mixing in turbulent shear flows. Part 1. Sc ≫ 1,” J. Fluid. Mech. 317:21-71, 1996, doi:10.1017/S0022112096000651.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, L.K., and Clemens, N.T., “Planar measurements of the full three-dimensional scalar dissipation rate in gas-phase turbulent flows,” Exp. Fluids 27(6):507-521, 1999, doi:10.1007/s003480050375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mi, J., and Nathan, G.J., “The influence of probe resolution on the measurement of a passive scalar and its derivatives,” Exp. Fluids 34(6):687-696, 2003, doi:10.1007/s00348-003-0603-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ghandhi, J.B., “Spatial resolution and noise considerations in determining scalar dissipation rate from passive scalar image data,” Exp. Fluids 40(4):577-588, 2006, doi:10.1007/s00348-005- 0097-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G.-H., Barlow, R.S., and Clemens, N.T., “Quantification of resolution and noise effects on thermal dissipation measurements in turbulent non-premixed jet flames,” P. Combust. Inst. 31(1):1525- 1532, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2006.07.242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, G., and Barlow, R.S., “Spatial resolution effects on the measurement of scalar variance and scalar gradient in turbulent nonpremixed jet flames,” Exp. Fluids 44(4):633-645, 2008, doi:10.1007/s00348-007-0423-y.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiser, S.A., and Frank, J.H., “The effects of laser-sheet thickness on dissipation measurements in turbulent non-reacting jets and jet flames,” Meas. Sci. Technol. 22(4):045403, 2011, doi:10.1088/0957-0233/22/4/045403.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., “High resolution passive scalar dissipation measurements in an internal combustion engine,” Ph.D. thesis, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin- Madison, Madison, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakamura, K., “Fluorescence of fluorobenzene,” J. Chem. Phys. 53(3):998-1004, 1970, doi:10.1063/1.1674170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siegman, A.E., Sasnett, M.W., and Johnston, T.F., “Choice of clip levels for beam width measurements using knife-edge techniques,” IEEE J. Quantum Elect. 27(4):1098-1104, 1991, doi:10.1109/3.83346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siegman A. E., “How to (Maybe) Measure Laser Beam Quality,” in DPSS (Diode Pumped Solid State) Lasers: Applications and Issues, Dowley M., ed., Vol. 17 of OSA Trends in Optics and Photonics (Optical Society of America, 1998), paper MQ1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heim, D.M., Jesch, D., and Ghandhi, J.B., “Size-scaling effect on the velocity field of an internal combustion engine, part II: Turbulence characteristics,” Int. J. Engine Res. 0(0):1-16, 2013, doi:10.1177/1468087413501316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heim, D.M., “In-cylinder investigation of engine size- and speed-scaling effects,” Ph.D. thesis, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraser, R. and Bracco, F., “Cycle-Resolved LDV Integral Length Scale Measurements Investigating Clearance Height Scaling, Isotropy, and Homogeneity in an I.C. Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 890615, 1989, doi:10.4271/890615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tennekes, H., and Lumley, J.L., “A First Course in Turbulence,” MIT Press, Cambridge, ISBN 9780262200196, 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiles, M., Probst, D., and Ghandhi, J., “Bulk Cylinder Flowfield Effects on Mixing in DISI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01- 0096, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
