<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Multi-Science Publishing Company</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40151424</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">43749335</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Operating Experience and Economic Assessment of Small Wind Turbine Generators in the United Kingdom</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>G.S.</given-names>
                  <surname>Saluja</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1988</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>105</fpage>
         <lpage>117</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 1988 Multi-Science Publishing Company Ltd</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/43749335"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This study comprises an updated and extended version of the paper presented at the Tenth Annual Conference of the British Wind Energy Association held at the CEGB headquarters in London on 23-25 March 1988. In the UK interest in wind generated energy is focused on large utility owned wind turbine generators (WTGs). Operating experience on commercially produced and privately owned small grid-connected WTGs has been very limited. This study describes experience in the private sector with owning, running and maintaining four WTGSs over the last 3-5 years. The economics of owning the systems have been considered from the owners' point of view. The structure of electricity tariffs and direct utilisation of wind generated electricity override many other considerations including a high wind regime location, higher buyback rates by the electricity authorities and better WTG performance. Local authority rates (property tax) are a severe penalty for non-agricultural WTG owners.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d57e169a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e176" publication-type="other">
Harnessing the Wind, Wind Energy Technology in Britain. Department of Energy,
London, November 1987, p. 1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e186a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e193" publication-type="other">
Harrison, L. Shell backs first U.K. Wind/arm', Windpower Monthly, Vol. 4, No.
5, May 1988, pp. 8-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e203a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e212" publication-type="other">
Page, D.I., Bedford, L.A.W., McAnulty, K.F. and Maskell, C.W.A .A pro-
gress report on the UK Department of Energy's wind energy programme. Wind
Energy Conversion 1987, Proc of the Ninth BWEA Wind Energy Conference, Edin-
burgh, 1987, Mechanical Engineering Publications, London, pp. 1-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e228a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e235" publication-type="other">
'Large Scale Wind Power Comes of Age in Orkney.' Review, Department of Energy,
London, Issue 2, January 1988, p. 1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e246a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e253" publication-type="other">
Haines, R.S., Quarton, D.C. and McDonald, R. The aerodynamic response
of the WEG MSI wind turbine at high angles of attack. Wind Energy Conversion
1987, Proc of the Ninth BWEA Wind Energy Conference, Edinburgh, 1987,
Mechanical Engineering Publications, London, pp. 131-138.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e269a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e276" publication-type="other">
Anderson, M.B., Grocel, K.M., and Powles, S.J.R. Analysis of data from the
25m variable geometry vertical axis wind turbine. Wind Energy Conversion 1987,
Proc of the Ninth BWEA Wind Energy Conference, Edinburgh, 1987, Mechanical
Engineering Publications, London, pp. 333-339.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e292a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e299" publication-type="other">
Sinclair, B.A., Stevenson, W.G. and Somerville, W.M. Wind power
generation on Fair Isle. Energy for Rural and Island Communities III, Proc of the
Third International Conference, Inverness, 1983, Pergamon Press, Oxford, pp. 155-
162.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e315a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e322" publication-type="other">
Musgrove, P J. The economics of existing wind turbines in the size range of 10 to
100 metres diameter. Wind Energy Conversion 1983, Proc of the Fifth BWEA Wind
Energy Conference, Reading, 1983, Mechanical Engineering Publications, Lon-
don, pp. 34-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e338a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e345" publication-type="other">
Macrae, A. and Saluja, G .S. Application of cost engineering techniques to wind
turbines. Proceedings of the Third European Cost Engineering Forum held at the
Institution of Civil Engineers in London, 24 March 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e358a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e365" publication-type="other">
Engstrom, S. The wind energy programme in Sweden. Wind Energy Conversion
1985, Proc of the Seventh BWEA Wind Energy Conference, Oxford, 1985,
Mechanical Engineering Publications, London, pp. 7-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e379a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e386" publication-type="other">
Mai Phat, T. Fatigue analysis for the 4 MW vertical axis wind turbine : Project
Eole. Intersol 85, Proc of the Ninth Biennial Congress of the International Solar
Energy Society, Montreal, 1985, Pergamon Press, New York, pp. 2057-2061.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e399a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e406" publication-type="other">
Lipman, N.H. A review of small and medium sized wind turbine activities.
Energy for Rural and Island Communities III Inverness, 1983, Pergamon Press,
Oxford, pp. 123-135.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e419a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e426" publication-type="other">
Kell, J.R. and Martin, P.L. Faber and Kell's Heating and Air-Conditioning of
Buildings, 6th edition (with amendments), 1984, Architectural Press, London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e436a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e443" publication-type="other">
Saluja, G.S. Aberdeenshire farms use wind turbines. Windirections, Vol. VII, No.
3, Jan 1988, pp 25-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e453a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e460" publication-type="other">
Saluja, G.S. Economic assessment of four privately owned grid-connected, small
wind turbine generators in Scotland, Paper presented at the 10th Annual BWEA
Conference held at the CEGB Headquarters in London, 23-25 March, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e473a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e480" publication-type="other">
Agricultural Improvement Schemes (National) and (EC). Explanatory Leaflets:
Leaflet AIS(N)1 (August 1987) and Leaflet AIS(EC)1, August 1987. Department of
Agriculture and Fisheries for Scotland, Edinburgh.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e494a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e501" publication-type="other">
Saluja, G.S., Robertson, P. and Stewart, R.S. The 55 k W wind energy con-
version system for a holiday chalet complex in the Shetland Isles. Wind Energy
Conversion 1986, Proc of the Eighth BWEA Wind Energy Conference, Cambridge,
1986, Mechanical Engineering Publications, London, pp. 173-177.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e517a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e526" publication-type="other">
Madsen, B.T., Rasmussen, Fl. and Christensen C J. Technology develop-
ment for commercial windmills. Wind Energy Research and Technological
Development in Denmark, 1987, Danish Ministry of Energy, pp. 16-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e539a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e546" publication-type="other">
Poulsen, J. and Meller, T. Reaping the rewards of a lesson hard learned.
Windpower Monthly News Magazine, Vol. 3, No. 9, 1987, pp. 12-14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e556a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e563" publication-type="other">
Saluja, G.S., MacMillan, S., Robertson, P. and Williamson, L.A.
Economics of the 55 kW wind turbine at Scalloway, Shetland Islands. Wind
Energy Conversion 1987, Proc of the Ninth BWEA Wind Energy Conference, Edin-
burgh, 1987, Mechanical Engineering Publications, London, pp. 93-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e579a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e586" publication-type="other">
Bonus Wind Turbine Literature (1987), Bonus Energy, Brande.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e593a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e600" publication-type="other">
MacMillan, S. and Saluja, G.S. A discrete methodology for the prediction of
wind speeds at potential wind generator sites. Paper presented at the 1988 European
Community Wind Energy Conference held at Herning Congress Centre, Denmark,
6-10 June 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e617a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e624" publication-type="other">
Page, D.I., Moughton, E. A. Swansborough, R. Economics of grid-connected
wind turbines in agriculture. Energy for Rural and Island Communities IV, Proc of
the Third International Conference, Inverness, 1985, Pergamon Press, Oxford, pp.
193-199.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e640a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e647" publication-type="other">
Lo rd, R. Local authority rating of the WEG Ltd wind turbine generator in Devon.
Paper presented at the European Wind Energy Association Workshop on Wind
Energy and the Environment held at the CEGB Headquarters in London on 22-22
March, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e663a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e670" publication-type="other">
Sulley, J.L. (Tariffs and Economics Manager, NSHEB). Private Communica-
tion, North of Scotland Hydro Electric Board, Edinburgh, March 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


