<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464784</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464825</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tolerance for Failure and Corporate Innovation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Xuan</given-names>
                  <surname>Tian</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tracy Yue</given-names>
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>211</fpage>
         <lpage>255</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464825"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Based on a sample of venture capital (VC)-backed IPO firms, we examine whether tolerance for failure spurs corporate innovation. We develop a novel measure of VC investors' failure tolerance by examining their willingness to continue investing in underperforming ventures. We find that IPO firms backed by more failure-tolerant VC investors are significantly more innovative and VC failure tolerance is particularly important for ventures that are subject to high failure risk. We show that these results are not driven by endogenous matching between failure-tolerant VC firms and start-ups with high ex ante innovative potential. We also examine the determinants of the cross-sectional heterogeneity in a VC firm's failure tolerance. We find that both capital constraints and career concerns can negatively distort a VC firm's failure tolerance. Less experienced VC firms are more exposed to these distortions, making them less failure tolerant than are more established VC firms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d36e272a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e279" publication-type="other">
Recent empirical research that tests the implications of Manso (2011) includes Ederer and Manso (2010), who
conduct a controlled laboratory experiment, and Azoulay, Graff Zivin, and Manso (2011), who exploit key
differences across funding streams within the academic life sciences. Both studies provide supporting evidence
for Manso's theory.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e295a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e302" publication-type="other">
Other articles have examined the effect of a firm's ownership structure, organizational structure, stock liquidity,
and financing choices on corporate innovation (e.g., Atanassov, Nanda, and Seru 2007; Aghion, Van Reenen,
and Zingales 2009; Belenzon and Berkovitz 2010; Fang, Tian, and Tice 2011; Lerner, Sorensen, and Stromberg
2011; Seru, forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e318a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e325" publication-type="other">
For the purpose of our illustration here, we focus on thresholds that are only a function of the posterior mean,
but the results can be generalized to the cases in which the thresholds are a function of both posterior mean and
precision.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e338a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e345" publication-type="other">
It can be shown that = jj*- —=—4—rT &lt; 0- This is because for an eventually failed project, the realized
performance signals must be on average negative, i.e., 3 &lt; 0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e356a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e363" publication-type="other">
A subtle but relevant concern is whether our measure is capturing a VC investor's attitude toward risk or attitude
toward failure. Tolerance for risk is an investor's attitude ex ante toward uncertainties of investment outcomes,
while tolerance for failure reflects how an investor reacts ex post to a project's unfavorable outcome. Our measure
is more likely to capture a VC investor's tolerance for failure, rather than risk, for two reasons: First, the VC
industry is known as the high-risk-high-return industry. Therefore, VC investors are relatively homogeneous in
their attitude toward risk. Otherwise, they will not invest in the VC industry in the first place. Second, our VC
failure tolerance measure is computed on the basis of the VC investor's past failed investments. Therefore, how
long a VC firm waits before writing off the project reflects its ex post reaction to an unsuccessful outcome, rather
than its ex ante willingness to accept high uncertainty in the investment outcomes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e395a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e402" publication-type="other">
We choose 1980 as the beginning year of our sample period because of the regulatory shift in the U.S.
Department of Labor's clarification of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act's "prudent man" rule
in 1979. This Act allowed pension funds to invest in VC partnerships, leading to a large influx of capital to VC
funds and a significant change of VC investment activities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e418a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e425" publication-type="other">
For robustness, we have also classified a firm as a written-off firm if it does not receive any financing within a
five-year span after its very last financing round. The results are robust to this modification.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e435a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e442" publication-type="other">
We choose 1985 as the beginning year of our IPO sample so that we have a long enough time gap between the
beginning year of our VC sample (i.e., 1980), in which the Failure Tolerance measure is constructed, and the
beginning year of our IPO sample, in which the Failure Tolerance measure is utilized. By doing so, we minimize
the possibility that a VC-backed IPO firm has no Failure Tolerance information available.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e458a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e465" publication-type="other">
To avoid losing firm-year observations with zero patent or patent citation in the logarithmic transformation, we
add a small number (0.1) to the actual value when calculating the natural logarithm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e475a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e482" publication-type="other">
In untabulated regressions, we replace the lead VC failure tolerance with VC Syndicate Failure Tolerance, and
results continue to hold. We also replace separate industry and year fixed effects with industry-year fixed effects
to control for possible industry trends in innovation, and the results are robust to such modification.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e496a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e503" publication-type="other">
Since we examine equilibrium matching outcomes, the same analysis applies irrespective of whether VC
investors select projects or projects select VC investors. Thus, for expositional ease, when we discuss selection
ability, we describe it as selection by VC investors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e516a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e523" publication-type="other">
One possible concern is that our measure of failure tolerance captures a VC investor's overconfidence. An
overconfident VC investor thinks incorrectly that his projects are better than average and thus is unwilling to
terminate them despite the underperformance. Such overconfidence certainly leads to longer investment duration
in eventually failed projects. However, the ex post innovative outcome of a future successful project depends on
the true quality of the project, rather than the perceived quality by the overconfident VC investor. Thus, if a
lengthier investment duration in a failed project is driven by overconfidence, then there is no omitted variable
problem. In other words, we do not expect VC overconfidence to systematically predict high innovation outcome
in start-up firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e552a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e559" publication-type="other">
The average IPO exit rate in our sample could be higher than the averages in the entire VC sample. This is
because all the lead VC firms in our sample have had at least one IPO exit in the sample period. Thus, the least
successful VC firms are not in our sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e572a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e579" publication-type="other">
Hall, Jaffe, and Trajtenberg (2005) have six categories: chemicals, pharmaceutical drugs and medical instru-
mentation, computers and communications, electrical, metals and machinery, and miscellaneous. We group
chemicals with pharmaceutical drugs for two reasons: First, we only have a few observations of chemical
patents. Second, both the chemical patents and the pharmaceutical drug patents in our sample mainly come
from industries with three-digit SIC 283. Software programming patents (computer-related patents generated by
the three-digit SIC industry 737) belong to the computers and communications category. For finer comparisons
between different types of patents, we single out software programming. We then group patents related
to computer hardware, communications, and electrics together. Finally, we group metals, machinery, and
miscellaneous together because we do not have many observations of these patents and label this category as
miscellaneous patents.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e614a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e621" publication-type="other">
If a VC firm invests in multiple industries in a given year, we choose the industry in which the VC firm invests
the largest amount of capital in that year for the industry fixed effect. A VC firm may focus its resources in
different industries in different years. Therefore, the industry fixed effects are not subsumed when the VC fixed
effects are included.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e646a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e650" publication-type="other">
Acharya, v., and K. Subramanian. 2009. Bankruptcy Codes and Innovation. Review oj Financial Studies
22:4949-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e660a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e664" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V., R. Baghai, and K. Subramanian. 2009. Labor Laws and Innovation. Working Paper, New York
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e674a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e678" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Wrongful Discharge Laws and Innovation. Working Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e685a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e689" publication-type="other">
Adams, C., and V. Brantner. 2006. Estimating the Cost of New Drug Development: Is It Really 802 Million
Dollars? Health Aff (Millwood) 25:420-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e700a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e704" publication-type="other">
Aghion, P., J. Van Reenen, and L. Zingales. 2009. Innovation and Institutional Ownership. Working Paper,
Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e714a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e718" publication-type="other">
Armour, J., and D. Cumming. 2008. Bankruptcy Law and Entrepreneurship. American Law and Economics
Review 10:303-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e728a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e732" publication-type="other">
Atanassov, J., V. Nanda, and A. Seru. 2007. Finance and Innovation: The Case of Publicly Traded Firms.
Working Paper, University of Oregon.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e742a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e746" publication-type="other">
Azoulay, P., J. Graff Zivin, and G. Manso. 2011. Incentives and Creativity: Evidence from the Academic Life
Sciences. Rand Journal of Economics 42:527-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e756a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e760" publication-type="other">
Bayar, O., and T. Chemmanur. Forthcoming. IPOs versus Acquisitions and the Valuation Premium Puzzle: A
Theory of Exit Choice by Entrepreneurs and Venture Capitalists. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e770a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e774" publication-type="other">
Belenzon, S., and T. Berkovitz. 2010. Innovation in Business Groups. Management Science 56:519-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e786" publication-type="other">
Boot, A. 1992. Why Hang on to Losers? Divestitures and Takeovers. Journal of Finance 47:1401-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e793a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e797" publication-type="other">
Bottazzi, L., M. Da Rin, and T. Hellmann. 2008. Who Are the Active Investors? Evidence from Venture Capital.
Journal of Financial Economics 89:488-812.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e807a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e811" publication-type="other">
Brau, J., B. Francis, and N. Kohers. 2003. The Choice of IPO versus Takeover: Empirical Evidence. Journal of
Business 76:583-612.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e821a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e825" publication-type="other">
Chevalier, J., and G. Ellison. 1999. Career Concerns of Mutual Fund Managers. Quarterly Journal of Economics
114:389—432.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e835a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e839" publication-type="other">
Ederer, F., and G. Manso. 2010. Is Pay-for-performance Detrimental to Innovation? Working Paper, UCLA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e846a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e850" publication-type="other">
Fan, W., and M. White. 2003. Personal Bankruptcy and the Level of Entrepreneurial Activity. Journal of Law
and Economics 46:543-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e861a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e865" publication-type="other">
Fang, V., X. Tian, and S. Tice. 2011. Does Stock Liquidity Enhance or Impede Firm Innovation? Working Paper,
Rutgers University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e875a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e879" publication-type="other">
Goel, A., V. Nanda, and M. Narayanan. 2004. Career Concerns and Resource Allocation in Conglomerate.
Review of Financial Studies 17:99-128.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e889a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e893" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P. 1995. Optimal Investments, Monitoring, and the Staging of Venture Capital. Journal of Finance
50:1461-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e903a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e907" publication-type="other">
. 1996. Grandstanding in the Venture Capital Industry. Journal of Financial Economics 42:133-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e914a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e918" publication-type="other">
. 2007. Venture Capital. In E. Eckbo (ed.), The Handbook of Corporate Finance: Empirical Corporate
Finance. New York: Elsevier/North Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e928a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e932" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., A. Kovner, and J. Lerner. 2009. Specialization and Success: Evidence from Venture Capital.
Journal of Economics and Management Strategy 18:817-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e947" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., and J. Lerner. 1998. What Drives Venture Capital Fund-raising? Brookings Papers on Economic
Activity—Microeconomics, pp. 149-192.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e957a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e961" publication-type="other">
. 2000. Money Chasing Deals? The Impact of Fund Inflows on Private Equity Valuations. Journal of
Financial Economics 55:281-325.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e975" publication-type="other">
. 2004. The Venture Capital Cycle. 2nd ed. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e986" publication-type="other">
Griliches, Z., B. Hall, and A. Pakes. 1987. The Value of Patents as Indicators of Inventive Activity. In P.
Dasgupta and P. Stoneman (eds.), Economic Policy and Technological Performance. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e999a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1003" publication-type="other">
Hall, B., A. Jaffe, and M. Trajtenberg. 2001. The NBER Patent Citations Data File: Lessons, Insights, and
Methodological Tools. NBER Working Paper No. 8498.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1013a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1017" publication-type="other">
. 2005. Market Value and Patent Citations. Rand Journal of Economics 36:16-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1025a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1029" publication-type="other">
Hellmann, T., and M. Puri. 2000. The Interaction Between Product Market and Financing Strategy: The Role of
Venture Capital. Review of Financial Studies 13:959-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1039a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1043" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D. 1992. Reputation, Incentives, and Managerial Decisions. Entry. In P. Newman, M. Milgate, and
J. Eatwell (eds.), New Palgrave Dictionary of Money and Finance, pp. 332-37. New York: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1053a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1057" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Y., A. Ljungqvist, and Y. Lu. 2007. Whom You Know Matters: Venture Capital Networks and
Investment Performance. Journal of Finance 62:251-301.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1067a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1071" publication-type="other">
Holmstrom, B. 1989. Agency Costs and Innovation. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization 12:
305-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1081a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1085" publication-type="other">
Kortum, S., and J. Lerner. 2000. Assessing the Contribution of Venture Capital to Innovation. Rand Journal of
Economics 31:674-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1095a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1099" publication-type="other">
Lee, P., and S. Wahal. 2004. Grandstanding, Certification, and the Underpricing of Venture Capital Backed IPOs.
Journal of Financial Economics 73:375-407.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1110a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1114" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J. 1994. Venture Capital and the Decision to Go Public. Journal of Financial Economics 35:293-316.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1121a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1125" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J., M. Sorensen, and P. Stromberg. 2011. Private Equity and Long-run Investment: The Case of
Innovation. Journal of Finance 66:445-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1135a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1139" publication-type="other">
Manso, G. 2011. Motivating Innovation. Journal of Finance 66:1823-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1146a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1150" publication-type="other">
Nahata, R. 2008. Venture Capital Reputation and Investment Performance. Journal of Financial Economics
90:127-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1160a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1164" publication-type="other">
Puri, M., and R. Zarutskie. Forthcoming. On the Lifecycle Dynamics of Venture-capital- and Non-venture-
capital-financed Firms. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1174a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1178" publication-type="other">
Sahlman, W. 1990. The Structure and Governance of Venture Capital Organizations. Journal of Financial
Economics 27:473-521.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1189a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1193" publication-type="other">
Sahlman, W., and M. Gorman. 1989. What Do Venture Capitalists Do? Journal of Business Venturing 4:231—48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1200a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1204" publication-type="other">
Seru, A. Forthcoming. Do Conglomerates Stifle Innovation? Journal of Financial Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1215" publication-type="other">
Sorensen, M. 2007. How Smart Is Smart Money? A Two-sided Matching Model of Venture Capital. Journal of
Finance 62:2725-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1229" publication-type="other">
Tian, X. 2011. The Causes and Consequences of Venture Capital Stage Financing. Journal of Financial
Economics 101:132-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


