<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169016</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Life-Cycle Greenhouse Gas and Criteria Air Pollutant Emissions of Electric Vehicles in the United States</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cai</surname>
                  <given-names>Hao</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Elgowainy</surname>
                  <given-names>Amgad</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeongwoo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>July 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169008</issue-id>
         <fpage>325</fpage>
         <lpage>336</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169016"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>While electric vehicles including plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs) and battery-powered electric vehicles (BEVs) are considered as promising alternative vehicle/fuel systems to significantly reduce petroleum consumption of the transportation sector, it is important to analyze the emission characteristics and to assess the emission reduction potentials of electric vehicles so that their environmental impacts in terms of climate change, air quality, as well as human health effects could be better understood. To fulfill this objective, we explicitly analyzed the emission characteristics of greenhouse gases (GHG) and criteria air pollutants (CAP, representing VOC, CO, NOₓ, PM<sub>10</sub>and PM<sub>2.5</sub>, and SOₓ,) of the U.S. power sector, a pivotal upstream sector that impacts the life-cycle GHG and CAP emissions associated with electric vehicles. In particular, we established statistically robust probability distribution functions (PDFs) to address the uncertainty and variation in both thermal and environmental performances of various types of power plants that can result in uncertainties of the life-cycle GHG and CAP emissions of electric vehicles. With the detailed characterization of the GHG and CAP emissions from the power sector, we performed a life-cycle analysis (LCA) of the GHG and CAP emissions of electric vehicles in the United States, with the GREET (Greenhouse Gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy Use in Transportation) model developed at Argonne National Laboratory. The LCA results with the inherent uncertainties investigated illuminate the real-world chances of GHG and CAP emission reduction benefits that are influenced by uncertain factors when introducing electric vehicles to displace gasoline vehicles in the United States.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hawkins, T.R., Gausen, O.M., and Stromman, A.H., “Environmental impacts of hybrid and electric vehicles-A review,” Int. J. Life Cycle Ass. 17, 997-1014, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Q., DeLuchi, M.A. and Sperling, D., “Emission impacts of electric vehicles,” J. Air Waste Manag. Assoc. 40(9):1275-1284, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Q. and Deluchi, M.A., “Impacts of electric vehicles on primary energy consumption and petroleum displacement,” Energy 17, 351-366, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Q. and Santini, D., “Magnitude and value of electric vehicle emissions reductions for six driving cycles in four U.S. cities with varying air quality problems,” Argonne National Lab., Univ. of Chicago, U.S. Dept. of Energy, Chicago, Illinois, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lave, L., Hendrickson, C.T. and McMichael, F.C., “Environmental implications of electric cars,” Science 268:993-995, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Daniel, J.J. and Rosen, M.A., “Exergetic environmental assessment of life cycle emissions for various automobiles and fuels,” Exergy 2(4): 283-294, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kintner-Meyer, M., Schneider, K. and Pratt, R., “Impact Assessment of Plug-in Hybrid Vehicles on Electric Utilities and Regional U.S. Power Grids,” Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, http://www.ferc.gov/about/com-mem/wellinghoff/5-24-07-technical-analy-wellinghoff.pdf, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPRI (Electric Power Research Institute). “Environmental assessment of plug-in hybrid electric vehicles volume 1: Nationwide greenhouse gas emissions,” Palo Alto, 2011c.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elgowainy, A., Burnham, A., Wang, M., Molburg, J. and Roussau, A., “Well-to-wheel analyisi of energy use and greenhouse gas emissions analysis of plug-in hybrid electric vehicles”, Argonne National Lab., Univ. of Chicago, U.S. Dept. of Energy, Chicago, Illinois, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Samaras, C. and Meisterling, K., “Life cycle assessment of greenhouse gas emissions from plug-in hybrid vehicles: Implications for policy,” Environ. Sci. Technol. 42(9):3170-3176, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCleese, D.L. and LaPuma, P.T., “Using Monte Carlo simulation in life cycle assessment for electric and internal combustion vehicles,” Int. J. Life Cycle Ass. 7, 230-236, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, M., “GREET 1.5-Transportation Fuel-Cycle Model, Vol. 1: Methodology, Use, and Results,” Report No. ANL/ESD-39, Argonne National Laboratory, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA. “The Emissions &amp; Generation Resource Integrated Database (eGRID 2010 Version 1.1),” http://www.epa.gov/cleanenergy/energyresources/egrid, 2011a.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iglewicz, B. and Hoaglin, D, “Volume 16: How to Detect and Handle Outliers, in The ASQC Basic References in Quality Control: Statistical Techniques,” Mykytka E.F., Editor, ASQC Quality Press, Milwaukee, WI, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA. “The Internet Version of the Factor Information Retrieval Data System,” http://cfpub.epa.gov/webfire/index.cfm?action=fire.main., 2011b.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA. “2007 Annual, All Programs, Unit-Level Emission Database,” http://camddataandmaps.epa.gov/gdm/index.cfm? fuseaction=emissions.wizard, 2007a.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EIA (U.S. Energy Information Administration). “Form EIA-906, EIA-920, and EIA-923 Data,” 2007a.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA. “Emissions Factors &amp; AP 42, Compilation of Air Pollutant Emission Factors. Fifth Edition,” http://www.epa.gov/ttn/chief/ap42, 2011c.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA. “Locating &amp; Estimating (L&amp;E) Documents,” http://www.epa.gov/ttn/chief/le, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EIA. “Form FERC-423 Data, Monthly Cost and Quality of Fuels for Electric Plants Data,” 2007b.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FR (Federal Register). “Revisions to Definition of Cogeneration Unit in Clean Air Interstate Rule (CAIR), CAIR Federal Implementation Plans, Clean Air Mercury Rule (CAMR); and Technical Corrections to CAIR, CAIR FIPs, CAMR, and Acid Rain Program Rules,” 59190, Vol 72, No. 202, http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/FR-2007-10-19/pdf/E7-20447.pdf, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA. “Environmental Footprints and Costs of Coal-Based Integrated Gasification Combined Cycle and Pulverized Coal Technologies,” EPA-430/R-06/006, http://www.epa.gov/air/caaac/coaltech/2007_01_epaigcc.pdf, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Society of Automotive Engineers (SAE). “Utility Factor Definitions for Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles Using 2001 U.S. DOT National Household Travel Survey Data,” http://standards.sae.org/j2841_200903, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
