<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277697</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>High-Speed Characterization of ECN Spray A Using Various Diagnostic Techniques</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Meijer</surname>
                  <given-names>Maarten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eindhoven University Of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Galle</surname>
                  <given-names>Jonas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ghent University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Somers</surname>
                  <given-names>L.M.T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eindhoven University Of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Griensven</surname>
                  <given-names>J.G.H</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical University - Eindhoven</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Verhelst</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ghent University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1238</fpage>
         <lpage>1248</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277697"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Diesel spray experimentation at controlled high-temperature and high-pressure conditions is intended to provide a more fundamental understanding of diesel combustion than can be achieved in engine experiments. This level of understanding is needed to develop the high-fidelity multi-scale CFD models that will be used to optimize future engine designs.</p>
            <p>Several spray chamber facilities capable of high-temperature, high-pressure conditions typical of engine combustion have been developed, but because of the uniqueness of each facility, there are uncertainties about their operation. The Engine Combustion Network (ECN) is a worldwide group of institutions using combustion vessels, whose aim is to advance the state of spray and combustion knowledge at engine-relevant conditions. A key activity is the use of spray chamber facilities operated at specific target conditions in order to leverage research capabilities and advanced diagnostics of all ECN participants. The first target condition, called “Spray A”, has been defined with detailed ambient and injector conditions.</p>
            <p>For this paper, we describe results from the constant-volume pre-burn vessel at Eindhoven University of Technology. The executed measurements include a wide range of diagnostics to characterize “spray A” in reacting and non-reacting conditions in great detail. Observations of spray penetration, ignition, liquid length and flame lift-off location by using several high-speed imaging diagnostics are discussed and compared with other ECN participating institutes.</p>
            <p>Comparison Spray A data from the other participating institutes, as it was presented during the 2<sup>nd</sup>ECN workshop is gathered from the ECN website database [1]. It can be concluded that the obtained results from the standardized ECN spray diagnostics, show satisfactory similarity, despite of the challenge to reach similar boundary conditions (ambient and injector) in each of the unique facilities. The differences in results are within the measurement deviation and uncertainty or can be explained by the usage of (slightly) different injectors. Combining the results of the different measurement techniques provides an overall (time resolved) overview where the different phases of fuel injection are directly linked and summarized. The presented overview provides a direct input for (CFD) modeling validation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network data archive for diesel spray combustion. http://www.sandia.gov/ECN/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meijer M. et al., Engine Combustion Network (ECN): Characterization and Comparison of Boundary Conditions for Different Combustion Vessels. Atomization and Spray 6083 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baert, R., Frijters, P., Somers, B., Luijten, C. et al., “Design and Operation of a High Pressure, High Temperature Cell for HD Diesel Spray Diagnostics: Guidelines and Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0649, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0649.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meijer M., Christians R.J., Griensven J.G.H. v., Somers L.M.T., de Goey L.P.H.. Engine Combustion Network: implementation and analysis of combustion vessel spray A conditions, Illass-Americas NA 23rd conference, paper 151. 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., and Idicheria, C., “Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Genzale, C., Bruneaux, G., Malbec, L. et al., “Comparison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High-Temperature, High-Pressure Facilities,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):156-181, 2010, doi: a10.4271/2010-01-2106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meijer M., Malbec L-M., Bruneaux G., Somers L.M.T.. Engine Combustion Network: “Spray A” basic measurements and advanced diagnostics. Iclass 2012 paper 1260.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., Siebers, D., and Aradi, A., “Diesel-Spray Ignition and Premixed-Burn Behavior,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0940, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lillo, P., Pickett, L., Persson, H., Andersson, O. et al., “Diesel Spray Ignition Detection and Spatial/Temporal Correction,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1330-1346, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri R., Salvador F.J., Gimeno J., de la Morena J., “Effects of nozzle geometry on direct injection diesel engine combustion process”, Applied Thermal Engineering 29, 10(2009)2051-2060.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. and Siebers, D., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu L., Lu C., Yi Xu, Jia J., “Image smoothing via L0 gradient minimization”, ACM Transactions on Graphics, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes J.M., Pastor J.V., Garcia-Oliver J.M., Pastor, “A 1D model for the description of mixing-controlled reacting diesel sprays”, Combustion and Flame 156 (2009);234-249</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. and Siebers, D., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manin J., Bardi M. and Pickett L.M.. Evaluation of the liquid length via diffused back-illumination imaging in vaporizing diesel sprays. The eighth international conference for modeling and diagnostics for advanced engine systems (COMODIA 2012), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
