<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816623</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Psychology and the Demand for Redistribution (Behavioral)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Invisible inequality leads to punishing the poor and rewarding the rich</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hauser</surname>
                  <given-names>Oliver P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kraft-Todd</surname>
                  <given-names>Gordon T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rand</surname>
                  <given-names>David G.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nowak</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Norton</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael I.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>21</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816623"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>How does lack of awareness of income inequality affect behaviour towards the rich and poor? To address this question, we assigned participants either at random or based on merit to one of five income levels (reflective of the U.S. income distribution), who then played a repeated public goods game with punishment, reward or both. When participants did not know the income distribution, they punished the poor and rewarded the rich. When incomes were known, conversely, participants punished the rich and rewarded the poor What explains this reversal? When incomes were hidden, participants punished those who gave the least in absolute amounts (the poor) and rewarded those who gave the most in absolute amounts (the rich). When incomes were revealed, however, participants were sensitive to people’s ability to contribute: they punished those who contributed the smallest <italic>percentage</italic> of their income (the rich) and rewarded those who contributed the highest <italic>percentage</italic> (the poor). Moreover, revealing incomes led to greater overall contributions to the public good, suggesting that awareness of inequality may offer societal benefits.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abeler, J., Falk, A., Goette, L., &amp; Huffman, D. (2011). Reference Points and Effort Provision. American Economic Review, 101(2), 470-492. http://doi.org/10.2307/29783680</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alesina, A., &amp; Angeletos, G.-M. (2005). Fairness and redistribution, 151(3712), 867-868. http://doi.org/10.2307/4132701</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Ambrus, A., &amp; Ben Greiner. (2012). Imperfect Public Monitoring with Costly Punishment: An Experimental Study. American Economic Review, 102(7), 3317-3332. http://doi.org/10.1257/aer.102.7.3317</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Antinyan, A., Corazzini, L., &amp; Neururer, D. (2015). Public good provision, punishment, and the endowment origin: Experimental evidence. Journal of Behavioral and ….</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bolton, G. E., &amp; Ockenfels, A. (2000). A Theory of Equity, Reciprocity, and Competition. American Economic Review, 90(1), 166-193. http://doi.org/10.2307/117286</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bornstein, G., &amp; Weisel, O. (2010). Punishment, Cooperation, and Cheater Detection in ``Noisy“” Social Exchange. Games, 1, 18-33. http://doi.org/10.3390/g1010018</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Buckley, E., &amp; Croson, R. (2006). Income and wealth heterogeneity in the voluntary provision of linear public goods. Journal of Public Economics, 90(4-5), 935-955. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpubeco.2005.06.002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Cappelen, A. W., Hole, A. A. D., Sørensen, E. Ø., &amp; Tungodden, B. (2007). The Pluralism of Fairness Ideals: An Experimental Approach. American Economic Review, 97(3), 818-827.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Cappelen, A. W., Konow, J., Sørensen, E. Ø., &amp; Tungodden, B. (2013). Just Luck: An Experimental Study of Risk-Taking and Fairness. American Economic Review, 103(4), 1398-1413. http://doi.org/10.1257/aer.103.4.1398</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Charité, J., Fisman, R., &amp; Kuziemko, I. (2015). Reference points and demand for redistribution: Experimental evidence. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Charness, G., &amp; Rabin, M. (2002). Understanding social preferences with simple tests. Quarterly Journal of Economics. http://doi.org/10.2307/4132490</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Congressional Budget Office. (2007). Average Federal Tax Rates. Retrieved from http://www.cbo.gov/publication/42870</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Cruces, G., Perez-Truglia, R., &amp; Tetaz, M. (2013). Biased perceptions of income distribution and preferences for redistribution: Evidence from a survey experiment. Journal of Public Economics, 98, 100-112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Davidai, S., &amp; Gilovich, T. (2015). Building a More Mobile America-One Income Quintile at a Time. Perspectives on Psychological Science, 10(1), 60-71. http://doi.org/10.1177/1745691614562005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Durante, R., Putterman, L., &amp; van der Weele, J. (2014). Preferences for Redistribution and Perception of Fairness: An experimental study. Journal of the European Economic Association, 12(4), 1059-1086. http://doi.org/10.1111/jeea.12082</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Fehr, E., &amp; Gächter, S. (2002). Altruistic punishment in humans. Nature, 415(6868), 137-140. http://doi.org/10.1038/415137a</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Fehr, E., &amp; Schmidt, K. M. (1999). A Theory of Fairness, Competition, and Cooperation. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 114(3), 817-868. http://doi.org/10.1162/003355399556151</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gächter, S., Mengel, F., Tsakas, E., &amp; Vostroknutov, A. (2014). Growth and Inequality in Public Good Games. Working Paper. http://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2351717</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Hauser, O. P., Hendriks, A., Rand, D. G., &amp; Nowak, M. A. (2016). Preserving the global commons. Available on SSRN. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2722407</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Herrmann, B., Thöni, C., &amp; Gächter, S. (2008). Antisocial Punishment Across Societies. Science, 319(5868), 1362-1367. http://doi.org/10.1126/science.1153808</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Isaac, R. M., &amp; Walker, J. M. (1988). Communication and free-riding behavior: The voluntary contribution mechanism. Economic Inquiry, 26(4).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Keser, C., Markstädter, A., &amp; Schmidt, M. (2014a). Mandatory Minimum Contributions, Heterogenous Endowments and Voluntary Public-Good Provision. Working Paper. http://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2539601</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Keser, C., Markstädter, A., Schmidt, M., &amp; Schnitzler, C. (2014b). Social cost of inequality - Heterogeneous endowments in public-good experiments. Working Paper, 1-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Kiatpongsan, S., &amp; Norton, M. I. (2014). How Much (More) Should CEOs Make? A Universal Desire for More Equal Pay. Perspectives on Psychological Science, 9(6), 587-593. http://doi.org/10.1177/1745691614549773</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Konow, J. (2000). Fair shares: Accountability and cognitive dissonance in allocation decisions. The American Economic Review, 90(4), 1072-1091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Kraus, M. W., Piff, P. K., &amp; Keltner, D. (2009). Social class, sense of control, and social explanation. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 97(6), 992-1004. http://doi.org/10.1037/a0016357</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Kuziemko, I., Norton, M. I., Saez, E., &amp; Stantcheva, S. (2015). How Elastic Are Preferences for Redistribution? Evidence from Randomized Survey Experiments. American Economic Review, 105(4), 1478-1508. Retrieved from http://www.nber.org/papers/w18865</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Lago-Peñas, I., &amp; Lago-Peñas, S. (2010). The determinants of tax morale in comparative perspective: Evidence from European countries. European Journal of Political Economy, 26(4), 441-453. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejpoleco.2010.06.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Nikiforakis, N., Noussair, C. N., &amp; Wilkening, T. (2012). Normative conflict and feuds: The limits of self-enforcement. Journal of Public Economics, 96(9-10), 797-807. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpubeco.2012.05.014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Nishi, A., Shirado, H., Rand, D. G., &amp; Christakis, N. A. (2015). Inequality and visibility of wealth in experimental social networks. Nature, 1-14. http://doi.org/10.1038/nature15392</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Norton, M. I., &amp; Ariely, D. (2011). Building a Better America-One Wealth Quintile at a Time. Perspectives on Psychological Science, 6(1), 9-12. http://doi.org/10.1177/1745691610393524</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Norwegian Tax Administration. (2015). Norway Income Database. Retrieved from http://www.skatteetaten.no/nn/Person/Skatteoppgjer/Sok-i-skattelistene/Hva-star-i-skattelistene/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Piff, P. K., Kraus, M. W., Côté, S., Cheng, B. H., &amp; Keltner, D. (2010). Having less, giving more: The influence of social class on prosocial behavior. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 99(5), 771-784. http://doi.org/10.1037/a0020092</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Rand, D. G., Dreber, A., Ellingsen, T., Fudenberg, D., &amp; Nowak, M. A. (2009). Positive interactions promote public cooperation. Science, 325, 1272-1275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Rawls, J. (1971). A theory of justice. Belknap.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Reuben, E., &amp; Riedl, A. (2013). Enforcement of contribution norms in public good games with heterogeneous populations. Games and Economic Behavior, 77(1), 122-137. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.geb.2012.10.001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Sefton, M., Shupp, R., &amp; Walker, J. M. (2007). The effect of rewards and sanctions in provision of public goods. Economic Inquiry, 45(4), 671-690. http://doi.org/10.1111/j.1465-7295.2007.00051.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Sidanius, J., &amp; Pratto, F. (2001). Social dominance: An intergroup theory of social hierarchy and oppression. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Sutter, M., Haigner, S., &amp; Kocher, M. G. (2010). Choosing the Carrot or the Stick? Endogenous Institutional Choice in Social Dilemma Situations. Review of Economic Studies, 77(4), 1540-1566. http://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-937X.2010.00608.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">U.S. Census Bureau. (2013). Income and Poverty in the United States. Retrieved from http://www.census.gov/hhes/www/income/data/incpovhlth/2013/table4.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">van Kleef, G. A., Oveis, C., van der Löwe, I., LuoKogan, A., Goetz, J., &amp; Keltner, D. (2008). Power, distress, and compassion turning a blind eye to the suffering of others. Psychological Science, 19(12), 1315-1322.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>The income distribution in our game and the main experimental manipulation between the hidden and revealed conditions. A Each player in a group of five was randomly assigned to a position in an income distribution. In the first experiment, we used the 2007 U.S. pre-tax income distribution (Congressional Budget Office, 2007): in each of ten rounds, the top quintile participant received 55 units, while the bottom quintile player received 4 units. B When making decisions to punish and reward, participants in the hidden condition saw their own income and the sum of all incomes. C In the revealed condition, participants viewed all players’ incomes.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Amount of received reward (top panels) and punishment (bottom panels) depends on income quintile and whether income was hidden (left panels) or revealed (right panels). A Participants rewarded higher income participants more in the hidden condition, but B less in the revealed condition. C Punishment behaviour is a mirror image of reward: participants punished poorer participants more in the hidden condition, while D punishing richer participants more in the revealed condition.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Who contributes more? A In the hidden condition, only absolute contributions could be assessed, such that richer participants appeared to contribute more. B In the revealed condition, where participants could view contributions relative to income, it was clear that lower income participants contributed a larger fraction of their income.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Received punishment and reward depends on percentage of income contributed in the revealed condition (top panels) and on absolute income contributed in the hidden condition (bottom panels). A,B When incomes were revealed, participants who contributed a higher percentage of their income were A punished less and B rewarded more. C,D Conversely, when incomes were hidden, participants who contributed a higher absolute amount were C punished less and D rewarded more. Bubble size is proportional to the fraction of corresponding participants.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
