<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285073</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis of NOx Emissions during Crank-Start and Cold Fast-Idle in a GDI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rodriguez</surname>
                  <given-names>J. Felipe</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Cheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Wai K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>646</fpage>
         <lpage>655</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285073"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The NOx emissions during the crank-start and cold fast-idle phases of a GDI engine are analyzed in detail. The NOx emissions of the first 3 firing cycles are studied under a wide set of parameters including the mass of fuel injected, start of injection, and ignition timing. The results show a strong dependence of the NOx emissions with injection timing; they are significantly reduced as the mixture is stratified. The impact of different valve timings on crank-start NOx emissions was analyzed. Late intake and early exhaust timings show similar potential for NOx reduction; 26-30% lower than the baseline. The combined strategy, resulting in a large symmetric negative valve overlap, shows the greatest reduction; 59% lower than the baseline. The cold fast-idle NOx emissions were studied under different equivalence ratios, injection strategies, combustion phasing, and valve timings. Slightly lean air-fuel mixtures result in a significant reduction of NOx. The engine-out emissions are highly sensitivity to combustion phasing. Initial retard results in lower mass NOx emissions up to CA50 around 40 °CA aTDC-compression. After this point the increase in fuel consumption and the reduction on residual fraction reverse the trend leading to an increase in NOx mass emissions for later combustion phasing. Moderate exhaust timing advance is beneficial for NOx emissions and has no impact on the exhaust enthalpy flow.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davis, Stacy, Williams Susan, Boundy Ridge, and Moore Sheila. “Vehicle Technologies Market Report 2015.”Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ball, D., Negohosian, C., Ross, D., Moser, D. ., "Comparison of Cold Start Calibrations, Vehicle Hardware and Catalyst Architecture of 4-Cylinder Turbocharged Vehicles," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(4):1922– 1933, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2593.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Myung, Cha-Lee, Juwon Kim, Wonwook Jang, Dongyoung Jin, Simsoo Park, and Lee Jeongmin. “Nanoparticle Filtration Characteristics of Advanced Metal Foam Media for a Spark Ignition Direct Injection Engine in Steady Engine Operating Conditions and Vehicle Test Modes.” Energies 8, no. 3 (March 9, 2015): 1865–81. doi:10.3390/en8031865.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez, J. and Cheng, W. “Cycle-by-Cycle Analysis of Cold Crank- Start in a GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. of Engines 9(2):1210-1219, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0824.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez, J. and Cheng, W. “Reduction of Cold-Start Emissions through Valve Timing in a GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. of Engines 9(2):1220-1229, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0827.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez, J. and Cheng, W., “Effect of Operation Strategy on First Cycle CO, HC, and PM/PN Emissions in a GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):1098–1106, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Felipe Rodriguez, J., and Cheng Wai K. “Fuel Carbon Pathway in the First Cranking Cycle of a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine.” International Journal of Engine Research, October 5, 2015. doi:10.1177/1468087415609852.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cedrone, K. and Cheng, W., "Using Valve Timing and Exhaust Back Pressure to Improve Catalyst Warm-Up Time," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2656, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2656.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cedrone, K. and Cheng, W., "SI Engine Control in the Cold-Fast-Idle Period for Low HC Emissions and Fast Catalyst Light Off," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):968–976, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ketterer, J. and Cheng, W., "On the Nature of Particulate Emissions from DISI Engines at Cold-Fast-Idle," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):986–994, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burke, D., Foti, D., Haller, J., and Fedor, W., "Fuel Rail Pressure Rise during Cold Start of a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0393, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0393.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tang, H., Burke, R., Akehurst, S., Brace, C. ., "Behaviours of a GDI Gasoline Engine during Start," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1374, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, John B. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. New York: M/cGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
