<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26745564</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reduction of Cyclic Variations by Using Advanced Ignition Systems in a Lean-Burn Stationary Natural Gas Engine Operating at 10 Bar BMEP and 1800 rpm</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Almansour</surname>
                  <given-names>Bader</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vasu</surname>
                  <given-names>Subith</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gupta</surname>
                  <given-names>Sreenath</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26745559</issue-id>
         <fpage>57</fpage>
         <lpage>68</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26745564"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In stationary natural gas engines, lean-burn combustion offers higher engine efficiencies with simultaneous compliance with emission regulations. A prominent problem that one encounters with lean operation is cyclic variations. Advanced ignition systems offer a potential solution as they suppress cyclic variations in addition to extending the lean ignition limit. In this article, the performance of three ignition systems-conventional spark ignition (SI), single-point laser ignition (LI), and prechamber equipped laser ignition (PCLI)-in a single-cylinder natural gas engine is presented.</p>
            <p>First, a thorough discussion regarding the efficacy of several metrics, besides coefficient of variation of indicated mean effective pressure (COV_IMEP), in representing combustion instability is presented. This is followed by a discussion about the performance of the three ignition systems at a single operational condition, that is, same excess air ratio (λ) and ignition timing (IT). Next, these metrics are compared at the most optimal operational points for each ignition system, that is, at points where λ and IT are optimized to achieve highest efficiency.</p>
            <p>From these observations, it is noted that PCLI achieves the highest increase in engine efficiency, Δη = 2.1% points, and outperforms the other two methods of ignition. A closer look reveals that the coefficient of variation in ignition delay (COV_ID) was negligible, whereas that in coefficient of variation in combustion duration (COV_CD) was significantly lower by 2.2% points. However, the metrics COV_ID and COV_CD are not well correlated with COV_IMEP.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">McMillian, M. H., Woodruff, S. D., Richardson, S. W., and McIntyre, D. L. “Laser Spark Ignition: Laser Development and Engine Testing,” Fall Technical Conference of the ASME ICE Division, Long Beach, California, USA, Vol. ICEF2004-917, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Dale, J.D., Checkel, M., and Smy, P., “Application of High Energy Ignition Systems to Engines,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 23(5):379-398, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Sjöberg, M., Zeng, W., Singleton, D., Sanders, J.M. et al., “Combined Effects of Multi-Pulse Transient Plasma Ignition and Intake Heating on Lean Limits of Well-Mixed E85 DISI Engine Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(4):1781-1801, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Gao, H., Matthews, R.D., Hall, M.J., and Hari, S., “From Spark Plugs to Railplugs-The Characteristics of a New Ignition System,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2978, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Gupta, S.B., Biruduganti, M., Bihari, B., and Sekar, R., “Natural Gas Fired Reciprocating Engines for Power Generation: Concerns and Recent Advances,” Natural Gas-Extraction to End Use. Intech, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Toulson, E., Huisjen, A., Chen, X., Squibb, C. et al., “Visualization of Propane and Natural Gas Spark Ignition and Turbulent Jet Ignition Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(4):1821-1835, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-32-0002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Morsy, M.H., “Review and Recent Developments of Laser Ignition for Internal Combustion Engines Applications,” Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 16:4849-4875, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Kalghatgi, G.T., “Spark Ignition, Early Flame Development and Cyclic Variation in IC Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 870163, 1987, doi:10.4271/870163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Ozdor, N., Dulger, M., and Sher, E., “Cyclic Variability in Spark Ignition Engines a Literature Survey,” SAE Technical Paper 940987, 1994, doi:10.4271/940987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Reyes, M., Tinaut, F., Giménez, B., and Pérez, A., “Characterization of Cycle-to-Cycle Variations in a Natural Gas Spark Ignition Engine,” Fuel 140:752-761, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Saito, H., Sakurai, T., Sakonji, T., Hirashima, T. et al., “Study on Lean Burn Gas Engine Using Pilot Oil as the Ignition Source,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0143, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Richardson, S., McMillian, M.H., Woodruff, S.D., and McIntyre, D., “Misfire, Knock and NOx Mapping of a Laser Spark Ignited Single Cylinder Lean Burn Natural Gas Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1853, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1853.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Almansour, B., Vasu, S., Gupta, S.B., Wang, Q. et al., “Performance of a Laser Ignited Multicylinder Lean Burn Natural Gas Engine,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 139(11):111501, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Almansour, B., Vasu, S., Gupta, S.B., Wang, Q. et al., “Prechamber Equipped Laser Ignition for Improved Performance in Natural Gas Engines,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 139(10):101501, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Zhu, G.G., Daniels, C.F., and Winkelman, J., “MBT Timing Detection and its Closed-Loop Control Using in-Cylinder Pressure Signal,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3266, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Bradley, D., Sheppard, C., Suardjaja, I., and Woolley, R., “Fundamentals of High-Energy Spark Ignition with Lasers,” Combustion and Flame 138(1):55-77, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Endo, T., Takenaka, Y., Sako, Y., Johzaki, T. et al., “An Experimental Study on the Ignition Ability of a Laser-Induced Gaseous Breakdown,” Combustion and Flame 178:1-6, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Ghorbani, A., Steinhilber, G., Markus, D., and Maas, U., “Ignition by Transient Hot Turbulent Jets: An Investigation of Ignition Mechanisms by Means of a PDF/REDIM Method,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 35(2):2191-2198, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Single-cylinder engine specification (RSi-130Q).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Schematic of the engine test setup.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Ignition geometries that were tested: (a) SI, (b) single-point LI, and (c) PCLI.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Prominent ignition and combustion metrics.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Pressure traces averaged over 500 cycles for IT = 19 CA BTDC and several air-to-fuel ratios.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Combustion parameters for the three air-fuel ratios, IT 19 CA BTDC using SI system.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>COV_IMEP and BSNOx variation with ignition timing.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>COV for SI system.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Cyclic variation of IMEP and A_PP at two ignition timings and λ = 1.58 for SI and LI.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Instability metrics at λ = 1.58 for SI and LI.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Acceleration of heat release with laser ignition at λ = 1.65 and several ignition timings.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Combustion characteristics for the three ignition systems at their optimal operational conditions.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Instability metrics of PCLI system at IT = 15 CA BTDC and several λ.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Ignition delay and combustion duration cyclic variation at IT = 17 CA BTDC and λ = 1.58.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Cyclic variation metrics at optimal operating points for each ignition system.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Statistical parameters at various ignition timings and systems.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Distribution of IMEP, PP, and A_PP at the optimal points of operation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Distribution of MFB50% and statistical parameters at several operating conditions.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
