<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277518</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of a 3rd Generation SCR NH₃-Direct Dosing System for Highly Efficient DeNOx</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gerhart</surname>
                  <given-names>Christian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AlzChem Trostberg GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Krimmer</surname>
                  <given-names>Hans-Peter</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AlzChem Trostberg GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hammer</surname>
                  <given-names>Benedikt</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AlzChem Trostberg GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schulz</surname>
                  <given-names>Bernd</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>NIGU Chemie Waldkraiburg</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kröcher</surname>
                  <given-names>Oliver</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Paul Scherrer Institut</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Peitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Paul Scherrer Institut</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sattelmayer</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical University Munich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Toshev</surname>
                  <given-names>Plamen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical University Munich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wachtmeister</surname>
                  <given-names>Georg</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical University Munich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Heubuch</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical University Munich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jacob</surname>
                  <given-names>Eberhard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Emissionskonzepte</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>938</fpage>
         <lpage>946</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277518"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In this project funded by the Bayerische Forschungsstiftung two fundamental investigations had been carried out: first a new N-rich liquid ammonia precursor solution based on guanidine salts had been completely characterized and secondly a new type of side-flow reactor for the controlled catalytic decomposition of aqueous NH₃ precursor to ammonia gas has been designed, applied and tested in a 3 liter passenger car diesel engine.</p>
            <p>Guanidine salts came into the focus due to the fact of a high nitrogen-content derivate of urea (figure 1). Specially guanidinium formate has shown extraordinary solubility in water (more than 6 kg per 1 liter water at room temperature) and therefore a possible high ammonia potential per liter solution compared to the classical 32.5% aqueous urea solution (AUS32) standardized in ISO 22241 and known as DEF (diesel emission fluid), ARLA32 or AdBlue®. Additionally a guanidine based formulation could be realized with high freezing stability down to almost −30 °C (−11 °C for AUS32). The decomposition of this new precursor to ammonia NH₃ could be realized on a gold doped TiO₂ catalyst completely without any critical side products at temperatures above 240 °C.</p>
            <p>Due to the fact of temperatures above 240 °C required for the complete residue-free decomposition to ammonia gas, a side flow reactor concept has been developed for controlled decomposition of the precursor solution. In addition, this reactor concept could be operated with various liquid ammonia precursor such as AUS32 or aqueous guanidinium formate. In this heated catalytic reactor the decomposition is realized under controlled conditions independent of the main exhaust flow and operation conditions of the engine. NH₃-gas is produced in real-time and directly dosed to the main exhaust flow without any buffer. With a venturi nozzle setup the homogeneous mixing of the NH₃-gas into the exhaust flow is realized. Measurements in steady state and transient cycles show an up to 60 % more efficient NOx reduction (DeNOx) on a standard SCR catalyst in comparison to a classical urea to exhaust dosing system. Specially for exhaust conditions below 200 °C much higher efficiencies could be achieved by direct NH₃-gas dosing than with liquid AUS32 dosing.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacob, E. Perspektiven der mobilen SCR-Technik. 15. Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik 2006, Vol. 2, pp. 1303-1336, October 9-11, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kröcher, O., Elsener, M., Jacob, E.. New reducing agents for the low- NOx SCR technology, 5th International Exhaust Gas and Particulate Emissions Forum 19-20 February 2008, Ludwigsburg (Germany).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kröcher, O., Elsener, M., Jacob, E., A model gas study of ammonium formate, methanamide and guanidinium formate as alternative ammonia precursor compounds for the selective catalytic reduction of nitrogen oxides in diesel exhaust gas, Appl. Catal. B 88 (2009) 66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peitz, D., Bernhard, A., Elsener, M., Kröcher, O. (2011) Rev. Sci. Inst., 82, 084101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peitz, D., Kröcher, O., Elsener, M., Toshev, P., Sattelmayer, Th., Heubuch, A., Wachtmeister, G., Schulz, B., Gerhart, C., Krimmer, H.- P., Jacob, E., Catalytic decomposition of guanidinium formate for onboard ammonia gas production, independent of engine operation. Proc. of 9. FAD Konferenz “Herausforderung Abgasnachbehandlung für Dieselmotoren” 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devadas, M., Kröcher, O., Wokaun, A. (2005) React. Kinet. Catal. Lett., 86, 347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kröcher, O., Aspects of catalyst development for mobile urea-SCR systems - from vanadia-titania catalysts to metal-exchanged zeolites, Stud. Surf. Sci. Catal. 171 (2007) 261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsubota, S., Haruta, M., Kobayashi, T., Ueda, A., Nakahara, Y. (1991) In Preparation of Catalysts V; Poncelet, G., Jacobs, P.A., Grange, P., Delmon, B., Eds.; Elsevier Sci-ence B.V.: Amsterdam, pp. 695-704.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lignier, P., Morfin, F.. Piccolo, L., Rousset, J.-L., Caps, V. (2007) Catal. Today, 122, 284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Todorova, T., Kröcher, O., Delley, B.. DFT study of structural and vibrational properties of guanidinium derivatives. Journal of Molecular Structure: Theochem, Vol. 907, Iss. 1-3, pp. 16-21, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Todorova, T., Peitz, D., Kröcher, O., Wokaun, A., Delley, B. (2011) J. Phys. Chem. C 115, 1195-1203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grünwald, J. D. Verbesserung der Reduktionsmitteldispersion und-verdun- stung in SCR-Abgasanlagen. Phd 2007, Lehrstuhl Thermodynamik, TU-München.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bettoni, F., Untersuchungen zum stationären und dynamischen Verhalten eines Entstickungssystems nach dem SCR-Prinzip mit realem Dieselabgas, Dissertation ETH Nr. 12443, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toshev, P., Sattelmayer, Th., Jacob, E., Gerhart, C., Reactor for the Conversion of Aqueous Guanidinium Formate (GuFo) to Ammonia, Proc. of 3rd Conference “MinNOx - Minimization of NOx-Emissions Through Exhaust Aftertreatment”, IAV, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gerhart, C., Krimmer, H.-P., Schulz, B., Kröcher, O., Peitz, D., Sattelmayer, Th., Toshev, P., Heubuch, A., Wachtmeister, G. (2010) CIMAC Paper No. 242, CIMAC Con-gress 2010, Bergen, Norway, June 14-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krämer, L. Assessment of 3rd Generation SCR Systems for Potential Future Applications. Proc. of 2nd Conference “MinNOx - Minimization of NOx-Emissions Through Exhaust Aftertreatment”, IAV, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hupfeld, B., Steiger, W., Stolte, U.M., Gottschling, M., Weißels, S.. The vision of a decoupled Emission Technology. Proc. of 7. FAD Konferenz “Herausforderung Abgasnachbehandlung für Dieselmotoren” 2009, pp. 117-130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
