<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186387</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44434046</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Supercharged Engine Performance, Calculated and Actual</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Opie</given-names>
                  <surname>Chenoweth</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1927</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>256</fpage>
         <lpage>268</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44434046"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>A method of predicting the power output of a given aircraft engine equipped with a direct gear-driven centrifugal supercharger is outlined. The calculations are based on the fundamental assumptions common to internal-combustion engineering. Three superchargers of different ratings are considered for the purpose of selecting the one giving the best all-round performance. Con-siderations of weight, compactness, mechanical reliability, simplicity and general arrangement enter into the selection of the best all-round rating. The effect of superchargers of various ratings on engine power-output, as well as the effect of various factors on engine performance, is shown by curves. Tests of a supercharged Curtiss D-12 engine were conducted in the altitude chamber of the Bureau of Standards and the results of this test were compared with the calculated results obtained by the method outlined. Conclusions reached are that, for all-round performance to a definite altitude, an intermediate supercharger rating should be selected, and that the performance of engines equipped with direct-driven centrifugal superchargers can be predicted with a fair degree of accuracy by the methods outlined.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


