<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26926852</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Global Sensitivity Analysis Approach for Engine Friction Modeling</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Krecker</surname>
                  <given-names>Oleg</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hiltner</surname>
                  <given-names>Christoph</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26926847</issue-id>
         <fpage>543</fpage>
         <lpage>566</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26926852"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Mechanical friction simulations offer a valuable tool in the development of internal combustion engines for the evaluation of optimization studies in terms of time efficiency. However, system modeling and evaluation of model performance may be highly complex. A high number of interacting submodels and parameters as well as a limited model transparency contribute to uncertainties in the modeling process. In particular, model calibration and validation are complicated by the unknown effect of parameters on the model output. This article presents an advanced and model-independent methodology for identifying sensitive parameters of engine friction. This allows the user to investigate an unlimited number of parameters of a model whose structure and properties are prior unknown. In contrast to widely used parameter studies, in which only one parameter is varied at a time, the use of the elementary effect method enables the consideration of interactions in the entire parameter space. Based on a sensitivity analysis (SA), the methodology offers a comprehensive and practicable approach to improve model performance and effectiveness of predictive optimization studies. The methodology is validated utilizing an exemplary friction model of a modern inlet valve train, and its further details are described in the form of a practicable guideline. The multifunctional application of the methodology (<italic>parameter prioritization, model calibration</italic>, and <italic>friction optimization</italic>) is also outlined. Especially the process of calibration is shown in the example of a complementary subsystem, the exhaust valve train model. Hereby, the advantages of the methodology are presented regarding the improvement of model and measurement correlation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Landerl, C., Spanring, D., Rülicke, M., Durst, B. et al., “The New 3-and 4-Cylinder Gasoline Engines of BMW Group - Modular Engine Family NEXT GENERATION,” in 26th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology, 2017, 35-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Krecker, O. and Huber, B., “Modellierungsansatz zur Abbildung gesamtmotorischer Reibungsverluste,” in 7. ATZFachtagung Tribologie - Reibung in Antrieb und Fahrzeug, 2018, 21-46, doi:10.1007/978-3-658-25302-8_2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Saltelli, A., Gatelli, D., Campolongo, F., Cariboni, J. et al., Global Sensitivity Analysis. The Primer (John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd, 2008), doi:10.1002/9780470725184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Schwieger V., “Nicht-lineare Sensitivitätsanalyse gezeigt an Beispielen zu bewegten Objekten,” Habilitationsschrift, Universität Stuttgart, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Saltelli, A., Tarantola, S., Campolongo, F., and Ratto, M., Sensitivity Analysis in Practice (John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd, 2004), doi:10.1002/0470870958.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Pianosi, F., Bevenf, K., Freerc, J., Halld, J.W. et al., “Sensitivity Analysis of Environmental Models: A Systematic Review with Practical Workflow,” Environmental Modelling and Software 79:214-232, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.envsoft.2016.02.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Campolongo, F., Saltelli, A., and Cariboni, J., “From Screening to Quantitative Sensitivity Analysis. A Unified Approach,” Computer Physics Communications 182(4):978-988, Apr. 2011, doi:10.1016/J.CPC.2010.12.039.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Specka X., “Analyse und Parametrisierung eines komplexen Agrarökosystemmodells für Fragestellungen der ökologischen Folgeabschätzung des Energiepflanzenanbaus,” Dissertation, Brandenburgische Technische Universität Cottbus-Senftenberg, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Iooss, B. and Lemaître, P., “A Review on Global Sensitivity Analysis Methods,” Operations Research/Computer Science Interfaces Series 59:101-122, 2015, doi:10.1007/978-1-4899-7547-8_5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Campolongo, F., Cariboni, J., and Saltelli, A., “An Effective Screening Design for Sensitivity Analysis of Large Models,” Environmental Modelling &amp; Software 22(10):1509-1518, Oct. 2007, doi:10.1016/J.ENVSOFT.2006.10.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Morris, M.D., “Factorial Sampling Plans for Preliminary Computational Experiments,” Technometrics 33(2):161, May 1991, doi:10.2307/1269043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Campolongo, F., Cariboni, J., Saltelli, A., and Schoutens, W., “Enhancing the Morris Method,” in Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Sensitivity Analysis of Model Output, 2005, 369-379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Sarrazin, F., Pianosi, F., and Wagener, T., “Global Sensitivity Analysis of environmental models: Convergence and Validation,” Environmental Modelling and Software 79:135-152, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.envsoft.2016.02.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Lindauer M., “Dynamische Sensitivitätsanalysemethoden energetischer Wohngebäudequartierssimulationen,” Dissertation, Technische Universität München, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Pianosi, F., Sarrazin, F., and Wagener, T., “A Matlab toolbox for Global Sensitivity Analysis,” Environmental Modelling and Software, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.envsoft.2015.04.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">“SAFE Toolbox,” [Online], https://www.safetoolbox.info/, accessed May 1, 2019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">van Griensven, A., Meixner, T., Grunwald, S., Bishop, T. et al., “A Global Sensitivity Analysis Tool for the Parameters of Multi-Variable Catchment Models,” Journal of Hydrology 324(1-4):10-23, June 2006, doi:10.1016/j. jhydrol.2005.09.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Monari, F. and Strachan, P., “Characterization of an Airflow Network Model by Sensitivity Analysis: Parameter Screening, Fixing, Prioritizing and Mapping,” Journal of Building Performance Simulation 10(1):17-36, Jan. 2017, doi:10.1080/19401493.2015.1110621.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Ziliani, L., Surian, N., Coulthard, T.J., and Tarantola, S., “Reduced-Complexity Modeling of Braided Rivers: Assessing Model Performance by Sensitivity Analysis, Calibration, and Validation,” Journal of Geophysical Research: Earth Surface 118(4):2243-2262, Dec. 2013, doi:10.1002/jgrf.20154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Efron, B. and Tibshirani, R., An Introduction to the Bootstrap (Chapman &amp; Hall, 1994).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Ruano, M.V., Ribes, J., Ferrer, J., and Sin, G., “Application of the Morris Method for Screening the Influential Parameters of Fuzzy Controllers Applied to Wastewater Treatment Plants,” Water Science and Technology 63(10):2199-2206, 2011, doi:10.2166/wst.2011.442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Stöcker M., “Untersuchung von Optimierungsverfahren für rechenzeitaufwändige technische Anwendungen in der Motorenentwicklung,” Diplomarbeit, Technische Universität Chemnitz, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">GT-SUITE, “Optimization Manual,” Gamma Technologies LLC, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">“GT-SUITE,” [Online], https://www.gtisoft.com/about-gt/, accessed May 1, 2019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Booker, J.F., “Dynamically Loaded Journal Bearings: Mobility Method of Solution,” Journal of Basic Engineering 87:537, 1965, doi:10.1115/1.3650602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Goenka, P.K., “Analytical Curve Fits for Solution Parameters of Dynamically Loaded Journal Bearings,” Journal of Tribology 106(4):421-427, 1984, doi:10.1115/1.3260950.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Taylor, C.M., “Engine Bearings: Background and Lubrication Analysis,” Tribology Series 26:89-112, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Flores, P., “Journal Bearings Subjected To Dynamic Loads: The Analytical Mobility Method,” Mechanica Experimental 13, 115-127, 2006, ISSN-122 922.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Martin, F.A., “Engine Bearing Design: Design Studies, Wider Aspects and Future Developments,” Tribology Series 26:113-157, 1993, doi:10.1016/S0167-8922(08)70010-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">GT-SUITE, “Mechanics Theory Manual,” Gamma Technologies LLC, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Greenwood, J.A. and Tripp, J.H., “The Contact of Two Nominally Flat Rough Surfaces,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers 185(1):625-633, June 1970, doi:10.1243/PIME_PROC_1970_185_069_02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c32">GT-SUITE, “Valve Train Application Manual,” Gamma Technologies LLC, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Martin, F.A., “Oil Flow in Plain Steadily Loaded Journal Bearings: Realistic Predictions Using Rapid Techniques,” Journal of Engineering Tribology (Part J) 212:413-425, 1997, doi:10.1243/1350650981542227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c34">von Hollen J., “Reibung von Kurbelwellen-Wälzlagern,” Dissertation, Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz Universität Hannover, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Dowson, D., Higginson, G.R., and Archard, J.F., Elasto- Hydrodynamic Lubrication: The Fundamentals of Roller and Gear Lubrication First Edition (Oxford: Pergamon Press, 1966).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c36">van Leeuwen, H., “The Determination of the Pressure- Viscosity Coefficient of a Lubricant through an Accurate Film Thickness Formula and Accurate Film Thickness Measurements,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part J: Journal of Engineering Tribology 223(8):1143-1163, Aug. 2009, doi:10.1243/13506501JET504.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Bartel, D., Simulation von Tribosystemen (Wiesbaden: Vieweg+Teubner, 2010), doi:10.1007/978-3-8348-9656-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Palmgren, A., “Neue Untersuchungen über Energieverluste in Wälzlagern,” VDI Berichte 20:117-212, 1957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Schaeffler Technologies, Ed., “Schmierung von Wälzlagern: Grundlagen, Schmierverfahren, Schmierstoffauswahl und -prüfung, Aufbewahrung und Handhabung,” Schaeffler Technologies AG &amp; Co. KG, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c40">McCool, J.I., “Relating Profile Instrument Measurements to the Functional Performance of Rough Surfaces,” Journal of Tribology 109(2):264, Apr. 1987, doi:10.1115/1.3261349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Tomanik, E., Chacon, H., and Teixeira, G., “A Simple Numerical Procedure to Calculate the Input Data of Greenwood-Williamson Model of Asperity Contact for Actual Engineering Surfaces,” Tribology Series 41:205-215, Jan. 2003, doi:10.1016/S0167-8922(03)80133-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Bonneau, D., Fatu, A., and Souchet, D., Internal Combustion Engine Bearings Lubrication in Hydrodynamic Bearings (Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., 2014), doi:10.1002/9781119005025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Faraon I.C., “Mixed Lubricated Line Contacts,” Ph.D. dissertation, University of Twente, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Mathavan, J.J. and Patnaik, A., “Analysis of Wear Properties of Aluminium Based Journal Bearing Alloys with and without Lubrication,” IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering 149(1):012052, 2016, doi:10.1088/1757-899X/149/1/012052.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c45">GT-SUITE, “Template Help,” Gamma Technologies LLC, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Whitehouse, D.J. and Archard, J.F., “The Properties of Random Surfaces of Significance in their Contact,” Proceedings of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences 316(1524):97-121, 1970, doi:10.1098/rspa.1970.0068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Liu Q., “Friction in Mixed and Elastohydrodynamic Lubricated Contacts Including Thermal Effects,” Ph.D. dissertation, University of Twente, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Böge, A. and Böge, W., Technische Mechanik (Wiesbaden: Springer Fachmedien Wiesbaden, 2017), doi:10.1007/978-3-658-16203-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Evans, C.R. and Johnson, K.L., “The Rheological Properties of Elastohydrodynamic Lubricants,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part C: Journal of Mechanical Engineering Science 200(5):303-312, Sept. 1986, doi:10.1243/PIME_PROC_1986_200_134_02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Shi, X. and Polycarpou, A.A., “Measurement and Modeling of Normal Contact Stiffness and Contact Damping at the Meso Scale,” Journal of Vibration and Acoustics 127(1):52, Feb. 2005, doi:10.1115/1.1857920.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Muthukumar S., “A Contact Element Approach with Hysteresis Damping for the Analysis and Design of Pounding in Bridges,” Ph.D. dissertation, Georgia Institute of Technology, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Popov, V.L., Kontaktmechanik und Reibung (Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2015), doi:10.1007/978-3-662-45975-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Lorenz, A., Tuozzolo, C., and Louge, M.Y., “Measurements of Impact Properties of Small, Nearly Spherical Particles,” Experimental Mechanics 37(3):292-298, Sept. 1997, doi:10.1007/BF02317421.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Liu, Z., “Study of Valve Seat Landing Stiffness and Damping,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2873, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Maissen, A., “Festkörperreibung: Reibungszahlen verschiedener Werkstoffe,” Schweizer Ingenieur und Architekt 111(3), 1993, doi:10.5169/seals-78120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Viehof, M. and Winner, H., “Stand der Technik und der Wissenschaft : Modellvalidierung im Anwendungsbereich der Fahrdynamiksimulation,” Forschungsbericht, Technische Universität Darmstadt, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Henriksen, J.O., “Taming the Complexity Dragon,” Journal of Simulation 2(1):3-17, Mar. 2008, doi:10.1057/palgrave. jos.4250029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Overview of the methodology and its possible applications within a modeling and simulation process. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Overview of SA within the parameter identification. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Friction contacts in an exhaust valve train assembly. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Modeling objects in GT-SUITE for major friction contacts of an exhaust valve train assembly. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Selection of potential model-calibration parameters (12 in total) for friction in camshaft journal bearings (index CSB). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Selection of potential model-calibration parameters (9 in total) for friction in a Cam-Roller Contact (index CR). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Selection of potential model-calibration parameters (9 in total) for friction in a RFF-Valve Contact (index RV). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Selection of potential model-calibration parameters (5 in total) for friction in a RFF-HLA Contact (index RH). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Selection of potential model-calibration parameters (6 in total) for friction in a valve guide assembly (index V). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Operating points for DOE simulation. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Normalized Morris sensitivity indices for total friction torque of an exhaust valve train at operating point 1 (T<sub>Oil</sub> = 30°C, n<sub>Eng</sub> = 1000 rpm, and r = 10). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Evaluation of convergence at operating point 1 (T<sub>Oil</sub> = 30°C, n<sub>Eng</sub> = 1000 rpm and r = 30) for variations of sensitivity indices with sample size. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Normalized Morris sensitivity indices for total friction torque of an exhaust valve train at operating point 1 (T<sub>Oil</sub> = 30°C, n<sub>Eng</sub> = 1000 rpm, and r = 30). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Normalized Morris sensitivity indices for total friction torque of an exhaust valve train at operating point 2 (T<sub>Oil</sub> = 30°C, n<sub>Eng</sub> = 5000 rpm and r = 30). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Normalized Morris sensitivity indices for total friction torque of an exhaust valve train at operating point 3 (T<sub>Oil</sub> = 110°C, n<sub>Eng</sub> = 1000 rpm, and r = 30). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Normalized Morris sensitivity indices for total friction torque of an exhaust valve train at operating point 4 (T<sub>Oil</sub> = 110°C, n<sub>Eng</sub> = 2000 rpm, and r = 30). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Normalized Morris sensitivity indices for total friction torque of an exhaust valve train at operating point 5 (T<sub>Oil</sub> = 110°C, n<sub>Eng</sub> = 5000 rpm, and r = 30). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Total number of sensitive parameters for further use in model-calibration process (resulting from the SA with sample size r = 30 and threshold T = 0.1). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Model validation of exhaust valve train friction torque and its correlation to measurement data at oil temperature level T<sub>Oil</sub> = 90°C. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Comparison of overall model performance before and after using NSGA-III as calibration algorithm (top: global view, bottom: local view). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Values of base and best parameter set of model validation at oil temperature level T<sub>Oil</sub> = 90°C (see also Figure 11). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
