<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26926849</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Study of Pore Size and Distribution Effects on Gasoline Particulate Filter Performance</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Pengze</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Strzelec</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26926847</issue-id>
         <fpage>489</fpage>
         <lpage>508</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26926849"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The improved brake thermal efficiency of Gasoline Direct Injection (GDI) engines is accompanied by a significant increase in Particulate Matter (PM) mass and higher Particulate Number (PN) emissions as compared to (multi)Port Fuel Injected (PFI) engines. Gasoline particulate filters (GPFs) with high filtration efficiency and low backpressure will be required to meet the future, stringent PM/PN regulations. A two-dimensional (2D) CFD study was performed to determine the effects of pore size and distribution on the interdependent performance parameters of filtration efficiency and back-pressure for clean GPFs. Simulation results show an on linear change infiltration efficiency as the pore size distribution tightens and determine a recommended distribution range, controlling the quantity of small-sized pores. Pore size distributions beyond this recommended range can cause a filtration performance loss or intolerable backpressure penalty for the GPF. In addition, a recent collaborative publication from our group has demonstrated our ability to create a hierarchical porous filter, with variable pore size in each layer. Knowing that filtration efficiency and pressure drop increase as the average pore size decreases offers inspiration for a novel wall design with small pores comprising the top 40% of the wall layers and larger pores on bottom 60%. The model predicts that such a wall would result in an 8% increase in filtration efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Maricq, M., “How Are Emissions of Nuclei Mode Particles Affected by Emission Control,” in HEI-Conference, May 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE International Journal of Engines 9(2):1258-1275, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Johnson, T. and Joshi, A., “Review of Vehicle Engine Efficiency and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0907, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Heyder, J., “Deposition of Inhaled Particles in the Human Respiratory Tract and Consequences for Regional Targeting in Respiratory Drug Delivery,” Proceedings of the American Thoracic Society 1(4):315-320, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Donaldson, K. et al., “Nanoparticles and the Cardiovascular System: A Critical Review,” Nanomedicine 8(3):403-423, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Lambert, C.K. et al., “Analysis of High Mileage Gasoline Exhaust Particle Filters,” SAE International Journal of Engines 9(2):1296-1304, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0941.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Badshah, H., Kittelson, D., and Northrop, W., “Particle Emissions from Light-Duty Vehicles during Cold-Cold Start,” SAE International Journal of Engines 9(3):1775-1785, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bissett, E.J., “Mathematical Model of the Thermal Regeneration of a Wall-Flow Monolith Diesel Particulate Filter,” Chemical Engineering Science 39(7-8):1233-1244, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Konstandopoulos, A.G. and Johnson, J.H., “Wall-Flow Diesel Particulate Filters-Their Pressure Drop and Collection Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 890405, 1989, doi:10.4271/890405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Konstandopoulos, A.G., “Flow Resistance Descriptors for Diesel Particulate Filters: Definitions, Measurements and Testing,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0846, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0846.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Konstandopoulos, A.G. et al., “Fundamental Studies of Diesel Particulate Filters: Transient Loading, Regeneration and Aging,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1016, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Konstandopoulos, A.G., Skaperdas, E., and Masoudi, M., “Inertial Contributions to the Pressure Drop of Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0909, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0909.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Sheppard, J., “Size-Dependent Filtration of Cakeless Diesel Particulate Filters,” in Mechanical Engineering (College Station, TX: Texas A&amp;M University, 2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dalla Nora, M., Lanzanova, T.D.M., and Zhao, H., “Effects of Valve Timing, Valve Lift and Exhaust Backpressure on Performance and Gas Exchanging of a Two-Stroke GDI Engine with Overhead Valves,” Energy Conversion and Management 123:71-83, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Payatakes, A.C., Tien, C., and Turian, R.M., “A New Model for Granular Porous Media: Part I. Model Formulation,” AIChE Journal 19(1):58-67, 1973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Lee, K.W. and Gieseke, J.A., “Collection of Aerosol Particles by Packed Beds,” Environmental Science &amp; Technology 13(4):466-470, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Kuwabara, S., “The Forces Experienced by a Lattice of Elliptic Cylinders in a Uniform Flow at Small Reynolds Numbers,” Journal of the Physical Society of Japan 14(4):522-527, 1959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Huang, K., Pan, L., and Yoon, R.-H., “A Capillary Flow Model for Filtration,” Minerals Engineering 115:88-96, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gong, J. and Rutland, C.J., “Based Heterogeneous Multiscale Filtration Model,” Environmental Science &amp; Technology 49(8):4963-4970, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gong, J. and Rutland, C.J., “Filtration Characteristics of Fuel Neutral Particulates Using a Heterogeneous Multiscale Filtration Model,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 137(11):111507, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Gong, J. et al., “Importance of Filter’s Microstructure in Dynamic Filtration Modeling of Gasoline Particulate Filters (GPFs): Inhomogeneous Porosity and Pore Size Distribution,” Chemical Engineering Journal, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Meng, Z. et al., “Experimental Study on the Influence of DPF Micropore Structure and Particle Property on Its Filtration Process,” Journal of Combustion 2016, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Opris, C. and Johnson, J., “A 2-D Computational Model Describing the Flow and Filtration Characteristics of a Ceramic Diesel Particulate Trap,” SAE Technical Paper 980545, 1998, doi:10.4271/980545.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Rumpf, H. and Gupte A., “The Influence of Porosity and Grain Size Distribution on the Permeability Equation of Porous Flow,” NASA STI/Recon Technical Report N, 1975, 75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Porter, Q. and Strzelec, A., “Benchtop Investigation of Filtration Efficiency and Pressure Drop Behavior of Commercial High Porosity Gasoline Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2019-01-0054, 2019, doi:10.4271/2019-01-0054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Viswanathan, S. et al., “Experimental Investigation of the Effect of Inlet Particle Properties on the Capture Efficiency in an Exhaust Particulate Filter,” Journal of Aerosol Science 113:250-264, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Chen, L. et al., “Characterizing Particulate Matter Emissions from GDI and PFI Vehicles under Transient and Cold Start Conditions,” Fuel 189:131-140, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Huang, X. et al., “Assembly of Large Area Crack Free Clay Porous Films,” RSC Advances 8(2):1001-1004, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Porter, Q., “Experimental Investigation of Filtration Efficiency and Pressure Drop Behavior of High Porosity Gasoline Particle Filters,” 2018, unpublished, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, TX.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Custer, N. et al., “Lubricant-Derived Ash Impact on Gasoline Particulate Filter Performance,” SAE International Journal of Engines 9(3):1604-1614, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0942.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Particulate mass and number emissions from GDI and PFI engines based on the data from [1], with the proposed standards shown by the vertical and horizontal dash lines. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Vehicle PN emissions during cold start [7]. The majority of vehicles in this study emitted particulates &gt;23 nm, higher than EURO 6 PN limit. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Sample GPF wall properties. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Sample GPF wall substrate pore size distribution and cumulative pore volume profile based on the mercury porosimetry data provided by Dinex. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>SEM image of a typical GPF wall, showing the cavities and pores microstructure. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>The GPF wall is described by an array of “circular obstacles.” The cavities that exhaust flows through are represented by blue dashed lines. Where d is the diameter of the obstacle, a is the horizontal pore spacing; b is the vertical pore spacing, and D is the diameter of the cavity. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>(a) Flow field and (b) particle tracking results of a typical CFD study. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Quantity of different sized pores in the 2D baseline geometry. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Measure baseline pore size distribution of the sample GPF in (a) logarithmic scale and (b) stacked column graph. The quantity of each pore size is elaborated in Table 2. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Depiction of the 2D CFD wall geometry for the baseline pore size distribution. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Depiction of the baseline pore size distribution and its wide, tight, and monodisperse variations in (a) logarithmic scale and (b) arithmetic scale and stacked column graph. Variance is elaborated in Table 3. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Quantity of different-sized pores in the 2D geometry for the wide, tight, and monodisperse cases. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>The 2D CFD wall geometry with (a) wide pore distribution, (b) tight pore distribution, and (c) monodisperse pore distribution. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>GPF wall models for the same pore size distribution, with (a) orderly obstacle layout and (b) staggered obstacle layout. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Size-dependent filtration efficiency of staggered and orderly circular obstacle layout GPF wall model for the baseline, tight, wide, and monodisperse pore size distribution. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>The baseline pore size distribution (a) shifted to the right, with average pore size of 20 um; (b) shifted to the left, with average pore size of 10 um. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>The 2D CFD wall geometry with baseline pore size distribution (a) shifted to the left, with average pore size of 10 um, and (b) shifted to the right, with average pore size of 20 um. The wall thickness and porosity remain unchanged from the baseline condition. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Size-dependent filtration efficiency comparison between the 2D CFD simulation described in this work, the 0D model, and experiment [29]. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Size-dependent filtration efficiency Ê for the baseline, tight, wide, and monodisperse pore distributions. For details of the quantities of different pore size for each pore size distribution, please refer to Table 3. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Filtration efficiency comparison for 75 nm particles between various pore size distributions in this study indicates the potential existence of an “optimal distribution.” For details of the quantities of the different pore size for each pore size distribution, please refer to Table 3. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Velocity contours of the (a) baseline and (b) tight pore distributions. High flow velocity regions due to flow merging are marked by red dashed rectangles. Low flow regions resulting from divergence are marked by red solid line rectangular. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Particle tracking for the (a) tight and (b) baseline pore distributions. Three numbered streamlines shown in red are singled out to show flow divergence and merging. Regions with low or no flow are marked by red dashed rectangles. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Quantity of different-sized pores in “optimum distribution” comparing to the baseline and tight distribution. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>The hypothesized “optimum pore size distribution” in stacked column graph, next to the baseline, wide, tight, and monodisperse distribution. The quantity of each pore size in the “Optimum” distribution is elaborated in Table 4. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>The hypothesized “optimum pore size distribution” shows similar filtration efficiency with the baseline and tight cases at nearly all particle sizes. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Recommended range of pore size distribution for sample GPF. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Pressure drop comparison. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 23</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Size-dependent filtration efficiency with changing average pore size. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 24</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Velocity contour for (a) the baseline, (b) 20 um average pore size, and (c) 10 um average pore size. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 25</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Particle tracking of (a) baseline, (b) 20 um average pore size, and (c) 10 um average. A streamline is highlighted in red for each case. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>Pressure drop comparison. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 26</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>Proposed GPF wall with varying porosity. The top 2/5 of the wall is composed of 10 um pores, and the bottom 3/5 is composed of 20 um pores. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 27</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>Novel GPF wall design shows increased filtration efficiency as compared to the baseline. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
