<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000370</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40006945</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Diagnostic Tool for German Syntax</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Nerbonne</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Klaus</given-names>
                  <surname>Netter</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Abdel Kader</given-names>
                  <surname>Diagne</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Judith</given-names>
                  <surname>Klein</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ludwig</given-names>
                  <surname>Dickmann</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>85</fpage>
         <lpage>107</lpage>
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1993 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40006945"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>In this paper we describe an ongoing effort to construct a catalogue of syntactic data exemplifying the major syntactic patterns of German. The purpose of the corpus is to support the diagnosis of errors in the syntactic components of natural language processing (NLP) systems. Secondary aims are the evaluation of NLP syntax components and support of theoretical and empirical work on German syntax. The data consist of artificially and systematically constructed expressions, including also negative (ungrammatical) examples. The data are organized into a relational database and annotated with some basic information about the phenomena illustrated and the internal structure of the sample sentences. The organization of the data supports selected systematic testing of specific areas of syntax, but also serves the purpose of a linguistic database. The paper first gives some general motivation for the necessity of syntactic precision in some areas of NLP and discusses the potential contribution of a syntactic database to the field of component evaluation. The second part of the paper describes the set up and control methods applied in the construction of the sentence suite and annotations to the examples. We illustrate the approach with examples from verbal government and sentential coordination. This section also contains a description of the abstract data model, the design of the database and the query language used to access the data. The final sections compare our work to existing approaches and sketch some future extensions. We invite other research groups to participate in our effort, so that the diagnostics tool can eventually become public domain. Several groups have already accepted this invitation, and progress is being made.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <fn-group>
            <title>[Footnotes]</title>
            <fn id="d2188222e171a1310">
               <label>3</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e178" publication-type="other">
Colliander
(1983),</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e187" publication-type="other">
Engel (1970),</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e193" publication-type="other">
Engelen (1975),</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e200" publication-type="other">
Götze (1979),</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e206" publication-type="other">
Helbig (1980)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e212" publication-type="other">
Weisgerber (1983).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d2188222e219a1310">
               <label>4</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e226" publication-type="other">
Carnegie Mellon. Cf. Sleator and Temperley
(1991).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d2188222e245a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e249" publication-type="other">
Alfred V. Aho, Brian W. Kernighan and Peter J. Weinberger. The awk programming
language. Addison Wesley: Wokingham, 1988</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e259a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e263" publication-type="other">
István Batori and Martin Volk: Das Verhältnis von natiiürlichsprachlichen Korpora zu sys-
tematischen Sammlungen konstruierter Texte. Workshop presentation, Repräsentatives
Korpus der deutschen Gegenwartssprache, 15-16.Oct.1992. to appear in a report of
the Institut für Kommunikationsforschung und Phonetik, Bonn.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e279a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e283" publication-type="other">
E. Black et al: A Procedure for Quantitatively Comparing the Syntactic Coverage of
English Grammars. Proceedings of the February 1991 Speech and Natural Language
Workshop. Morgan Kaufmann: San Mateo, California, 1991</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e296a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e300" publication-type="other">
Peter Colliander: Das Korrelat und die obligatorische Extraposition. Kopenhagener
Beiträge zur Germanistischen Linguistik. Sonderband 2. Kopenhagen, 1983.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e311a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e315" publication-type="other">
P. Chen: The entity-relationship model. Toward a unified view of data. ACM Transactions
on Database Systems. No. 1, 1976.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e325a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e329" publication-type="other">
Abdel Kader Diagne: DlTO-A Diagnostic Tool for German Syntax. Data Base and User's
Manual. DFKI Technical Document D-92-05, DFKI, Saarbriicken, 1992.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e339a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e343" publication-type="other">
Daniel Flickinger, John Nerbonne, Ivan Sag, and Thomas Wasow: Towards evaluation of
natural language processing systems. Technical report, Hewlett-Packard Laboratories,
1987.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e356a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e360" publication-type="other">
Ulrich Engel: Die deutschen Satzbauplane. In Wirkendes Wort 20, pages 361-392, 1970.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e367a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e371" publication-type="other">
Bernhard Engelen: Untersuchungen zu Satzbauplan und Wortfeld in der geschriebenen
deutschen Sprache der Gegenwart. Reihe I 3.3 Verblisten. München, 1975.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e381a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e385" publication-type="other">
LutzGötze: Valenzstrukturen deutscher Verben und Adjektive. München, 1979.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e393a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e397" publication-type="other">
Giovanni Guida and Giancarlo Mauri: Evaluation of natural language processing systems:
Issues and approaches. Proceedings of the IEEE, 74(7): 1026-1035, 1986.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e407a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e411" publication-type="other">
Gerhard Helbig: Wörterbuch zur Valenz und Distribution deutscher Verben. Leipzig, 5th
ed., 1980.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e421a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e425" publication-type="other">
Judith Klein and Ludwig Dickmann: Daten-Dokumentation: Verbrektion und Koordina-
tion. DFKI Technical Document D-92-04, DFKI, Saarbrücken 1992.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e435a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e439" publication-type="other">
Brigitte Krenn: Funktionsverbgefüge: Eine Datenbeschreibung. unpub. Documentation,
Institut für angewandte Informationsforschung, Saarbrücken.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e449a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e453" publication-type="other">
Mark Liberman: Text on Tap: the ACL/DCI. In Proceedings of the October 1989 Speech
and Natural Language Workshop. Morgan Kaufmann: San Mateo, California, 1989,
pp.173-188.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e466a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e470" publication-type="other">
Judith Klein, Ludwig Dickmann, Abdel Kader Diagne, John Nerbonne, and Klaus Net-
ter: DiTo: Ein Diagnostikwerkzeug für die syntaktische Analyse. In Tagungsband
KONVENZ92. Springer: Berlin, 1992, pp.380-385.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e484a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e488" publication-type="other">
Dave S. Pallett et al.: DARPA Research Management Benchmark Test Results, June 1990.
In Proceedings of the June 1990 Speech and Natural Language Workshop. Morgan
Kaufmann: San Mateo, California, 1990, pp.298-305.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e501a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e505" publication-type="other">
Martha Palmer and Tim Finin: Workshop on the Evaluation of Natural Language Processing
Systems. In: Computational Linguistics 16(3), 1990, pp.175-181.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e515a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e519" publication-type="other">
Walter Read, Alex Quilici, John Reeves, Michael Dyer, and Eva Baker: Evaluating natural
language systems: A sourcebook approach. In COLING '88, pages 530-534, 1988.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e529a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e533" publication-type="other">
Ivan Sag: Linguistic Theory and Natural Language Processing. In Ewan Klein and Frank
Veltman, eds. Natural Language and Speech. Symposium Proceedings. Springer-
Verlag: Berlin, 1991.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e546a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e550" publication-type="other">
Daniel D. K. Sleator and Davy Temperley : Parsing English with a Link Grammar. Carnegie
Mellon School of Computer Science Technical Report CMU-CS-91-196, October 1991.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e560a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e564" publication-type="other">
Martin Volk and Hanno Ridder: GTU - eine Grammatik Testumgebung mit Testsatzarchiv
to appear in: LDV-Forum 1.1992.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e575a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e579" publication-type="other">
Martin Volk: Kurzbeschreibung der Testsatzsammlung zu den Relativsätzen unpub. Doc-
umentation, Universität Koblenz.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2188222e589a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2188222e593" publication-type="other">
Monika Weisgerber: Valenz und Kongruenzbeziehungen. Frankfurt a. M., 1983.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
