<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437935</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Women, Men and the Redistribution of Income</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>HOLLY</given-names>
                  <surname>SUTHERLAND</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">18</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437932</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>22</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1997</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437935"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper explores the implications of examining the effect of policy changes on individual incomes rather than household incomes. Conceptual problems arise from the treatment of collective resources and responsibilities, particularly children. These are dealt with in a manner that is transparent with the aim of establishing a practical method of analysing policy at the individual (and gender-specific) level. Two policy-related issues are examined in this framework: the impact of a minimum wage and the effect of introducing a minimum pension guarantee. In each case, the implications of choosing the individual as the income unit are examined and an analysis of the issue by gender is presented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d50e214a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e221" publication-type="other">
One exception is that we do not assume complete take-up of means-tested benefits. We assume randomly-
applied take-up rates (on a claimant headcount basis) of 91 per cent for housing benefit and council tax benefit,
62 per cent for family credit and 81 per cent for income support. See Redmond and Wilson (1995) for more
information.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e237a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e244" publication-type="other">
The household is a collection of people who live at the same address with common housekeeping
arrangements (Central Statistical Office, 1992). The family unit is the nuclear family: a couple or single person
and any dependent children sharing the same household. Children are defined as people aged under 16, or
under 19 if in full-time secondary education.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e260a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e267" publication-type="other">
As defined by the Family Expenditure Survey. In the case of couples, this will be the man. Across generations
or in households of siblings or unrelated adults, the designation of head of household depends on the ownership
of the dwelling or responsibility for the rent (Central Statistical Office, 1992, p. 78).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e280a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e289" publication-type="other">
FES micro-data for 1991 indicate that 27 out of a total 53 family credit recipients in couples were male. This
is not consistent with the statement 'In two-parent families it is the woman who receives the benefit and it is
she who must make the claim' (Department of Social Security, 1992). This suggests that the recorded
information in the FES is not necessarily accurate with respect to identification of the individual within the
family who is the claimant. We have ignored the recorded information in this regard, as well as in simulating
the size of the family entitlement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e313a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e320" publication-type="other">
In May 1995, 9 per cent of all claims made by couples were made by women (calculated from Social Security
Statistics 1996, Tables A2.11, A2.12, A2.13 and A2.14).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e330a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e337" publication-type="other">
An y individual income that children themselves receive from outside the household is allocated in the same
manner as responsibility for the children.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e347a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e354" publication-type="other">
Using the McClements equivalence scale.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e361a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e368" publication-type="other">
Responsibility for children, assumed to fall on mothers, scales down the respective adult incomes in the same
proportions as assumed for lone parents in the conventional operation of the scale.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e378a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e385" publication-type="other">
Gini coefficients for the two distributions are 0.32 (household) and 0.45 (individual). Gini coefficients are
calculated using the computer package 1NEQ, written by Frank Cowell of the London School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e395a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e402" publication-type="other">
The differences between the household and individual distributions presented here are decomposed and
reconciled by Sutherland (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e413a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e420" publication-type="other">
Gini coefficients for the male and female distributions are 0.38 and 0.44 respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e427a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e434" publication-type="other">
The UK currently has no minimum wage. The introduction of an illustrative £4 flat-rate hourly minimum is
simulated for UK employees aged 18 to 64. No changes in behaviour on the part of employees or employers are
modelled.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e447a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e454" publication-type="other">
Small net cash losses may occur because of non-linearities in the system of means-tested benefits: there are
minimum payments attached to some benefits and some non-tapered thresholds of entitlement (e.g. for the
levels of non-dependant deduction in income support and housing benefit).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e467a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e474" publication-type="other">
Sutherland (1996) shows that, unlike most of the other results reported here, the estimates of the numbers of
losers are sensitive to the choice of income allocation rule. Assumptions that imply a greater degree of within-
household or within-family sharing of social security income result in more individuals losing (the losses being
shared by more people).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e490a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e497" publication-type="other">
Women who have made sufficient contributions in their own right qualify for their own full pension and
widows of full pensioners inherit a full derived rights pension.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e507a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e514" publication-type="other">
In 1995-96, the basic insurance pension for a single person was £58.85 per week. The addition for a wife
(where she did not have a pension based on her own contributions) was £35.25. The social assistance (income
support) levels for a couple and a single person aged 65 (with no extra needs) were £101.05 and £65.10
respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e531a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e538" publication-type="other">
We assume that the MPG is introduced for people aged 65 or more, and that take-up of the MPG is complete.
Throughout this section, 'pensioners' are defined as people aged 65 or more.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e548a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e555" publication-type="other">
The net revenue cost is made up of a gross cost of £6.09 billion, offset by an increase in income tax of £0.28
billion and a reduction in the cost of social assistance of £2.46 billion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e565a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e572" publication-type="other">
A11 households are included, not only those containing pensioners.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e579a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e586" publication-type="other">
Sutherland (1996) explores the effect of splitting the payment in other proportions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d50e602a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e606" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. B. (1995), Incomes and the Welfare State: Essays on Britain and Europe, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e616a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e620" publication-type="other">
Borooah, V. K. and McKee, P. M. (1994), 'Modelling intra-household income transfers: an
analytical framework with an application to the UK', in J. Creedy (ed.), Taxation, Poverty and
Income Distribution, London: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e633a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e637" publication-type="other">
Browning, M., Bourguignon, F., Chiappori, P.-A. and Lechene, V. (1994), 'Incomes and outcomes:
a structural model of intra-household allocation', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 102, pp.
1067-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e650a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e654" publication-type="other">
Central Statistical Office (1992), Family Spending: A Report on the 1991 Family Expenditure
Survey, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e665a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e669" publication-type="other">
Davies, H. and Joshi, H. (1994), 'Sex, sharing and the distribution of income', Journal of Social
Policy, vol. 23, pp. 301-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e679a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e683" publication-type="other">
— and — (1995), 'Social and family security in the redress of unequal opportunities', in J.
Humphries and J. Rubery (eds), The Economics of Equal Opportunities, Manchester: Equal
Opportunities Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e696a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e700" publication-type="other">
Department of Social Security (1992), 'Family credit: advisers briefing pack', leaflet FC47, DSS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e707a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e711" publication-type="other">
— (1996), Households Below Average Income: A Statistical Analysis 1979-1993/4, London:
HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e721a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e725" publication-type="other">
Duncan, A., Giles, C. and Webb, S. (1994), Social Security Reform and Women's Independent
Incomes, Research Discussion Series no. 6, Manchester: Equal Opportunities Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e735a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e739" publication-type="other">
Esam, P. and Berthoud, R. (1991), Independent Benefits for Men and Women, London: Policy
Studies Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e750a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e754" publication-type="other">
Findlay, J. and Wright, R. E. (1996), 'Gender poverty and the intra-household distribution of
resources', Review of Income and Wealth, vol. 42, pp. 335-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e764a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e768" publication-type="other">
Giles, C. and Johnson, P. (1994), 'Tax reform in the UK and changes to the progressivity of the tax
system 1985-95', Fiscal Studies, vol. 15, no. 3, pp. 64—86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e778a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e782" publication-type="other">
Gosling, A. (1996), 'Minimum wages: possible effects on the distribution of income', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 17, no. 4, pp. 31-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e792a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e796" publication-type="other">
Harding, A. (1993), Lifetime Income Distribution and Redistribution, Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e803a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e807" publication-type="other">
Jenkins, S. P. (1991), 'Poverty measurement and the within-household distribution: agenda for
action', Journal of Social Policy, vol. 20, pp. 457-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e817a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e821" publication-type="other">
Jones, G. (1992), 'Short-term reciprocity in parent-child economic exchanges', in C. Marsh and S,
Arber (eds), Household and Family: Divisions and Change, London: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e832a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e836" publication-type="other">
Lundberg, S. J., Pollak, R. A. and Wales, T. J. (1995), 'Do husbands and wives pool their
resources? Evidence from the UK child benefit', University of Washington, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e846a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e850" publication-type="other">
McClements, D. (1977), 'Equivalence scales for children', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 8,
pp. 191-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e860a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e864" publication-type="other">
Redmond, G. and Sutherland, H. (1995), 'How has tax and social security policy changed since
1978/9? A distributional analysis', University of Cambridge, Department of Applied
Economics, Microsimulation Unit, Discussion Paper no. MU9508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e877a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e881" publication-type="other">
—, — and Wilson, M. (1996), 'POLIMOD: an outline', second edition, University of Cambridge,
Department of Applied Economics, Microsimulation Unit, Research Note no. MU/RN/19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e891a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e895" publication-type="other">
— and Wilson, M. (1995), 'Validating POLIMOD output', University of Cambridge, Department
of Applied Economics, Microsimulation Unit, Research Note no. MU/RN/14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e905a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e909" publication-type="other">
Sutherland, H. (1991), 'The immediate impact of a minimum wage on family incomes', London
School of Economics, STICERD, Microsimuiation Policy Modelling Unit, Research Note no.
1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e923a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e927" publication-type="other">
— (1995), 'Minimum wage benefits', New Economy, vol. 2, pp. 204-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e934a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e938" publication-type="other">
— (1996), 'Households, individuals and the re-distribution of income', University of Cambridge,
Department of Applied Economics, Microsimulation Unit, Discussion Paper no. MU9601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e948a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e952" publication-type="other">
Vogler, C. and Pähl, J. (1993), 'Social and economic change and the organisation of money within
marriage', Work, Employment and Society, vol. 7, pp. 71-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e962a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e966" publication-type="other">
Webb, S. (1993), 'Women's incomes: past, present and prospects', Fiscal Studies, vol. 14, no. 4,
pp. 14—36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
