<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277855</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>1-D Simulation Study of Divided Exhaust Period for a Highly Downsized Turbocharged SI Engine - Scavenge Valve Optimization</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hu</surname>
                  <given-names>Bo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Akehurst</surname>
                  <given-names>Sam</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brace</surname>
                  <given-names>Chris</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Copeland</surname>
                  <given-names>Colin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Turner</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jaguar Land Rover</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1443</fpage>
         <lpage>1452</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277855"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Fuel efficiency and torque performance are two major challenges for highly downsized turbocharged engines. However, the inherent characteristics of the turbocharged SI engine such as negative PMEP, knock sensitivity and poor transient performance significantly limit its maximum potential. Conventional ways of improving the problems above normally concentrate solely on the engine side or turbocharger side leaving the exhaust manifold in between ignored. This paper investigates this neglected area by highlighting a novel means of gas exchange process.</p>
            <p>Divided Exhaust Period (DEP) is an alternative way of accomplishing the gas exchange process in turbocharged engines. The DEP concept engine features two exhaust valves but with separated function. The blow-down valve acts like a traditional turbocharged exhaust valve to evacuate the first portion of the exhaust gas to the turbine. While the scavenge valve feeding the latter portion of the exhaust gas directly into the low resistant exhaust pipe behaves similarly to valves in a naturally aspirated engine. By combining the characteristics of both turbocharged and naturally aspirated engines, high backpressure between the turbine inlet and the exhaust port is maintained in the blowdown phase while significant reduction of the backpressure could be achieved in the latter displacement phase. This is directly beneficial for pumping work and residual gas scavenging. Combustion phasing &amp; stability and turbocharger efficiency could also benefit from such concept.</p>
            <p>This simulation study was carried out using a validated 1D model of a highly downsized SI engine. Two degrees of freedom including the lift and the duration of the scavenge valve were optimized to achieve minimum BSFC. The potential for higher attainable BMEP was also briefly investigated at low engine speed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petitjean, D., Bernardini, L., Middlemass, C., and Shahed, S., “Advanced Gasoline Engine Turbocharging Technology for Fuel Economy Improvements,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0988, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Möller, C., Johansson, P., Grandin, B., and Lindström, F., “Divided Exhaust Period - A Gas Exchange System for Turbocharged SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1150, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westin, F., Grandin, B., and Ångström, H., “The Influence of Residual Gases on Knock in Turbocharged SI-Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2840, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gundmalm, S., Cronhjort, A., and Angstrom H.E., “Divided Exhaust Period on Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines,” THIESEL 2012 Conference on Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Direct Injection Engines, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G. et al., “Ultra Boost for Economy: Extending the Limits of Extreme Engine Downsizing”, SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):387-417, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roth, D., Keller, P., and Sisson, J., “Valve-Event Modulated Boost System,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1222, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roth, D. and Becker, M., “Valve-Event Modulated Boost System: Fuel Consumption and Performance with Scavenge-Sourced EGR,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):538-546, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012- 01-0705.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technology</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gundmalm, S., Cronhjort, A., and Angstrom, H., “Divided Exhaust Period: Effects of Changing the Relation between Intake, Blow- Down and Scavenging Valve Area,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):739- 750, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0578.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Douaud, A. and Eyzat, P., “Four-Octane-Number Method for Predicting the Anti-Knock Behavior of Fuels and Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 780080, 1978, doi:10.4271/780080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gundmalm, S., “Divided Exhaust Period on Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines,” Ph.D. thesis, Department of Machine Design, Royal Institute of Technology, Sweden, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
