<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284826</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of Black Surface Treatment Applicable to Bolts for Motorcycles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoshida</surname>
                  <given-names>Hiroyuki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hirayama</surname>
                  <given-names>Hiroshi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mochizuki</surname>
                  <given-names>Shinsuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Inoue</surname>
                  <given-names>Manabu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Dipsol Chemicals Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kato</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Dipsol Chemicals Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Inomata</surname>
                  <given-names>Toshiki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Dipsol Chemicals Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>436</fpage>
         <lpage>444</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284826"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A black surface treatment without using hexavalent chromium and applicable to bolts of motorcycles has been developed. The surface treatment also satisfies the requirements of bolts for motorcycles such as fastening performance, corrosion resistance, weather resistance and appearance of outer finish.</p>
            <p>There is a method of coating a black chemical conversion film using trivalent chromium on the zinc-plated surface as one of the surface treatments that do not use the hexavalent chromium. Such a black film, however, is thinner than the film using hexavalent chromium, and unable to ensure satisfactory black appearance. Meanwhile, although the dip-coating using a black paint can provide a sufficient black color, it is necessary to apply coating two times to eliminate an irregular color. As a result, thick paint films are formed on the roots of thread, making it difficult to fit into the internal thread. To simultaneously solve the above-mentioned two issues, two measures were executed. One was to apply the black film using trivalent chromium as an undercoat of dip-coating. The second was to develop paints that the amount of pigments in paints was adjusted on the assumption of the color of the undercoat. Thus a proper fit of thread was ensured when fastening in addition to a satisfactory black appearance even with the dip-coating only once. Also, the friction coefficient was controlled at an appropriate level by the selection of friction modifier. Moreover, the adhesion was improved by the enhancement of anchor effect of coating with the elimination of finishing process of the black chemical conversion film, and the requested corrosion resistance was achieved.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) (1990) Chromium and chromium compounds. In: IARC monographs on the evaluation of the carcinogenic risk of chemicals to humans. CHROMIUM, NICKEL AND WELDING. Volume.49: 49-256</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Community legislation in force: (Directive 2000/53/EC of the European Parliament and of Council of 18 September 2000 on end-of-life vehicles). Official Journal L269, p34. 21/10/2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Commission decision of 27 June 2002, amending Annex II of Directive 2000/53/EC of the European Parliament and of Council on end-of-life vehicles. Official Journal of the European Communities. L170, p81-84 (2002)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takikawa, K., Miyadera, T. Ohtsuka, T. Shirakawa, A., Takashima, M. Matsuoka, Y., “Development of Hexavalent Chromium-free Surface Treatment” Honda R&amp;D Technical Review. Vol.17 No.1, p117-123 (April 2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanada, Y. Higo, S. Ohkubo, H. Okumura, T. Nabeoka, K., “Research and Development of Technology for Use of Trivalent Chromating as substitution Aimed at Abolition of Hexavalent chromium” KOMATSU TECHNICAL REPORT. Vol.55 No.162, p2-13 (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasegawa, T., “The trivalent Chromate for Zinc Electroplating” Journal of The Surface Finishing Society of Japan. Vol.53 No.6, p376-379 (2002)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kashiwada, S., “COSMER NC” Anew non-chromium Rust Preventive for Zinc or Zinc Alloy Galvanized Steel. Research on coatings (Kansai Paint Co., Ltd) No.139 p40-44 (Nov. 2002)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Enomoto, H., “Technology of Black and Blackish finish” Journal of The Surface Finishing Society of Japan. Vol.49 No.11, p1140-1146 (2002)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Corrosion-proof performance of Zinc and Zinc Alloy Plating” Technology research Institute of Osaka. Technical Sheet No.99040 (1999)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takasaki, H., “The dry method of chromate conversion film and the corrosion resistance” Jitsumu Hyomen Gijutsu. 77-10, p1-8 (1977)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshimoto, I., “Point of design screw connection object” Japanese Standards Association. P166 (1992)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inoue, M., “Technology of hexavalent chromium free black conversion coating” MATEREAL STAGE. Vol.4, No.11 p72-76 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizumachi, H., “Handbook of Surface treatment technology” NTS Co., Ltd. P71-76. (2000)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
