<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440296</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Would a Flat-Rate Tax Stimulate Entrepreneurship in Germany? A Behavioural Microsimulation Analysis Allowing for Risk</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Frank M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Fossen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440093</issue-id>
         <fpage>179</fpage>
         <lpage>218</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2009</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440296"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>When potential income tax reforms are debated, the suspected impact on entrepreneurship is often used as an argument in favour of or against a certain policy. Quantitative ex-ante evaluations of the effect of certain tax reform options on entrepreneurship are very rare, however. This paper estimates the ex-ante effects of the German tax reform 2000 and of two hypothetical flat-rate tax scenarios on entries into and exits out of self-employment based on a structural microsimulation model with econometrically estimated transition rates under risk. The simulation results indicate that flatter tax systems do not encourage people to choose self-employment, but rather discourage them from doing so. This is explained by the reduction of entrepreneurs' income risk through progressive taxation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e214a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e221" publication-type="other">
Submitted July 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e228a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e235" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, Federal Ministry of Finance (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e242a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e249" publication-type="other">
Their model additionally includes an 'income shifting' effect, which emerges from the option to
incorporate ex post based on realised earnings. This effect is less relevant in Germany because the
incorporation decision must be taken in advance and does not affect the taxation of earnings in the past.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e262a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e269" publication-type="other">
including Fossen and Steiner (2009), Moore (2004), Parker (2003a), Bruce (2000 and 2002) and
Schuetze (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e280a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e287" publication-type="other">
See Schuetze and Bruce (2004) for a survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e294a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e301" publication-type="other">
See Steiner et al. (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e308a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e315" publication-type="other">
For example, see Dealing et al. (2007), Steiner and Wrohlich (2005) and Haan and Steiner (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e322a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e329" publication-type="other">
The first step of tax rate reductions in 2001 had already been scheduled for 2002 by the Tax
Reduction Act 1999/2000/2002 of 24 March 1999, but it was pulled forward one year by the Tax
Reduction Act. This step is treated as part of the tax reform 2000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e342a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e349" publication-type="other">
See Corneo (2005) and Bönke and Corneo (2006); Haan and Steiner (2005) reported increasing
inequality.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e359a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e366" publication-type="other">
The revenue losses were estimated for the years of introduction of each of the three steps and then
summed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e377a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e384" publication-type="other">
A business tax reform was launched simultaneously on 1 January 2001. Among other measures, it
reduced the corporate income tax rate from 40 per cent for retained and 35 per cent for distributed profits
to uniformly 25 per cent, introduced the half-income system for distributed dividends, and replaced the
limitation of the top marginal personal income tax rate for tradesmen (§32c of EStG, income tax law)
with a lump-sum credit of the local business tax deductible from the personal income tax liability.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e403a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e410" publication-type="other">
The Council of Economic Advisers to the Ministry of Finance (2004) suggested a similar (but not
revenue-neutral) flat tax with a basic allowance of €10,000 and a tax rate of 30 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e420a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e427" publication-type="other">
Davies and Hoy (2002) demonstrated that revenue-neutral flat tax reforms with lower basic
allowances than in the pre-reform graduated-rate tax schedule result in higher inequality than the pre-
reform situation according to any inequality index. If a higher basic allowance is chosen, a certain
revenue-neutral combination of the flat tax rate and the basic allowance exists that does not change a
given inequality index - for example, the Gini coefficient - in comparison with the situation without the
reform. This combination is found in scenario HH.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e450a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e457" publication-type="other">
The splitting of household net income between individuals within households is described in Section
III.3.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e467a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e474" publication-type="other">
The changes are not exactly zero, as only full-time working people are considered in this table and as
Fuest, Peichl and Schaefer (2008) simulated the revenue-neutral flat tax scenarios for 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e484a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e491" publication-type="other">
For further comparison, the self-employment rate was 13.4 per cent in the UK and 12.6 per cent in
the Slovak Republic, which introduced a flat-rate tax of 19 per cent in 2004. The cross-country
comparisons must be interpreted with caution, however, especially if not limited to Europe: for the US,
the OECD reports a self-employment rate of only 7.5 per cent in 2005, which is due to a different
treatment of incorporated self-employed, according to Blanchflower (2000). In contrast, Holtz-Eakin and
Rosen (2005) found that the self-employment rate is higher in the US than in Germany, based on a
comparison of the SOEP with a similar panel data set for the US, the Panel Study of Income Dynamics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e518a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e525" publication-type="other">
For the US, the corresponding shares of people working in micro enterprises (respectively, SMEs)
were 21.5 per cent (49.1 per cent) in 2000. These even lower numbers cannot be directly related to those
measured in Europe, however, as they do not include sole proprietorships, which are particularly
important in the US according to the European Commission (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e541a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e548" publication-type="other">
For example, see Taylor (1996) and Evans and Leighton (1989); for German data, see Georgellis and
Wall (2005) and Holtz-Eakin and Rosen (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e558a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e565" publication-type="other">
See Brown, Farrel and Sessions (2006), Parker (2005) and Bruce (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e572a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e579" publication-type="other">
Similar results are obtained if the parameters are allowed to differ between the entry and exit models;
see Fossen (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e589a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e596" publication-type="other">
For example, Eckstein and Wolpin (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e603a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e610" publication-type="other">
The income tax of married couples is calculated by applying the tax function to half of the sum of the
spouses' taxable incomes and then doubling the resulting tax amount.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e621a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e628" publication-type="other">
For example, Haan and Steiner (2005) and van Soest (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e635a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e642" publication-type="other">
See, for instance, Haan and Steiner (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e649a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e656" publication-type="other">
As an exception, artists, writers and journalists are covered by mandatory statutory health insurance
if certain requirements are met.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e666a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e673" publication-type="other">
About 0.85 per cent of the self-employed in Germany were not covered by any health insurance in
2003 (Greß, Walendzik and Wasem, 2005). Since 1 January 2009, health insurance has been obligatory
for all self-employed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e686a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e693" publication-type="other">
Mandatory pension insurance applies for self-employed teachers without employees, nurses,
midwives, artists, writers, journalists, craftsmen (who may contract out after contributing for 18 years)
and other less frequent groups.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e706a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e713" publication-type="other">
The basic pension is also available for dependently employed people who wish to supplement their
statutory pension insurance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e724a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e731" publication-type="other">
Parker (2003b) provided insights into the private and public pension wealth of older self-employed
people in Great Britain.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e741a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e748" publication-type="other">
A new option for people becoming self-employed, having been dependency employed, to stay in
unemployment insurance upon application was introduced in February 2006 but is not relevant for this
analysis as it was not available in 2005.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e761a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e768" publication-type="other">
The prerequisites for private pension insurance basically ensure that the funds are not consumed
before old age. For all taxpayers (independently of the status as a dependently employed or self-employed
person), upper limits of the provisions deductible as special expenses exist and are modelled in the
STSM.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e784a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e791" publication-type="other">
The so-called 'Ich-AG' ('Me-Incorporation') programme, which came into effect in January 2003,
was only available to the unemployed, so it is not relevant for this analysis. In August 2006, both the
bridging allowance and 'Me-Incorporation' programmes were replaced by a single new start-up subsidy
programme (Gründungszuschuss), which is only available to unemployed people receiving
unemployment benefits, so again it is irrelevant for transitions between dependent employment and self-
employment.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e814a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e821" publication-type="other">
In the baseline scenario, the individuals observed in dependent employment have an hourly net wage
annuity of €11.64 on average and would earn €14.53 if they were self-employed. Risk aversion may
explain why they chose dependent employment nevertheless, because they would face a much higher
variance annuity in self-employment than they do in dependent employment. The large variance predicted
for the counterfactual state results from the estimated large influence of the selection on unobserved
characteristics (for the detailed results, see Fossen (2007)). The self-employed would earn slightly more if
they were dependently employed, and they would have a smaller income variance; apparently, non-
pecuniary factors compensate them for this small disadvantage in earnings (cf. Hamilton, 2000). Money
and risk alone obviously do not completely explain the phenomenon of self-employment. However, for
the analysis of tax reforms, the partial effects of changes in net income and its variance are decisive,
which this study could identify.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e859a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e866" publication-type="other">
Notwithstanding, a large share of the population have lower net income annuities under the flat tax
than under the progressive tax. Especially for younger people with a still low, but rising, income, the
current tax loss has a higher weight than the discounted gain in the future, so the annuity of their income
stream decreases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e883a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e890" publication-type="other">
As the changes in the exit rates for the self-employed due to the flat tax scenarios are not significant,
the sample of the self-employed is not discussed here further.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e900a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e907" publication-type="other">
These figures refer to the probability of being observed as self-employed or dependently employed at
the time of the interview in year t and non-employed at the time of the interview in t+1. The risk of short-
term non-employment is thus higher.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e920a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e927" publication-type="other">
Unemployment benefits in Germany depend on the last net wage of an unemployed person, where
net wage is calculated using a lump-sum social security contributions rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e937a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e944" publication-type="other">
Shorter periods of benefit entitlement apply for people who have not previously contributed to
unemployment insurance for a sufficient number of months, and longer periods for older people with a
sufficient contributions record.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e957a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e964" publication-type="other">
See Steiner et al. (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e971a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e978" publication-type="other">
See Fossen (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e986a1310">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e993" publication-type="other">
y, is normalised to 0 for the base category j = 'unemployment/inactivity'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e1000a1310">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e1007" publication-type="other">
Having a self-employed father is used as an exclusion restriction as this characteristic is likely to
have an impact on the probability of being self-employed (e.g. Dunn and Holtz-Eakin, 2000) but is not
expected to have an influence on earnings after controlling for other relevant factors (cf. Taylor, 1996). In
Germany, self-employed mothers were rare in the generation of most respondents' parents, so only self-
employed fathers are used.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e1026a1310">
            <label>42</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e1033" publication-type="other">
The number of children and marital status are well known to influence the decision to participate in
the labour market and the choice between part-time and full-time work, especially for women, but are not
expected to influence gross earnings (cf. Rees and Shah, 1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e1046a1310">
            <label>43</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e1053" publication-type="other">
Income information for year t is obtained from retrospective questions in wave t+1 about a
respondent's average monthly gross income in I, differentiated by income from dependent employment
and self-employment. Income from self-employment (employment) is only averaged over months in
which the respondent was actually self-employed (employed), so the information remains accurate if the
respondent switched between employment states. Earnings levels rather than log earnings are used in the
regression to avoid excluding people who report zero earnings, which is sometimes observed for the self-
employed during temporary periods (cf. Hamilton, 2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e1079a1310">
            <label>44</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e1086" publication-type="other">
Additionally, dummy variables for German nationality and physical handicap are added to the
earnings equations, as these variables turn out to be important for the prediction of earnings. Year
dummies are also included to account for the business cycle.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e1099a1310">
            <label>45</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e1106" publication-type="other">
To obtain consistent predictions for the squared residuals, the predicted values from the log model
must be exponentiated and multiplied by the expected value of exp(e,y). A consistent estimator for the
expected value of exp(e,?) is obtained from a regression of the squared residuals on the exponentiated
predicted values from the log model through the origin. This procedure does not require normality of e,j.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e1123a1310">
            <label>46</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e1130" publication-type="other">
A11 monetary variables are deflated using the consumer price index (2001 = 100). The estimated real
hourly gross incomes are converted into nominal yearly gross incomes before entering the STSM, and the
resulting nominal yearly net incomes are converted back to real hourly net incomes afterwards, using the
average number of hours worked in the sample of full-time working people.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e1146a1310">
            <label>47</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e1153" publication-type="other">
The regression results for the other years are available from the author upon request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d29e1169a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1173" publication-type="other">
Bach, S., Corneo, G. and Steiner, V. (2008), 'Effective taxation of top incomes in Germany,
1992-2002', German Institute for Economic Research (DIW), Discussion Paper no. 767.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1183a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1187" publication-type="other">
Baumgartner, H. J. and Caliendo, M. (2008), 'Turning unemployment into self-employment:
effectiveness of two start-up programmes', Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics,
vol. 70, pp. 347-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1200a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1204" publication-type="other">
Blanchflower, D. G. (2000), 'Self-employment in OECD countries', Labour Economics, vol.
7, pp. 471-505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1218" publication-type="other">
— and Oswald, A. J. (1998), 'What makes an entrepreneur?', Journal of Labor Economics,
vol. 16, pp. 26-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1229a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1233" publication-type="other">
Bönke, T. and Corneo, G. (2006), 'Was hätte man sonst machen können? Alternativszenarien
zur rot-grünen Einkommensteuerreform' (What else could one have done? Alternative
scenarios in comparison to the income tax reform of the governmental coalition of Social
Democrats and Greens), Journal of Applied Social Science Studies, vol. 126, pp. 489-519.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1249a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1253" publication-type="other">
Borjas, G. J. and Bronars, S. G. (1989), 'Consumer discrimination and self-employment',
Journal of Political Economy, vol. 97, pp. 581-605.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1263a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1267" publication-type="other">
Brown, S., Farrel, L. and Sessions, J. G. (2006), 'Self-employment matching: an analysis of
dual earner couples and working households', Small Business Economics, vol. 26, pp.
155-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1280a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1284" publication-type="other">
Bruce, D. (1999), 'Do husbands matter? Married women entering self-employment', Small
Business Economics, vol. 13, pp. 317-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1294a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1298" publication-type="other">
— (2000), 'Effects of the United States tax system on transitions into self-employment',
Labour Economics, vol. 7, pp. 545-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1308a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1312" publication-type="other">
— (2002), 'Taxes and entrepreneurial endurance: evidence from the self-employed', National
Tax Journal, vol. 55, pp. 5-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1323a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1327" publication-type="other">
Caliendo, M. and Uhlendorff, A. (2008), 'Self-employment dynamics, state dependence and
cross-mobility patterns', Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no.
3900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1340a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1344" publication-type="other">
Corneo, G. (2005), 'The rise and likely fall of the German income tax, 1958-2005', CESifo
Economic Studies, vol. 51, pp. 159-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1354a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1358" publication-type="other">
Council of Economic Advisers to the Ministry of Finance (2004), 'Flat Tax oder Duale
Einkommensteuer? Zwei Entwürfe zur Reform der deutschen Einkommensbesteuerung'
(Flat tax or dual income tax? Two blueprints for a reform of German income taxation),
http://www.bundesfinanzministerium.de/nn_53848/DEAVirtschaft und Verwaltung/Fi
nanz und Wirtschaftspolitik/Wissenschaftlicher Beirat/Gutachten und Stellungna
hmen/Ausgewaehlte Texte/25707.html? nnn=true.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1381a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1385" publication-type="other">
Gullen, J. B. and Gordon, R. H. (2007), 'Taxes and entrepreneurial risk-taking: theory and
evidence for the U.S.', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 91, pp. 1479-505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1395a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1399" publication-type="other">
Davies, J. B. and Hoy, M. (2002), 'Flat rate taxes and inequality measurement', Journal of
Public Economics, vol. 84, pp. 33—46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1409a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1413" publication-type="other">
Dearing, H., Hofer, H., Lietz, C., Winter-Ebmer, R. and Wrohlich, K. (2007), 'Why are
mothers working longer hours in Austria than in Germany? A comparative
microsimulation analysis', Fiscal Studies, vol. 28, pp. 463-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1427a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1431" publication-type="other">
Disney, R. and Gathergood, J. (2009), 'Housing wealth, liquidity constraints and self-
employment', Labour Economics, vol. 16, pp. 79-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1441a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1445" publication-type="other">
Domar, E. D. and Musgrave, R. A. (1944), 'Proportional income taxation and risk-taking',
Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 58, pp. 388^-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1455a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1459" publication-type="other">
Dunn, T. and Holtz-Eakin, D. (2000), 'Financial capital, human capital, and the transition to
self-employment: evidence from intergenerational links', Journal of Labor Economics,
vol. 18, pp. 282-305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1472a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1476" publication-type="other">
Eckstein, Z. and Wolpin, K. I. (1989), 'The specification and estimation of dynamic stochastic
discrete choice models: a survey', Journal of Human Resources, vol. 24, pp. 562-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1486a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1490" publication-type="other">
European Commission (2004), 2003 Observatory of European SMEs, Luxembourg: Office for
Official Publications of the European Communities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1500a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1504" publication-type="other">
Evans, D. S. and Jovanovic, B. (1989), 'An estimated model of entrepreneurial choice under
liquidity constraints', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 97, pp. 808-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1515a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1519" publication-type="other">
— and Leighton, L. S. (1989), 'Some empirical aspects of entrepreneurship', American
Economic Review, vol. 79, pp. 519-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1529a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1533" publication-type="other">
Federal Ministry of Finance (2001), 'Stand und voraussichtliche Entwicklung der
Finanzwirtschaft im gesamtwirtschaftlichen Zusammenhang' (State and prospective
development of public finance within the macroeconomic context), Finanzbericht 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1546a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1550" publication-type="other">
— (2004), 'Steuerpolitik für den Mittelstand: Bilanz der Steuerreformpolitik der
Bundesregierung' (Tax policy for small and medium-sized businesses: taking stock
of the federal government's tax reform policy), Monatsbericht 6,
http://www.bundesfinanzministerium.de/nn_53848/DE/BMF Startseite/ Aktuelles/Monat
sbericht des BMF/2004/06/24751.html? nnn=true.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1569a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1573" publication-type="other">
Fossen, F. M. (2007), 'Risky earnings, taxation and entrepreneurial choice: a
microeconometric model for Germany', German Institute for Economic Research (DIW),
Discussion Paper no. 705.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1586a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1590" publication-type="other">
— (2008), 'Would a flat tax stimulate entrepreneurship in Germany? A behavioural
microsimulation analysis allowing for risk', German Institute for Economic Research
(DIW), Discussion Paper no. 773.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1603a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1607" publication-type="other">
— and Steiner, V. (2009), 'Income taxes and entrepreneurial choice: empirical evidence from
two German natural experiments', Empirical Economics, vol. 36, pp. 487-513.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1618a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1622" publication-type="other">
Fraser, S. and Greene, F. J. (2006), 'The effects of experience on entrepreneurial optimism
and uncertainty', Economica, vol. 73, pp. 169-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1632a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1636" publication-type="other">
Frick, J. R. and Grabka, M. M. (2004), 'Missing income data in the German SOEP: incidence,
imputation and its impact on the income distribution, updated version', German Institute
for Economic Research (DIW), Discussion Paper no. 376.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1649a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1653" publication-type="other">
Fuest, C., Peichl, A. and Schaefer, T. (2008), 'Is a flat tax reform feasible in a grown-up
democracy of western Europe? A simulation study for Germany', International Tax and
Public Finance, vol. 15, pp. 620-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1666a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1670" publication-type="other">
Gentry, W. M. and Hubbard, R. G. (2000), 'Tax policy and entrepreneurial entry', American
Economic Review, vol. 90, pp. 283-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1680a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1684" publication-type="other">
— and — (2004), "'Success taxes", entrepreneurial entry, and innovation', National Bureau
of Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 10551.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1694a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1698" publication-type="other">
Georgeliis, Y. and Wall, H. J. (2005), 'Gender differences in self-employment', International
Review of Applied Economics, vol. 19, pp. 321—42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1709a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1713" publication-type="other">
Greß, S., Walendzik, A. and Wasem, J. (2005), 'NichtVersicherte Personen im
Krankenversicherungssystem der Bundesrepublik Deutschland: Bestandsaufnahme und
Lösungsmöglichkeiten' (Non-insured people in Germany's health insurance system: stock
taking and possible solutions), University of Duisburg-Essen, Diskussionsbeitrag aus dem
Fachbereich Wirtschaftswissenschaften 147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1736" publication-type="other">
Haan, P. and Steiner, V. (2005), 'Distributional effects of the German tax reform 2000: a
behavioral microsimulation analysis', Journal of Applied Social Science Studies, vol. 125,
pp. 39^19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1749a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1753" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, B. H. (2000), 'Does entrepreneurship pay? An empirical analysis of the returns to
self-employment', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 108, pp. 604—31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1763a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1767" publication-type="other">
Heaton, J. and Lucas, D. (2000), 'Portfolio choice and asset prices: the importance of
entrepreneurial risk', Journal of Finance, vol. 55, pp. 1163-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1777a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1781" publication-type="other">
Holt, C. A. and Laury, S. K. (2002), 'Risk aversion and incentive effects', American
Economic Review, vol. 92, pp. 1644-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1791a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1795" publication-type="other">
Holtz-Eakin, D. and Rosen, H. S. (2005), 'Cash constraints and business start-ups:
deutschmarks versus dollars', Contributions to Economic Analysis and Policy, vol. 4, pp.
1-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1809a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1813" publication-type="other">
Hurst, E. and Lusardi, A. (2004), 'Liquidity constraints, household wealth, and
entrepreneurship', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 112, pp. 319-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1823a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1827" publication-type="other">
Kanbur, R. S. M. (1982), 'Entrepreneurial risk taking, inequality, and public policy: an
application of inequality decomposition analysis to the general equilibrium of progressive
taxation', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 90, pp. 1-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1840a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1844" publication-type="other">
Kihlstrom, R. E. and Laffont, J-J. (1979), 'A general equilibrium entrepreneurial theory of
firm formation based on risk aversion', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 87, pp. 719—
48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1857a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1861" publication-type="other">
Kirchhof, P. (2003), Einkommensteuergesetzbuch: ein Vorschlag zur Reform der Einkommen-
und Körperschaftsteuer (Code of income tax law: a proposal for a reform of income and
corporate taxes), Heidelberg: C. F. Müller Verlag.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1874a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1878" publication-type="other">
Lang, O., Nöhrbaß, K-H. and Stahl, K. (1997), 'On income tax avoidance: the case of
Germany', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 66, pp. 327—47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1888a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1892" publication-type="other">
Maddala, G. S. (1983), Limited-Dependent and Qualitative Variables in Econometrics, New
York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1903a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1907" publication-type="other">
McFadden, D. L. (1974), 'Conditional logit analysis of qualitative choice behavior', in P.
Zarembka (ed.), Frontiers in Econometrics, New York: Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1917a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1921" publication-type="other">
Mitschke, J. (2004), Erneuerung des deutschen Einkommensteuerrechts: Gesetzestextentwurf
und Begründung (Reform of the German income tax law: draft of a legal text and
justification), Cologne: Verlag Otto Schmidt.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1934a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1938" publication-type="other">
Moore, K. (2004), 'The effects of the 1986 and 1993 tax reforms on self-employment', Board
of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (US), Finance and Economics Discussion
Series, Working Paper no. 2004-05.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1951a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1955" publication-type="other">
Parker, S. C. (2003a), 'Does tax evasion affect occupational choice?', Oxford Bidletin of
Economics and Statistics, vol. 65, pp. 379-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1965a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1969" publication-type="other">
— (2003b), 'The distribution of wealth of older self-employed Britons', Fiscal Studies, vol.
24, pp. 23—43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1979a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1983" publication-type="other">
— (2005), 'Entrepreneurship among married couples in the United States: a simultaneous
probit approach', Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 1712.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1994a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1998" publication-type="other">
Pratt, J. W. (1964), 'Risk aversion in the small and in the large', Econometrica, vol. 32, pp.
122-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2008a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2012" publication-type="other">
Rees, H. and Shah, A. (1986), 'An empirical analysis of self-employment in the U.K.',
Journal of Applied Econometrics, vol. 1, pp. 95-108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2022a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2026" publication-type="other">
Schuetze, H. J. (2000), 'Taxes, economic conditions and recent trends in male self-
employment: a Canada-US comparison', Labour Economics, vol. 7, pp. 507^44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2036a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2040" publication-type="other">
— and Bruce, D. (2004), 'Tax policy and entrepreneurship', Swedish Economic Policy
Review, vol. 11, pp. 223-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2050a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2054" publication-type="other">
Schulze Buschoff, K. (2007), "'Neue Selbstständige" und soziale Sicherheit: ein europäischer
Vergleich' (The 'new self-employed' and social security: a European comparison), WSI
Mitteilungen, vol. 7, pp. 387-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2067a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2071" publication-type="other">
Steiner, V. and Wrohlich, K. (2005), 'Work incentives and labor supply effects of the "mini-
jobs reform" in Germany', Empirica, vol. 32, pp. 91-116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2082a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2086" publication-type="other">
—, —, Haan, P. and Geyer, J. (2008), Documentation of the Tax-Benefit Microsimulation
Model STSM: Version 2008, Data Documentation no. 31, Berlin: German Institute for
Economic Research (DIW).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2099a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2103" publication-type="other">
Taylor, M. P. (1996), 'Earnings, independence or unemployment: why become self-
employed?', Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, vol. 52, pp. 253-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2113a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2117" publication-type="other">
Van Praag, C. M. and Versloot, P. H. (2007), 'What is the value of entrepreneurship? A
review of recent research', Institute for the Study of Labor (IZA), Discussion Paper no.
3014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2130a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2134" publication-type="other">
Van Soest, A. (1995), 'Structural models of family labor supply: a discrete choice approach',
Journal of Human Resources, vol. 30, pp. 63-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e2144a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e2148" publication-type="other">
Wagner, G. G., Frick, J. R. and Schupp, J. (2007), 'The German Socio-Economic Panel Study
(SOEP): scope, evolution and enhancements', Journal of Applied Social Science Studies,
vol. 127, pp. 139-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
