<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000441</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008299</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Current Research in Machine Translation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Harold L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Somers</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>231</fpage>
         <lpage>246</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1993 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008299"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper, accompanied by peer group commentary and author's response, is a discussion paper concerning the state of the art in Machine Translation. The current orthodoxy is first summarized, then criticized. A number of research projects based on the standard architecture are discussed: they involve the use of Artificial Intelligence techniques, advanced linguistic theories, and sublanguage. Alternative approaches discussed are systems which develop or update their grammars semi-automatically, dialogue MT, and corpus-based MT including example-based and statistical approaches.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Second generation</kwd>
            <kwd>linguistics</kwd>
            <kwd>sublanguage</kwd>
            <kwd>dialogue MT</kwd>
            <kwd>corpus</kwd>
            <kwd>statistical</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d4469856e148a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e152" publication-type="other">
Abeillé, Anne, Yves Schabes and Aravind K. Joshi. 1990. Using Lexicalized Tags for
Machine Translation. In Karlgren, Vol. 3:1-6.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e162a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e166" publication-type="other">
Alam, Yukiko Sasaki. 1986. A Lexical-Functional approach to Japanese for the purpose of
Machine Translation. Computers and Translation 1, 199-214.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e176a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e180" publication-type="other">
Amores Carredano, José Gabriel. 1990. An LFG Machine Translation System in DCG-
PROLOG', MSc dissertation, UMIST, Manchester.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e190a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e194" publication-type="other">
Appelo, Lisette, Carol Fellinger and Jan Landsbergen. 1987. Subgrammars, rule classes and
control in the Rosetta translation system. Third Conference of the European Chapter of
the Association for Computational Linguistics (Copenhagen, April 1987), Proceedings,
118-133.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e211a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e215" publication-type="other">
Bateman, John A. 1990. Finding Translation Equivalents: an Application of Grammatical
Metaphor. In Karlgren, Vol. 2:13-18.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e225a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e229" publication-type="other">
Bátori, István, and Heinz J. Weber (Hgg.) 1986. Neue Ansätze in Maschineller
Sprachübersetzung: Wissensrepräsentation und Textbezug (Sprache und Information
13), Tübingen: Niemeyer Verlag.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e242a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e246" publication-type="other">
Beaven, John L., and Pete Whitelock. 1986. Machine Translation using isomorphic UCGs.
In Vargha, 32-35.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e256a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e260" publication-type="other">
Boitet, Ch. 1989. Speech synthesis and dialogue based Machine Translation. ATR Sympo-
sium on Basic Research for Telephone Interpretation, Kyoto, Japan, December 1989.
Proceedings. 6-5-1-9.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e273a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e277" publication-type="other">
Boitet, Christian, and Nikolai Nedobejkine. 1981. Recent developments in Russian-French
Machine Translation at Grenoble. Linguistics 19, 199-271.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e287a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e291" publication-type="other">
Brown, Peter F, John Cocke, Stephen A. Della Pietra, Vincent J. Della Pietra, Fredrick
Jelinek, Robert L. Mercer and Paul S. Roossin. 1988a. A statistical approach to
French/English translation. Proceedings, Second International Conference on Theo-
retical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation of Natural Languages, June
12-14, 1988, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. (Page numbers
not integrated).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e315a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e319" publication-type="other">
Brown, P.F., J. Cocke, S. Della Pietra, V. Della Pietra, F. Jelinek, R. Mercer and P. Roossin.
1988b. A statistical approach to language translation. In Vargha, 71-76.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e329a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e333" publication-type="other">
Carbonell, Jaime G., and Masaru Tomita. 1987. Knowledge-based Machine Translation,
the CMU approach. In Nirenburg (ed.), 68-89.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e343a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e347" publication-type="other">
Carroll, Jeremy J. 1989. Graph grammars: an approach to transfer-based M.T. exemplified
by a Turkish-English system. Ph.D. Thesis, Centre for Computational Linguistics,
UMIST, Manchester.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e360a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e364" publication-type="other">
Chevalier, M., P. Isabelle, F. Labelle and C. Laîné. 1981. La Traduction Appliquée á la
Traduction Automatique, Meta 26, 35-47.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e374a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e378" publication-type="other">
Durand Jacques, Paul Bennett, Valerio Allegranza, Frank van Eynde, Lee Humphreys, Paul
Schmidt and Erich Steiner. 1991. The Eurotra linguistic specifications: an overview.
Machine Translation 6, 103-147.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e391a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e395" publication-type="other">
Elliston, J.S.G. 1979. Computer-aided translation: a business viewpoint. In Barbara M.
Snell (ed.) Translating and the Computer, Amsterdam: North-Holland. 149-158.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e406a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e410" publication-type="other">
Green, Roy. 1982. The MT errors which cause most trouble to posteditors. In Veronica Law-
son (ed.) Practical Experience of Machine Translation, Amsterdam: North-Holland.
101-104.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e423a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e427" publication-type="other">
Hauenschild, Christa. 1986. KIT/NASEV oder die Problematik des Transfers bei der
maschinellen Übersetzung. In Bátori and Weber, 167-195.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e437a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e441" publication-type="other">
Huang, Xiuming. 1988. Semantic analysis in XTRA, an English-Chinese Machine Trans-
lation system. Computers and Translation 3, 101-120.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e451a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e455" publication-type="other">
Hutchins, W.J. 1986. Machine Translation: Past, present, future. Chichester: Ellis Horwood.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e462a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e466" publication-type="other">
Isabelle, Pierre, Marc Dymetman and Elliott Macklovitch. 1988. CRITTER: a translation
system for agricultural market reports. In Vargha, 261-266.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e476a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e480" publication-type="other">
Johnson, R.L. 1983. Parsing-an MT perspective. In Karen Sparck Jones and Yorick Wilks
(eds.) Automatic Natural Language Parsing, Chichester: Ellis Horwood. 32-38.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e491a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e495" publication-type="other">
Johnson, Roderick L. and Peter Whitelock. 1987. Machine Translation as an expert task.
In Nirenburg, 136-144.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e505a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e509" publication-type="other">
Jones, D. and J. Tsujii. High quality machine-driven text translation. Third International
Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation of Nat-
ural Languages, Austin, Texas (June 1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e522a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e526" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, Ronald M., Klaus Netter, Jürgen Wederkind and Annie Zaenen. 1989. Translation
by structural correspondences. Fourth Conference of the European Chapter of the
Association for Computational Linguistics, Manchester. Proceedings, 272-281.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e539a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e543" publication-type="other">
Karlgren, Hans (ed.) 1990. COLING-90: Papers presented to the 13th International Con-
ference on Computational Linguistics, Helsinki: Yliopistopaino.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e553a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e557" publication-type="other">
Kittredge, R. and J. Lehrberger (eds.) 1982. Sublanguage: Studies of language in restricted
semantic domains. Berlin: de Gruyter.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e567a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e571" publication-type="other">
Kosaka, Michiko, Virginia Teller and Ralph Grishman. 1988. A sublanguage approach to
Japanese-English Machine Translation. In Dan Maxwell, Klaus Schubert and Toon
Witkam (eds.) New Directions in Machine Translation (Distributed Language Trans-
lation 4), Dordrecht: Foris, 109-120.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e588a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e592" publication-type="other">
Kudo, Ikuo and Hirosato Nomura. 1986. Lexical-functional transfer: a transfer framework
in a Machine Translation system based on LFG. 11th International Conference on
Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of Coling '86, Bonn. 112-114.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e605a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e609" publication-type="other">
Landsbergen, Jan. 1987a. Isomorphic grammars and their use in the ROSETTA transla-
tion system. In Margaret King (ed.) Machine Translation Today: the state of the art,
Edinburgh: Edinburgh University Press. 351-372.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e622a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e626" publication-type="other">
Landsbergen, Jan. 1987b. Montague grammar and Machine Translation. In P. Whitelock,
M.M. Wood, H.L. Somers, R. Johnson and P. Bennett (eds.) Linguistic Theory and
Computer Applications, London (1987): Academic Press. 113-147.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e639a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e643" publication-type="other">
Lehrberger, John and Laurent Bourbeau. 1988. Machine Translation: Linguistic Charac-
teristics of MT Systems and General Methodology of Evaluation, Amsterdam: John
Benjamins.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e656a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e660" publication-type="other">
McCord, Michael C. 1989. Design of LMT: a Prolog-based Machine Translation system.
Computational Linguistics 15, 33-52.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e670a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e674" publication-type="other">
McDonald, David D. 1987. Natural language generation: complexities and techniques. In
Nirenburg, 192-224.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e685a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e689" publication-type="other">
Nagao, Makoto. 1984. A Framework of a Mechanical Translation between Japanese and
English by Analogy Principle. In A. Elithorn and R. Banerji (eds) Artificial and Human
Intelligence, Amsterdam: North Holland, 172-180.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e702a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e706" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, Sergei (ed.). 1987. Machine Translation: Theoretical and methodological issues,
Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e716a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e720" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, Sergei. 1989. Knowledge-based Machine Translation. Machine Translation 4,
5-24.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e730a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e734" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, Sergei and Jaime Carbonell. 1987. Integrating discourse pragmatics and propo-
sitional knowledge for multilingual natural language processing. Computers and Trans-
lation!2, 105-116.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e747a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e751" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, Sergei and Lori Levin. 1989. Knowledge representation support. Machine
Translation 4, 25-52.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e761a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e765" publication-type="other">
Nishida, Fujio, Shinobu Takamatsu, Tadaaki Tani and Tsunehisa Doi. 1988. Feedback of
correcting information in postediting to a Machine Translation system. In Vargha,
476-481.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e779a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e783" publication-type="other">
Nishida, Fujio and Shinobu Takamatsu. 1990. Automated procedures for the improvement
of a Machine Translation system by feedback from postediting. Machine Translation
5, 223-246.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e796a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e800" publication-type="other">
Pym, P.J. 1990. Pre-editing and the use of simplified writing for MT: an engineer's ex-
perience of operating an MT system. In Pamela Mayorcas (ed.) Translating and the
Computer 10: The translation environment 10 years on, London: Aslib. 80-96.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e813a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e817" publication-type="other">
Raw, Anthony, Bart Vandecapelle and Frank van Eynde. 1988. Eurotra: an overview.
Interface 3, 5-32.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e827a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e831" publication-type="other">
Raw, Anthony, Frank van Eynde, Pius ten Hacken, Heleen Hoekstra and Bart Vande-
capelle. 1989. An introduction to the Eurotra Machine Translation system. Working
Papers in Natural Language Processing 1, TAAL Technologie, Utrecht and Katholieke
Universiteit Leuven.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e847a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e851" publication-type="other">
Rohrer, Christian. 1986. Maschinelle Übersetzung mit Unifikationsgrammatiken. In Bátori
and Weber, 75-99.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e861a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e865" publication-type="other">
Rupp, C.J. 1989. Situation Semantics and Machine Translation. Fourth Conference of
the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Manchester,
Proceedings, 308-318.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e879a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e883" publication-type="other">
Sadler, Louisa, Ian Crookston, Doug Arnold and Andy Way. 1990. LFG and Iranslation.
Third International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine
Translation of Natural Languages, Austin, Texas (June 1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e896a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e900" publication-type="other">
Saito Hiroaki and Masaru Tomita. On automatic composition of stereotypic documents in
foreign languages. Presented at 1st International Conference on Applications of Artifi-
cial Intelligence to Engineering Problems, Southampton, April 1986. Research Report
CMU-CS-86-107, Department of Computer Science, Carnegie-Mellon University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e916a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e920" publication-type="other">
Sato, Satoshi and Makoto Nagao. 1990. Toward Memory-Based Iranslation. In Karlgren,
Vol. 3:247-252.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e930a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e934" publication-type="other">
Slocum, Jonathan. 1985. A survey of Machine Translation: its history, current status, and
future prospects. Computational Linguistics 11, 1-17.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e944a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e948" publication-type="other">
Somers, Harold. 1986. Some Thoughts on Interface Structure(s). In WolFram Wilss und
Klaus-Dirk Schmitz (Hgg.) Maschinelle Übersetzung-Methoden und Werkzeuge,
Tübingen: Max Niemeyer Verlag, 81-99.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e961a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e965" publication-type="other">
Somers, Harold. 1988. Where will MT be in the next 20 years-honestly? (Position paper for
Panel Session "Paradigms for MT" Second International Conference on Theoretical
and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation of Natural Languages, Camegie
Mellon University, Pittsburgh PA, June 12-14, 1988. CCL/UMIST Report No. 88/5,
Centre for Computational Linguistics, UMIST, Manchester, May/September 1988.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e985a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e989" publication-type="other">
Somers, Harold L., Jun-ichi Tsujii and Danny Jones. 1990. Machine Translation without a
source text. In Karlgren, Vol. 3:271-276.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e999a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1003" publication-type="other">
Steiner, Erich (ed.). 1991. Special issues on Eurotra. Machine Translation 6 (2-3).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1010a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1014" publication-type="other">
Sumita, Eiichiro, Hitoshi Iida and Hideo Kohyama. 1990. Translating with Examples: A
New Approach to Machine Translation. Third International Conference on Theoretical
and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation of Natural Languages, Austin, Texas
(June 1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1030a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1034" publication-type="other">
Trabulsi, Sami. 1989. Le système SYSTRAN. In La Traduction Assistée par Ordi-
nateur: Perspectives technologiques, industrielles et économiques envisageables à
l'horizon 1990, Actes du Séminaire international (Paris 17-18 mars 1988) et dossiers
complémentaires. Paris: DAICADIF. 15-27.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1050a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1054" publication-type="other">
Tsujii, Jun-ichi, Sophia Ananiadou, Jeremy J. Carroll and John D. Phillips. 1990. Method-
ologies for Development of Sublanguage MT Systems, CCL Report 90/10, Centre for
Computational Linguistics, UMIST, Manchester.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1067a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1071" publication-type="other">
Tsujii, Jun-ichi and Makoto Nagao. 1988. Dialogue translation vs. text translation-inter-
pretation based approach. In Vargha, 688-693.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1082a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1086" publication-type="other">
van der Korst, Bieke. 1989. Functional Grammar and Machine Translation. In John H.
Connolly and Simon C. Dik (eds.) Functional Grammar and the computer, Dordrecht:
Foris. 289-316.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1099a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1103" publication-type="other">
van Eynde, Frank. 1988. The analysis of tense and aspect in Eurotra. In Vargha, 699-704.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1110a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1114" publication-type="other">
van Noord, Gertjan, Joke Dorrepaal, Pim van der Eijk, Maria Florenza and Louis des Tombe.
1991. The MiMo2 Research System. Third International Conference on Theoretical and
Methodological Issues in Machine Translation of Natural Languages, Austin, Texas
(June 1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1130a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1134" publication-type="other">
Vargha, Dénes (ed.). 1988. COLING Budapest: Proceedings of the 12th International
Conference on Computational Linguistics, Budapest: John von Neumann Society for
Computing Sciences.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1147a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1151" publication-type="other">
Vasconcellos, Muriel and Marjorie León. 1985. SPANAM and ENGSPAN: Machine Trans-
lation at the Pan American Health Organization. Computational Linguistics 11, 122-
136.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1164a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1168" publication-type="other">
Vauquois, Bernard. 1988. The approach of Geta to automatic translation: comparison
with some other methods. Paper presented at International Symposium on Machine
Translation, Riyadh, March 1985; in Christian Boitet (ed.) Bernard Vauquois et la
TAO: Vingt-cinq ans de traduction automatique-Analectes, Grenoble: Association
Champollion, 631-686.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1188a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1192" publication-type="other">
Vauquois, Bernard and Christian Boitet. 1985. Automated translation at Grenoble Univer-
sity. Computational Linguistics 11, 28-36.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1202a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1206" publication-type="other">
Vsyesoyouznyi Centr Perevodov. 1989. Meždunarodnyi Seminar po Mašinomu Perevodu
"Evm i Perevod 89" (Tbilisi, 27 noyabra-2 dekabrya, 1989 g.) Tezisy Dokladov.
Moskva: VCP.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1219a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1223" publication-type="other">
Wehrli, Eric. 1990. STS: an Experimental Sentence Translation System. In Karlgren, Vol.
1:76-78.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1233a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1237" publication-type="other">
Whitelock, P.J., M. McGee Wood, B.J. Chandler, N. Holden and H.J. Horsfall. Strategies
for Interactive Machine Translation: the Experience and Implications of the UMIST
Japanese Project. 11th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Pro-
ceedings of Coling '86, Bonn, 329-334.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1253a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1257" publication-type="other">
Wilks, Yorick. More advanced Machine Translation? International Forum for Translation
Technology IFTT '89 "Harmonizing Human Beings and Computers in Translation",
Oiso, Japan, April 1989. Manuscripts &amp; Program, 59.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1270a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1274" publication-type="other">
Mary McGee Wood and Brian J. Chandler. 1988. Machine Translation for Monolinguals.
In Vargha, 760-763.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1285a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1289" publication-type="other">
World SYSTRAN Conference. 1986. Terminologie et Traduction 1 Numéro Spécial.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d4469856e1296a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d4469856e1300" publication-type="other">
Zajac, Rémi. 1990. A Relational Approach to Translation. Third International Confer-
ence on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation of Natural
Languages, Austin, Texas (June 1990).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
