<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277987</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of the Combustion Instability-NOx Tradeoff in a Dual Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Klos</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Janecek</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kokjohn</surname>
                  <given-names>Sage</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>821</fpage>
         <lpage>830</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277987"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The tradeoff between NOx emissions and combustion instability in an engine operating in the dual-fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) combustion mode was investigated using a combination of engine experiments and detailed CFD modeling. Experiments were performed on a single cylinder version of a General Motors/Fiat JTD 1.9L four-cylinder diesel engine. Gasoline was injected far upstream of the intake valve using an air assisted injector and fuel vaporization system and diesel was injected directly into the cylinder using a common rail injector. The timing of the diesel injection was swept from −70° ATDC to −20° ATDC while the gasoline percentage was adjusted to hold the average combustion phasing (CA50) and load (IMEPg) constant at 0.5° ATDC and 7 bar, respectively. At each operating point the variation in IMEP, peak PRR, and CA50 was calculated from the measured cylinder pressure trace and NOx, CO, soot and UHC were recorded. It was observed that a late injection strategy with start-of-injection (SOI) timings ranging from −30° ATDC to −20° ATDC could significantly reduce cycle-to-cycle variation with only a marginal increase in NOx emissions. To explain the sources of increased combustion stability, detailed computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations were used. The CFD simulations confirmed that the late injection timing produced a higher equivalence ratio ignition site that is less sensitive to fluctuations. By optimizing injection timing large improvements in combustion instability can be made while still maintaining low temperature combustion-like emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “An Experimental Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):700-716, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Curran, S., Wagner, R., and Reitz, R., “Effects of Biofuel Blends on RCCI Combustion in a Light-Duty, Multi- Cylinder Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):488-503, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01- 1653.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Yang, Y., and Dronniou, N., “Boosted HCCI - Controlling Pressure-Rise Rates for Performance Improvements using Partial Fuel Stratification with Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1169-1189, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente V., Tunestal P. and Johansson B., “Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion, the Future of Internal Combustion Engines?,” International Journal of Engine Research, vol. 12, no. 3, pp. 194-208, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn S., Hanson R., Splitter D. and Reitz R., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Combustion: A Pathway to High Efficiency Clean Combustion,” Int. J. Engine Res., vol. 12, no. 3, pp. 209-226, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsy A., “Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) with Alternative Fuels, Phd Thesis in Mechanical Engineering,” University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolodziej C. P. and Ciatti S. A., “Effects of Injector Nozzle Inclusion Angle on Extending the Lower Load Limit of Gasoline Compression Ignition Using 87 AKI Gasoline,” in ASME ICEF, Columbus, IN, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden A., “KIVA-3V, Release 2, Improvments to KIVA-3V. LAUR- 99-915,” 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abani N., Munnannur A. and Reitz R., “Reduction of Numerical Parameter Dependencies in Diesel Spray Models,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, vol. 130, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale J. and Reitz R., “Modeling Spray Atomization with the Kelvin- Helmholtz/Rayleigh-Taylor Hybrid Model,” Atomization and Sprays, vol. 9, pp. 623-650, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han Z. and Reitz R., “Turbulence Modeling of INternal Combustion Engines using RNG k-e Models,” Combustion Science and Technology, vol. 106, pp. 267-295, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra Y. and Reitz R., “A Combustion Model for IC Engine Combustion Simulations with Multi-component Fuels,” Combust. Flame, vol. 158, no. 1, pp. 69-90, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun Y., Diesel Combustion Optimization and Emissions Reduction using Adaptive Injection Strategies (AIS) with Improved Numerical Models, PhD Thesis in Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin - Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puduppakkam, K., Liang, L., Naik, C., Meeks, E. et al., “Use of Detailed Kinetics and Advanced Chemistry-Solution Techniques in CFD to Investigate Dual-Fuel Engine Concepts,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1127- 1149, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0895.S.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Kadota, T., “Models for Combustion and Formation of Nitric Oxide and Soot in Direct Injection Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 760129, 1976, doi:10.4271/760129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P., and Amsden, A., “A Spray/Wall Interaction Submodel for the KIVA-3 Wall Film Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0271, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goodwin D., “Cantera: An object-oriented software toolkit for chemical kinetics, thermodynamics, and transport processes,” 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V., Curran, S., Barone, T., Lewis, S. et al., “Emission Characteristics of a Diesel Engine Operating with In-Cylinder Gasoline and Diesel Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):946-955, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
