<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014679</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Development of Complexity, Accuracy and Fluency in L2 Written Production through Informal Participation in Online Activities</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kusyk</surname>
                  <given-names>Meryl</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Strasbourg, University of Education Karlsruhe.</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Meryl Kusyk is a PhD candidate in a joint doctoral program between the University of Strasbourg and the University of Education Karlsruhe. Her research interests include second language development from a dynamic systems perspective and second language development through exposure to online media in both formal and informal contexts.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014673</issue-id>
         <fpage>75</fpage>
         <lpage>96</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014679"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>Research into the online informal learning of English (OILE) examines how nonnative speakers of English may develop L2 skills through participation in leisure activities on the Internet in the target language. Such activities include, e.g., watching television series, films, or videos, interacting on Facebook, reading articles, or listening to music. Recent OILE studies have focused on students at French universities and have sought to both inventory language users’ online participation habits and track their L2 development (Kusyk &amp; Sockett, 2012; Sockett, 2011, 2014; Sockett &amp; Kusyk, 2015; Toffoli &amp; Sockett, 2015). This article provides updated OILE participation data on French students and, for the first time, German university students. In order to increase awareness about current OILE practices, results of a questionnaire (N = 953) of OILE habits are presented. In addition, development in complexity, accuracy, and fluency of three individual study participants was tracked over a period of five months. Results show a great deal of inter- and intraindividual variation, highlighting the need to consider L2 development as a complex and nonlinear process, especially when analyzed within an online, informal context.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>online informal learning of English (OILE)</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>second language development</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>L2 written production</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>case studies</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Dynamic Systems Theory</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>usage-based language learning</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>CAF</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aubin, D., &amp; Dahan Dalmedico, A. (2002). Writing the history of dynamical systems and chaos: Longue durée and revolution, disciplines and cultures. Historia Mathematica, 29(3), 273–339. https://doi.org/10.1006/hmat.2002.2351</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baba, K. &amp; Nitta, R. (2014). Phase transitions in development of writing fluency from a complex dynamic systems perspective. Language Learning, 64(1), 1–35. https://doi.org/10.1111/lang.12033</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Behrens, H. (2009). Usage-based and emergentist approaches to language acquisition. Linguistics, 47(2), 383–411. https://doi.org/10.1515/LING.2009.014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bybee, J. (2008). Usage-based grammar and second language acquisition. In P. Robinson &amp; N. C. Ellis (Eds.), Handbook of cognitive linguistics and second language acquisition (pp. 216–236). New York, NY; London: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bybee, J., &amp; Beckner, C. (2009). Usage-based theory. In B. Heine &amp; H. Narrog (Eds.), The Oxford handbook of linguistic analysis (pp. 827–855). Oxford: Oxford University Press. https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199544004.013.0032</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cameron, L., &amp; Larsen-Freeman, D. (2007). Complex systems and applied linguistics. International Journal of Applied Linguistics, 17(2), 226–240. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1473-4192.2007.00148.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cook, V. (2002). Background to the L2 User. In V. Cook (Ed.), Portraits of the L2 User (pp. 1–28). Clevedon: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Council of Europe. (2011). Common reference levels self-assessment grid. http://www.coe.int/t/dg4/education/elp/elpreg/Source/assessement_grid/assessment_grid_english.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Bot, K., &amp; Larsen-Freeman, D. (2011). Researching second language development from a dynamic systems theory perspective. In M. Verspoor, K. de Bot, &amp; W. Lowie (Eds.), A dynamic approach to second language development: Methods and techniques (pp. 5–23). Amsterdam/Philadelphia: John Benjamins Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.29.01deb</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Bot, K., Lowie, W., Thorne, S. L., &amp; Verspoor, M. (2103). Dynamic systems theory as a comprehensive theory of second language development. In M. d. P. García Mayo, M. J. Gutiérrez Mangado, &amp; M. M. Adrián (Eds.), Contemporary approaches to second language acquisition (pp. 199–220). Amsterdam: John Benjamins.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Bot, K., Lowie, W., &amp; Verspoor, M. (2007). A Dynamics Systems Theory approach to second language acquisition. Bilingualism: Language and Cognition, 10(1), 7–22. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1366728906002732</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dörnyei, Z. (2009). The psychology of second language acquisition. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellis, R., &amp; Barkhuizen, G. (2005). Analyzing learner language. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hunt, K. (1965). Grammatical structures written at three grade levels. Urbana, IL: The National Council of Teachers of English.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishikawa, T. (2007). The effect of manipulating task complexity along the [+/− Here-and-Now] dimension on L2 written narrative discourse. In M. d. P. García Mayo (Ed.), Investigating tasks in formal language learning (pp. 136–156). Clevedon: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawauchi, C. (2005). The effects of strategic planning on the oral narratives of learners with low and high intermediate L2 proficiency. In R. Ellis (Ed.), Planning and task performance in a second language (pp. 143–165). Amsterdam: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.11.09kaw</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kusyk, M., &amp; Sockett, G. (2012). From informal resource usage to incidental language acquisition: Language uptake from online television viewing in English. ASp, La Revue Du GERAS, 62, 45–65. https://doi.org/10.4000/asp.3104</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langacker, R. (1987). Foundations of cognitive grammar (Vol. 1). Stanford, CA: Stanford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsen-Freeman, D. (1997). Chaos/complexity science and second language acquisition. Applied Linguistics, 18(2), 141–165. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/18.2.141</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsen-Freeman, D. (2006). The emergence of complexity, fluency, and accuracy in the oral and written production of five Chinese learners of English. Applied Linguistics, 27(4), 590–619. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/aml029</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsen-Freeman, D. (2015). Ten “lessons” from Complex Dynamic Systems Theory: What is on offer. In Z. Dörnyei, P. MacIntyre, &amp; A. Henry (Eds.), Motivational dynamics in language learning (pp. 11–19). Bristol: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsen-Freeman, D., &amp; Cameron, L. (2008). Research methodology on language development from a Complex Systems perspective. The Modern Language Journal 92(2), 200–213. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2008.00714.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Norris, J. M., &amp; Ortega, L. (2009). Towards an organic approach to investigating CAF in instructed SLA: The case of complexity. Applied Linguistics, 30(4), 555–578. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/amp044</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nowak, A., Vallacher, R., &amp; Zochowski, M. (2005). The emergence of personality: Dynamic foundations of individual variation. Developmental Review, 25(3–4), 351–385. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dr.2005.10.004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skehan, P. (1996). Second language acquisition research and task-based instruction. In J. Willis &amp; D. Willis (Eds.), Challenge and change in language teaching (pp. 17–30). Oxford: Heinemann.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skehan, P. (1998). Task-based instruction. Annual Review of Applied Linguistics, 18, 268–286. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0267190500003585</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skehan, P. (2009). Modelling second language performance: Integrating complexity, accuracy, fluency, and lexis. Applied Linguistics, 30(4), 510–532. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/amp047</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sockett, G. (2011). From the cultural hegemony of English to online informal learning: Cluster frequency as an indicator of relevance in authentic documents. ASp, La Revue Du GERAS, 60, 5–20. https://doi.org/10.4000/asp.2469</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sockett, G. (2014). The online informal learning of English. Basingstoke: Palgrave Macmillan. https://doi.org/10.1057/9781137414885</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sockett, G., &amp; Kusyk, M. (2015). Online informal learning of English: Frequency effects in the uptake of chunks of language from participation in web-based activities. In T. Cadierno &amp; S. W. Eskildsen (Eds.), Usage-based perspectives on second language learning (pp. 153–177). Berlin: De Gruyter Mouton. https://doi.org/10.1515/9783110378528-009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Storch, N., &amp; Wigglesworth, G. (2007). Writing tasks. The effects of collaboration. In M. d. P. García Mayo (Ed.), Investigating tasks in formal language learning (pp. 157–177). Clevedon: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toffoli, D., &amp; Sockett, G. (2010). How non-specialist students of English practice informal learning using web 2.0 tools. ASp, La Revue Du GERAS, 58, 125–144. https://doi.org/10.4000/asp.1851</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toffoli, D., &amp; Sockett, G. (2015). University teachers’ perceptions of online informal learning of English (OILE). Computer Assisted Language Learning, 28(1), 7–21. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2013.776970</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomasello, M. (2000). First steps toward a usage-based theory of language acquisition. Cognitive Linguistics, 11(1–2), 61–82. https://doi.org/10.1515/cogl.2001.012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomasello, M. (2009). The usage-based theory of language acquisition. In E. L. Bavin (Ed.), The Cambridge handbook of child language (pp. 69–88). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511576164.005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Geert, P. (1991). A dynamic systems model of cognitive and language growth. Psychological Review, 98(1), 3–53. https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-295X.98.1.3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Geert, P., &amp; Steenbeek, H. (2005). Explaining after by before: Basic aspects of a dynamic systems approach to the study of development. Development as Self-Organization: New Approaches to the Psychology and Neurobiology of Development, 25(3–4), 408–442. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dr.2005.10.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VanPatten, B. (1990). Attending to form and content in the input: An experiment in conciousness. Studies in Second Language Acquisition, 12(03), 287–301. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0272263100009177</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vercellotti, M. L. (2015). The development of complexity, accuracy, and fluency in second language performance: A longitudinal study. Applied Linguistics. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/amv002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verspoor, M., &amp; Behrens, H. (2011). Dynamic systems theory and a usage-based approach to second language development. In M. Verspoor, K. de Bot, &amp; W. Lowie (Eds.), A dynamic approach to second language development: Methods and techniques (pp. 25–38). Amsterdam/Philadelphia, PA: John Benjamins Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.29</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verspoor, M., de Bot, K., &amp; Lowie, W. (Eds.) (2011). A dynamic approach to second language development: Methods and techniques. Amsterdam/Philadelphia, PA: John Benjamins Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.29</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, J. (2015). Designing for language learning in the wild: Creating social infrastructure for second language learning. In T. Cadierno &amp; S. W. Eskildsen (Eds.), Usage-based Perspectives on Second Language Learning (pp. 75–101). Berlin: De Gruyter Mouton. https://doi.org/10.1515/9783110378528-006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wendel, J. (1997). Planning and second language narrative production (Doctoral dissertation). Temple University. Available from ProQuest dissertation and theses database. UMI No.9813575.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolfe-Quintero, K., Inagaki, S., &amp; Kim, H.-Y. (1998). Second language development in writing: Measures of fluency, accuracy and complexity. Honolulu: University of Hawai’i Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
