<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794433</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Finance and Business Taxes</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Impact of Financial Transaction Taxes on Stock Markets</article-title>
            <subtitle>Timing, Heterogeneity, and Migration</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Eichfelder</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lau</surname>
                  <given-names>Mona</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>45</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794433"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We focus on the impact of the French 2012 financial transaction tax (FTT) on trading volumes and volatility. We extend the empirical research by identifying FTT announcement and short-run treatment effects, which can distort difference-in-differences estimates. We also consider long-run volatility measures that better fit the French FTT’s legislative design, the heterogeneity of market reactions and the migration of trading volumes to potential substitute stocks. While we find a strong short-term impact on trading volume (announcement effects and short-run effects), the long-run treatment effect is much weaker and only significant for less liquid stocks not participating at the Supplemental Liquidity Provision program of NYSE Euronext. We further find a significant reduction of long-term volatility measures after the FTT effective date as evidence for a market-stabilizing effect, and a significant increase in the trading volume of potential substitute stocks traded at NYSE Euronext as evidence for a migration of trading volumes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Aliber, R. Z., Chowdhry, B. and Yan, S. (2003) Some evidence that a Tobin tax on foreign exchange transactions may increase volatility, European Finance Review 7, 481–510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Baltagi, B. H., Li, D. and Li, Q. (2006) Transaction tax and stock market behavior: Evidence from an emerging market, Empirical Economics 31, 393–408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Becchetti, L., Ferrari, M. and Trenta, U. (2014) The impact of the French Tobin tax, Journal of Financial Stability 15, 127–148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bertrand, M., Duflo, E. and Mullainathan, S. (2004) How much should we trust in difference-indifferences estimates? Quarterly Journal of Economics 119, 249–275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Blouin, J., Ready, J. S. and Shackelford, D. (2002) Equity price pressure from the 1998 reduction in the capital gains holding period, Journal of the American Taxation Association 24 (Supplement), 70–93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bond, S., Hawkins, M. and Klemm, A. (2005) Stamp duty on shares and its effect on share prices, FinanzArchiv 61, 275–297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Brooks, R. M., Patel, A. and Su, T. (2003) How the equity market responds to unanticipated events, Journal of Business 76, 109–133.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Burman, L. E., Gale, W. G., Gault, S., Kim, B., Nunns,. J., Rosenthal, S., (2016) National Tax Journal 69, 171–216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Capelle-Blancard, G. (2015) Curbing the growth of stock trading? Order-to-trade ratios and financial transaction taxes, BAFFI CAREFIN Centre Research Paper Series No. 2015–6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Capelle-Blancard, G. (2016) The abrogation of the “impÔt sur les óperations de bourse” did not foster the French stock market, Finance Research Letters 17, 257–266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Capelle-Blancard, G. and Havrylchyk, O. (2013) The impact of the French securities transaction tax on market liquidity and volatility, CES Working Paper No. 2013.85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Coelho, M. (2016) Dodging Robin Hood: Responses to France and Italy’s financial transaction taxes, SSRN Working Paper No. 2389166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Colliard, J.-E. and Hoffmann, P. (2013) Sand in the chips? Evidence on taxing transactions in modern markets, Unpublished Working Paper, European Central Bank, Frankfurt.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Colliard, J.-E. and Hoffmann, P. (2017) Financial transaction taxes, market composition, and liquidity, Journal of Finance (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Dávila, E., 2016. Optimal financial transaction taxes, Working Paper, NYU Stern.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Deng, Y., Liu, X. and Wei, S.-J. (2014) One fundamental and two taxes: When does a Tobin tax reduce financial price volatility? NBER Working Paper No. 19974.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Dhaliwal, D. and Li, O. Z. (2016) Investor tax heterogeneity and ex-dividend day trading volume, Journal of Finance 61, 463–490.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Eichfelder, S., Noth, F., Lau, M. (2017) Financial transaction taxes: Announcement effects, short-run effects and long-run effects, IWH Working Paper 4/2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Fama, E. F. (1970) Efficient capital markets: A review of theory and empirical work, Journal of Finance 25, 383–417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gomber, P., Haferkorn, M. and Zimmermann, K. (2016) Securities transaction tax and market quality – The case of France, European Financial Management 22, 313–337.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Habermeier, K. and Kirilenko, A. (2003) Securities transaction taxes and financial markets, International Monetary Fund Staff Papers 50, 165–180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Haferkorn, M. and Zimmermann, K. (2013) Securities transaction tax and market quality – The case of France, Working Paper, Faculty of Economics and Business Administration, Goethe University Frankfurt.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hau, H. (2006) The role of transaction costs for financial volatility: Evidence from the Paris Bourse, Journal of the European Economic Association 4, 862–890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Hemmelgarn, T. and Nicodème, G. (2010) The 2008 financial crisis and taxation policy, CESifo Working Paper Series No. 2939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Hirshleifer, D., Lim, S. S. and Teoh, S. H. (2009) Driven to distraction: Extraneous events and underreaction to earnings news, Journal of Finance 63, 2287–2323.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">House, C.L., Shapiro, M.D. (2008) Temporary investment tax incentives: Theory with evidence from bonus depreciation. American Economic Review 98 (3), 737–768.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Hu, S.-Y. (1998) The effects of the stock transaction tax on the stock market – Experiences from Asian markets, Pacific-Basin Finance Journal 6, 347–364.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Jones, C. M. and Seguin, P. J. (1997) Transaction costs and price volatility: Evidence from commission deregulation, American Economic Review 87, 728–737.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Kennedy, P. (1981) Estimation with correctly interpreted dummy variables in semi-logarithmic equations, American Economic Review 71, 801.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Liu, S. and Zhu, Z. (2009) Transaction costs and price volatility: New evidence from the Tokyo Stock Exchange, Journal of Financial Services Research 36, 65–83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Matheson, T. (2011) Taxing financial transactions: Issues and evidence. IMF Working Paper 11/54, IMF, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Matheson, T. (2014) The effect of a low-rate transaction tax on a highly liquid market, FinanzArchiv 70, 487–510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Meyer, S., Wagener, M. and Weinhardt, C. (2015) Politically motivated taxes in financial markets: The case of the French financial transaction tax, Journal of Financial Services Research 47, 177–202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">NYSE Euronext (2012) Annual renewal of the Supplemental Liquidity Provider programme on European blue chips, Info Flash European Cash Markets, https://www.euronext.com/sites/www.euronext.com/files/ifca120326.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Pellizari, P. and Westerhoff, F. (2009) Some effects of transaction taxes under different micro structures, Journal of Economic Behavior and Organisation 72, 850–863.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Petersen, M. A. (2009) Estimating standard errors in finance panel data sets: Comparing approaches, Review of Financial Studies 22, 435–480.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Pomeranets, A. and Weaver, D. (2013) Securities transaction taxes and market quality, SSRN Working Paper No. 1980185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">PriceWaterhouseCoopers (2012) French financial transaction tax on equity securities, https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/financial-services/financial-transaction-taxes-timeline/assets/frenchaug1.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Schwert, G. W. and Seguin, P. J. (1993) Securities transaction taxes: An overview of costs, benefits and unresolved questions. Financial Analysts Journal 49, 27–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Shackelford, D. A., Shaviro, D. N. and Slemrod, J. (2010) Taxation and the financial sector, National Tax Journal 63, 781–806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Song, F. M. and Zhang, J. (2005) Securities transaction tax and market volatility, Economic Journal 115, 1103–1120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Stiglitz, J. E. (1989) Using tax policy to curb speculative short-term trading, Journal of Financial Services Research 3, 101–115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Summers, L. H. and Summers, V. P. (1989) When financial markets work too well: A cautious case for a securities transactions tax, Journal of Financial Services Research 3, 261–286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Tetlock, P. C. (2011) All the news that’s fit to reprint: Do investors react to stale information? Review of Financial Studies 24, 1481–1512.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Umlauf, S. R. (1993) Transaction taxes and the behavior of the Swedish stock market, Journal of Financial Economics 33, 277–210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>FTT introduction process in France</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Trading volume, German and UK large cap as control</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Trading volume, French small cap as control</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Volatility measures, German and UK large cap as control</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Migration of trading volume to Dutch and LUX stocks</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Descriptive statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Trading volume, baseline tests</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Volatility, baseline tests</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Volume, heterogeneity tests</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Volatility, heterogeneity tests</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Migration of Trading Volume</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
