<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277861</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Design and Evaluation of Output Profile Shaping of an Internal Combustion Engine for Noise &amp; Vibration Improvement</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yamaura</surname>
                  <given-names>Hiroki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Mitsubishi Automotive Engineering Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ishihama</surname>
                  <given-names>Masao</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Kanagawa Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Togai</surname>
                  <given-names>Kazuhide</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Osaka Sangyo University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1514</fpage>
         <lpage>1522</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277861"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Engine torque profile shaping strategies have been proposed to reduce noise &amp; vibration for passenger cars. However, it has not been sufficiently studied that feasible torque profile for vibration suppression is dependent on engine speed and target torque shape. On the other hand, combustion pressure profile shaping strategies have been proposed to reduce noise. However, there is almost no research of the quantitative evaluation of contribution of combustion pressure profile.</p>
            <p>First, the torque profile shaping was studied. Pre-compensated torque and 2-step torque were selected as typical target torque profiles. An effectiveness of vibration suppression by two torque profiles was evaluated by both drivetrain vibration model and engine torque profile model which have been established well. As a result of studying the torque profile shaping, timing of torque rise by the 2-step torque generation is delayed or advanced. Torque profile by the pre-compensation is deformed in steep change part. Relative degree of deterioration in 2-step torque generation is smaller than that of the pre-compensator.</p>
            <p>Second, the combustion pressure profile shaping was studied. A combustion noise generation model was constructed by the combustion pressure, a vibration transfer function in an engine structure, and a radiation factor at the engine surface. The surge in combustion pressure was modeled as triangular shape projection and analyzed in frequency domain to evaluate a contribution to combustion noise. As a result of studying the combustion pressure profile shaping, new analysis method by these models is proposed, so that radiation pressure for quantitative evaluation be obtained.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inoue T., Active Vibration Control Technology of Vehicle Cabin Noise, Journal of the Society of Instrument and Control Engineers, Vol.51. No.12, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Togai K., Choi K. and Takeuchi T., Vibration Suppression Strategy with Model Based Command Shaping: Application to Passenger Car Powertrain, Proc. of the Society of Instrument and Control Engineers annual congress 2002 in Osaka, SICE02 -0607, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuwahara, S., Kubonoya, H., Mizuno, H., Kaigawa, M. et al., “Toyota's New Integrated Drive Power Control System,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1306, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Togai K., Plattern M., Input Torque Shaping For Driveline NVH Improvement and Torque Profile Approximation Problem with Combustion Pressure, FISITA2012, F2012-J02-009, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Togai, K. and Tamaki, H., “A Reduced Order Powertrain Model Concept for Model Based Development Process with a Driver Agent,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1628, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1628.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Togai K., Tamaki H., Powertrain Output Torque Profile Shaping for Noise &amp; Vibration Reduction, AVEC'10, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Togai K., Kido K., Yamaura H., NVH Problem Causes in Passenger Car Drive Line and Alleviation Measures with Input Force Shaping Based on Excitation and Transfer Path Modeling, JSME International Conference on Motion and Power Transmissions (MPT2009), 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishihama M, Measurement of Transfer Function from Combustion to Engine Vibration, JSAE 20114529, Vol 65, No. 7, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crocker M.J., Comparison between Surface Intensity, Acoustic Intensity and Selective Wrapping Noise Measurements on a Diesel Engine, Engine Noise, Plenum Press, pp279-311, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wen Zhe LI, Miyamoto N, Relationship between Combustibility and Torque Harmenics in Internal Combustion Engines, Bulletin of the Faculty of Engineering, Hokkaido University, No. 168, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
