<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275564</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Lotus Range Extender Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Turner</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Blake</surname>
                  <given-names>Darren</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moore</surname>
                  <given-names>Jason</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Burke</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pearson</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Patel</surname>
                  <given-names>Rishin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Blundell</surname>
                  <given-names>Dave</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chandrashekar</surname>
                  <given-names>Rashmesh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Matteucci</surname>
                  <given-names>Luigi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Barker</surname>
                  <given-names>Phil</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Card</surname>
                  <given-names>Clive</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Lotus Engineering</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>318</fpage>
         <lpage>351</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 Lotus Cars Ltd.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275564"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The paper discusses the concept, specification and performance of a new, dedicated range extender engine for plug-in series hybrid vehicles conceived and designed by Lotus Engineering. This has been undertaken as part of a consortium project called Limo Green, part-funded by the UK government.</p>
            <p>The Lotus Range Extender engine has been conceived from the outset specifically as an engine for a plug-in series hybrid vehicle, therefore being free of some of the constraints placed on engines which have to mate to conventional, stepped mechanical transmissions. The paper starts by defining the philosophical difference between an engine for range extension and an engine for a full series hybrid vehicle, a distinction which is important with regard to how much power each type must produce. As part of this, the advantages of the sparkignition engine over the diesel are outlined. The rationale leading to the adoption of an in-line 3-cylinder configuration and specification is then discussed, followed by a description of the principal design characteristics of the engine; it also points out any significant differences from what might be expected were a ‘conventional’ engine to be designed.</p>
            <p>The use of ‘monoblock’ construction which integrates the cylinder block with the cylinder head and also with a water-cooled exhaust manifold is described. An indication of the likely parts reduction possible with this approach is made, together with a brief discussion of the pros and cons of the approach and which other engine types this architecture might suit.</p>
            <p>Engine performance on 95 RON unleaded gasoline is detailed, together with observations on why the engine has been additionally protected to operate on ethanol and methanol.</p>
            <p>The paper also includes a brief discussion of other engine concepts which might suit the purpose of range extension, but which (compared to the more conventional reciprocating spark-ignition engine embodied by this approach) will necessarily require greater development even if they may offer the potential for further improved efficiency, package volume and/or NVH characteristics.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Metz, B., Davidson, O., Bosch, P., Dave, R., and Meyer, L. (Eds.), “Climate change 2007: Mitigation of climate change”, Contribution of working group 3 to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, UK and New York, USA, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stern, N., “The Economics of Climate Change”, Vol. I: Report, Select Committee on Economic Affairs, HL Paper 12-I, The Stationery Office Limited, London, July 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bossel, U., Eliasson, B. and Taylor, G., “The Future of the Hydrogen Economy: Bright or Bleak?”, Cogeneration and Distributed Generation Journal, Vol. 18, No. 3, pp. 29-70, Summer 2003, April 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Romm, J., “The car and fuel of the future”, Energy Policy, Vol. 34, pp. 2609-2614, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hammerschlag, R. and Mazza, R., “Questioning hydrogen”, Energy Policy, Vol. 33, pp. 2039-2043, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., Barker, P., Blake, D., Moore, J. et al., “The Concept and Design of the Lotus Range Extender Engine,” SAE Oral-Only presentation at SAE 2010 World Congress, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lohner- Porsche_Mixte_Hybrid</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., Blundell, D.W., Pearson, R.J., Patel, R. et al., “Project Omnivore: A Variable Compression Ratio ATAC 2-Stroke Engine for Ultra-Wide-Range HCCI Operation on a Variety of Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 938-955, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1249.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blundell, D.W., Turner, J., Pearson, R., Patel, R. et al., “The Omnivore Wide-range Auto-Ignition Engine: Results to Date using 98RON Unleaded Gasoline and E85 Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0846, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0846.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, R., Fraidl, G.K., Hubmann, C., Kapus, P.E., Kunzemann, R., Sifferlinger, B. and Beste, F., “Range Extender Module - Enabler for Electric Mobility”, ATZautotechnology Vol. 9 pp. 40-46, May 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kemper, H., Hülshorst, T., Bollig, C., Wittek, K., Sehr, A., Wolschendorf, J. and Rzemien, K., “E-Vehicles with Range Extender - Properties and Potentials”, Proceedings of the 18th Aachen Colloquium, pp. 1001-1024, October 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garside, D.W., “Development of the Norton Rotary Motorcycle Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 821068, 1982, doi:10.4271/821068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Froede, W., “The Rotary Engine of the NSU Spider,” SAE Technical Paper 650722, 1965, doi: 10.4271/650722.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feller, F., “The 2-stage rotary engine - a new concept in diesel power”, Proc. Instn Mech. Engrs 1970-71, Vol. 185 13/71, pp. 139-158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimizu, R., Tadokoro, T., Nakanishi, T., and Funamoto, J., “Mazda 4-Rotor Rotary Engine for the Le Mans 24-Hour Endurance Race,” SAE Technical Paper 920309, 1992, doi: 10.4271/920309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lotus Fuel Mixture Database Version 05/08, proprietary software of Lotus Engineering.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dobes, T., Kapus, P., Schöggl, P., Jansen, H. and Bogner, E., “CO2 Reduction in Everyday Operation - Influence of Engine Calibration”, 29th International Vienna Motor Symposium, Year 2008 Series 12 No./Vol. 672-1 No. 16, Vienna, Austria, April 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bassett, M., Fraser, N., Brooks, T., Taylor, G. et al., “A Study of Fuel Converter Requirements for an Extended- Range Electric Vehicle,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):631-654, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0832.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lückert, P., Waltner, A., Rau, E., Vent, G. and Schaupp, U., “The New V6 Gasoline Engine with Direct Injection by Mercedes-Benz”, MTZ 11/2006, Volume 67, pp. 830-840, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langen, P., Melcher, T., Missy, S., Schwarz, C. and Schünemann, E., “New BMW Six- and Four-Cylinder Petrol Engines with High Precision Injection and Stratified Combustion”, 28th International Vienna Motor Symposium, Vienna, Austria, 26th-27th April 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gumpesberger, M., Landerl, C., Miritsch, J., Mosmüller, E., Müller, P. and Ohrnberger, G., “The Drive of the New BMW F 800”, MTZ 06/2006, Vol. 67, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ueda, T., Okumura, T., Sugiura, S., and Kojima, S., “Effects of Squish Area Shape on Knocking in a Four-Valve Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1494, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1494.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pearson, R.J., Turner, J.W.G., Eisaman, M.D., and Littau, K.A., “Extending the Supply of Alcohol Fuels for Energy Security and Carbon Reduction,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2764, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2764.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., Burke, P., Balding, A. and Osborne, K., “Concepts to Reduce Architectural Complexity and Mass in Reciprocating Engines”, 6th Lean Weight Vehicle Conference, Warwick, UK, December 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ludvigsen, K., “Classic Racing Engines”, Haynes Publishing, Sparkford, Somerset, UK, 2001, ISBN 1 85960 649 0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akima, K., Seko, K., Taga, W., Torii, K. et al., “Development of New Low Fuel Consumption 1.8L i-VTEC Gasoline Engine with Delayed Intake Valve Closing,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0192, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coltman, D., Turner, J.W.G., Curtis, R., Blake, D. et al., “Project Sabre: A Close-Spaced Direct Injection 3-Cylinder Engine with Synergistic Technologies to Achieve Low CO2 Output,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1): 129-146, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klüting, M. and Landerl, C., “The New BMW Inline Six- Cylinder Spark-Ignition Engine Part 1: Concept and Construction”, MTZ, November 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sandford, M., Page, G., and Crawford, P., “The All New AJV8,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1060, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1060.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoffmeyer, H., Montefrancesco, E., Beck, L., Willand, J. et al., “CARE - CAtalytic Reformated Exhaust Gases in Turbocharged DISI-Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1): 139-148, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., Pearson, R.J., Curtis, R., and Holland, B., “Effects of Cooled EGR Routing on a Second-Generation DISI Turbocharged Engine Employing an Integrated Exhaust Manifold,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1487, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1487.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pearson, R.J. Turner, J.W.G. and Peck, A.J., “Gasoline- Ethanol-Methanol Tri-Fuel Vehicle Development and its Role in Expediting the use of Sustainable Synthetic Fuels for Transport”, I.Mech.E. Low Carbon Vehicles Conference, London, UK, May, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch Automotive Handbook, 5th Ed., Robert Bosch GmbH, Stuttgart, Germany, 2000, ISBN 0-7680-0669-4. 34. Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw-Hill Book Company, New York, USA, 1988, ISBN 0-07-028637-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.uqm.com/pdfs/powerphase%2075%20spec %20sheet%20update.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusstar, M., Stuhldreher, M., Swain, D., and Pidgeon, W., “High Efficiency and Low Emissions from a Port- Injected Engine with Neat Alcohol Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2743, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2743.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusstar, M.J. and Gray, C.L.Jr., “High Efficiency with Future Alcohol Fuels in a Stoichiometric Medium Duty Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3993, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
