<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284926</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Impact of Rh Oxidation State on NOx Reduction Performance of Multi-Component Lean NOx Trap (LNT) Catalyst</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Junhui</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Currier</surname>
                  <given-names>Neal</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yezerets</surname>
                  <given-names>Aleksey</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chen</surname>
                  <given-names>Hai-Ying</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Johnson Matthey Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hess</surname>
                  <given-names>Howard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Johnson Matthey Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mulla</surname>
                  <given-names>Shadab</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Johnson Matthey Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>September 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284904</issue-id>
         <fpage>1615</fpage>
         <lpage>1622</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284926"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Typical Lean NOx Trap (LNT) catalyst composition includes precious metal components (Pt, Pd, and/or Rh), responsible for NO oxidation during lean operation and NOx reduction during rich operation. It was found that redox history of commercial LNT catalyst plays a significant role on deciding its NOx conversion under Lean/Rich cyclic condition. Further test had shown that fully formulated LNT catalyst being pre-reduced had shown much better NO reduction activity during the temperature-programmed reduction (TPRx) of NO than the same LNT catalyst being oxidized. The following study with Rh-only and Pt-only catalyst had demonstrated that Rh plays a key role on the large variation of the NO reduction function due to oxidation state change over LNT catalyst.</p>
            <p>Kinetic analysis of the NO reduction was performed in an attempt to elucidate the underlying mechanistic relationship, where it was found that NO reduction over reduced Rh can be well described by an Arrhenius equation with first-order dependence on NO concentration while the oxidized catalyst had been changing its surface redox state during NO reduction. The activation energy of the NO reduction process over reduced fully formulated LNT catalyst was found to be ∼180±14kJ/mol, which is consistent with Rh-only catalyst but very different from Pt-only catalyst. The observed apparent activation energy of NO reduction on LNT catalyst was independent of the reductant used or the degree of hydrothermal aging either from field-aging or lab aging. These findings are consistent with NO dissociation being the rate-limiting step in the NO reduction process. The hydrothermal aging, redox state as well as the reductant type would only change the total number of sites available, active sites accessible as well as the surface coverage, respectively.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Epling, W.S., Campbell, L. E., Yezerets, A., Currier, N. W., and Parks J. E., II, “Overview of the Fundamental Reactions and Degradation Mechanisms of NOx Storage/Reduction Catalysts,” Catal. Reviews 46: 163-245, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Novakova, J., “Reduction of NO by Hydrogen versus Reduction by CO over Pt, Pd and Rh Clusters in NaX Zeolite,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 30: 445-457, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roy, S., Hedge, M.S., and Madras, G., “Catalysis for NOx abatement” Appl. Energy 86: 2283-2297, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakatsuji, T., and Komppa, V., “A catalytic NOx reduction system using periodic two steps: an operation in oxidizing conditions and a relatively short operation in reducing conditions,” Appl. Cat. B: Environ 30: 209- 223, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oh, S. E., and Carpenter, J. E., “The Oxidation State and Catalytic Activity of Supported Rhodium,” J. Catal. 80: 472-478, 1983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Root, T. W., Schmidt, T. W., and Fisher, G., “Adsorption and reaction of nitric oxide and oxygen on Rh(111),” Surface Science 134: 30-45, 1983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fisher, G. B., Oh, S. H., Carpenter, J. E., Dimaggio, C. L., Schmieg, S. J., Goodman, D. W., Root, T. W., Schwartz, S. B., Schmidt, L. D. “Mechanisms of the Carbon Monoxide Oxidation and Nitric Oxide Reduction Reactions over Single Crystal and Supported Rhodium Catalysts: High Pressure Rates Explained Using Ultrahigh Vacuum Surface Science,” Studies in Surface Science and Catalysis 30:215-220, 1987</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Root, T.W., Schmidt, L.D. and Fisher, G. B. “Nitric oxide reduction by CO ON Rh(111): Temperature programmed reaction,” Surface Science 150: 173-192, 1985</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grunwaldt, J., Basini, L., and Clausen, B. “In-situ EXAFS Study of Rh/Al2O3 Catalysts for Catalytic Partial Oxidation of Methane,” J. Catal. 200: 321-329, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, J., and Overbury, S. H., “H2 reduction of CeO2 (111) surface via boundary Rh-O mediation,” J. Catal. 222:167-173, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomczak, D.C., Lei, G. D., Schunemann, Trevino, V., H., and Sachtler, W. M. H., “Chemistry of rhodium in zeolite Y,” Micro. Mater. 5: 263- 278, 1996</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newton, M. A., Dent, A.J., Fiddy, S. G., Jyoti, B., and Evans, J., “Combining diffuse reflectance infrared spectroscopy (DRIFTS) dispersive EXAFS and mass spectrometry with high time resolution Potential limitations and application to the study of NO interaction with supported Rh catalysts,” Catal. Today 126: 64-72, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Holles, J. H., Switzer, M.A., and Davis, R. J. “Influence of Ceria and Lanthana Promoters on the Kinetics of NO and N2O Reduction by CO over Alumina-Supported Palladium and Rhodium,” J. Catal. 190: 247- 260, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Penner, S., Jenewein, B., Wang, D., Schlogl, R., and Hayek, K., “Structure-activity correlation in thin film model catalysts: CO hydrogenation on Rh/VOx Part I: The morphology, composition and structure of vanadia-supported and -promoted Rh particles upon oxidation and reduction,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen 308: 31-42, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, F., Wang, Y., and Goodman, D. W., “CO/NO and CO/NO/O2 reactions over a Au-Pd single crystal catalyst,” J. Catal. 268: 115-121, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, W. A., and King, D. A., “NO Chemisorption and Reactions on Metal Surfaces: A New Perspective,” J. Phys. Chem. B 104: 2578-2595, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cao, C., Bourane, A., Schlup, J. R., and Hohn, K. L., “In situ IR investigation of activation and catalytic ignition of methane over Rh/Al2O3 catalysts,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen 344: 78-87, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dent, A. J., Evans, J., Fiddy, S. G., Jyoti, B., Newton, M. A., and Tromp, M., “Rhodium dispersion during NO/CO conversions,” Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 46: 5356-5358, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhong, F., Xiao, Y., Weng, X., Wei, K., Cai, G., Zheng, Y., and Zheng, Q., “Thermally stable CeO2-ZrO2-La2O3 Ternary Oxides Prepared by Deposition-Precipitation as Support of Rh Catalyst for Catalytic Reduction of NO by CO,” Catal. Lett. 133: 125-133, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grunwaldt, J., Basini, L., and Clausen, B. S., “In Situ EXAFS Study of Rh/Al2O3 Catalysts for Catalytic Partial Oxidation of Methane,” J. Catal. 200: 321-329, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Legage, M., Visser, T., Soulimani, F., Beale, A.M., Iglesias-Juez, A., Eerden, A., and Weckhuysen, B. M., “Promotion Effects of the Oxidation of CO over Zeolite-supported Rh Nanoparticles,” J. Phys. Chem. C 112: 9394-9404, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manuel, I., Chaubet, J., Thomas, C., Colas, H., Matthess, N., and Djega- Mariadassou, G., “Simulation of the transient CO oxidation over Rh0/SiO2 and Rhx+/Ce0.68Zr0.32O2 catalysts,” J. Catal. 224: 269-277, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xiao, L., and Schneider, W. F., “Influence of alumina supports on oxygen binding to Pd, Ag, Pt and Au,” Chem. Phys. Lett. 484: 231-236, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Djega-Mariadassou, G., Fajardie, F., Tempere, J., Manoli, J., Touret, O., and Blanchard, G., “A general model for both three-way and deNOx catalysis: dissociative or associative nitric oxide adsorption, and its assisted decomposition in the presence of a reductant Part I. Nitric oxide decomposition assisted by CO over reduced or oxidized rhodium species supported on ceria,” J. Molecular Catal. A: Chem. 161: 179-189, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adamowska, M., Krzton, A., Najbar, M., Camra, J., Djega-Mariadassou, G., and Costa, P. D., “Ceriazirconia-supported rhodium catalyst for NOx reduction from coal combustion flue gases,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 90: 535-544, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu, Y., Grififiths, K., and Norton, P. R., “Surface science studies of selective catalytic reduction of NO: progress in the last ten years,” Surf. Sci. 603: 1740-1750, 209</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kašpar, J., Fornasiero, P., and Hickey, N., “Surface science studies of selective catalytic reduction of NO: progress in the last ten years,” Catal. Today 77: 419-449, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neyertz, C., Volpe, M., Perez, D., Costilla, I., Sanchez, M., and Gigola, C., “NO reduction with CO in the presence and absence of H2O over Pd/γ-Al2O3 and Pd-VOx/γ-Al2O3 catalysts: The formation of HNCO, NH3 and stable surface species,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen 368: 146-157, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lindholm, A., Currier, N. W., Fridell, E., Yezerets, A., and Olsson, L., “NOx storage and reduction over Pt based catalysts with hydrogen as the reducing agent: Influence of H2O and CO2,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 75: 78-87, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, J., Currier, N., Yezerets, A., Chen, H. et al., "Evaluation of Spatially Resolved Performance of NOx Adsorber Catalysts," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0275, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Granger, P., Lecomte, J. J., Dathy, C., Leclercq, L., and Leclercq, G., “Kinetics of the CO+NO Reaction over Rhodium and Platinum- Rhodium on Alumina,” J. Catal. 175: 194-203, 1998</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Granger, P., Delannoy, L., Lecomte, J. J., Dathy, C., Praliaud, H., Leclercq, L., Leclercq, G., “Kinetics of the CO+NO Reaction over Bimetallic Platinum-Rhodium on Alumina: Effect of Ceria Incorporation into Noble Metals,” J. Catal. 207: 202-212, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huuhtanen, M., Kolli, T., Maunula, T., Keiski, R.L. “In situ FTIR study on NO reduction by C3H6 over Pdbased catalysts,” Catal. Today 75: 379-384, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berlowitz, P.J., Peden, C. H. F., and Goodman, D. W., “Kinetics of CO Oxidation on Single-Crystal Pd, Pt, and Ir,” J. Phys. Chem. 92: 5213- 5221, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salomons, S., Hayes, R.E., and Votsmeier, M., “The promotion of carbon monoxide oxidation by hydrogen on supported platinum catalyst,” Appl. Catal. A: Gen 352: 27-34, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhatia, D., Harold, M. P., Balakotaiah, V., “Kinetic and bifurcationanalysis of the cooxidation of CO and H2 in catalytic monolith reactors,” Chemical Engineering Science 64: 1544-1558, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hauptmann, W., Votsmeier, M., Vogel, H., and Vlachos, D.G., “Modeling the simultaneous oxidation of CO and H2 on Pt - Promoting effect of H2 on the CO-light-off,” Applied Catalysis A: General 397: 174-182, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fernandes, D. M., Scofield, C. F., Neto, A. A., Baldini Cardoso, M. J., and Zanon Zotina, F. M., “Thermal deactivation of Pt/Rh commercial automotive catalysts,” Chemical Engineering Journal 160: 85-92, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
