<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275554</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comparison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High-Temperature, High-Pressure Facilities</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Genzale</surname>
                  <given-names>Caroline L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bruneaux</surname>
                  <given-names>Gilles</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Malbec</surname>
                  <given-names>Louis-Marie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hermant</surname>
                  <given-names>Laurent</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Christiansen</surname>
                  <given-names>Caspar</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical Univ. of Denmark</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schramm</surname>
                  <given-names>Jesper</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical Univ. of Denmark</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>156</fpage>
         <lpage>181</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275554"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Diesel spray experimentation at controlled high-temperature and high-pressure conditions is intended to provide a more fundamental understanding of diesel combustion than can be achieved in engine experiments. This level of understanding is needed to develop the high-fidelity multi-scale CFD models that will be used to optimize future engine designs. Several spray chamber facilities capable of high-temperature, high-pressure conditions typical of engine combustion have been developed, but because of the uniqueness of each facility, there are uncertainties about their operation. For this paper, we describe results from comparative studies using constant-volume vessels at Sandia National Laboratories and IFP. Targeting the same ambient gas conditions (900 K, 60 bar, 22.8 kg/m ³, 15% oxygen) and using the same injector specifications (common rail, 1500 bar, KS 1.5/86 nozzle, 0.090 mm orifice diameter, n-dodecane, 363 K), we describe detailed measurements of the temperature and pressure boundary conditions at each facility, followed by observations of spray penetration, ignition, and combustion using high-speed imaging. The spray diagnostics show reasonable similarity despite the challenges of providing matched boundary conditions at these unique facilities. Performing experiments at the same high-temperature, high-pressure operating conditions is an objective of the Engine Combustion Network (http://www.ca.sandia.gov/ECN/), which seeks to leverage the research capabilities and advanced diagnostics of all participants in the ECN. Thus, in addition to the presentation of a comparative study, this paper demonstrates steps that are needed for other interested groups to participate in ECN spray research. We expect that this collaborative effort will generate a high-quality dataset to be used for advanced computational model development at engine conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vishwanathan, G. and Reitz, R.D., “Numerical Predictions of Diesel Flame Lift-off Length and Soot Distributions under Low Temperature Combustion Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1331, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell, J.W., Gosman, A.D., and Hardy, G., “Analysis of Premix Flame and Lift-Off in Diesel Spray Combustion using Multi-Dimensional CFD,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1): 571-590, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kärrholm, F.P., Tao, F., and Nordin, N., “Three- Dimensional Simulation of Diesel Spray Ignition and Flame Lift-Off Using OpenFOAM and KIVA-3V CFD Codes,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0961, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Errico, G., Ettorre, D., and Lucchini, T., “Simplified and Detailed Chemistry Modeling of Constant-Volume Diesel Combustion Experiments,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):452-465, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0954.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">d'Errico, G., Lucchini, T., Montenegro, G., Onarati, A., and Etorre, D., “Fundamental and applied studies of detailed chemistry based models for diesel combustion,” THIESEL 2008, Valencia, Spain.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucchini, T., D'Errico, G., Etorre, D., and Ferrari, G., “Numerical Investigation of Non-Reacting and Reacting Diesel Sprays in Constant-Volume Vessels,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):966-975, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vishwanathan, G. and Reitz, R., “Modeling soot formation using reduced polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon chemistry in n-heptane lifted flames with application to low temperature combustion,” J. of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, pp. 032801, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abraham, J. and Pickett, L.M., “Computed and Measured Fuel Vapor Distribution in a Diesel Spray,” Atomization and Sprays 20:241-250, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turbulent Nonpremixed Flame Workshop. .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network data archive. .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">JetSurF - A Jet Surrogate Fuel Model. .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, Physical and Life Sciences Directive. .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baert, R.S.G., Frijters, P.J.M., Somers, B., Luijten, C.C.M. et al., “Design and Operation of a High Pressure, High Temperature Cell for HD Diesel Spray Diagnostics: Guidelines and Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0649, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0649.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P.C. and Gouldin, F.C., “Determination of the time constant of fine-wire thermocouples for compensated temperature measurements in premixed turbulent flames,” Combust. Sci. Tech. 83:1-19, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petit, C., Gajan, P., Lecordier, J.C., and Paranthoen, P., “Frequency response of fine-wire thermocouple”, J. Phys. E: Sci. Instrum., 15:760, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heitor, M. V. and Moreira, A.L.N., “Thermocouple and sample probes for combustion studies,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 19:259-278, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dupont, A., Paranthoen, P., Lecordier, J.C. and Gajan, P., “Influence of temperature on the frequency response of fine-wire thermocouples over the range (300 K-800 K) in airflows”, J. Phys. E: Sci. Instrum., 17:808-812, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paranthoen, P., Petit, C. and Lecordier, J.C., “The effect of the thermal prong-wire interaction on the response of a cold wire in gaseous flows (air, argon and helium)”, J. Fluid Mech., 124:457-473, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malbec, L.-M. and Bruneaux, G., “Study of Air Entrainment of Multi-hole Diesel Injection by Particle Image Velocimetry - Effect of Neighboring Jets Interaction and Transient Behavior After End of Injection,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):107-123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L. “Scaling Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays Based on Mixing-Limited Vaporization,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0528, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giannadakis, E., Gavaises, M., and Theodorakakos, A., “The Influence of Variable Fuel Properties in High-Pressure Diesel Injectors,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0832, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0832.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allison, S.W. and Gillies, G.T. “Remote thermometry with thermographic phosphors: Instrumentation and applications”, Review of Scientific Instruments 68(7): 2615-2650, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kashdan, J.T. and Thirouard, B., “A Comparison of Combustion and Emissions Behaviour in Optical and Metal Single-Cylinder Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1857-1872, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Kook, S., and Williams, T.C., “Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool-Flame, Ignition, High-Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High-Speed Imaging,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 439-459, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Settles, G.S., Schlieren and Shadowgraph Techniques, Springer-Verlag, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J.D. and Siebers, D.L., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Pickett, L.M., and Musculus, M.P.B., “Influence of Diesel Injection Parameters on End-of-Injection Liquid Length Recession,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1194-1210, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Pastor, J.V., Garcia-Oliver, J.M., and Pastor, J.M., “A 1D model for the description of mixingcontrolled reacting diesel sprays,” Combust. Flame 156:234-249, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D. and Higgins, B., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct- Injection Diesel Sprays Under Quiescent Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0530, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Siebers, D.L., and Idicheria, C.A., “Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Combustion structure of free and wallimpinging diesel jets by simultaneous laser-induced fluorescence of formaldehyde, poly-aromatic hydrocarbons, and hydroxides,” Int. J. Engine Research 9:249-265, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Kook, S., Persson, H., and Andersson, O., “Diesel fuel jet lift-off stabilization in the presence of laserinduced plasma ignition,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 32:2793-2800, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D., “Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L.M., and Idicheria, C.A., “End-of-Injection Over-Mixing and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions in Low-Temperature- Combustion Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0907, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot in diesel fuel jets: effects of ambient temperature, ambient density, and injection pressure,” Combust. Flame 138:114-135, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
