<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422623</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental and Numerical Investigation of the Engine Operational Conditions’ Influences on a Small Un-Scavenged Pre-Chamber’s Behavior</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>XU</surname>
                  <given-names>Guoqing</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zürich / Liebherr Machines Bulle SA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wright</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuri Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zürich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kyrtatos</surname>
                  <given-names>Panagiotis</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zürich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bardis</surname>
                  <given-names>Konstantinos</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zürich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Schiliro</surname>
                  <given-names>Michele</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Liebherr Machines Bulle SA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Boulouchos</surname>
                  <given-names>Konstantinos</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zürich</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422609</issue-id>
         <fpage>2414</fpage>
         <lpage>2428</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422623"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Despite significant benefits in terms of the ignition enhancement, the strength and timing of the turbulent flame jets subsequently issuing into the main chamber strongly depend on the pre-chamber combustion process and, thus, are sensitive to the specific engine operating conditions it experienced. This poses considerable difficulties in optimizing engine operating conditions as well as controlling engine performance. This paper investigates the influence of engine operating conditions on the pre-chamber combustion event using both experimental and numerical methods. A miniaturized piezo-electric pressure transducer was designed to be placed inside the engine cylinder head to record the pre-chamber inner volume pressure, in addition to conventional pressure indication inside the main chamber. The pressure difference between the main chamber and the pre-chamber (Δ<italic>p</italic> = <italic>p<sub>pre-chamber</sub>
               </italic> - <italic>p<sub>main chamber</sub>
               </italic>) served as an indicator of the pre-chamber combustion event, through the study of the crank angle resolved Δ<italic>p</italic> under different engine operating conditions. The variations include spark timing, air-fuel ratio and engine speed, as well as engine intake air temperature and boost pressure, for which a single-parameter sensitivity approach was carried out. 3D-CFD simulation in the RANS context and 0D modeling was further employed to estimate the turbulence level and thermo-physical conditions inside the pre- and main chambers in dependence of the engine operating conditions. The results indicate that the Δ<italic>p</italic> peak value and its timing show the highest sensitivity to the air-fuel ratio variation, followed by the intake air temperature, while the sensitivity of Δ<italic>p</italic> peak value and its timing to the pressure difference and the absolute pressure level at spark timing were observed to be considerably lower. Based on the observations, two correlations were proposed to predict the Δ<italic>p</italic> peak value and its timing for which successful validation against a large number of engine operating conditions was demonstrated.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Schock, H., and Attard, W., "A Review of Pre-Chamber Initiated Jet Ignition Combustion Systems," SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2263, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schlatter, S., Schneider, B., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., "Comparative Study of Ignition Systems for Lean Burn Gas Engines in an Optically Accessible Rapid Compression Expansion Machine," SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0112, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ashok, B., Denis Ashok S., and Ramesh Kumar C., LPG diesel dual fuel engine - A critical review. Alexandria Engineering Journal, 2015. 54(2): p. 105-126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schlatter, S., et al., N-heptane micro pilot assisted methane combustion in a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine. Fuel, 2016. 179: p. 339-352.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schlatter, S., Schneider, B., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., "Experimental Study of Ignition and Combustion Characteristics of a Diesel Pilot Spray in a Lean Premixed Methane/Air Charge using a Rapid Compression Expansion Machine," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0825, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morsy, M.H., Review and recent developments of laser ignition for internal combustion engines applications. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 2012. 16(7): p. 4849-4875.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roethlisberger, R.P. and Favrat D., Comparison between direct and indirect (prechamber) spark ignition in the case of a cogeneration natural gas engine, Part II: Engine operating parameters and turbocharger characteristics. Applied Thermal Engineering, 2002. 22(11): p. 1231-1243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noguchi, M., Sanda, S., and Nakamura, N., "Development of Toyota Lean Burn Engine," SAE Technical Paper 760757, 1976, doi:10.4271/760757.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adams, T., "Theory and Evaluation of Auxiliary Combustion (Torch) Chambers," SAE Technical Paper 780631, 1978, doi:10.4271/780631.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oppenheim, A., Teichman, K., Hom, K., and Stewart, H., "Jet Ignition of an Ultra-Lean Mixture," SAE Technical Paper 780637, 1978, doi:10.4271/780637.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinet, C., Higelin, P., Moreau, B., Pajot, O. et al., "A New Firing Concept for Internal Combustion Engines: “I'APIR”," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0621, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0621.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Couet, S., Higelin, P., and Moreau, B., "APIR: A New Firing Concept for the Internal Combustion Engines -sensitivity to knock and incylinder aerodynamics," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1954, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1954.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roethlisberger, R.P. and Favrat D., Investigation of the prechamber geometrical configuration of a natural gas spark ignition engine for cogeneration: Part II. Experimentation. International Journal of Thermal Sciences, 2003. 42(3): p. 239-253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawabata, Y. and Mori, D., "Combustion Diagnostics &amp; Improvement of a Prechamber Lean-Burn Natural Gas Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0979, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W. and Parsons, P., "Flame Kernel Development for a Spark Initiated Pre-Chamber Combustion System Capable of High Load, High Efficiency and Near Zero NOx Emissions," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):408-427, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2260.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunce, M. and Blaxill, H., "Sub-200 g/kWh BSFC on a Light Duty Gasoline Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0709, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0709.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, A., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., "Effect of Pre-Chamber Volume and Nozzle Diameter on Pre-Chamber Ignition in Heavy Duty Natural Gas Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0867, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, A., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., "CFD Simulations of Pre-Chamber Jets' Mixing Characteristics in a Heavy Duty Natural Gas Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1890, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Watson, H., and Attard, W., "Modeling Alternative Prechamber Fuels in Jet Assisted Ignition of Gasoline and LPG," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0721, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0721.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gholamisheeri, M., et al., Rapid compression machine study of a premixed, variable inlet density and flow rate, confined turbulent jet. Combustion and Flame, 2016. 169: p. 321-332.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gholamisheeri, M., Thelen, B., Gentz, G., and Toulson, E., "CFD Modeling of an Auxiliary Fueled Turbulent Jet Ignition System in a Rapid Compression Machine," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0599, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0599.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thelen, B.C. and Toulson E., A computational study on the effect of the orifice size on the performance of a turbulent jet ignition system. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thelen, B. and Toulson, E., "A Computational Study of the Effects of Spark Location on the Performance of a Turbulent Jet Ignition System," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0608, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Biswas, S., et al., On ignition mechanisms of premixed CH4/air and H2/air using a hot turbulent jet generated by pre-chamber combustion. Applied Thermal Engineering, 2016. 106: p. 925-937.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Biswas, S. and Qiao, L., "Prechamber Hot Jet Ignition of Ultra-Lean H2/Air Mixtures: Effect of Supersonic Jets and Combustion Instability," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(3):1584-1592, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vedula, R.T., et al., Thermal efficiency of a dual-mode turbulent jet ignition engine under lean and near-stoichiometric operation. International Journal of Engine Research. 0(0): p. 1468087417699979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brettschneider, J., Bosch technische Berichte, 1979. 6: p. 177-186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CD-adapco, Methodology Star-CD Version 4.24. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CD-adapco, es-ice User Guide Version 4.24. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yakhot, V., et al., Development of turbulence models for shear flows by a double expansion technique. Physics of Fluids A, 1992. 4(7): p. 1510-1520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koch, J., Xu, G., Wright, Y., Boulouchos, K. et al., "Comparison and Sensitivity Analysis of Turbulent Flame Speed Closures in the RANS G-Equation Context for Two Distinct Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(4):2091-2106, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2236.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, G., Hanauer, C., Wright, Y., and Boulouchos, K., "CFD-Simulation of Ignition and Combustion in Lean Burn Gas Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0800, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., "A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine," SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi:10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiodi, M. and Bargende, M., "Improvement of Engine Heat-Transfer Calculation in the Three-Dimensional Simulation Using a Phenomenological Heat-Transfer Model," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3601, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ikegami, M., Shioji M., and Koike M., A stochastic approach to model the combustion process in direct-injection diesel engines. Symposium (International) on Combustion, 1985. 20(1): p. 217-224.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, N., Turbulent Combustion. 2000, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
