<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275528</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Clean Diesel Combustion by Means of the HCPC Concept</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Musu</surname>
                  <given-names>Ettore</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Università di Pisa</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rossi</surname>
                  <given-names>Riccardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Università di Pisa</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gentili</surname>
                  <given-names>Roberto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Università di Pisa</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>964</fpage>
         <lpage>981</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275528"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Homogeneous-charge, compression-ignition (HCCI) combustion is triggered by spontaneous ignition in dilute homogeneous mixtures. The combustion rate must be reduced by suitable solutions such as high rates of Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) and/or lean mixtures. HCCI is considered a very effective way to reduce engine pollutant emissions, however only a few HCCI engines have entered into production. HCCI combustion currently cannot be extended to the whole engine operating range, especially to high loads, since the use of EGR displaces air from the cylinder, limiting engine mean effective pressure, thus the engine must be able to operate also in conventional mode.</p>
            <p>This paper concerns a study of an innovative concept to control HCCI combustion in diesel-fuelled engines. The concept consists in forming a pre-compressed homogeneous charge outside the cylinder and gradually admitting it into the cylinder during the combustion process. In this way, combustion can be controlled by the transfer flow rate and high pressure rise rates, typical of standard HCCI combustion, can be avoided. This new combustion concept was called Homogenous Charge Progressive Combustion (HCPC).</p>
            <p>The paper illustrates a CFD analysis focused on improving efficiency and reducing pollutant emissions at medium and heavy load. Different geometries of the transfer duct were considered. Results show negligible soot emission up to equivalence ratios around 0.85, with indicated efficiency around 46 %. As well, a moderate level of external cooled EGR allows reducing NOx emissions up to levels that are typical of low-temperature combustion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., Asmus, T.N., Assanis, D.N., Dec, J.E. et al., “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” SAE International, Warrendale, PA, ISBN 978-0-7680-1123-4, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martinez-Frias, J., Aceves, S.M., Flowers, D., Smith, J.R. et al., “HCCI Engine Control by Thermal Management,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2869, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, J., Culp, T., and Kenney, T., “Development of a Gasoline Engine System Using HCCI Technology - The Concept and Test Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2832, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marriott, C.D. and Reitz, R.D., “Experimental Investigation of Direct Injection-Gasoline for Premixed Compression Ignited Combustion Phasing Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0418, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Odaka, M., Suzuki, H., Koike, N., and Ishii, H., “Search for Optimizing Control Method of Homogeneous Charge Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0184, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiraya, K., Hasegawa, K., Urushihara, T., Iiyama, A. et al., “A Study on Gasoline Fuelled Compression Ignition Engine - A Trail of Operation Region Expansion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0416, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Hultqvist, A., and Johansson, B., “Demonstrating the Multi Fuel Capability of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine with Variable Compression Ratio,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3679, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haraldsson, G., Tunestål, P., Johansson, B., and Hyvönen, J., “HCCI Combustion Phasing in a Multi Cylinder Engine Using Variable Compression Ratio,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2858, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., Peng, Z., Williams, J., and Ladommatos, N., “Understanding the Effects of Recycled Burnt Gases on the Controlled Autoignition (CAI) Combustion in Four-Stroke Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3607, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nishijima, Y., Asaumi, Y., and Aoyagi, Y., “Inpingement Spray System with Direct Water Injection for Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0109, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaneko, N., Ando, H., Ogawa, H., and Miyamoto, N., “Expansion of the Operating Range with In-Cylinder Water Injection in a Premixed Charge Compression Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1743, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ricklin, P.U., Kazakov, A., Dryer, F.L., Kong, S.C. et al., “The Effects of NOx Addition on the Auto Ignition Behavior of Natural Gas under HCCI Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1746, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Furutani M. et al., “An ultra-lean premixed compressionignition engine concept and its characteristics”, Proceedings of COMODIA '98, pp. 173-177 (1998).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamagna, D., Ra, Y., and Reitz, R.D., “Multidimensional Simulation of PCCI Combustion Using Gasoline and Dual- Fuel Direct Injection with Detailed Chemical Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0190, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L., Hanson, R. M, Splitter, D.A., and Reitz, R.D., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okude, K., Mori, K., Shiino, S., and Moriya, T., “Premixed Compression Ignition (PCI) Combustion for Simultaneous Reduction of NOx and Soot in Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1907, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P.W., Schleyer, C.H., Duffy, K.P., Hardy, W.L. et al., “Effects of Fuel Property Changes on Heavy- Duty HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0191, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J.-O., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., “Boosting for High Load HCCI,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0940, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, M., Liu, H., Zhang, B., and Zheng, Z., “The Influence of Boost Pressure and Fuel Chemistry on Combustion and Performance of a HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0051, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryan, T.W., III and Callahan, T.J., “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition of Diesel Fuel”, SAE Technical Paper 961160, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gray, A., III and Ryan, T.W., III, “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) of Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 971676, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takeda, Y., Keiichi, N., and Keiichi, N., “Emission Characteristics of Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion with Extremely Early Staged Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 961163, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S. et al., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High- Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mase, Y., Kawashima, J.-I., Sato, T., and Eguchi, M., “Nissan's New Multivalve DI Diesel Engine Series,” SAE Technical Paper 981039, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamagna D., Musu, E., Gentili R., “A Preliminary Study Towards an Innovative Diesel HCCI Combustion” ASME Paper No. ICEF2007-1743 (2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musu, E., Gentili, R., and Reitz, R.D., “Homogeneous Charge Progressive Combustion (HCPC): CFD Study of an Innovative Diesel HCCI Concept,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1344, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musu E., Rossi R., Gentili R., “Improvements in Efficiency and Mixture Formation for an Innovative Diesel HCCI Concept” ASME Paper No. ICEF2009-14046 (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tiainen, J., Saarinen, A., Grönlund, T., and Larmi, M., “Novel Two-Stroke Engine Concept, Feasibility Study,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3211, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grönlund, T. and Larmi, M., “Valve Train Design for a New Gas Exchange Process,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0607, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">www.scuderigroup.com</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coney W. M., Linnemann C., Morgan E.R., “A Novel Internal Combustion Engine With Simultaneous Injection of Fuel and Pre-Compressed Pre-Heated Air” ASME Paper No. ICEF2002-485 (2002).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL FIRE User's guide version 8.5, AVL LIST GmbH, (2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL FIRE Combustion manual version 8.52, AVL LIST GmbH, (2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dukowicz, J.K.: Particle-Fluid Numerical Model for Liquid Spray of Computational Physics 35,229-253(1980).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale, J.C., and Reitz, R.D., “Modeling Spray Atomization with the Kelvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh- Taylor Hybrid Model,” Atomization and Sprays, Vol. 9, pp. 623-650, (1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dukowicz, J.K.: Quasi-Steady Droplet Change in the Presence of Convection, Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, LA7997-MS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos A., Assanis D. N., Flowers D. L., Aceves S. M., Hessel R. P.: “A fully coupled computational fluid dynamics and multi-zone model with detailed chemical kinetics for the simulation of premixed charge compression ignition engines”, International Journal of Engine Research, Volume 6, Number 5 / 2005, pages 497-512 (2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Ra, Y., Gonzalez D., M.A., Krieger, R. et al., “Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L. and Reitz, R.D., “A Computational Investigation of Two-Stage Combustion in a Light-Duty Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):1083-1104, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L., Swor, T.A., Andrie, M.J., and Reitz R.D., “Experiments and Modeling of Adaptive Injection Strategies (AIS) in Low Emission Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):16-32, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malgrem, A., Sidders, J., Stephenson, P., and Coney, M., “Experiments and Simulations of Quasi-Isothermal Compressor for a Novel High Efficiency Engine,” IMechE Conference Transaction, International Conference on Compressors and Their System, pages 461-472, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
