<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438438</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comparing In- Work Benefits and the Reward to Work for Families with Children in the US and the UK</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>MIKE</given-names>
                  <surname>BREWER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2001</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438400</issue-id>
         <fpage>41</fpage>
         <lpage>77</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2001</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438438"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The income transfer systems for low-income families in the US and the UK try both to reduce poverty and to encourage work. In-work benefits are a key part of both countries' strategies through the earned income tax credit and the working families' tax credit (and predecessors) respectively. But tax credits are only one part of the whole tax and welfare system. In-work benefits, taxes and welfare benefits combine in both countries to provide good financial incentives for lone parents to do minimum-wage work, but poorer incentives to increase earnings further. But direct comparisons of budget constraints hide important points of detail. First, not enough is known about what determines take-up of in-work benefits. Second, the considerable differences in assessment and payment mechanisms and frequency between EITC and WFTC mean that low-income families in the US and the UK may respond very differently to apparently similar financial incentives.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e324a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e331" publication-type="other">
US studies talk about the phase-out range of a benefit where increases in income lead to reduced benefit
entitlement; this is known as a taper in the UK, so I say that an in-work benefit is tapered away as income rises.
Income is disregarded if it does not affect the value of a means-tested benefit or tax credit. The marginal
withdrawal rate is the amount of benefit lost and tax paid when income increases at the margin.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e347a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e354" publication-type="other">
The caseload of a welfare benefit is the number of families claiming it; the take-up rate is the caseload as a
proportion of the total number of eligible families.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e364a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e371" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Cossa, Heckman and Lochner (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e378a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e385" publication-type="other">
Discussed further in Gottschalk (2000), Burtless (forthcoming) and Dickens (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e393a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e400" publication-type="other">
In 1999, the official US poverty standard for a couple with one child was $13,423, and, for a family of four, it
was $16,895. Sixty per cent of median income net of housing costs was £8,788 and £10,503 for the same
family types in the UK in 1998-99. The OECD's purchasing power parity conversion rate for the UK is 0.665
(so £1 =$1.50).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e416a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e423" publication-type="other">
US estimates from Bernstein and Hartmann (2000); UK estimates from Gregg, Harkness and Machin (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e430a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e437" publication-type="other">
Committee on Ways and Means (1998) describes the rules that the federal government imposes on states.
Gallagher et al. (1998) provide a comprehensive description of the TANF rules in all states as of October 1997.
The Welfare Rules database at the Urban Institute is an online database of the key parameters in states' TANF
programmes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e453a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e460" publication-type="other">
Hotz and Scholz (2001) provide a recent and comprehensive review of the operation and impact of E1TC.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e467a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e474" publication-type="other">
In 1999, EITC spending was $31.9 billion, compared with $16.7 billion spent on TANF and $19.0 billion on
food stamps (cited in Hotz and Scholz (2001)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e484a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e491" publication-type="other">
See Gruber (2000) for more details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e499a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e506" publication-type="other">
Blau (2000) is a thorough review of the US federal childcare programmes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e513a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e520" publication-type="other">
Discussed further by Brewer, Myck and Reed (2001), who focus on the additional support given to families
with children compared with that given to those without.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e530a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e537" publication-type="other">
The rates given are as at November 2000, to be consistent with the US rates. These, and other UK figures, are
taken from George et al. (2000), which provides a description of the UK's benefit system and is updated
annually.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e550a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e557" publication-type="other">
From 2003, adults without children will be able to claim an employment tax credit, to be based on the WFTC
(HM Treasury, 2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e567a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e574" publication-type="other">
See Department of Social Security (2000a and 2000b) for out-of-work families and Hansard (2000) for
WFTC claimants, but note that the latter estimate assumes that all families newly eligible for WFTC — very
few of whom would be eligible for HB — claim WFTC.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e587a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e594" publication-type="other">
For loans taken out since October 1995, there is a 40-week qualifying period; for loans taken out before
October 1995, there is an eight-week qualifying period followed by an 18-week period of a 50 per cent reduced
rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e608a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e615" publication-type="other">
See Table A.3 for the main rates and Gale (1997) for an analysis of the whole UK tax system from a US
perspective.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e625a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e632" publication-type="other">
A non-refundable tax credit reduces the annual tax bill by a certain amount. If the amount of tax due before
the credit is less than the value of the credit, the excess value is lost.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e642a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e649" publication-type="other">
See Blundell et al. (2000) and Dilnot and McCrae (1999) for a more detailed comparison of WFTC and FC.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e656a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e663" publication-type="other">
Assuming TANF payments in Florida, chosen partly as it seems to contain the median — or at least decisive
— US voter. I am updating Walker and Wiseman (1997) and Blundell and MaCurdy (1998) — who both
compare the budget constraint for low-income families in the UK and the US in 1996 — to reflect the reforms
to TANF and WFTC since then. I have ignored employers' payroll taxes and National Insurance contributions
in these graphs, mostly to avoid having to analyse incidence. Take-up rates are discussed below; if TANF time-
limits reduce take-up, then the incentive to work will be greater than shown here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e686a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e693" publication-type="other">
US median female full-time gross weekly earnings in 2000Q3 were $491, 3 per cent lower than the UK figure
of £338 in 2000 at $1.50 = £1. Sources: Bureau of Labour Statistics, 2000; Office for National Statistics, 2000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e703a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e710" publication-type="other">
These tables are drawn from Acs et al. (1998), who model work incentives in 12 states accounting for the
effects of TANF, food stamps, federal income tax, federal EITC, state-level income taxes and state-level earned
income tax credits. Their data relate to 1997; the main changes since then have been expansion in some state
EITCs. Meyer and Rosenbaum (2000) produce comparable figures for lone mothers between 1984 and 1996,
considering taxes, welfare, Medicaid and employer benefits. Maag and Urn Rogers (2000) offer similar
estimates for 13 states in 1999, although the focus is on generosity rather than work incentives.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e734a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e741" publication-type="other">
The figures are based on the 2000-01 tax and benefit system with the addition of the children's tax credit.
which was due to be introduced in April 2001 at £442 a year but is now worth £520 a year after the March
2001 Budget (too late to affect these calculations).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e754a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e761" publication-type="other">
Brewer (2000) shows the effect of WFTC on the budget constraint, replacement ratios and average
withdrawal rates under the previous work scenarios.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e771a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e778" publication-type="other">
These are the median values in Table 6 in Acs et al. (1998). The equivalent figures for the UK lone parent are
18 per cent and 15 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e788a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e795" publication-type="other">
Gosling and Lemieux (2000) present changes in the distribution of female wages in the US and the UK, but
they do not isolate lone mothers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e805a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e812" publication-type="other">
See Council of Economic Advisers (1999) and Zedlewski and Brauner (1999) for two studies amongst many
that attempt to explain this phenomenon.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e822a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e829" publication-type="other">
This implies a gross income of over £140 a week and rent levels above the national average for social
housing.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e840a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e847" publication-type="other">
The overall taper rate is calculated as 32% + 55%x(l-32%) + 65%x[l - {32% + 55%x(l-32%)}] = 89.3%.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e854a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e861" publication-type="other">
The HB taper of 65 per cent applies to income after taxes and WFTC, and the award calculation incorporates
the future changes in tax, National Insurance contributions and WFTC.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e871a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e878" publication-type="other">
Thomas and Pettigrew (1998), cited in Snape, Molloy and Kumar ( 1999), although this does refer to
households surviving on out-of-work benefits only. Snape et al. (1999) also find that out-of-work families
prefer to be paid benefits weekly or fortnightly to aid them in budgeting weekly. Wheatley (2001) cites
examples of claimants who would prefer WFTC to be paid fortnightly rather than together with wages.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e894a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e901" publication-type="other">
The average withdrawal rate on extra earnings in non-assessment periods is 32 per cent, compared with 69
per cent in assessment periods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e911a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e918" publication-type="other">
When introduced, EITC payments did count as income in AFDC calculations; the 1991 reform therefore
increased the value of EITC to families with low earnings, especially when taken alongside the reform in the
same year that removed the requirement for claimants to earn more in a year than they received in AFDC
payments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e934a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e941" publication-type="other">
This was also the case under family credit. Giles, Johnson and McCrae (1997) illustrate the effect of the
interaction of HB and FC on the gain to work for tenants in the social sector.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e952a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e959" publication-type="other">
A US phrase, as the US tax system depends upon marital status; I use 'couple' to mean 'married couple' in
the US and 'married or cohabiting couple' in the UK.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e969a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e976" publication-type="other">
Hotz and Scholz (2001) summarise the parameters of EITC since 1975.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d15e992a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e996" publication-type="other">
Acs, G., Coe, N., Watson, K. and Lerman, R. I, (1998), Does Work Pay? An Analysis of the Work
Incentives under TANF, Occasional Paper no. 9, Washington, DC: Urban Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1006a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1010" publication-type="other">
Barrow, L. and McGranahan, L. (2000), 'The effects of the earned income tax credit on the
seasonality of household expenditures', National Tax Journal, vol. 53, no. 4, part 2, pp. 1211—
43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1023a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1027" publication-type="other">
Bernstein, J. and Hartmann, H. (2000), 'Defining and characterising the low-wage labour market',
in K. Kaye and D. S. Nightingale (eds), The Low-Wage Labour Market: Challenges and
Opportunities for Economic Self-Sufficiency, Washington, DC: Urban Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1040a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1044" publication-type="other">
Blank, R. M., Card, D. E. and Robins, P, K. (2000), 'Financial incentives for increasing work and
income among low-income families', in D. Card and R, M. Blank (eds), Finding Jobs: Work
and Welfare Reform, New York: Russell Sage Foundation,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1058a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1062" publication-type="other">
Blau, D. M. (2000), 'Child care subsidy programs', in R. Moffitt (ed.), Means-Tested Transfer
Programs in the U.S., Chicago: University of Chicago Press, forthcoming,
http://www.nber.org/books/means-tested/index.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1075a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1079" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. (2000), 'Work incentives and in-work benefit reforms: a review', Oxford Review of
Economic Policy, vol. 16, pp. 27-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1089a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1093" publication-type="other">
—, Duncan, A., McCrae, J. and Meghir, C. (2000), 'The labour market impact of the working
families' tax credit', Fiscal Studies, vol. 21, pp. 75-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1103a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1107" publication-type="other">
— and Hoynes, H. (2000), 'In-work benefit reform and the labour market', in R. Blundell, D. Card
and R. B. Freeman (eds), Seeking a Premier League Economy, Chicago: University of Chicago
Press, forthcoming. Download from http://www.nber.org/books/bcf/benefitl2-6-00.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1120a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1124" publication-type="other">
— and MaCurdy, T. (1998), 'Labour supply: a review of alternative approaches', Institute for
Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. 98/18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1134a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1138" publication-type="other">
— and Walker, I. (2000), 'Working families' tax credit: a review of the evidence, issues and
prospects for further research', mimeo, Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1149a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1153" publication-type="other">
Brewer, M. (2000), 'Comparing in-work benefits and financial work incentives for low-income
families in the US and UK', Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. 00/16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1163a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1167" publication-type="other">
—, Myck, M. and Reed, H. (2001), Financial Support for Families with Children: Options for the
New Integrated Child Credit, Commentary no. 82, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1177a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1181" publication-type="other">
Bureau of Labour Statistics (2000), Usual Weekly Earnings of Wage and Salary Workers, Third
Quarter 2000. Download from http://stats.bls.gov/newsrels.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1191a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1195" publication-type="other">
Burtless, G. (forthcoming), 'The employment experiences and potential earnings of welfare
recipients', in S. H. Danziger and D. H. Weinberg (eds), Fighting Poverty: What Works and
What Doesn't, Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1208a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1212" publication-type="other">
Committee on Ways and Means (various years), Green Book: Background Material and Data on
Programs within the Jurisdiction of the Committee on Ways and Means, Washington, DC: US
House of Representatives Committee on Ways and Means.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1225a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1229" publication-type="other">
Cossa, R., Heckman, J. L. and Lochner, L. (1999), 'Wage subsidies and skill formation: a study of
the earned income tax credit', mimeo, University of Chicago, http://lily.src.uchicago.edu/
papers/labor.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1243a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1247" publication-type="other">
Council of Economic Advisers (1999), The Effect of Welfare Policy and the Economic Expansion
on Welfare Caseloads: An Update, Washington, DC: Executive Office of the President.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1257a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1261" publication-type="other">
Department of Social Security (2000a), Income Support Quarterly Enquiry, London: Government
Statistical Service.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1271a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1275" publication-type="other">
— (2000b), Housing Benefit and Council Tax Benefit Quarterly Enquiry, London: Government
Statistical Service.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1285a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1289" publication-type="other">
— (2000c), Income Related Benefits Estimates of Take-Up in 1998/9, London: Government
Statistical Service.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1299a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1303" publication-type="other">
Dickens, R. (forthcoming), 'Caught in a trap? Wage mobility in Britain: 1975-1995', Economica.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1310a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1314" publication-type="other">
— and Ellwood, D. (2000), 'Whither poverty in Great Britain and the United States? The
determinants of changing poverty and whether work will work', in R. Blundell, D. Card and R.
B. Freeman (eds), Seeking a Premier League Economy, Chicago: University of Chicago Press,
forthcoming. Download from http://www.nber.org/books/bcf/povertyl2-5-00.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1331a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1335" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A. and McCrae, J. (1999), Family Credit and the Working Families' Tax Credit, Briefing
Note no. 3/99, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies, http://www.ifs.org.uk/labmarket/wftc.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1345a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1349" publication-type="other">
Eissa, N. and Hoynes, H. W. (1999), 'Good news for low-income families? Tax-transfer schemes
and marriage', mimeo, University of California, Berkeley, http://elsa.berkeley.edu/users/hilary/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1359a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1363" publication-type="other">
— and — (2000), 'Explaining the fall and rise in the tax cost of marriage: the effect of tax laws and
demographic trends 1984-1997', mimeo, University of California, Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1373a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1377" publication-type="other">
Gale, W. (1997), 'What can America learn from the British tax system?', Fiscal Studies, vol. 18,
pp. 341-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1387a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1391" publication-type="other">
Gallagher, L. J., Gallagher, M., Perese, K., Schreiber, S. and Watson, K. (1998), One Year after
Federal Welfare Reform: A Description of State TANF Decisions as of October 1997,
Washington, DC: Urban Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1404a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1408" publication-type="other">
General Accounting Office (1997), 'Earned income credit', Testimony before the Committee on
Ways and Means, GAO/T-GGD-97-105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1419a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1423" publication-type="other">
George, C., Allirajah, D., Donnelly, C., Fitzpatrick, P., Frobisher, F., Hynes, B., Mitchell, S.,
Robinson, S., Simmons, D., Stagg, P., Tait, G., Thurley, D. and Turville, P. (2000), Welfare
Benefits Handbook 2000/2001, London: Child Poverty Action Group.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1436a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1440" publication-type="other">
Giles, C., Johnson, P. and McCrae, J. (1997), 'Housing benefit and financial returns to employment
for tenants in the social sector', Fiscal Studies, vol. 18, pp. 49-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1450a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1454" publication-type="other">
Gosling, A. and Lemieux, T. (2000), 'Labour market reforms and changes in wage inequality in the
UK and US', in R. Blundell, D. Card and R. B. Freeman (eds), Seeking a Premier League
Economy, Chicago: University of Chicago Press, forthcoming. Download from
http://www.nber.org/books/bcf/reformsl2-5-00.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1470a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1474" publication-type="other">
Gottschalk, P. (2000), 'Work as a stepping stone for welfare recipients: what is the evidence?', in
K. Kaye and D. S. Nightingale (eds), The Low-Wage Labour Market: Challenges and
Opportunities for Economic Self-Sufficiency, Washington, DC: Urban Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1487a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1491" publication-type="other">
Gregg, P., Harkness, S. and Machin, S. (1999), 'Poor kids: trends in child poverty in Britain,
1968-96', Fiscal Studies, vol. 20, pp. 163-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1501a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1505" publication-type="other">
Gruber, J. (2000), 'Medicaid', in R. Moffitt (ed.), Means-Tested Transfer Programs in the U.S.,
Chicago: University of Chicago Press, forthcoming, http://www.nber.org/books/means-
tested/index.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1519a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1523" publication-type="other">
Hansard (2000), Official Report 20 March 2000, col. 441W, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1530a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1534" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (2000), 'Tackling poverty and making work pay: tax credits for the 21st century', The
Modernisation of Britain's Tax and Benefit System, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1544a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1548" publication-type="other">
Hotz, V. J. and Scholz, J. K. (2001), 'The earned income tax credit', in R. Moffitt (ed.), Means-
Tested Transfer Programs in the U.S., Chicago: University of Chicago Press, forthcoming.
http://www.nber.org/books/means-tested/index.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1561a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1565" publication-type="other">
Inland Revenue (2000a), Working Families' Tax Credit Application Form April 2000, Form
WFTC1, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1579" publication-type="other">
— (2000b), Working Families' Tax Credit April 2000: Notes on Applying, Form WFTC6, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1586a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1590" publication-type="other">
— (2000c), Working Families' Tax Credit Quarterly Enquiry, August 2000, London: Government
Statistical Service.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1601a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1605" publication-type="other">
Internal Revenue Service (1999a), 1999 1040 Instructions, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1612a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1616" publication-type="other">
— (1999b), Exemptions, Standard Deduction, and Filing Information, Publication 501,
Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1626a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1630" publication-type="other">
— (2000a), Earned Income Credit, Publication 596, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1637a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1641" publication-type="other">
— (2000b), Statistics of Income Bulletin, Publication 1136, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1648a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1652" publication-type="other">
Johnson, N. (1999), A Hand Up: How State Earned Income Tax Credits Help Working Families
Escape Poverty, 1999 Edition, Washington, DC: Center on Budget and Policy Priorities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1662a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1666" publication-type="other">
— (2000), A Hand Up: How State Earned Income Tax Credits Help Working Families Escape
Poverty in 2000: An Overview, Washington, DC: Center on Budget and Policy Priorities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1677a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1681" publication-type="other">
Joint Committee on Taxation (1998), Present Law and Analysis Relating to Individual Marginal
Effective Tax Rates, JCS-3-98, Washington, DC: US Government Printing Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1691a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1695" publication-type="other">
Kaye, K. and Nightingale, D. S. (eds) (2000), The Low-Wage Labour Market: Challenges and
Opportunities for Economic Self-Sufficiency, Washington, DC: Urban Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1705a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1709" publication-type="other">
Link, R. J., Bibus, A. and Lyons, K. (2000), When Children Pay: US Welfare Reform and Its
Implications for UK Policy, London: Child Poverty Action Group.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1719a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1723" publication-type="other">
Maag, E. and Lim Rogers, D. (2000), The New Federalism and State Tax Policies toward the
Working Poor, Occasional Paper no. 38, Washington, DC: Urban Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1733a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1737" publication-type="other">
Meyer, B. D. and Rosenbaum, D. T. (2000), 'Making single mothers work: recent tax and benefit
policy and its effects', National Bureau of Economic Research, Working Paper no. 7491.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1747a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1751" publication-type="other">
Office for National Statistics (2000), New Earnings Survey 2000, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1759a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1763" publication-type="other">
Scholz, J. K. (1994), 'The earned income tax credit: participation, compliance and anti-poverty
effectiveness', National Tax Journal, March, pp. 59-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1773a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1777" publication-type="other">
Smeeding, T. M., Phillips, K. R. and O'Connor, M. (2000), 'The EITC: expectation, knowledge,
use and economic and social mobility', mimeo, Center for Policy Research, Syracuse
University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1790a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1794" publication-type="other">
Snape, D., Molloy, D. and Kumar, M. (1999), Relying on the State, Relying on Each Other,
Research Report no. 103, London: Department of Social Security.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1804a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1808" publication-type="other">
Thomas, A. and Pettigrew, N. (1998), Attitudes towards Methods of Paying Benefits, DSS In-
House Report no. 51, London: Department of Social Security.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1818a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1822" publication-type="other">
US Department of Agriculture (1999), Food Stamps, Form FNS-313, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1829a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1833" publication-type="other">
Walker, R. and Wiseman, I. (1997), 'The possibility of a British earned income tax credit', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 18, pp. 401-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1844a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1848" publication-type="other">
Zedlewski, S. R. and Brauner, S. (1999), 'Declines in food stamp and welfare participation: is there
a connection?', Urban Institute, Discussion Paper no. 99-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
