<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440054</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Quantifying the Costs of Investment Limits for Chilean Pension Funds</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Solange M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Berstein</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Rómulo A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Chumacero</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2006</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440047</issue-id>
         <fpage>99</fpage>
         <lpage>123</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2006</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440054"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Since the creation of the Chilean pension fund industry in 1981, pension fund administrators have not been free to choose their investment portfolios because of stringent regulation of investment limits. The diagnosis implicit with the imposition of limits was that the Chilean capital market was not deep, that there was an important demand for funds to finance the expansion of the productive sector and that, due to principal–agent problems, protection for uninformed account holders was needed. As this regulation entails an inefficient combination of risk and return, this paper quantifies its costs.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e190a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e197" publication-type="other">
The authors thank Luis Ahumada, Rodrigo Fuentes, José Manuel Garrido, Leonardo Hernandez, Luis
Oscar Henera, Christian Johnson, Guillermo Larrain, Eduardo Lopez, Jorge Meyer, Robert Rivas, Klaus
Schmidt-Hebbel, Rodrigo Valdés, Salvador Zurita, two anonymous referees, and seminar participants at
the Central Bank of Chile, University of Chile, LACEA and EcoMod for helpful comments and
suggestions. Carlos Pereira provided able research assistance. The usual disclaimer applies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e216a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e223" publication-type="other">
For a detailed analysis of pension fund reforms, see Valdés (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e230a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e237" publication-type="other">
See Cheyre (1991 ) and Superintendence of Pension Funds Administrators (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e244a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e251" publication-type="other">
Cardinale (2003) attempts to find the optimal portfolio in the absence of limits on investment abroad,
but does not consider the specific investment regulation in Chile.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e262a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e269" publication-type="other">
See Vittas (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e276a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e283" publication-type="other">
Even after 24 years of the Chilean pension system, account holders appear not to be well informed
about prices, returns and other important variables. According to surveys conducted in 2001 (Barömetro-
CERC) and 2002 (EPS Survey), more than 90 per cent of them did not know how much they were
charged by PFAs for administration fees. Lack of information on pensions or financial education in
general appears to be not just a Chilean but a worldwide characteristic (Bernheim, 1998; D'ambrosio,
2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e306a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e313" publication-type="other">
The income considered for contributions has a ceiling of 60UF (around US$2,040) a month.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e320a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e327" publication-type="other">
Walker and Valk (1995) analyse investment regulations and their performance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e334a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e341" publication-type="other">
Investment limits abroad have continued to increase. By Law, this limit can go up to 30 per cent with
no distinction between variable and fixed income instruments. The limit is currently set by the Central
Bank at the maximum level of 30 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e354a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e361" publication-type="other">
In August 2002, the average rate of return to compute the minimum return was changed from an
average over the past 12 months to an average over the past 36 months.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e372a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e379" publication-type="other">
When the rate of return is above the average plus 2 percentage points, or 150 per cent of that
average, whichever is higher, the excess returns must be used as a reserve if returns go below the
minimum threshold.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e392a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e399" publication-type="other">
See Zurita and Jara (1999) for an analysis of the performance of pension funds in Chile.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e406a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e413" publication-type="other">
See French and Poterba (1991) and Lewis (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e420a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e427" publication-type="other">
We thank a referee for pointing this out.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e434a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e441" publication-type="other">
Appendix A provides further details of the data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e448a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e455" publication-type="other">
As pointed out by the referees, one could use a more diversified global portfolio (such as the MSCI
world index) instead of the Dow-Jones. However, the contemporaneous correlation of the monthly returns
between the indices is 0.82. Furthermore, as discussed below, our results are robust to using the MSCI
index.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e472a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e479" publication-type="other">
Appendix B defines and briefly describes the approaches considered for modelling the portfolio
choice of PFAs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e489a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e496" publication-type="other">
Operationally, the net inflows are computed from (1) by using the information on total assets and
observed returns of the system reported by the Superintendence of Pension Funds Administrators every
month. A methodological description of the valuation of assets can be found in its Circular #1216 of July
2002.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e512a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e519" publication-type="other">
We explored several settings for H and fixed it at 36 (three years) for the numerical exercises
reported below.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e529a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e536" publication-type="other">
Voluntary contributions to the system were always allowed. Changes in regulation in 2002 made this
option even more attractive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e546a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e553" publication-type="other">
See Appendix B for details and definitions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e560a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e567" publication-type="other">
We set J = 36 (three-year average).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e575a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e582" publication-type="other">
Alexander and Baptista (2002) show that when returns are normally distributed, minimum-VaR
portfolios converge to minimum-variance portfolios as the confidence level at which VaR is computed
increases («decreases). As we chose to obtain a minimum-VaR portfolio that matches the average return
of the whole sample, we calibrated VaR only once.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e598a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e607" publication-type="other">
Alternatively, the portfolio without limits could have been chosen by lifting the restrictions and
using the values for parameters such as B and VaR obtained from the procedures described above. This
would have led to 'better' return-volatility combinations for the agent (the PFAs) than the ones obtained
here. However, this would have made it impossible to evaluate the effects of regulation on the principal
(account holders) without knowing their preferences. By matching volatilities, we obtain straightforward
(and conservative) estimates of the costs of investment limits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e630a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e637" publication-type="other">
Interestingly, the investment limits were beneficial during the 'black Monday' episode (and in
general at the end of the 1980s and beginning of the 1990s). As investment abroad was not allowed, total
assets with limits were greater than the assets that would have been obtained without limits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e650a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e657" publication-type="other">
The results are robust to the choice of instrument used for foreign variable income. For example, if
the MSCI world index were used instead of the Dow-Jones index and if portfolio strategy q were selected,
the average portfolio composition in fixed income domestic, variable income domestic, fixed income
foreign and variable income foreign instruments would have been 54 per cent, 14 per cent, 17 per cent
and 15 per cent respectively. The probability that the limit on foreign variable income instruments would
have been binding is 86 per cent, and the average gap per account holder would have been UF27
(approximately US$920).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e683a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e690" publication-type="other">
The results for the q and v portfolios are qualitatively similar to those for the p portfolio and are not
included.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e700a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e707" publication-type="other">
A referee suggested considering a different counterfactual scenario with more flexible limits. Figure
4 suggests that if (for example) the investment limits prevailing at the end of the sample period were in
place from the beginning, the costs would still have been substantial as the limits on investing abroad
would have been binding at least 38 per cent of the time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e724a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e731" publication-type="other">
In fact, as Table 3 suggests, the differences in portfolio allocations are not substantial, and the
trajectory of the ratio of assets with and without limits is in accordance with that reported in Figure 3.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e741a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e748" publication-type="other">
See Shiller (2002) for a discussion about the use of the Chilean UF and indexed units of account
around the world.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e758a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e765" publication-type="other">
The correlation between the Dow-Jones and the MSCI world index over the sample period was 0.82.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e772a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e779" publication-type="other">
See Dowd (1998) and Johnson (2001) for details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d29e795a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e799" publication-type="other">
Alexander, G. and Baptista, A. (2002), 'Economic implications of using a mean-VaR model
for portfolio selection: a comparison with mean-variance analysis', Journal of Economic
Dynamics and Control, vol. 26, pp. 1159-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e812a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e816" publication-type="other">
Arrau, P. and Chumacero, R. (1998), 'Tamano de los fondos de pensiones en Chile y su
desempeno financiero', Cuadernos de Economia, vol. 105, pp. 205-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e826a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e830" publication-type="other">
Bernheim, D. (1998), 'Financial illiteracy, education, and retirement savings', in O. Mitchell
and S. Schieber (eds), Living with Defined Contribution Plans, Philadelphia, PA:
University of Pennsylvania Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e843a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e847" publication-type="other">
Brandimarte, P. (2002), Numerical Methods in Finance: A MATLAB-Based Introduction,
New York, NY : John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e858a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e862" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J., Lo, A. and MacKinlay, C. (1997), The Econometrics of Financial Markets,
Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e872a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e876" publication-type="other">
Cardinale, M. (2003), 'Optimal portfolio allocations and funded pension systems: the case of
Chile', Imperial College Management School, Watson Wyatt Technical Paper no. 2003-
GP02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e889a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e893" publication-type="other">
Cheyre, H. (1991), La prevision en Chile ayer y hoy, second edition, Santiago: Centro de
Estudios Püblicos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e903a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e907" publication-type="other">
Corbo, V. and Schmidt-Hebbel, K. (2003), 'Efectos macroeconömicos de la reforma de
pensiones en Chile: resultados y desaffos de las reformas a las pensiones', edited by
Corporation for Research, Study and Development of Social Security (CIEDESS),
Santiago: Federaciôn Internacional de Administradoras de Fondos de Pensiones.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e923a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e927" publication-type="other">
D'ambrosio, M. (2003), 'Ignorance is not bliss: the importance of financial education',
Contractual Savings Conference: Supervisory and Regulatory Issues in Private Pensions
and Life Insurance, World Bank, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e940a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e944" publication-type="other">
D.L. 3.500 (1980), Regulations D.L. no. 3.500 and D.F.L. no. 101 (updated text, February
2002).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e955a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e959" publication-type="other">
Dowd, K. (1998), Beyond Value at Risk: The New Science of Risk Management, Chichester,
NY: Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e969a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e973" publication-type="other">
French, K. and Poterba, J. (1991), 'Investor diversification and international equity markets',
American Economic Review, vol. 81, pp. 222-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e983a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e987" publication-type="other">
Gourieroux, C., Laurent, J. and Scaillet, O. (2000), 'Sensitivity analysis of values at risk',
Journal of Empirical Finance, vol. 7, pp. 225-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e997a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1001" publication-type="other">
Huang, C. and Litzenberger, R. (1988), Foundations for Financial Economics, Englewood
Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1011a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1015" publication-type="other">
Johnson, C. (2001), 'Value-at-risk: teoria y aplicaciones', Estudios de Economi'a, vol. 28, pp.
217-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1025a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1029" publication-type="other">
Lai, T., Wang, K., Chan, S. and Lee, D. (1992), 'A note on optimal portfolio selection and
diversification benefits with short sale restrictions on real estate assets', Journal of Real
Estate Research, vol. 7, pp. 493-501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1043a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1047" publication-type="other">
LeRoy, S. and Werner, J. (2001), Principles of Financial Economics, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1057a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1061" publication-type="other">
Lewis, K. (1999), 'Trying to explain home bias in equities and consumption', Journal of
Economic Literature, vol. 37, pp. 571-608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1071a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1075" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R. (2002), 'Indexed units of account: theory and assessment of historical experience',
in F. Lefort and K. Schmidt-Hebbel (eds), Indexation, Inflation, and Monetary Policy,
Series on Central Banking, Analysis, and Economic Policies 2, Santiago: Central Bank of
Chile.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1091a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1095" publication-type="other">
Superintendence of Pension Funds Administrators (2003), The Chilean Pension System based
on Individual Capitalization, fourth edition, edited by A. Ferreiro, Santiago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1105a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1109" publication-type="other">
Valdés, S. (1997), 'Financing a pension reform toward private funded pensions', in S.
Valdés-Prieto (ed.), The Economics of Pensions, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1119a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1123" publication-type="other">
— and Ramirez, M. C. (1999), 'Herding in DC pension funds: regulation or market forces?',
Pontificia Universidad Catölica de Chile, Instituto de Economfa, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1134a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1138" publication-type="other">
Vittas, D. (1996), 'Pension funds and capital markets', World Bank, Financial Sector
Development, Note no. 71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1148a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1152" publication-type="other">
Walker, E. and Valk, E. (1995), 'La inversion de los fondos de pensiones: historia, normativa
y resultados', in S. Baeza and F. Margozzini (eds), Quince ahos después: una mirada al
sistema privado de pensiones, Santiago: Centra de Estudios Püblicos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1165a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1169" publication-type="other">
Zurita, S. and Jara, C. (1999), 'Desempeno financière de fondos de pensiones', Estudios
Püblicos, vol. 74, pp. 227-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
