<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830656</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830658</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FARM CREDIT AND THE FACTORS AFFECTING THE UPTAKE OF LOANS BY FARMERS IN IRAN / CRÉDIT AGRICOLE ET FACTEURS INFLUENÇANT L'INCIDENCE DE PRÊTS PAR LES FERMIERS IRANIENS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Saeed</given-names>
                  <surname>Yazdani</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Kisan</given-names>
                  <surname>Gunjal</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>263</fpage>
         <lpage>277</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830658"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>A notable feature of Iranian agriculture is the predominance of small and poor farmers. Therefore improving small farmers' productivity is an important objective of economic policies. Provision of agricultural credit has been a focus of attention in this regard. The purpose of this paper is to examine the impact of credit and the contribution of different characteristics of farmers towards their borrowing behaviour. The principal finding from this analysis suggests that the use of credit is associated with higher levels of farm output and income. A Multivariate Discriminant Analysis (MDA) methodology is used to identify the factors that are likely to influence farmers' borrowing behaviour significantly. The application of discriminant analysis in this study has made an important contribution over simple univariate analysis in that it identified the impact of different variables simultaneously. The analysis suggests that credit from Agricultural Bank in Iran is mainly directed towards large size, high income and more educated farmers. Therefore, increasing an uptake of loans by small size and low income farmers would help improve not only their productivity but also income equity. Un fait marquant de l'agriculture Iranienne est la prédominance de petites fermes et de pauvres fermiers. L'augmentation de la productivité de ces fermes est donc un objectif important pour toute politique agricole. L'obtention de crédit pour ces opérations est un sujet de grand intérét â cet égard. Le but de cet article est d'examiner l'impact du crédit agricole et la contribution de différentes caractéristiques dans le comportement d'emprunt des fermiers. Le résultat le plus important provenant de notre analyse est que l'utilisation du crédit est associé à des niveaux de production plus élevés, ainsi qu'à des revenus accrus. La méthodologie MDA ("Multi variate Discriminant Analysis") a été utilisé pour cerner les éléments susceptibles d'influencer le comportement d'emprunt des agriculteurs. L'utilisation de MDA dans cette étude a été d'une grande importance, vue la possibilité d'identifier l'impact de plusieurs variables simultanément. Ceci est une nette amélioration comparativement à l'utilisation de la "simple univariate analysis". Notre analyse démontre que le crédit de la Banque Agricole est principalement alloué aux fermes de plus grande envergure, aux agriculteurs mieux instruits et à revenus plus élevés.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e174a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e181" publication-type="other">
Adams, D. W. (1982), "Why Agricultural Credit Programmes in Low Income Countries Perform Poorly".
Economics and Sociology Occasional Paper, Ohio State University. 23pp.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e191a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e198" publication-type="other">
Agricultural Bank of Iran (1976-1993). Annual Reports.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e205a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e212" publication-type="other">
Baker, W. S. (1970). Agricultural Credit and Colombia's Economic Development. Ph.D thesis, Ohio State
University, U.S.A.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e222a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e229" publication-type="other">
Begashaw, G. (1980). Supervised Credit Projects in Jamaica. PhD Thesis, Ohio University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e237a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e244" publication-type="other">
Bourne, C. (1983). Effects of Subsidised Credit on the Size Distribution of Farm Household Incomes". Social and
Economic Studies, 32(1): 81 -101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e254a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e261" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Iran (1996). The Annual Economic Reports.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e268a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e275" publication-type="other">
David, C. C. and Meyer, R.L. (1983). Measuring the farm Level Impact of Agricultural Loans. Rural Financial
Markets in Developing Countries. Edited by Von Pischke, Adams, D.W. and Donald, G. The Johns Hopkins
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e288a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e295" publication-type="other">
Ekhlaspour, R. (1997). Studying production effects of credit and factors affecting farmers credit used. MSc Thesis,
University of Thehran.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e305a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e312" publication-type="other">
Fabiyi, Y. L. and K. O. Osotimehin. (1984). "An Analysis of the Impact of Credit in Rice Production: A Case Study
of Ondo and Oyo States, Nigeria". Saving and Development, 8(4) : 351-362.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e322a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e329" publication-type="other">
Hair, J.F., Anderson, R.E., Tatham, R.L. and Black, W.C. (1987). Multivariate data Analysis with Readings. Third
ed. McMillan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e340a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e347" publication-type="other">
Khan, R.A.R. (1987). "Institutional Agricultural Credit and its Role on Rulal Development in Pakistan". Journal
of Rural Development and Administration, 19(1) : 19-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e357a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e364" publication-type="other">
Morrison, D.F. (1990). Multivariate Statistical Methods. Third edition, Mcgraw Hill International Editions.495p.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e371a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e378" publication-type="other">
Nyanin, 0.0.(1978). Credit and Small Farmers in South Korea. MSc, Thesis, The Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e385a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e392" publication-type="other">
Rahmani, S. (1996). The impact of Agricultural Loans on Farmers performance. MSc Thesis, University of
Tehran.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e402a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e409" publication-type="other">
Schultz, W.T. (1964). Transforming Traditional Agriculture. The University of Chicago Press, Chicago, 212pp.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e416a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e423" publication-type="other">
Shahinfar, A (1995). Studying the Agricultural Bank's Performance in Province of Khorasan (Iran). MSc Thesis,
University of Tehran.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e434a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e441" publication-type="other">
Singh, G. (1974). Farm Level Determinants of Credit Affecting the Demand for Agricultural Credit at the Farm
Level. MSc. Thesis, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e451a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e458" publication-type="other">
Statistical Centre of Iran (1998). Reports on Population Characteristic. Hamshahri Newspaper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e465a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e472" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke, J.D. and Adams D.W. (1980). "Fungibility and the Design and Evaluation of Agricultural Credit
Projects". American Journal of Agricultural Economics. 62(4) : 719-726.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e482a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e489" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke, J.D., Adams, D.W. and Donald, G. (1983). Rural Financial Markets in Developing Countries. The
Johns Hopkins University Press, U.S.A. 441 p.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


