<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26789709</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Solar Panels on Electrified Vehicles</article-title>
            <subtitle>Applications and Off-Cycle CO₂ Credit</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Abdelhamid</surname>
                  <given-names>Mahmoud</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rhodes</surname>
                  <given-names>Kevin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Christen</surname>
                  <given-names>Erik</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kok</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">WCX18 Best Papers Special Issue</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26789698</issue-id>
         <fpage>311</fpage>
         <lpage>322</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 Ford Motor Co.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26789709"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The objective of this article is to provide a comprehensive investigation of the opportunities and applications of using solar panels in electrified vehicles. The use of photovoltaic (PV) panels as an auxiliary energy source of on-board fuel in plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs), full hybrid electric vehicles (FHEVs), and battery electric vehicles (BEVs) is investigated. The electrical architectures and the benefits of various possible applications are presented, such as active vehicle cabin ventilation, charging the low voltage battery, and charging the high voltage (HV) traction battery to extended driving ranges. In addition, the possibility of using PV panels to cool down the HV battery in extreme temperature environments is also investigated, supported by experimental tests used to properly model the thermal behavior of the HV battery and the effect of the cooling. This work also analyzes the CO₂ off-cycle credits made available, by the United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and European Commission (EC), for automakers, which equip their vehicles with solar panels. Finally, the challenges and market outlook that make the on-board solar panel a more economical and effective solution for electrified vehicles are highlighted.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Singh, R., Alapatt, G.F., and Abdelhamid, M., “Green Energy Conversion &amp; Storage for Solving India’s Energy Problem through Innovation in Ultra Large Scale Manufacturing and Advanced Research of Solid State Devices and Systems,” Presented at in 2012 International Conference on Emerging Electronics (ICEE), IEEE, 2012, 1-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Singh, R., Asif, A., Ganesh K., Venayagamoorthy, G.K. et al., “Emerging Role of Photovoltaics for Sustainably Powering Underdeveloped, Emerging, and Developed Economies,” Presented at in 2014 2nd International Conference on Green Energy and Technology (ICGET), IEEE, 2014, 1-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Cygan, D., Abbasi, H., Kozlov, A., Pondo, J. et al., “Full Spectrum Solar System: Hybrid Concentrated Photovoltaic/Concentrated Solar Power (CPV-CSP),” MRS Advances 1(43):2941-2946, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Winston, R., Yablonovitch, E., Jiang, L., Widyolar, B. et al., “Hybrid Solar Collector Using Nonimaging Optics and Photovoltaic Components,” Presented at in SPIE, Vol. 9572, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Widyolar, B.K., Abdelhamid, M., Jiang, L., Winston, R. et al., “Design, Simulation and Experimental Characterization of a Novel Parabolic Trough Hybrid Solar Photovoltaic/Thermal (PV/T) Collector,” Renewable Energy 101:1379-1389, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Abdelhamid, M., Widyolar, B.K., Jiang, L., Winston, R. et al., “Novel Double-Stage High-Concentrated Solar Hybrid Photovoltaic/Thermal (PV/T) Collector with Nonimaging Optics and GaAs Solar Cells Reflector,” Applied Energy 182:68-79, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Winston, R., Jiang, J., Abdelhamid, M., Bennett, K.B.K. et al., “Nonimaging Optics Maximizing Exergy for Hybrid Solar System,” Presented at in SPIE Optical Engineering+ Applications, International Society for Optics and Photonics, 2016, 99550N-99550N.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Massoud Amin, S. and Wollenberg, B.F., “Toward a Smart Grid: Power Delivery for the 21st Century,” IEEE Power and Energy Magazine 3(5):34-41, Sept.-Oct. 2005, doi:10.1109/MPAE.2005.1507024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Wu, X., Hu, X., Moura, S., Yin, X. et al., “Stochastic Control of Smart Home Energy Management with Plug-In Electric Vehicle Battery Energy Storage and Photovoltaic Array,” Journal of Power Sources 333:203-212, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Arsie, I., Rizzo, G., and Sorrentino, M., “Optimal Design and Dynamic Simulation of a Hybrid Solar Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-2997, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-2997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Abdelhamid, M., Haque, I., Singh, R., Pilla, S. et al., “Optimal Design and Techno-Economic Analysis of a Hybrid Solar Vehicle: Incorporating Solar Energy as an On- Board Fuel toward Future Mobility,” Presented at in ASME 2016 International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference, American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 2016, V003T01A033-V003T01A033.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Abdelhamid, M., “A Comprehensive Assessment Methodology Based on Life Cycle Analysis for On-Board Photovoltaic Solar Modules in Vehicles,” Ph.D. thesis, Automotive Engineering Department, Clemson University, SC, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Kimura, K., Kudo, Y., and Sato, A., “Techno-Economic Analysis of Solar Hybrid Vehicles Part 1: Analysis of Solar Hybrid Vehicle Potential Considering Well-to-Wheel GHG Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-1287, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-1287.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Abdelhamid, M., Haque, I., Pilla, S., Filipi, Z. et al., “Impacts of Adding Photovoltaic Solar System Onboard to Internal Combustion Engine Vehicles towards Meeting 2025 Fuel Economy CAFE Standards,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power 5(2):237-248, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-1165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Jung, H., Song, M., and Kim, S., “A Development of Energy Management System with Semi-Transparent Solar Roof and Off-Cycle Credit Test Methodology for Solar Power Assisted Automobile,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 10(1):170-177, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Abdelhamid, M., Pilla, S., Singh, R., Haque, I. et al., “A Comprehensive Optimized Model for On-Board Solar Photovoltaic System for Plug-In Electric Vehicles: Energy and Economic Impacts,” International Journal of Energy Research 40(11):1489-1508, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Abdelhamid, M., Singh, R., and Haque, I., “Role of PV Generated DC Power in Transport Sector: Case Study of Plug-In EV,” Presented at in 2015 IEEE First International Conference on DC Microgrids (ICDCM), IEEE, 2015, 299-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Mathijsen, D., “Redefining the Motor Car,” Reinforced Plastics 60(3):154-159, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Abdelhamid, M., Singh, R., and Omar, M., “Review of Microcrack Detection Techniques for Silicon Solar Cells,” IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 4(1):514-524, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Tariq, M., Abdelhamid, M., Li, Y., Omar, M. et al., “Fusion of Thermal and Visible Acquisitions for Evaluating Production- Borne Scratches and Shunts in Photovoltaic PV Cells,” Journal of Materials Science Research 1(4):57, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">NREL, “Best Research Solar Cell Efficiencies,” Apr. 2017, https://www.nrel.gov/pv/assets/images/efficiency-chart.png.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Abdelhamid, M., Singh, R., Qattawi, A., Omar, M. et al., “Evaluation of On-Board Photovoltaic Modules Options for Electric Vehicles,” IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics 4(6):1576-1584, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Abdelhamid, M., Qattawi, A., Singh, R., and Haque, I., “Comparison of an Analytical Hierarchy Process and Fuzzy Axiomatic Design for Selecting Appropriate Photovoltaic Modules for Onboard Vehicle Design,” International Journal of Modern Engineering 15(1):23-35, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">International Energy Agency, “Global EV Outlook 2017,” https://www.iea.org/publications/freepublications/publication/GlobalEVOutlook2017.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">NREL Data, http://rredc.nrel.gov/solar/old_data/nsrdb/1961-1990/redbook/atlas/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Coupti, J.B., Lorenzo, E., and Chenlo, F., “A General Battery Model for PV System Simulation,” Progress in Photovoltaics 1:283-292, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Hu, X., Cao, D., and Egardt, B., “Condition Monitoring in Advanced Battery Management Systems: Moving Horizon Estimation Using a Reduced Electrochemical Model,” IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics 23(1):167-178, Feb. 2018, doi:10.1109/TMECH.2017.2675920.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Alzuwayer, B., Abdelhamid, M., Pisu, P., Giovenco, P. et al., “Modeling and Simulation of a Series Hybrid CNG Vehicle,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 3(1):20-29, May 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1802.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Peng, F.Z., Li, H., Gui-Jia, S., and Lawler, J.S., “A New ZVS Bidirectional DC-DC Converter for Fuel Cell and Battery Application,” IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics 19(1):54-65, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Bogno, B., Sawicki, J.-P., Salame, T., Aillerie, M. et al., “Improvement of Safety, Longevity and Performance of Lead Acid Battery in Off-Grid PV Systems,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy 42(5):3466-3478, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Rugh, J., Chaney, L., Lustbader, J., and Meyer, J., “Reduction in Vehicle Temperatures and Fuel Use from Cabin Ventilation, Solar-Reflective Paint, and New Solar-Reflective Glazing,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1194, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c32">United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), “Final Rulemaking for 2017-2025 Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards,” https://nepis.epa.gov/Exe/ZyPDF. cgi/P100F1E5.PDF?Dockey=P100F1E5.PDF.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c33">European Commission, “Technical Guidelines for the Preparation of Applications for the Approval of Innovative Technologies Pursuant to Regulation (EC) No. 443/2009 and Regulation (EU) No. 510/2011,” https://circabc.europa.eu/sd/a/bbf05038-a907-4298-83ee- 3d6cce3b4231/technical.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Margolis, R., Feldman, D., and Boff, D., “Q4 2016/Q1 2017 Solar Industry Update,” NREL/PR-6A20-68425, National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL), Golden, CO, Apr. 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>(a) Basic components of a PV module; (b) equivalent circuit of PV module.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Best research solar cell efficiencies. (This plot is courtesy of the National Renewable Energy Laboratory, Golden, CO [21].)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>List of OEMs’ announcements on electric car ambitions, as of April 2017 (Source: © OECD/IEA 2017, Global EV Outlook, IEA Publishing. License: www.iea.org/t&amp;c [24]).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Traction HV battery charging.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Extended daily driving range by on-board PV panel.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Charge 12 V battery and power low voltage (LV) loads.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Charging 12 V battery by PV panel.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Active cabin ventilation using solar panel.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Reduction in temperature for solar-powered ventilation system using 17 W solar panel (Data from [31]).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Solar-powered battery thermal management system.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Sensor locations for cabin temperature measurements taken in Arizona during August.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Arizona sedan temperature data vs. location in-vehicle.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Lumped capacitance HV battery model.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Thermal response of battery pack.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Thermal response of battery pack in trunk.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Solar-powered battery thermal management system impact on battery temperature.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>gCO₂/mile credit for solar panel in the United States for different application.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Estimation of solar correction coefficient (SCC) [33].</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Return on investment (ROI). (a) Active cabin ventilation, (b) traction HV battery charging, (c) both HV battery charging and active cabin ventilation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Comparison of the credit available in the United States versus Europe using 100 W solar panel.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
