<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169229</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Comparison of 25 High Speed Tire Disablements Involving Full and Partial Tread Separations</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Beauchamp</surname>
                  <given-names>Gray</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Koch</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Thornton</surname>
                  <given-names>Dana E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Kineticorp LLC</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>August 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169217</issue-id>
         <fpage>364</fpage>
         <lpage>385</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169229"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Tire tread separation events, a category of tire disablements, can be sub-categorized into two main types of separations. These include full tread separations, in which the tread around the entire circumference of the tire separates from the tire carcass, and partial tread separations, in which a portion of the tread separates and the flap remains attached to the tire for an extended period of time. In either case, the tire can remain inflated or lose air. Relatively, there have been few partial tire tread separation tests presented in the literature compared to full tread separation tests. In this study, the results of 25 full and partial tire tread separation tests, conducted with a variety of vehicles at highway speeds, are reported. Cases in which the tire remains inflated and loses air pressure are both considered. The testing was performed on a straight section of road and primarily focused on rear tire disablements. The driver steering inputs required to keep the vehicle within its travel lane and the vehicle's dynamic response during the events were documented with video and data acquisition equipment. The results from the testing are presented and compared. It was found that the steering inputs required to keep the vehicle within its lane during a partial tread separation were similar in magnitude to those in the full separation testing. These results were also similar to the results of full separation testing documented by other researchers. In all cases, the vehicle was controlled within its lane with minor corrective steering. Figure 1 depicts video documentation and vehicle speed during one of the test runs.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gardner, James D., and Shapley Christopher G.. The Role of Blowouts in Accident Causation. Publication no. 87-WA/SAF-4. New York City: American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1987. Print.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gardner, Jim. The Role of Tread/Belt Detachment in Accident Causation. Rep. no. 27A. ITEC, 1998. Print.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dickerson, C., Arndt, M., and Arndt, S., “Vehicle Handling with Tire Tread Separation,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0120, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fay, R., Robinette, R., Smith, J., Flood, T. et al., “Drag and Steering Effects from Tire Tread Belt Separation and Loss,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0447, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0447.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klein, E. and Black, T., “Anatomy of Accidents Following Tire Disablements,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0446, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arndt, Mark W., and Arndt Stephen M.. The Influence of a Rear Tire Tread Separation on a Vehicle's Stability and Control. Rep. no. 258. Amsterdam: Enhanced Safety of Vehicles Conference, 2001. Print.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arndt, M. W., Rosenfield M., Arndt S. M., and Stevens D. C.. Analysis of Causes of an Unintended Rollover During a Tread Separation Event Test. Rep. Athens: ICrash, 2006. Print.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tandy, D., Tandy, K., Durisek, N., Granat, K. et al., “An Analysis of Yaw Inducing Drag Forces Imparted During Tire Tread Belt Detachments,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0836, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Durisek, N., Tandy, D., Granat, K., Tandy, K. et al., “Comparative Dynamic Analysis of Tire Tread Belt Detachments and Stepped Diameter (“Lumpy”) Tires,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0846, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0846.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tandy, D., Granat, K., Durisek, N., Tandy, K. et al., “Vehicle Response Comparison to Tire Tread Separations Induced by Circumferentially Cut and Distressed Tires,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0733, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0733.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Renfroe, David, and Roberts Alex. An Analysis of the Mechanism Causing Loss of Control During A Tire Delamination. Rep. no. 09-0209. Stuttgart: Enhanced Safety of Vehicles Conference, 2009. Print.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tandy, D., Pascarella, R., Ault, B., Coleman, C. et al., “Steering and Handling Performance During a Full Tire Tread Belt Separation,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 4(1):791-806, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
