<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277902</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Use of a Partial Flow Filter to Assist the Diesel Particulate Filter and Reduce Active Regeneration Events</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lefort</surname>
                  <given-names>Isaline</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Herreros</surname>
                  <given-names>Jose</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tsolakis</surname>
                  <given-names>Athanasios</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Birmingham</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>October 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277873</issue-id>
         <fpage>1953</fpage>
         <lpage>1960</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277902"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study investigates the potential of using a partial flow filter (PFF) to assist a wall flow diesel particulate filter (DPF) and reduce the need for active regeneration phases that increase engine fuel consumption. First, the filtration efficiency of the PFF was studied at several engine operating conditions, varying the filter space velocity (SV), through modification of the exhaust gas flow rate, and engine-out particulate matter (PM) concentration. The effects of these parameters were studied for the filtration of different particle size ranges (10-30 nm, 30-200 nm and 200-400 nm). For the various engine operating conditions, the PFF showed filtration efficiency over 25% in terms of PM number and mass. The PFF filtration behaviour was also investigated at idle engine operation producing a high concentration of nuclei particulates for which the filter was able to maintain 60% filtration efficiency. After a 14 hour soot loading phase, the filter trapping efficiency remained over 20% and showed unexpectedly high small PM filtration efficiency. Finally, a system composed of a PFF placed upstream of a DPF was studied and the filtration efficiency, soot mass accumulated, as well as the pressure increase during a loading period of 7 hours were compared to the ones from a standalone DPF, in order to estimate the beneficial effects of using a PFF to assist the main DPF and reduce the regeneration duration and/or frequency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, N., Rutland, C., Foster, D., Narayanaswamy, K. et al., “Investigation into Different DPF Regeneration Strategies Based on Fuel Economy Using Integrated System Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1275, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, J. and Mital, R., “Effect of DPF Design Parameters on Fuel Economy and Thermal Durability,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01- 0847, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0847.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kinnunen, T., Matilainen, P., Scheder, D., Czika, W. et al., “Particle Oxidation Catalyst (POC®) - From Diesel To GDI - Studies on Particulate Number and Mass Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0845, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0845.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vaaraslahti, K., Ristimäki, J., Virtanen, A., Keskinen, J. et al., “Effect of Oxidation Catalysts on Diesel Soot Particles,” Environ. Sci. Technol. 40(15):4776-4781, 2006, doi:10.1021/es060615h.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayer, A., Czerwinski, J., Comte, P., and Jaussi, F., “Properties of Partial-Flow and Coarse Pore Deep Bed Filters Proposed to Reduce Particle Emission of Vehicle Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):497-511, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1087.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vakkilainen, A. and Lylykangas, R., “Particle Oxidation Catalyst (POC) for Diesel Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-28-0047, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-28-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Y., Ba, G., Kim, W., and Reck, A., “Continuously Regenerating Particulate Matter (PM Metalit®) in LDV &amp; HDV Retrofit Application Experiences from the Korean Retrofit Programme,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1547, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01- 1547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kramer, J., Pfahl, U., Bruestle, C., Diewald, R. et al., “The PM-Metalit: A PM control technology for Tier 4 Off-Highway Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2838, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2838.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Happonen, M., Matilainen, P., Kanniainen, K., Kinnunen, T. et al., “The Effect of a Particle Oxidation Catalyst (POC®) on Particle Emissions of a GDI Car during Transient Engine Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0839, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brück, R., Müller-Haas, K., Holz, O., Hirth, P. et al., “Application of PM-METALIT® and SCRi® Systems,” presented at the Fifth AVL International Commercial Powertrain Conference Proceedings, Austria, April 28-29, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brück, R., Hirth, P., and Rice, M., “NOX Aftertreatment for Passenger Cars and Heavy Duty Truck Applications for EU 6 and EUVI/US2010 Legislation,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0904, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0904.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pace, L., Konieczny, R., and Presti, M., “Metal Supported Particulate Matter-Cat, A Low Impact and Cost Effective Solution for a 1.3 Euro IV Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01- 0471, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0471.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rounce, P., Tsolakis, A., and York, A. P. E., “Speciation of particulate matter and hydrocarbon emissions from biodiesel combustion and its reduction by aftertreatment,” Fuel 96:90-99, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2011.12.071.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brück, R., Hirth, P., Reizig, M., Treiber, P. et al., “Metal Supported Flow-Through Particulate Trap; a Non-Blocking Solution,” SAE 2001-01-1950, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babu, K., Dias, C., Waje, S., Reck, A. et al., “PM Metalit® - A Continuously Regenerating Partial Flow Particulate Filter - Concept and Experience with Korean Retrofit Programme,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-28-0008, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-28-0008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, T., Chatterjee, S., Conway, R., Walker, A. et al., “Development of Partial Filter Technology for HDD Retrofit,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0213, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
