<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275419</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Instantaneous Engine Speed Measurement and Processing for MFB50 Evaluation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ponti</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabrizio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DIEM - University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ravaglioli</surname>
                  <given-names>Vittorio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DIEM - University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Serra</surname>
                  <given-names>Gabriele</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magneti Marelli Powertrain</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Stola</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magneti Marelli Powertrain</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>235</fpage>
         <lpage>244</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275419"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Evaluation of MFB50 is very useful for combustion control, since it gives an evaluation of the combustion process effectiveness. Real-time monitoring its value enables to detect for example the kind of combustion that is taking place (useful for example for HCCI applications), or could provide important information to improve real-time combustion control. While it is possible to determine the position where the 50% of mass burned inside the cylinder is reached using an incylinder pressure sensor, this work proposes to obtain this information from the engine speed fluctuation measurement. In-cylinder pressure sensors in fact are still not so common for on-board applications, since their cost will constitute an important portion of the whole engine control system cost. Engine speed measurement is instead already performed in modern engine control systems and therefore being capable of obtaining MFB50 related information from this signal means obtaining it at approximately no additional costs.</p>
            <p>The MFB50 estimation procedure presented in this paper is based on the measurement of the engine speed fluctuations and it mainly consists in two separated steps. As a first step, a torsional behavior model of the powertrain configuration is developed. The engine-driveline torsional model enables to estimate the indicated torque frequency components, from the corresponding components of the instantaneous engine speed fluctuation. This estimation can be performed cycle by cycle and cylinder by cylinder. As a second step, the analysis of the relationship between MFB50 and the phase of the frequency components over an engine cycle allowed defining the final estimation algorithm that reconstructs the MFB50 starting from the instantaneous engine speed fluctuation analysis. The developed approach has been applied with success to a diesel engine mounted on-board a vehicle.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iida, K., Akishino, K., Kido, K., IMEP Estimation from Instantaneous Crankshaft Torque Variation, SAE Technical Paper 900617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. J. Moskwa, W. Wang, D. J. Bucheger, A New Methodology for Engine Diagnostics and Control Utilizing "Synthetic" Engine Variables: Theoretical and Experimental Results, DSC-Vol. 64, Proceedings of the ASME, Dynamic Systems and Control Division, ASME 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jianqiu Li, Yang Minggao, Zhou Ming, Li Xihao, Advanced Torque Estimation and Control Algorithm of Diesel Engines, SAE Paper 2002-01-0198</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jaine, T., Chamaillard, Y., Charlet, A., Higelin, P., High-Frequency Imep Estimation and Filtering for Torque- Based SI Engine Control, SAE Paper 2002- 01-1276</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drakunov, S., Rizzoni, G., Yue-Yun Wang, On-Line Estimation of Indicated Torque in Ic Engines Using Nonlinear Observers, SAE Paper 950840</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maloney, P. J., Embedded Torque Estimator for Diesel Engine Control Application, SAE Paper 2004- 01-1371</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fam, M., Hendriks, E., A Load Torque Estimator, SAE Paper 2004-01-1372</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Walter, U. Kiencke, S. Jones, T. Winkler, Misfire Detection for Vehicles with Dual Mass Flywheel (DMF) Based on Reconstructed Engine Torque, SAE Paper 2007-01-3544, Asia Pacific Automotive Engineering Conference, Hollywood (CA), August 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walter, A., Lingenfelser, C., Kiencke, U., Jones, S. et al., “Cylinder Balancing Based on Reconstructed Engine Torque for Vehicles Fitted with a Dual Mass Flywheel (DMF),” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars – Mech Syst. 1(1):810-819, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ponti, F., Development of a Torsional Behavior Powertrain Model for Multiple Misfire Detection, Paper ICES2005-1035, ASME ICE 2005 Spring Technical Conference, Chicago, April 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ponti, F., Indicated Torque Estimation Using a Torsional Behavior Model of the Engine, SAE Powertrain &amp; Fuel Systems Conference &amp; Exhibition, Paper 2005-01-3761, San Antonio, Texas October 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, 1989, McGraw Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ligier, J. L., Baron, E., Acyclisme et Vibrations, 2002, Technip.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
