<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830189</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830194</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>PROBLEMS OF IMPLEMENTING REFORM OF PUBLIC EXPENDITURE MANAGEMENT IN NIGERIA / PROBLÈMES CONCERNANT LA RÉALISATION DES RÉFORMES DES DÉPENSES PUBLIQUES AU NIGERIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>O.A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Adeyemo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>267</fpage>
         <lpage>286</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830194"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper addresses three main issues in the public sector of the Nigerian economy, namely, problems in the management of public expenditure, constraints in the implementation of policy reforms to overcome the Management problems and prospects of successful implementation of policy reforms. It observes that while the management problems cannot be divorced from the largeness of the sector, size per se is not a sufficient condition for the existence of inefficiencies in this vital sector of the economy. The paper also finds that implementation problems had their roots in policy, structural and institutional inadequacies in both the public sector and the entire economy, particularly, before the implementation of the Structural Adjustment Programme (SAP). On the issue of efficiency of the sector, it avers that this is best tackled by means of a consistent package of reform measures with which the nation must persevere as the on-going Structural Adjustment Programme holds tremendous prospects for efficient economic management in the not-too-distant future. Cet article analyse les trois principaux aspects du secteur publique dans l'économie du Nigeria c'est à dire les difficultés de gérer les dépenses publiques, les contraintes concernant la réalisation des réformes nécessaires pour résoudre les problèmes de gestion et enfin les perspectives pour la meilleure réalisation des réformes souhaitées. On a pu constater que les problèmes de gestion doivent être analysés en tenant compte de l'ampleur du secteur publique même si sa dimension n'est pas le seul facteur responsable des aspects négatifs de ce secteur vital de l'économie nationale. L'article a pu aussi démontrer que les problèmes de gestion sont liés à la faible efficacité des politiques, des structures et des institutions dans le secteur publique et au niveau national, spécialement avant la mise en oeuvre du programme d'ajustement structurel (S.A.P.). En ce qui concerne le degré d'efficacité du secteur, on peut conclure que la meilleure solution consiste à réaliser un ensemble cohérent de mesures que le pays doit poursuivre avec constance. Par example le programme d'ajustement structurel permettra dans un futur pas trop lointain d'améliorer considérablement la gestion économique du secteur publique.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e144a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e151" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria, Economic and Financial Review (Various issues).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e158a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e165" publication-type="other">
Lewis, S.R. (Jr.), Taxation for Development, (New York: Oxford University Press, 1984).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e172a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e179" publication-type="other">
National Centre for Economic Management and Administration, (NCEMA), Report of National Workshops on
Public Expenditure Programming in Nigeria, (August, 1987).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e189a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e196" publication-type="other">
—, Reports on Training Programme on Macroeconomics for Public Sector Managers, October - November,
1987 and April-May, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e207a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e214" publication-type="other">
Sahni, B.S., «Public Sectors in Less Developed Countries: Development Goals and Efficiency*, Annals of
Public and Cooperative Economy, (September, 1983), Vol. 3, pp. 325-335.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


