<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">35</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24440341</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24440347</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>The IFS Annual Lecture</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Determinants of the Volatility of Fiscal Policy Discretion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Luca</given-names>
                  <surname>Agnello</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ricardo M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Sousa</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>91</fpage>
         <lpage>115</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440347"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper investigates the determinants of the volatility of fiscal policy discretion. Using a linear dynamic panel data model for 113 countries from 1980 to 2006 and a system-GMM estimator, we find that an increase in the number of episodes of government crisis, less democracy and presidentialist systems raise the volatility of the discretionary component of fiscal policy. Additionally, we show that countries with larger populations and less flexible exchange rate systems are more insured against uncertainty about the conduct of fiscal policy. Our results are robust to various regional dummy variables, different subsets of countries and the presence of high inflation and crisis episodes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d687011e199a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e206" publication-type="other">
Submitted July 2011.
The authors would like to thank the following for helpful comments: the Editor, two anonymous
referees and participants at the 2009 Annual Meeting of the European Economic Association and the
Econometric Society, the Economic Policies Research Unit (NIPE) seminar organised by the University
of Minho, the First International Symposium in Computational Economics and Finance (ISCEF 2010),
the 2010 Annual Meeting of the European Public Choice Society, the workshop on 'International Political
Economy and Cross-Border Effects' organised by Queen Mary University of London and the UECE
Conference on Economic and Financial Adjustments in Europe.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e235a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e242" publication-type="other">
Agnello and Neriich, 2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e249a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e256" publication-type="other">
Hughes Hallett, 2008; Hughes Hallett and Lewis, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e263a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e270" publication-type="other">
For instance, the literature has recently taken interest again in the relationship between
macroeconomic variables, wealth and asset returns (Sousa, 2010) and, in particular, government bond
yields (Sousa, 2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e284a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e291" publication-type="other">
Fatâs and Mihov, 2003.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e298a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e305" publication-type="other">
Lane, 2003; Gall and Perotti, 2003; Akitoby et al., 2004; Talvi and Vegh, 2005; Darby and Melitz,
2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e315a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e322" publication-type="other">
Afonso, Agnello and Furceri, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e329a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e336" publication-type="other">
Agnello, Furceri and Sousa, 2013a and 2013b.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e343a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e350" publication-type="other">
North, 1990; Keefer and Knack, 1995; Persson and Tabellini, 1996; Wagner, 1997; Persson, 2002;
Aisen and Veiga, 2013.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e360a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e367" publication-type="other">
Taylor (2000) and Blanchard and Perotti (2002) also compute fiscal policy discretion from the
estimated residuals of a fiscal policy rule.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e378a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e385" publication-type="other">
The nominal series of the general government budget deficit, government revenue and government
spending are converted to real terms by using the GDP deflator provided by the International Financial
Statistics (IFS) of the International Monetary Fund (IMF).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e398a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e405" publication-type="other">
As in Fatâs and Mihov (2003 and 2007), we instrument the output gap using its own lags (1 and 2),
lagged inflation and the index of real oil prices. As before, the series of the index of nominal oil prices is
converted to real terms by using the GDP deflator provided by the IFS of the IMF.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e418a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e425" publication-type="other">
In accordance with Ravn and Uhlig (2002), a Hodrick-Prescott filter with A = 6.25 is employed to
extract the cyclical component from the annual GDP data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e435a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e442" publication-type="other">
As Fatâs and Mihov (2003 and 2007) point out, the inclusion of inflation guarantees that the
occurrence of high inflation episodes (for instance, due to monetary instability) does not influence the
relationship between fiscal policy and output. Similarly, the inclusion of inflation squared controls for
potential non-linearities in the relationship between fiscal policy and inflation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e458a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e465" publication-type="other">
The periods are 1980-82, 1983-85,..., 2001-03 and 2004-06. We start by considering 180 countries
for which we have collected annual fiscal data (budget balance, government revenue and government
spending) over the period 1980-2006. For a number of countries, data are only available since 1980 and,
in a few cases, since 1990. As a result, for those countries where the number of instruments is larger than
the number of observations, the estimation of the first-stage regression (i.e. the fiscal rule) cannot be
performed. This ultimately reduces the number of observations in the second-stage estimation (i.e. the
linear dynamic panel data model). In addition, the number of observations over the three-year non-
overlapping windows is further reduced when at least a single missing observation falls into the window
of reference.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e497a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e504" publication-type="other">
We use an approach that is similar to the one found in works by Aisen and Veiga (2006, 2008 and
2013). Interestingly, however, they use it in different contexts. In fact, while Aisen and Veiga (2006)
assess whether political instability leads to higher inflation, Aisen and Veiga (2008) analyse the effects of
the quality of institutions, political instability and social polarisation on inflation volatility. Moreover, we
focus on the behaviour of the discretionary component of the dependent variable (in our case, the fiscal
stance) rather than the dependent variable per se. This is particularly relevant for developing countries,
because there is evidence of substantial volatility in their trend growth rates (see Aguiar and Gopinath
(2007)), which might, in tum, be transmitted to fiscal variables, especially government revenue.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e534a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e541" publication-type="other">
Nickell, 1981.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e548a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e557" publication-type="other">
The use of generalised method of moments (GMM) estimators is recommended in linear dynamic
panel data models where the number of cross-sectional units (AO is large and the number of time-series
observations (7) is relatively small (Arellano and Bond, 1991; Arellano and Bover, 1995; Blundell and
Bond, 1998), as in the current paper (N = 113 and T = 9). Consequently, if we had considered the standard
deviations of the discretionary component of fiscal policy for consecutive, non-overlapping, two-year
periods, the definition would have been rather imprecise and more vulnerable to the influence of outliers.
Moreover, the number of time-series units would have been relatively large (13), thereby reducing the
validity of the employed econometric model. In contrast, if we had computed the standard deviations of
the discretionary component of fiscal policy for consecutive, non-overlapping, four-year periods, the time
series dimension would have been small (six) and the measure would 'smooth out' sharp changes in fiscal
discretion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e595a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e602" publication-type="other">
Blundell and Bond, 1998.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e609a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e616" publication-type="other">
Arellano and Bover, 1995.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e623a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e630" publication-type="other">
Blundell and Bond, 1998.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e637a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e644" publication-type="other">
The list of instruments that we use in the regressions includes institutional and political variables
(such as the polity scale, cabinet changes, government crises, the political system and political
constraints), demographic variables (i.e. population) and macroeconomic variables (namely, trade
openness, financial openness and the exchange rate regime).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e661a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e668" publication-type="other">
The countries included in the study are listed in Table Al of the online appendix (available at
http://www.ifs.org.uk/docs/fsmarl4 agnello&amp;sousa appendix.pdf).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e678a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e685" publication-type="other">
We also remark that the number of observations in the second-stage estimation is further reduced
when at least a single missing observation falls into the three-year non-overlapping window of reference.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e695a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e702" publication-type="other">
A wide range of variables are available in the above-mentioned data sources. In accordance, we
checked the statistical significance of the inclusion of many of those economic, institutional and political
factors, but the results did not corroborate their inclusion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e715a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e722" publication-type="other">
Thiessen (2003) nicely shows that the empirical relationship between fiscal decentralisation and
capital formation, economic growth and total factor productivity growth is non-linear, being positive
when decentralisation is increasing from low levels, after which it reaches a peak and the linkages
become negative. Therefore, fiscal policy volatility may be detrimental for human capital.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e738a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e745" publication-type="other">
For a discussion of governments' failures as sources of instability, see King ( 1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e752a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e759" publication-type="other">
When the classification of exchange rate regimes constructed by Ilzetzki, Reinhart and Rogoff (2008)
runs in value from 1 (a hard peg, no separate legal tender) to 13 (freely floating), it can measure the
degree of flexibility in the exchange rate regime. The classification code 14 (freely falling) seems to be
less flexible than 13, while the classification code 15 (dual market in which parallel market data are
missing) can be observed in relatively fixed regimes. As a result, codes 14 and 15 do not imply
necessarily highly flexible regimes. Consequently, we recode the original exchange rate indicator and set
freely falling as 13, freely floating as 14, and omit 15.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e786a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e793" publication-type="other">
Taylor (2000), Lane (2003) and Chadha and Nolan (2007) also estimate fiscal policy rules that do not
include such a polynomial of inflation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e803a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e810" publication-type="other">
The inclusion of the lagged dependent variable can also be justified by the fact that changes in
government revenue tend to lead to changes in expenditure. Nevertheless, spending increases are easier to
accommodate than spending reductions. As a result, in the context of revenue volatility, there is a bias in
favour of deficits, which, in turn, generates persistence in budget balance volatility.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e826a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e835" publication-type="other">
This result is in contrast to the findings of Fatâs and Mihov (2003), who show that political
constraints have a statistically significant and negative impact on the volatility of the budget balance.
However, we note that their model only controls for three political and institutional variables (the political
system, political constraints and the frequency of elections) and that the authors do not account for the
persistence of fiscal policy discretion, which we do, by including the lagged dependent variable among
the set of regressors. As a result, the lack of significance of political constraints in our model may reflect
(i) the fact that we account for the effects of a wider set of control variables, thereby being less prone to
omitted variable bias and (ii) the potential correlation between political constraints and the lag of the
volatility of fiscal policy, whereby political constraints may largely reflect the inertia in the budgetary
process. As a result, including both the lag of the volatility of fiscal policy discretion and the political
constraints among the set of explanatory variables - as is done in our paper - is a way of disentangling
the effects of the inertia in the budgetary process and the effects of the constraints that governments face
in the course of policy implementation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d687011e880a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d687011e887" publication-type="other">
interestingly, Cerra and Saxena (2008) assess the impact of banking and currency crises on the
behaviour of output. They construct an exchange market pressure index (EMPI) to identify currency
crises, and obtain banking crisis data from the works of Kaminsky and Reinhart ( 1999) and Caprio and
Klingebiel (2003). In our case, we follow Reinhart and Rogoff (2009) and, as a result, our crisis episodes
data set is more up-to-date and also covers a wider typology of crises. Consequently, the sample size is
reduced by around 8 per cent in case a, by 6 per cent in cases b and c, and by 1 per cent in case d.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d687011e919a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e923" publication-type="other">
Afonso, A., Agnello, L. and Furceri, D. (2010), 'Fiscal policy responsiveness, persistence and
discretion', Public Choice, vol. 145, pp. 503-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e933a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e937" publication-type="other">
Agnello, L., Furceri, D. and Sousa, R. M. (2013a), 'Discretionary government consumption,
private domestic demand, and crisis episodes', Open Economies Review, vol. 24, pp. 79-
100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e950a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e954" publication-type="other">
—, — and — (2013b), 'How best to measure discretionary fiscal policy? Assessing its impact
on private spending', Economic Modelling, vol. 34, pp. 15-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e964a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e968" publication-type="other">
— and Neriich, C. (2012), 'On the severity of economic downturns: lessons from cross-
country evidence', Economics Letters, vol. 117, pp. 149-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e979a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e983" publication-type="other">
Aguiar, M. and Gopinath, G. (2007), 'Emerging market business cycles: the cycle is the
trend', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 115, pp. 69-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e993a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e997" publication-type="other">
Aisen, A. and Veiga, F. J. (2006), 'Does political instability lead to higher inflation? A panel
data analysis', Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, vol. 38, pp. 1379-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1007a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1011" publication-type="other">
— and — (2008), 'Political instability and inflation volatility', Public Choice, vol. 135, pp.
207-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1025" publication-type="other">
— and — (2013), 'How does political instability affect economic growth?', European
Journal of Political Economy, vol. 29, pp. 151-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1039" publication-type="other">
Akitoby, B., Clements, B., Gupta, S. and Inchauste, G. (2004), 'The cyclical and long-term
behavior of government expenditures in developing countries', International Monetary
Fund (IMF), Working Paper no. 202.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1052a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1056" publication-type="other">
Alesina, A., Campante, F. and Tabellini, G. (2008), 'Why is fiscal policy often procyclical?',
Journal of the European Economic Association, vol. 6, pp. 1006-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1067a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1071" publication-type="other">
— and Perotti, R. (1995), 'The political economy of budget deficits', IMF Staff Papers, vol.
42, pp. 1-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1081a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1085" publication-type="other">
Arellano, M. and Bond, S. (1991), 'Some tests of specification for panel data: Monte Carlo
evidence and an application to employment equations', Review of Economic Studies, vol.
58, pp. 277-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1098a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1102" publication-type="other">
— and Bover, O. (1995), 'Another look at the instrumental variable estimation of error-
component models', Journal of Econometrics, vol. 68, pp. 29-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1112a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1116" publication-type="other">
Azzimonti, M., de Francisco, E. and Quadrini, V. (2012), 'Financial globalization, inequality,
and the raising of public debt', Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia, Research
Department, Working Paper no. 6.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1129a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1133" publication-type="other">
Blanchard, O. and Perotti, R. (2002), 'An empirical characterization of the dynamic effects of
changes in government spending and taxes on output', Quarterly Journal of Economics,
vol. 117, pp. 1329-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1146a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1150" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. and Bond, S. (1998), 'Initial conditions and moment restrictions in dynamic
panel data models', Journal of Econometrics, vol. 87, pp. 115-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1165" publication-type="other">
Caprio, G. and Klingebiel, D. (2003), 'Episodes of systemic and borderline financial crises',
http://go.worldbank.org/5DYGICS7B0.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1175a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1179" publication-type="other">
Carmignani, F., Colombo, E. and Tirelli, P. (2011), 'Macroeconomic risk and the
(de)stabilizing role of government size', European Journal of Political Economy, vol. 27,
pp. 781-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1192a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1196" publication-type="other">
Cerra, V. and Saxena, S. C. (2008), 'Growth dynamics: the myth of economic recovery',
American Economic Review, vol. 98, pp. 439-57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1206a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1210" publication-type="other">
Chadha, J. S. and Nolan, C. (2007), 'Optimal simple rules for the conduct of monetary and
fiscal policy', Journal of Macroeconomics, vol. 29, pp. 665-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1220a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1224" publication-type="other">
Darby, J. and Melitz, J. (2007), 'Labour market adjustment, social spending and the automatic
stabilizers in the OECD', Centre for Economic Policy Research (CEPR), Discussion
Paper no. 6230.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1237a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1241" publication-type="other">
Fatâs, A. and Mihov, I. (2003), 'The case for restricting fiscal policy discretion', Quarterly
Journal of Economics, vol. 118, pp. 1419—47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1252a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1256" publication-type="other">
— and — (2006), 'The macroeconomic effects of fiscal rules in the US states', Journal of
Public Economics, vol. 90, pp. 101-17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1266a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1270" publication-type="other">
— and — (2007), 'Fiscal policy, volatility and growth', in T. Irwin, G. Perry, L. Servén and
R. Suescün (eds), Prudence or Abstinence: Fiscal Policy, Stabilization and Growth,
Washington DC: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1283a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1287" publication-type="other">
Gall, J. and Perotti, R. (2003), 'Fiscal policy and monetary integration in Europe', Fiscal
Policy, vol. 18, pp. 533-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1297a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1301" publication-type="other">
Gavin, M. and Perotti, R. (1997), 'Fiscal policy in Latin America', in B. Bernanke and J.
Rotemberg (eds), NBER Macroeconomics Annual, Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1315" publication-type="other">
Hallerberg, M. and Strauch, R. (2002), 'On the cyclicality of fiscal policy in Europe',
Empirica, vol. 29, pp. 183-207.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1329" publication-type="other">
Henisz, W. J. (2004), 'Political institutions and volatility', Economics and Politics, vol. 16,
pp. 1-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1340a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1344" publication-type="other">
Holtz-Eakin, D., Newey, W. and Rosen, H. S. (1988), 'Estimating vector autoregressions with
panel data', Econometrica, vol. 56, pp. 1371-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1354a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1358" publication-type="other">
Hughes Hallett, A. H. (2008), 'Sustainable fiscal policies and budgetary risk under alternative
monetary policy arrangements', Economic Change and Restructuring, vol. 41, pp. 1-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1372" publication-type="other">
— and Lewis, J. (2008), 'European fiscal discipline before and after EMU: crash diet or
permanent weight loss?', Macroeconomic Dynamics, vol. 12, pp. 404-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1386" publication-type="other">
Ilzetzki, E., Reinhart, C. and Rogoff, K. (2008), 'The country chronologies and background
material to exchange rate arrangements in the 21st century: which anchor will hold?',
University of Maryland, manuscript.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1403" publication-type="other">
Ito, H. and Chinn, M. (2012), 'Notes on the Chinn-Ito Financial Openness Index 2010
update', Portland State University, manuscript.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1417" publication-type="other">
Kaminsky, G. L. and Reinhart, C. M. (1999), 'The twin crises: the causes of banking and
balance-of-payments problems', American Economic Review, vol. 89, pp. 473-500.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1428a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1432" publication-type="other">
Keefer, P. and Knack, S. (1995), 'Institutions and economic performance: cross-country tests
using alternative institutional measures', Economics and Politics, vol. 7, pp. 207-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1442a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1446" publication-type="other">
King, M. (1994), 'Monetary policy in the UK', Fiscal Studies, vol. 15, no. 3, pp. 109-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1457" publication-type="other">
Lane, P. (2003), 'The cyclical behaviour of fiscal policy: evidence from the OECD', Journal
of Public Economics, vol. 87, pp. 2661-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1471" publication-type="other">
Leachman, L. L., Rosas, G., Lange, P. and Bester, A. (2007), 'The political economy of
budget deficits', Economics and Politics, vol. 19, pp. 369-420.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1481a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1485" publication-type="other">
Nickeil, S. (1981), 'Biases in dynamic models with fixed effects', Econometrica, vol. 49, pp.
1417-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1495a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1499" publication-type="other">
North, D. (1990), Institutions, Institutional Change, and Economic Performance, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1510a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1514" publication-type="other">
Persson, T. (2002), 'Do political institutions shape economic policy?', Econometrica, vol. 70,
pp. 883-905.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1524a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1528" publication-type="other">
—, Roland, G. and Tabellini, G. (1997), 'Separation of powers and political accountability',
Quarterly Journal of Economics, \ ol. 112, pp. 1163-202.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1542" publication-type="other">
— and Tabellini, G. (1996), 'Federal fiscal constitutions. Part I: risk sharing and moral
hazard', Econometrica, vol. 64, pp. 623—46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1552a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1556" publication-type="other">
— and — (1999), 'Political economy and macroeconomic policy', in J. Taylor and M.
Woodford (eds), Handbook of Macroeconomics, Amsterdam: North Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1566a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1570" publication-type="other">
— and — (2001), 'Political institutions and policy outcomes: what are the stylized facts?',
Centre for Economic Policy Research (CEPR), Working Paper no. 2872.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1580a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1584" publication-type="other">
Rand, J. and Tarp, F. (2002), 'Business cycles in developing countries: are they different?',
World Development, vol. 30, pp. 2071-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1595a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1599" publication-type="other">
Ravn, M. O. and Uhlig, H. (2002), 'On adjusting the Hodrick-Prescott filter for the frequency
of observations', Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 86, pp. 371-6.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1609a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1613" publication-type="other">
Reinhart, C. M. and Rogoff, K. S. (2009), This Time Is Different: Eight Centuries of
Financial Folly, Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1623a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1627" publication-type="other">
Rodrik, D. (1998), 'Why do more open economies have bigger governments?', Journal of
Political Economy, vol. 106, pp. 997-1032.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1637a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1641" publication-type="other">
Sorensen, B., Wu, L. and Yosha, O. (2001), 'Output fluctuations and fiscal policy: US state
and local governments 1978-1994', European Economic Review, vol. 45, pp. 1271-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1655" publication-type="other">
Sousa, R. M. (2010), 'Consumption, (dis)aggregate wealth, and asset returns', Journal of
Empirical Finance, vol. 17, pp. 606-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1665a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1669" publication-type="other">
— (2012), 'Linking wealth and labour income with stock returns and government bond
yields', European Journal of Finance, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1680a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1684" publication-type="other">
Talvi, E. and Vegh, C. (2005), 'Tax base variability and procyclical fiscal policy', Journal of
Economic Development, vol. 78, pp. 156-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1694a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1698" publication-type="other">
Tavares, J. and Wacziarg, R. (2001), 'How democracy affects growth', European Economic
Review, vol. 45, pp. 1341-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1708a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1712" publication-type="other">
Taylor, J. B. (2000), 'Reassessing discretionary fiscal policy', Journal of Economic
Perspectives, vol. 14, no. 3, pp. 21-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1722a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1726" publication-type="other">
Thiessen, U. (2003), 'Fiscal decentralisation and economic growth in high-income OECD
countries', Fiscal Studies, vol. 24, pp. 237-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1736a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1740" publication-type="other">
Wagner, R. (1997), 'Choice exchange and public finance', American Economic Review:
Papers and Proceedings, vol. 87, pp. 160-3.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d687011e1750a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d687011e1754" publication-type="other">
Woo, J. (2003), 'Economic, political, and institutional determinants of public deficits',
Journal of Public Economics, vol. 87, pp. 387—426.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


