<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816544</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Profit Shifting (International)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>On the interdependency of profit-shifting channels and the effectiveness of anti-avoidance legislation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dudar</surname>
                  <given-names>Olena</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nicolay</surname>
                  <given-names>Katharina</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nusser</surname>
                  <given-names>Hannah</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>17</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816544"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The issue of base erosion and profit-shifting (BEPS) has been on the international policy agenda for three years now. A key element in the discussion are strategies of multinationals using intra-group interest and royalty payments as well as transfer pricing to reallocate profits within the group in a tax minimizing manner. In recent years, anti-avoidance regulations have been introduced to limit these cross-border shifting activities. Existing evidence looks at the effectiveness of these regulations separately. The idea of this paper is to analyse the interdependence between different anti-avoidance regulations in place. Our empirical results confirm existing findings on the tax sensitivity of EBIT and the reduction of this sensitivity due to stricter transfer pricing regulations. In addition our results suggest that the positive impact of transfer pricing regulations is strongly mitigated if strict thin capitalization rules apply.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">E.J. Bartelsman and R. Beetsma. Why pay more? corporate tax avoidance through transfer pricing in oecd countries. Journal of Public Economics, 87(9-10):2225–2252, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">S. Beer and J. Loeprick. Profit shifting: Drivers and potential countermeasures. WU International Taxation Research Paper, 2013(3), 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">L. Blouin, H. Huizinga, L. Laeven, and G. Nicodeme. Thin capitalization rules and multinational firm capital structure. IMF Working Paper, 14(12), 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">T. Buettner, M. Overesch, U. Schreiber, and G. Wamser. The impact of thin-capitalization rules on the capital structure of multinational firms. Journal of Public Economics, 96 (11-12):930–938, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">T. Buettner, M. Overesch, and G. Wamser. Anti profit-shifting rules and foreign direct investment. CESifo Working Paper, 4710, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">H. Buslei and M. Simmler. The impact of introducing an interest barrier - evidence from the german corporation tax reform 2008. DIW Discussion Paper, 1215, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">D. Dreßler and U. Scheuering. Empirical evaluation of interest barrier effects. ZEW Discussion Paper, 12(046), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">J. Heckemeyer and M. Overesch. Multinationals’ profit response to tax differentials: Effect size and shifting channels. ZEW Discussion Paper, 13(045), 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">H. Huizinga and L. Laeven. International profit shifting within multinationals: A multicountry perspective. Journal of Public Economics, 92:1164–1182, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">K. J. Klassen and S. K. Laplante. Are u.s. multinational corporations becoming more aggressive income shifters? Journal of Accounting Research, 50(5):1245–1285, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">T. Lohse and N. Riedel. Do transfer pricing laws limit international income shifting? evidence from european multinationals. CESifo Working Paper, 4404, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">M. Overesch and U. Schreiber. Asset specificity, international profit shifting, and investment decisions. Zeitschrift für Betriebswirtschaft, 70(Special issue 2):23–47, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">M. Overesch and G. Wamser. Corporate tax planning and thin-capitalization rules: Evidence from a quasi experiment. Applied Economics, 42:563–573, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">M. J. Saunders-Scott. How does transfer-pricing enforcement affect reported profits? Job Market Paper, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">G. Wamser. The impact of thin capitalization rules on external debt usage: a propensity score matching approach. CESifo Working Paper, 62, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">A. Weichenrieder and H. Windischbauer. Thin capitalization rules and company responses. CESifo Working Paper, 2456, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Illustration of triple interaction in a margins plot</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
