<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272318</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Pilot Injection Ignition Properties Under Low-Temperature, Dilute In-Cylinder Conditions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miles</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sahoo</surname>
                  <given-names>Dipankar</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Busch</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Trost</surname>
                  <given-names>Johannes</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Friedrich-Alexander Universitat</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Leipertz</surname>
                  <given-names>Alfred</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Friedrich-Alexander Universitat</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>1888</fpage>
         <lpage>1907</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International and Copyright © 2013 KSAE</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272318"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Measurements of ignition behavior, homogeneous reactor simulations employing detailed kinetics, and quantitative incylinder imaging of fuel-air distributions are used to delineate the impact of temperature, dilution, pilot injection mass, and injection pressure on the pilot ignition process. For dilute, low-temperature conditions characterized by a lengthy ignition delay, pilot ignition is impeded by the formation of excessively lean mixture. Under these conditions, smaller pilot mass or higher injection pressures further lengthen the pilot ignition delay. Similarly, excessively rich mixtures formed under relatively short ignition delay conditions typical of conventional diesel combustion will also prolong the ignition delay. In this latter case, smaller pilot mass or higher injection pressures will shorten the ignition delay. The minimum charge temperature required to effect a robust pilot ignition event is strongly dependent on charge O₂ concentration. Measured fuel-air ratio distributions, coupled with the homogeneous reactor simulations, show this temperature dependency to be due to both kinetics and over-mixing caused by the long ignition delay associated with dilute mixtures.</p>
            <p>The simulations also show that the impact of dilution on the ignition process is dominated by the added heat capacity of the diluent rather than by changes in the kinetic pathways. For practical dilution levels (14-20% charge O₂ concentration) and moderate near-TDC temperatures (850-900 K), the simulations indicate that the optimal equivalence ratio to promote pilot ignition is between approximately 1.0 and 1.6, with the richer mixtures being appropriate to more dilute conditions. Lastly, pilot injection strategies are applied to a low-load, highly premixed operating condition. Robust pilot ignition events improve HC, CO and the COV of IMEP, but may deteriorate noise and soot emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hotta, Y., Inayoshi, M., Nakakita, K., Fujiwara, K. et al., “Achieving Lower Exhaust Emissions and Better Performance in an HSDI Diesel Engine with Multiple Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0928, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, S., “Simultaneous Reduction of NOx and Particulate Emissions by Using Multiple Injections in a Small Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-3084, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-3084.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y., and Aiyoshizawa, E., “Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low-Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anselmi, P., Kashdan, J., Bression, G., Ferrero-Lesur, E. et al., “Improving Emissions, Noise and Fuel Economy Trade-Off by using Multiple Injection Strategies in Diesel Low Temperature Combustion (LTC) Mode,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2162, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bression, G., Soleri, D., Savy, S., Dehoux, S. et al., “A Study of Methods to Lower HC and CO Emissions in Diesel HCCI,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):37-49, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlucci, P., Ficarella, A., and LaForgia, D., Effects on Combustion and Emissions of Early and Pilot Fuel Injections in Diesel Engines. International Journal of Engine Research 6 (1): pp. 43-60, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mendez, S. and Thirouard, B., “Using Multiple Injection Strategies in Diesel Combustion: Potential to Improve Emissions, Noise and Fuel Economy Trade-Off in Low CR Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1): 662-674, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vogel, T., Wensing, M., Leipertz, A., Iannuzzi, S. et al., “Influence of the fuel quantity on the spray formation and ignition under current engine relevant conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1928, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlucci, P., Ficarella, A., and Laforgia, D., “Effects of Pilot Injection Parameters on Combustion for Common Rail Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0700, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kastner, O., Atzler, F., et al. “Directly actuated piezo injector for advanced injection strategies towards cleaner diesel engines,” in 7th International Symposium Towards Clean Diesel Engines, ed. Shultz C.. Aachen, Germany, June 4-5, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A., d'Ambrosio, S., Finesso, R., Spessa, E. et al., “Combustion System Optimization of a Low Compression-Ratio PCCI Diesel Engine for Light-Duty Application,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1314-1326, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda, T., Kobayashi, S., Matsui, R., and Sono, H., “Study on Euro IV Combustion Technologies for Direct Injection Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0113, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitamura, T. and Ito, T., “Mixing-Controlled, Low Temperature Diesel Combustion with Pressure Modulated Multiple-Injection for HSDI Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):461-478, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0609.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beatrice, C., Belardini, P., Bertoli, C., Lisbona, M. et al., “Combustion Process Management in Common Rail DI Diesel Engines by Multiple Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-24-0007, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-24-0007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Badami, M., Millo, F., and D'Amato, D., “Experimental Investigation on Soot and NOx Formation in a DI Common Rail Diesel Engine with Pilot Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0657, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ricaud, J.C. and Lavoisier, F. “Optimizing the Multiple Injection Settings on an HSDI Diesel Engine,” pp. 251-275 in THIESEL 2002 Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines. Valencia, Spain, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dürnholz, M., Endres, H., and Frisse, P., “Preinjection A Measure to Optimize the Emission Behavior of DI-Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 940674, 1994, doi:10.4271/940674.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, L., “A Study of Pilot Injection in a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3493, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Azimov, U., Tomita, E., et al., Premixed mixture ignition in the end-gas region (PREMIER) combustion in a natural gas dual-fuel engine: operating range and exhaust emissions. International Journal of Engine Research 12 (5): pp. 484-497, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakono, T., Nakai, E., et al. “MAZDA SKYACTIV-D 2.2L Diesel Engine,” pp. 943-965 in 20th Aachen Colloquium on Automobile and Engine Technology. Aachen, Germany, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miyaura, T., Morikawa, A., Ito, Y., Ishizuka, K. et al., “Development of Diesel Engine using New Fuel Injection System - Direct Monitoring of Fuel Injection Pressure using Injector with Built-in Sensor, and its Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1739, 2013, doi: 10.4271/2013-01-1739.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. McGraw- Hill, Inc., 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sahoo, D., Petersen, B., and Miles, P., “Measurement of Equivalence Ratio in a Light-Duty Low Temperature Combustion Diesel Engine by Planar Laser Induced Fluorescence of a Fuel Tracer,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2312-2325, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sahoo, D., Miles, P.C., et al. “The Impact of Injection Pressure, Ambient Temperature, and Swirl Ratio on the Mixture Preparation of a Pilot Injection,” in 11th International Conference on Engines &amp; Vehicles. Capri, Italy, September 15-19, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stineman, R.W., A Consistently Well-Behaved Method of Interpolation, in Creative Computing, 1980. 6 (7): pp. 54-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Belardini, P., Bertoli, C., et al. “Ignition Delay Measurements in a Direct Injection Diesel Engine,” in International Conference on Combustion in Engineering, Instn. Mech. Engrs., C86/83, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Subramanian, G., Pires Da Cruz, A., et al., Chemical Impact of CO and H2 Addition on the Auto-Ignition Delay of Homogeneous N-Heptane/Air Mixtures. Combustion Science and Technology 179 (9): pp. 1937-1962, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W., Kim, D., Miles, P., Oh, S. et al., “A Detailed Comparison of Emissions and Combustion Performance Between Optical and Metal Single-Cylinder Diesel Engines at Low Temperature Combustion Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):505-519, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, X., Donovan, M.T., et al., An Experimental and Modeling Study of iso-Octane Ignition Delay Times under Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Conditions. Combustion and Flame 142 (3): pp. 266-275, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Influence of Fuel Autoignition Reactivity on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1): 39-58, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andree, A. and Pachernegg, S., “Ignition Conditions in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 690253, 1969, doi:10.4271/690253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakai, K., Nishida, K., Yoshizaki, T., and Hiroyasu, H., “Ignition Delays of DME and Diesel Fuel Sprays Injected by a D.I. Diesel Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3600, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-3600.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryan, T. and Callahan, T., “Engine and Constant Volume Bomb Studies of Diesel ignition and Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 881626, 1988, doi:10.4271/881626.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rofail, R. and Henein, N., “Simulation of the Effect of Recirculated Gases on Ignition Delay During Cold Starting of a Direct Injection Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0838, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0838.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lyn, W. and Valdmanis, E., “The Effects of Physical Factors on Ignition Delay,” SAE Technical Paper 680102, 1968, doi:10.4271/680102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CHEMKIN-PRO 15113, Reaction Design: San Diego, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westbrook, C.K., Pitz, W.J., et al., Detailed Chemical Kinetic Reaction Mechanisms for Primary Reference Fuels for Diesel Cetane Number and Spark-Ignition Octane Number. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 33 (1): pp. 185-192, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westbrook, C.K., Pitz, W.J., et al., A Comprehensive Detailed Chemical Kinetic Reaction Mechanism for Combustion of n-Alkane Hydrocarbons from n-Octane to n-Hexadecane. Combustion and Flame 156 (1): pp. 181-199, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, B.I. and Kesler, M.G., A Generalized Thermodynamic Correlation based on Three-Parameter Corresponding States. AIChE Journal 21 (3): pp. 510-527, 1975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamimoto, T., Akiyoshi, M., and Kosaka, H., “A Numerical Simulation of Ignition Delay in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 980501, 1998, doi:10.4271/980501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahlari, A., Hocking, C., Kurtz, E., and Ghandhi, J., “Comparison of Compression Ignition Engine Noise Metrics in Low-Temperature Combustion Regimes,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):541-552, 2013, doi: 10.4271/2013-01-1659.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
