<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">83</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">290</issue>
         <issue-id>i24488616</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24488677</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ADDITIVE SCHEMES (SPLITTING SCHEMES) FOR SOME SYSTEMS OF EVOLUTIONARY EQUATIONS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>PETR N.</given-names>
                  <surname>VABISHCHEVICH</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2787</fpage>
         <lpage>2797</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24488677"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>On the basis of additive schemes (splitting schemes) we construct efficient numerical algorithms to solve approximately the initial-boundary value problems for systems of time-dependent partial differential equations (PDEs). In many applied problems the individual components of the vector of unknowns are coupled together and then splitting schemes are applied in order to get a simple problem for evaluating components at a new time level. Typically, the additive operator-difference schemes for systems of evolutionary equations are constructed for operators coupled in space. In this paper we investigate more general problems where coupling of derivatives in time for components of the solution vector takes place. Splitting schemes are developed using an additive representation for both the primary operator of the problem and the operator at the time derivative. Splitting schemes are based on a triangular two-component representation of the operators.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d689063e114a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e121" publication-type="other">
Uri M. Ascher, Numerical methods for evolutionary differential equations, Computational Sci-
ence &amp;c Engineering, vol. 5, Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics (SIAM), Philadel-
phia, PA, 2008. MR2420042 (2009f:65001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e134a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e141" publication-type="other">
G. I. Barenblatt, V. M. Ryzhik, and V. M. Entov, Theory of fluid flows through natural rocks,
Springer, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e151a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e158" publication-type="other">
Sergio Blanes and Fernando Casas, On the necessity of negative coefficients for operator
splitting schemes of order higher than two, Appl. Numer. Math. 54 (2005), no. 1, 23-37, DOI
10.1016/j.apnum.2004.10.005. MR2134093 (2006b:65085)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e171a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e178" publication-type="other">
A. H.-D. Cheng, Multilayered aquifer systems: fundamentals and applications, Marcel Dekker,
2000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e189a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e196" publication-type="other">
Vincent Giovangigli, Multicomponent flow modeling, Modeling and Simulation in Science,
Engineering and Technology, Birkhauser Boston Inc., Boston, MA, 1999. MR1713516
(2000h:76168)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e209a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e216" publication-type="other">
Bertil Gustafsson, High order difference methods for time dependent PDE, Springer Se-
ries in Computational Mathematics, vol. 38, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 2008. MR2380849
(2009b:65207)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e229a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e236" publication-type="other">
Paul R. Halmos, Finite-dimensional vector spaces, 2nd ed., Springer-Verlag, New York, 1974.
Undergraduate Texts in Mathematics. MR0409503 (53 #13258)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e246a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e253" publication-type="other">
Peter Knabner and Lutz Angermann, Numerical methods for elliptic and parabolic partial
differential equations, Texts in Applied Mathematics, vol. 44, Springer-Verlag, New York,
2003. MR1988268 (2004j:65002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e266a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e273" publication-type="other">
Randall J. LeVeque, Finite difference methods for ordinary and partial differential equations,
Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics (SIAM), Philadelphia, PA, 2007. Steady-state
and time-dependent problems. MR2378550 (2009a:65173)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e286a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e293" publication-type="other">
Francisco J. Lisbona and Petr N. Vabishchevich, Operator-splitting schemes for solving
unsteady elasticity problems, Comput. Methods Appl. Math. 1 (2001), no. 2, 188—198.
MR1855832</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e307a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e314" publication-type="other">
G. I. Marchuk, Splitting and alternating direction methods, Handb. Numer. Anal., I, North-
Holland, Amsterdam, 1990, pp. 197-462. MR1039325</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e324a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e331" publication-type="other">
Tarek P. A. Mathew, Domain decomposition methods for the numerical solution of partial
differential equations, Lecture Notes in Computational Science and Engineering, vol. 61,
Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 2008. MR2445659 (2010b:65006)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e344a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e351" publication-type="other">
Yousef Saad, Iterative methods for sparse linear systems, 2nd ed., Society for Industrial and
Applied Mathematics, Philadelphia, PA, 2003. MR1990645 (2004h:65002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e361a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e368" publication-type="other">
Alfio Quarteroni, Riccardo Sacco, and Fausto Saleri, Numerical mathematics, 2nd ed., Texts
in Applied Mathematics, vol. 37, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 2007. MR2265914 (2007f:65001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e378a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e385" publication-type="other">
Alexander A. Samarskii, The theory of difference schemes, Monographs and Textbooks in
Pure and Applied Mathematics, vol. 240, Marcel Dekker Inc., New York, 2001. MR1818323
(2002c:65003)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e398a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e405" publication-type="other">
A. A. Samarskii and A. V. Gulin, Ustoichivost raznostnykh skhem (Russian, with Russian
summary), 2nd ed., Editorial URSS, Moscow, 2004. MR2263771 (2008a:65001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e416a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e423" publication-type="other">
A. A. Samarskii, P. P. Matus, and P. N. Vabishchevich, Difference schemes with operator
factors, Mathematics and its Applications, vol. 546, Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht,
2002. MR1950844 (2003k:65095)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e436a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e443" publication-type="other">
Aleksandr A. Samarskii and Evgenii S. Nikolaev, Numerical methods for grid equations. Vol.
/, Birkhauser Verlag, Basel, 1989. Direct methods; Translated from the Russian by Stephen
G. Nash. MR1004468 (90m:65003a)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e456a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e463" publication-type="other">
Alexander Samarskii and Petr Vabishchevich, Additive schemes for systems of time-dependent
equations of mathematical physics, Numerical methods and applications, Lecture Notes in
Comput. Sci., vol. 2542, Springer, Berlin, 2003, pp. 48-60, DOI 10.1007/3-540-36487-0JS.
MR2053248</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e479a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e486" publication-type="other">
A. A. Samarskii, Petr N. Vabishchevich, and Lubin G. Vulkov (eds.), Finite difference meth-
ods: theory and applications, Nova Science Publishers Inc., Commack, NY, 1999. MR1714030
(2000e:65004)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e499a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e506" publication-type="other">
Q. Sheng, Solving linear partial differential equations by exponential splitting, IMA J. Numer.
Anal. 9 (1989), no. 2, 199-212, DOI 10.1093/imanum/9.2.199. MR1000457 (90g:65163)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e516a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e523" publication-type="other">
R. Taylor and R. Krishna, Multicomponent mass transfer, Wiley-IEEE, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e531a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e538" publication-type="other">
P. N. Vabishchevich, Difference schemes for nonstationary vector problems, Differential Equa-
tions 40 (2004), no. 7, 1000-1008.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e548a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e555" publication-type="other">
P. N. Vabishchevich, On a new class of additive (splitting) operator-difference schemes, Math-
ematics of Computation 81 (2012), no. 277, 267-276.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e565a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e572" publication-type="other">
P. N. Vabishchevich and A. A. Samarskii, Solution of problems of the dynamics of an incom-
pressible fluid with variable viscosity (Russian, with Russian summary), Zh. Vychisl. Mat.
Mat. Fiz. 40 (2000), no. 12, 1813-1822; English transl., Comput. Math. Math. Phys. 40
(2000), no. 12, 1741-1750. MR1830357 (2001m:76083)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d689063e588a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d689063e595" publication-type="other">
N. N. Yanenko, The method of fractional steps. The solution of problems of mathematical
physics in several variables, Springer-Verlag, New York, 1971. Translated from the Russian
by T. Cheron. English translation edited by M. Holt. MR0307493 (46 #6613)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


