<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">jfinance</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100221</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00221082</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15406261</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25094512</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>"You Can Enter but You Cannot Leave...": U.S. Securities Markets and Foreign Firms</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>András</given-names>
                  <surname>Marosi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Nadia</given-names>
                  <surname>Massoud</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">63</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">5</issue>
         <issue-id>i25094500</issue-id>
         <fpage>2477</fpage>
         <lpage>2506</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 The American Finance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25094512"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Although a number of prior papers have argued the benefits to foreign firms of cross-listing their shares in the U.S., the number of foreign firms exiting U.S. capital markets has been increasing. This has occurred despite the difficulties foreign firms face in deregistering from the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). This paper examines the reasons underlying this trend. One of our main findings is that the passage of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act has reduced the net benefits of a U.S. listing and registration, particularly for smaller foreign firms with lower trading volume and stronger insider control.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group>
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d114e128a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e137" publication-type="other">
Karolyi (2006)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e143" publication-type="other">
Witmer (2006)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e150" publication-type="other">
Chaplinsky and Ramchand (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e156" publication-type="other">
Li (2006)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e162" publication-type="other">
Litvak (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e168" publication-type="other">
Smith (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d114e175a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e182" publication-type="other">
SEC's website for further details: http://www.sec.gov/rules/final/2007/34-55540.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e188" publication-type="other">
Baruch, Karolyi, and Lemmon (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d114e195a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e202" publication-type="other">
Licht (2003)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d114e209a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d114e216" publication-type="other">
http://library.findlaw.com/
2004/Oct/27/133621.html</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d114e235a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e239" publication-type="other">
Aggarwal, Reena, Sandeep Dahiya, and Leora F. Klapper, 2005, American Depositary Receipts
(ADR) holdings of U.S. based emerging market funds, Working paper 3538, World Bank Policy
Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e252a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e256" publication-type="other">
Bailey, Warren, George Andrew Karolyi, and Carolina Salva, 2006, The economic consequences
of increased disclosure: Evidence from international cross-listings, Journal of Financial Eco-
nomics 81, 175-213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e269a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e273" publication-type="other">
Bank of New York, Depositary Receipt Markets: The Year in Review: 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e280a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e284" publication-type="other">
Baruch, Shmuel, George Andrew Karolyi, and Michael L. Lemmon, 2007, Multi-market trading
and liquidity: Theory and empirical evidence, Journal of Finance 62, 2169-2200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e295a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e299" publication-type="other">
Binder, John J., 1985, On the use of the multivariate regression model in event studies, Journal of
Accounting Research 23, 370-383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e309a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e313" publication-type="other">
Brown, Stephen J., and Jerold B. Warner, 1985, Using daily stock returns: The case of event studies,
Journal of Financial Economics 14, 3-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e323a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e327" publication-type="other">
Burns, Natasha, Bill B. Francis, and Iftekhar Hasan, 2007, Cross-listing and legal bonding: Evi-
dence from mergers and acquisitions, Journal of Banking and Finance 31, 1003-1031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e337a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e341" publication-type="other">
Chaplinsky, Susan, and Latha Ramchand, 2007, From listing to delisting: Foreign firms' entry and
exit from the U.S., Working paper, University of Virginia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e351a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e355" publication-type="other">
Chevalier, Judith, 2004, What do we know about cross-subsidization? Evidence from merging firms,
Journal of Advances in Economic Analysis and Policy 4, Article 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e365a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e369" publication-type="other">
Coffee, John C, Jr., 1999, The future as history: The prospects for global convergence in corporate
governance and its implications, Northwestern University Law Review 93, 641-708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e380a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e384" publication-type="other">
Coffee, John C, Jr., 2002, Racing towards the top? The impact of cross-listings and stock-
market competition on international corporate governance, Columbia Law Review 102, 1757-
1831.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e397a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e401" publication-type="other">
Conniffe, Denis, Vanessa Gash, and Philip J. O'Connell, 2000, Evaluating state programmes: Nat-
ural experiments and propensity scores, Economic and Social Review 31, 283-308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e411a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e415" publication-type="other">
DeAngelo, Harry, Linda DeAngelo, and Douglas J. Skinner, 1996, Reversal of fortune: Dividend
signaling and the disappearance of sustained earnings growth, Journal of Financial Economics
40, 341-372.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e428a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e432" publication-type="other">
Djankov, Simeon, Rafael La Porta, Florencio Lopez-de-Silanes, and Andrei Shleifer, 2005, The law
and economics of self-dealing, NBER Working paper 11883, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e442a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e446" publication-type="other">
Doidge, Craig, 2004, U.S. cross-listings and the private benefits of control: Evidence from dual class
firms, Journal of Financial Economics 72, 519-553.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e456a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e460" publication-type="other">
Doidge, Craig, George Andrew Karolyi, and Rene M. Stulz, 2004, Why are foreign firms listed in
the U.S. worth more? Journal of Financial Economics 71, 205-238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e471a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e475" publication-type="other">
Doidge, Craig, George Andrew Karolyi, and Rene M. Stulz, 2007, Has New York become less com-
petitive in global markets? Evaluating foreign listing choices over time, Working paper 2007-
03-012, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e488a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e492" publication-type="other">
Drucker, Steven, and Manju Puri, 2005, On the benefits of concurrent lending and underwriting,
Journal of Finance 60, 2763-2799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e502a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e506" publication-type="other">
Eldridge, Susan W, and Burch T. Kealey, 2005, SOX costs: Auditor attestation under section 404,
Working paper, University of Nebraska at Omaha.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e516a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e520" publication-type="other">
Foerster, Stephen R., and George Andrew Karolyi, 1998, Multimarket trading and liquidity: A
transactions data analysis of Canada-US interlistings, Journal of International Financial
Markets, Institutions and Money 8, 393-412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e533a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e537" publication-type="other">
Foerster, Stephen R., and George Andrew Karolyi, 1999, The effects of market segmentation and
investor recognition on asset prices: Evidence from stock listing in the U.S., Journal of Finance
54, 981-1014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e550a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e554" publication-type="other">
Gledson de Carvalho, Antonio, and George G. Pennacchi, 2005, Can voluntary market reforms
promote efficient corporate governance? Evidence from firms' migration to premium markets
in Brazil, Working paper, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e568a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e572" publication-type="other">
Gozzi, Juan Carlos, Ross Levine, and Sergio L. Schmukler, 2006, Internationalization and the
evolution of corporate valuations, NBER Working paper 11023, University of Minnesota.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e582a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e586" publication-type="other">
Hail, Luzi, and Christian Leuz, 2006, Cost of capital effects and changes in growth expectations
around U.S. cross-listings, Working paper 46, ECGI-Finance.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e596a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e600" publication-type="other">
Healy, Paul M., and Krishna G. Palepu, 1990, Effectiveness of accounting-based dividend covenants,
Journal of Accounting and Economics 12, 97-124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e610a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e614" publication-type="other">
Karolyi, George Andrew, 2006, The world of cross-listings and cross-listings of the world: Challeng-
ing conventional wisdom, Review of Finance 10, 1-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e624a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e628" publication-type="other">
La Porta, Rafael, Florencio Lopez-de-Silanes, Andrei Shleifer, and Robert W Vishny, 1998, Law
and finance, Journal of Political Economy 106, 1113-1155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e638a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e642" publication-type="other">
Leuven, Edwin, and Barbara Sianesi, 2003, PSMATCH2: Stata module to perform full Mahalanobis
and propensity score matching, common support graphing, and covariate imbalance testing,
Statistical Software Components S432001, Boston College Department of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e656a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e660" publication-type="other">
Leuz, Christian, Alexander Triantis, and Tracy Wang, 2007, Why do firms go dark? Causes and eco-
nomic consequences of voluntary SEC deregistrations, Journal of Accounting and Economics
(forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e673a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e677" publication-type="other">
Li, Xi, 2006, The Sarbanes-Oxley Act and cross-listed foreign private issuers, Working paper, Uni-
versity of Miami.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e687a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e691" publication-type="other">
Licht, Amir, 2003, Cross-listing and corporate governance: Bonding or avoiding? Chicago Journal
of International Law 4, 141-163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e701a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e705" publication-type="other">
Lins, Karl V., Deon Strickland, and Marc Zenner, 2005, Do non-US firms issue equity in US stock
exchanges to relax capital constraints? Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 40,
109-134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e718a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e722" publication-type="other">
Litvak, Kate, 2007, The effect of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act on non-US companies cross-listed in the
U.S., Journal of Corporate Finance 13, 195-228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e736" publication-type="other">
Loughran, Tim, and Jay Ritter, 1996, Long-term market overreaction: The effect of low-priced
stocks, Journal of Finance 51, 1959-1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e747a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e751" publication-type="other">
Marosi, Andras, and Nadia Massoud, 2007, Why do firms go dark? Journal of Financial and Quan-
titative Analysis 42, 421-442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e761a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e765" publication-type="other">
Miller, Darius P., 1999, The market reaction to international cross-listings: Evidence from deposi-
tary receipts, Journal of Financial Economics 51, 103-123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e775a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e779" publication-type="other">
Newey, Whitney K., and Kenneth D. West, 1987, A simple positive semi-definite, heteroskedasticity
and autocorrelation consistent covariance matrix, Econometrica 55, 703-708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e793" publication-type="other">
Opler, Tim, and Sheridan Titman, 1993, The determinants of leveraged buyout activity: Cash flow
vs. financial distress costs, Journal of Finance 48, 1985-1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e803a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e807" publication-type="other">
Pagano, Marco, Ailsa A. Röell, and Josef Zechner, 2002, The geography of equity listing: Why do
companies list abroad? Journal of Finance 57, 2651-2694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e817a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e821" publication-type="other">
Petersen, Mitchell A., 2006, Estimating standard errors in finance panel data sets: Comparing
approaches, Working paper 329, Northwestern University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e832a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e836" publication-type="other">
Piotroski, Joseph D., and Suraj Srinivasan, 2007, The Sarbanes-Oxley Act and the flow of interna-
tional listings, Working paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e846a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e850" publication-type="other">
Pozen, Robert, 2004, Can European companies escape U.S. listings? Working paper 464, Harvard
Law School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e860a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e864" publication-type="other">
Sarkissian, Sergei, and Michael J. Schill, 2005, Are there permanent valuation gains to over-
seas listing? Evidence from market sequencing and selection, Working paper, University of
Virginia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e877a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e881" publication-type="other">
Schipper, Katherine, and Rex Thompson, 1983, The impact of merger-related regulations on the
shareholders of acquiring firms, Journal of Accounting Research 21, 184-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e891a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e895" publication-type="other">
Siegel, Jordan, 2005, Can foreign firms bond themselves effectively by renting US securities laws?
Journal of Financial Economics 75, 319-359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e905a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e909" publication-type="other">
Siegel, Jordan, 2007, Is there a better commitment mechanism than cross-listings for emerging
economy firms? Evidence from Mexico, Working paper, Harvard Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e920a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e924" publication-type="other">
Smith, Geoffrey Peter, 2007, A look at the impact of Sarbanes-Oxley on cross-listed firms, Working
paper, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e934a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e938" publication-type="other">
Spamann, Holger, 2006, On the insignificance and/or endogeneity of La Porta et al.'s "anti-director
rights index" under consistent coding, John M. Olin Center Discussion paper 7, Harvard Law
School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e951a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e955" publication-type="other">
Stulz, Rene, 1999, Globalization, corporate finance, and the cost of capital, Journal of Applied
Corporate Finance 12, 8-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e965a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e969" publication-type="other">
Witmer, Jonathan, 2006, Why do firms cross-delist? An examination of the determinants and effects
of cross-delisting, Working paper, Queens University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e979a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e983" publication-type="other">
World Federation of Exchanges, website: http://www.world-exchanges.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d114e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d114e994" publication-type="other">
Zingales, Luigi, 2006, Is the U.S. capital market losing its competitive edge? Working paper 1,
University of Chicago Graduate School of Business.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
