<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169068</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fuel Consumption and Cost Potential of Different Plug-In Hybrid Vehicle Architectures</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Namdoo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moawad</surname>
                  <given-names>Ayman</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shidore</surname>
                  <given-names>Neeraj</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rousseau</surname>
                  <given-names>Aymeric</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>May 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169060</issue-id>
         <fpage>88</fpage>
         <lpage>99</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169068"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles (PHEVs) have demonstrated the potential to provide significant reduction in fuel use across a wide range of dynamometer test driving cycles. Companies and research organizations are involved in numerous research activities related to PHEVs. One of the current unknowns is the impact of driving behavior and standard test procedure on the true benefits of PHEVs from a worldwide perspective. To address this issue, five different PHEV powertrain configurations (input split, parallel, series, series-output split and series-parallel), implemented on vehicles with different all-electric ranges (AERs), were analyzed on three different standard cycles (i.e., Urban Dynamometer Driving Schedule, Highway Fuel Economy Test, and New European Driving Cycle). Component sizes, manufacturing cost, and fuel consumption were analyzed for a midsize car in model year 2020 through the use of vehicle system simulations. These configurations represent typical mass-production vehicles, including the Toyota Prius PHEV, Chevrolet Volt, and Honda Accord PHEV.</p>
            <p>In addition, this study examined the impact of the transmission mechanical losses, and especially the planetary gear losses, modeled using power split ratio analysis. The powertrain components were sized to meet AER, performance, and grade-capacity requirements. The impact of driving behavior was analyzed through fuel consumption benefits. The PHEV system analysis in this study will provide insight into how PHEVs can be designed to support market introduction of a limited number of vehicle options to maximize market penetration.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higuchi, H., and Shimada, H. “Efficiency Enhancement of a New Two- Motor Hybrid System,” Proceedings of theEVS27 Conference, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Da Costa, A., Kim, N., Le Berr, F., Marc, N., et al., “Fuel Consumption Potential of Different Plug-in Hybrid Vehicle Architectures in the European and American Contexts,” Proceedings of the EVS26 Conference, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, I., and Kim, H. “Configuration Analysis of Plug-in Hybrid Systems Using Global Optimization,” Proceedings of the EVS27 Conference, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U. S. Department of Energy Vehicle Technologies Office, U.S. DRIVE, http://energy.gov/eere/vehicles/vehicle-technologies-office-us-drive.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ward, J., Moawad, A., Kim, N., and Rousseau, A. “Light-Duty-Vehicle Fuel Consumption, Cost and Market Penetration Potential by 2020,” Proceedings of the EVS26 Conference, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henrion, M. “Guide to Estimating Unbiased Probability Distributions for Energy R&amp;D Results,” DOE Risk Analysis Group, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rousseau, A., Kwon, J., Sharer, P., Pagerit, S. et al., “Integrating Data, Performing Quality Assurance, and Validating the Vehicle Model for the 2004 Prius Using PSAT,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0667, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0667.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N., Rousseau, A., Lee, D., and Lohse-Busch, H. “Thermal Model Development and Validation for 2010 Toyota Prius,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1784, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1784.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N., Duoba, M., Kim, N., and Rousseau, A. “Validating Volt PHEV Model with Dynamometer Test Data Using Autonomie,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 6(2):985-992, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallner, T. and Lohse-Busch, H. “Performance, Efficiency, and Emissions Evaluation of a Supercharged, Hydrogen-Powered, 4-Cylinder Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0016, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olszewski, M. “Evaluation of the 2007 Toyota Camry Hybrid Synergy Drive System,” Report for the U.S. Department of Energy, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tesla Motors, http://www.teslamotors.com/blog/induction-versus-dcbrushless- motors.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N., Kwon, J., and Rousseau, A. “Trade-off between Multi-Mode Powertrain Complexity and Fuel Consumption,” Proceedings of the EVS25 Conference, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Model and Simulate One-Dimensional Mechanical Systems, http://www.mathworks.com/products/simdrive/index.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Recommended Practice for Measuring the Exhaust Emissions and Fuel Economy of Hybrid-Electric Vehicles, Including Plug-in Hybrid Vehicles,” SAE Standard J1711, Rev. Jun. 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
