<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794458</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Optimal tax IV</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>How well targeted are soda taxes?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dubois</surname>
                  <given-names>Pierre</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Griffith</surname>
                  <given-names>Rachel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>O'Connell</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>7</lpage>
         <page-range>1, 1-50, 1-7</page-range>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794458"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Soda taxes aim to reduce excessive sugar consumption. Their effectiveness depends on whether they successfully target individuals for whom the harm of consumption is most severe. We estimate a model of individual drinks demand while "on-the-go and account for supply-side equilibrium pass-through of tax. Importantly, we exploit longitudinal data to estimate individual preference parameters, which allows flexible heterogeneity that we can relate to a wide array of individual characteristics. We show that soda taxes are effective at targeting young consumers, but not individuals with high sugar diets and they are unlikely to be strongly regressive.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Adams, A., L. Cherchye, B. De Rock, and E. Verriest (2014). Consume now or later? Time inconsistency, collective choice, and revealed preference. American Economic Review 104 (12), 4027{4070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Aguiar, M. and E. Hurst (2007). Life-Cycle Prices and Production. American Economic Review 97 (5), 1533{1559.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Arellano, M. and S. Bonhomme (2011). Nonlinear Panel Data Analysis. Annual Review of Economics 3 (1), 395{424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Arellano, M. and J. Hahn (2007). Understanding bias in nonlinear panel models: Some recent developments. In Econometric Society Monographs, Volume 43, pp. 381.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bajari, P. and C. L. Benkard (2005). Demand Estimation with Heterogeneous Consumers and Unobserved Product Characteristics: A Hedonic Approach. Journal of Political Economy 113 (6), 1239{1276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bajari, P., J. T. Fox, and S. P. Ryan (2007). Linear regression estimation of discrete choice models with nonparametric distributions of random coeacients. American Economic Review 97 (2), 459{463.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Banerjee, A. and S. Mullainathan (2010, May). The Shape of Temptation: Implications for the Economic Lives of the Poor. Working Paper 15973, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bernheim, B. D., D. Ray, and Sa. Yeltekin (2015). Poverty and Self-Control. Econo- metrica 83 (5), 1877{1911.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Berry, S., J. Levinsohn, and A. Pakes (1995). Automobile Prices in Market Equilibrium.Econometrica 63 (4), 841{890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Berry, S., J. Levinsohn, and A. Pakes (2004). Di erentiated products demand systems from combination of micro and macro data: The new car market. Journal of Political Economy 112 (1), 68{105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Berry, S. T. (1994). Estimating Discrete-Choice Models of Product Di erentiation.RAND Journal of Economics 25, 242{262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Besley, T. J. and H. S. Rosen (1999). Sales Taxes and Prices: An Empirical Analysis.National Tax Journal 52 (2), 157{78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Bonnet, C. and V. Raequillart (2013). Tax incidence with strategic arms in the soft drink market. Journal of Public Economics 106, 77{88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Browning, M. and P. A. Chiappori (1998). Eacient Intra-Household Allocation : AGeneral Characterization and Empirical Tests. Econometrica 66 (6), 1241{1278.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Burda, M., M. Harding, and J. Hausman (2008). A Bayesian mixed logit-probit model for multinomial choice. Journal of Econometrics 147 (2), 232{246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Cavadini, C., A. M. Siega-Riz, and B. M. Popkin (2000, July). US adolescent food intake trends from 1965 to 1996. Archives of Disease in Childhood 83 (1), 18{24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Cawley, J. (2010). The economics of childhood obesity. Health A airs 29 (3), 364{ 371.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Cawley, J. and D. E. Frisvold (2017, March). The Pass-Through of Taxes on Sugar-Sweetened Beverages to Retail Prices: The Case of Berkeley, California. Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 36 (2), 303{326.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">CDC (2016, September). Cut Back on Sugary Drinks. http://www.cdc.gov/nutrition/data-statistics/sugar-sweetened-beverages-intake.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Cutler, D., E. Glaeser, and J. Shapiro (2003). Why Have Americans Become More Obese? The Journal of Economic Perspectives 17 (3), 93{118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Delipalla, S. and O. O'Donnell (2001). Estimating tax incidence, market power and market conduct: The European cigarette industry. International Journal of Industrial Organization 19 (6), 885{908.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Dhaene, G. and K. Jochmans (2015, July). Split-panel Jackknife Estimation of Fixed-e ect Models. The Review of Economic Studies 82 (3), 991{1030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">DiMeglio, D. P. and R. D. Mattes (2000). Liquid versus solid carbohydrate: E ects on food intake and body weight. International journal of obesity 24 (6), 794.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Dubois, P., R. Griath, and A. Nevo (2014). Do Prices and Attributes Explain International Di erences in Food Purchases? American Economic Review 104 (3), 832{867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Fabra, N. and M. Reguant (2014). Pass-Through of Emissions Costs in Electricity Markets. The American Economic Review 104 (9), 2872{2899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Gilbert, D. T., M. J. Gill, and T. D. Wilson (2002, May). The Future Is Now: Temporal Correction in A ective Forecasting. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes 88 (1), 430{444.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Goldberg, P. K. and R. Hellerstein (2013). A structural approach to identifying the sources of local currency price stability. Review of Economic Studies 80 (1), 175{210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Grogger, J. (2015, May). Soda Taxes and the Prices of Sodas and Other Drinks: Evidence from Mexico. Working Paper 21197, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Gruber, J. and B. Koszegi (2004). Tax incidence when individuals are timeinconsistent: The case of cigarette excise taxes. Journal of Public Eco- nomics 88 (9-10), 1959{1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Haavio, M. and K. Kotakorpi (2011, May). The political economy of sin taxes.European Economic Review 55 (4), 575{594.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Hagenaars, A. J., K. De Vos, M. Asghar Zaidi, and others (1994). Poverty statistics in the late 1980s: Research based on micro-data.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Hahn, J. and W. Newey (2004). Jackknife and analytical bias reduction for nonlinear panel models. Econometrica 72 (4), 1295{1319.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Hall, K. D., G. Sacks, D. Chandramohan, C. C. Chow, Y. C. Wang, S. L. Gortmaker, and B. A. Swinburn (2011, August). Quantiacation of the e ect of energy imbalance on bodyweight. The Lancet 378 (9793), 826{837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Han, E. and L. M. Powell (2013, January). Consumption patterns of sugar sweetened beverages in the United States. Journal of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics 113 (1), 43{53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Harding, M., E. Leibtag, and M. F. Lovenheim (2012). The Heterogeneous Geographic and Socioeconomic Incidence of Cigarette Taxes: Evidence from Nielsen Homescan Data. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 4 (4), 169{198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Haushofer, J. and E. Fehr (2014, May). On the psychology of poverty. Sci- ence 344 (6186), 862{867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Hendel, I. and A. Nevo (2006). Measuring the implications of sales and consumer inventory behavior. Econometrica 74 (6), 1637{1673.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Kaplan, G. and G. Menzio (2015). The morphology of price dispersion. International Economic Review 56 (4), 1165{1206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Kenkel, D. S. (2005). Are alcohol tax hikes fully passed through to prices? Evidence from Alaska. American Economic Review: Papers &amp; Proceedings 95 (2).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Lewbel, A. and K. Pendakur (2017). Unobserved Preference Heterogeneity in Demand Using Generalized Random Coeacients. Journal of Political Econ- omy 125 (4).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Lillard, D. R. and A. Sfekas (2013). Just passing through: The e ect of the Master Settlement Agreement on estimated cigarette tax price pass-through. Applied economics letters 20 (4), 353{357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Lockwood, B. B. and D. Taubinsky (2017, January). Regressive Sin Taxes. Working Paper 23085, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Mani, A., S. Mullainathan, E. Shaar, and J. Zhao (2013, August). Poverty Impedes Cognitive Function. Science 341 (6149), 976{980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Mennella, J. A., N. K. Bobowski, and D. R. Reed (2016, June). The development of sweet taste: From biology to hedonics. Reviews in Endocrine and Metabolic Disorders 17 (2), 171{178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Nakamura, E. and D. Zerom (2010). Accounting for Incomplete Pass-Through.Review of Economic Studies 77 (3), 1192{1230.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Nevo, A. (2001). Measuring market power in the ready-to-eat cereal industry.Econometrica 69 (2), 307{342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Neyman, J. and E. L. Scott (1948, January). Consistent Estimates Based on Partially Consistent Observations. Econometrica 16 (1), 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Nielsen, S. J. and B. M. Popkin (2004, October). Changes in beverage intake between 1977 and 2001. American Journal of Preventive Medicine 27 (3), 205{ 210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">O'Donoghue, T. and M. Rabin (2006). Optimal sin taxes. Journal of Public Eco- nomics 90 (10-11), 1825{1849.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Poterba, J. M. (1989). Lifetime Incidence and the Distributional Burden of Excise Taxes. The American Economic Review 79 (2), 325{330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Rabin, M. (1998). Psychology and Economics. Journal of Economic Litera- ture 36 (1), 11{46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Read, D. and B. Van Leeuwen (1998). Predicting hunger: The e ects of appetite and delay on choice. Organizational behavior and human decision processes 76 (2), 189{205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Sanders, B. (2016, April). Bernie Sanders Op-Ed: A Soda Tax Would Hurt Philly's Poor.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Small, K. A. and H. S. Rosen (1981). Applied Welfare Economics with Discrete Choice Models. Econometrica 49 (1), 105{130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Train, K. E. (2003). Discrete Choice Methods with Simulation. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Train, K. E. (2008). EM algorithms for nonparametric estimation of mixing distributions.Journal of Choice Modelling 1 (1), 40{69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Wang, E. Y. (2015, June). The impact of soda taxes on consumer welfare: Implications of storability and taste heterogeneity. The RAND Journal of Eco- nomics 46 (2), 409{441.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">WHO (2015). Sugars intake for adults and children.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Sugar from soda</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Age groups</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Total dietary sugar</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Equivalized expenditure</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Drinks products</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Model estimates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Univariate distributions of consumer specific preference parameters</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Price effects</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Preferences variation with age</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Preferences variation with total dietary sugar</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Sugar preference parameters</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Effects of sugary soda tax at product level</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Reductions in sugar</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Revealed consumer welfare effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Effects by total equivalized grocery expenditure</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Participation in market</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Soda consumers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Price variation for Coca Cola</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Bivariate distributions of consumer specific preference parameters</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Preferences variation with equivalized expenditure</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Upper stage model estimates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Added sugar and soda (US)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Relationship between household income and grocery expenditure</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure C.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Relationship between bias and time in sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure C.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Relationship between bias and age</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure C.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Relationship between bias and dietary sugar</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure C.4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Preference parameter distribution</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table C.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Price Effects on Demand</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table D.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Effects of "broad" soda tax</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
