<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277847</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Assessment of Emissions from Light-Duty Vehicles using PEMS and Chassis Dynamometer Testing</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>May</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bosteels</surname>
                  <given-names>Dirk</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Favre</surname>
                  <given-names>Cecile</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>AECC</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1326</fpage>
         <lpage>1335</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277847"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>From 1 September 2014 new car types in the EU must meet ‘Euro 6’ emissions requirements. The ‘New European Driving Cycle’ (NEDC) is currently the main test for this, but the European Commission intends to also introduce PEMS (Portable Emissions Measurement Systems)-based procedures to ensure that emissions are well controlled in real use. ‘Random Cycles’ have also been considered and remain a possible option for ‘real world’ particle number measurement. At the same time, the UN Working Party on Pollution and Energy (GRPE) has developed the new Worldwide harmonized Light vehicles Test Procedure (WLTP) that is expected to be adopted in the EU in the near future. To identify and understand the differences in emissions that may arise between these various methodologies, AECC has conducted some initial tests on two modern light-duty vehicles.</p>
            <p>Chassis dynamometer emissions tests were conducted over the NEDC, the Common Artemis suite of test cycles (CADC), the new Worldwide Light-duty Test Cycle (WLTC - the test cycle for WLTP) and a set of cycles produced by a Random Cycle Generator based on ‘short trip’ segments from the EU database used to construct WLTC. A Portable Emissions Measurement System (PEMS) was used to measure emissions during real driving over pre-selected routes.</p>
            <p>The test results show that there can be substantial differences for some pollutants measured as ‘real driving emissions’ (RDE) using PEMS equipment, compared to the test cycles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weiss, Bonnel, Kühlwein, Provenza et al, “Will Euro 6 reduce the NOx emissions of new diesel cars? Insights from on-road tests with Portable Emissions Measurement Systems (PEMS)”, Atmospheric Environment 62657-665, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.atmosenv.2012.08.056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Communication from the Commission to the European Parliament, the Council, the European Economic and Social Committee and the Committee of the Regions. Cars 2020: Action Plan for a competitive and sustainable automotive industry in Europe”, (2012), COM (2012) 636 final, http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=COM:2012:0636:FIN:EN:PDF</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weiss, Bonnel, Hummel &amp; Steininger, “A complementary emissions test for light-duty vehicles: Assessing the technical feasibility of candidate procedures”, JRC Scientific and Policy Report EUR 25572 EN, 2013, http://publications.jrc.ec.europa.eu/repository/handle/111111111/27598 or doi:10.2790/65654.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UN Regulation No.83, Annex 4a, paragraph 6.1, www.unece.org/fileadmin/DAM/trans/main/wp29/wp29regs/r083r4e.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Draft Global technical regulation No. XX, Worldwide Harmonised Light Vehicle Test Procedures (WLTP), https://www2.unece. org/wiki/download/attachments/5801176/26.08.2013%20Draft. pdf?api=v2. Note this is the draft version of the Regulation (at September 2013) for approval by GRPE and is likely to be updated.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">André, “The ARTEMIS European driving cycles for measuring car pollutant emissions.” Science of the Total Environment 334-335, 73-84, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.scitotenv.2004.04.070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Favre, C., Bosteels, D., and May, J., “Exhaust Emissions from European Market-Available Passenger Cars Evaluated on Various Drive Cycles,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0154, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schindler, W., Haisch, C., Beck, H., Niessner, R. et al., “A Photoacoustic Sensor System for Time Resolved Quantification of Diesel Soot Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0968, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson, Giechaskiel et al, “Particle Measurement Programme (PMP) Light-duty Inter-laboratory Correlation Exercise (ILCE_LD) Final Report”, European Commission Joint Research Centre report EUR 22775 EN, 2007, http://ies.jrc.ec.europa.eu/uploads/fileadmin/Documentation/Reports/Emissions_and_Health/EUR_2006-2007/EUR_22775_EN.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mamakos, &amp; Manfredi, “Physical characterization of exhaust particle emissions from late technology gasoline vehicles”, European Commission Joint Research Centre report EUR 25382 EN, 2012, doi:10.2788/3251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maricq, Szente et al, “Influence of Mileage Accumulation on the Particle Mass and Number Emissions of Two Gasoline Direct Injection Vehicles”, Environmental Science &amp; Technology 47 (20), 11890-11896, 2013, doi:10.1021/es402686z.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontaras, Franco, Dilara, Martini &amp; Manfredi, “Development and review of Euro 5 passenger car emission factors based on experimental results over various driving cycles” Science of the Total Environment 468-469 1034-1042, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.scitotenv.2013.09.043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weiss, Bonnel et al, “On-Road Emissions of Light-Duty Vehicles in Europe”, Environmental Science &amp; Technology 45 (19) 8575-8581, 2011, doi:10.1021/es2008424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
