<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277681</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of a Three-Way Catalytic Converter on Particulate Matter from a Gasoline Direct-Injection Engine During Cold-Start</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Whelan</surname>
                  <given-names>Ian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. College Dublin</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Timoney</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. College Dublin</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Smith</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. College Dublin</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Samuel</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oxford Brookes University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1035</fpage>
         <lpage>1045</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277681"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This work investigates the effect of a three-way catalytic converter and sampling dilution ratio on nano-scale exhaust particulate matter emissions from a gasoline direct-injection engine during cold-start and warm-up transients. Experimental results are presented from a four cylinder in-line, four stroke, wall-guided direct-injection, turbo-charged and inter-cooled 1.6 litre gasoline engine. A fast-response particulate spectrometer for exhaust nano-particle measurement up to 1000 nm was utilised. It was observed that the three-way catalytic converter had a significant effect on particle number density, reducing the total particle number by up to 65 % over the duration of the cold-start test. The greatest change in particle number density occurred for particles less than 23 nm diameter, with reductions of up to 95 % being observed, whilst the number density for particles above 50 nm diameter exhibited a significant increase. The exhaust temperature plays a significant role on the influence of the catalytic converter on the nano-scale particulate matter. It is evident that the dilution ratio of the exhaust sample has a distinct effect on the particulate matter number and size distribution, influencing the engine-out PM more significantly than the tailpipe-out PM during cold-start engine operation. The catalytic converter also has a considerable effect on the estimated total particle mass.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B. Engines and Nanoparticles: A Review. Journal of Aerosol Science, 1998, 29(5/6), 575-588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graskow, B., Kittelson, D., Ahmadi, M., and Morris, J., “Exhaust Particulate Emissions from Two Port Fuel Injected Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1144, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-1144.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pearson, J.K., “Improving Air Quality,” Society of Automotive Engineers; Inc., Warrendale, PA, ISBN 978-0-7680-0236-2, 2001, doi: 10.4271/R-232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Anna, A. Combustion-formed nanoparticles. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 2009, 32, 593-613.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bouris, D., Crane, R.I., Evans, J.M. and Tippayawong, N. An approach to characterization and after-treatment of particulate emissions from gasoline engines. International Journal of Engine Research, 2000, 1, 291-300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hall, D., King, D., Morgan, T., Baverstock, S. et al., “A Review of Recent Literature Investigating the Measurement of Automotive Particulate; The Relationship with Environmental Aerosol, Air Quality and Health Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 982602, 1998, doi: 10.4271/982602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eastwood, P. Critical Topics in Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment. Hertfordshire, England: Research Studies Press Ltd.; 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. Boston: McGraw-Hill International Series, Automotive Technology Series; 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sougawa, Y., Koseki, K., Kawaguchi, H., Nishimura, J. et al., “Improvement of Repeatability in Tailpipe Emission Measurement with Direct Injection Spark Ignition (DISI) Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2710, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2710.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, H., Shamim, T., and Sengupta, S., “An Investigation of Catalytic Converter Performances during Cold Starts,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3473, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3473.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Samuel, S., Morrey, D., Fowkes, M., Taylor, D.H.C., Gerner, C.P. and Austin, L. Real-world performance of catalytic converters. IMechE Journal of Automobile Engineering, 2005, 219(D), 881-888.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Samuel, S., Hassaneen, A., and Morrey, D., “Particulate Matter Emissions and the Role of Catalytic Converter During Cold Start of GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2122, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hassaneen, A. and Lotfy, I., “Conversion Efficiency of a 2-Way Catalyst Fitted in a Used Vehicle without Feedback Emission Control System,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2164, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-2164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamura, Y., Kikuchi, S., Okada, K., Koga, K. et al., “Development of Advanced Emission-Control Technologies for Gasoline Direct-Injection Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0254, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0254.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korin, E., Reshef, R., Tshernichovesky, D., and Sher, E., “Improving Cold-Start Functioning of Catalytic Converters by Using Phase-Change Materials,” SAE Technical Paper 980671, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980671.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, S., Potter, T., Keyser, M., Brady, M. et al., “Reducing Cold-Start Emissions by Catalytic Converter Thermal Management,” SAE Technical Paper 950409, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950409.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Czerwinski, J., Comte, P., Violetti, N., Landri, P. et al., “Catalyst Aging and Effects on Particle Emissions of 2-Stroke Scooters,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0455, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0455.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., Lai, M.C. and Harrington, D.L. Automotive spark-ignited direct-injection gasoline engines. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 1999, 25, 437-562.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Price, P., Twiney, B., Stone, R., Kar, K. et al., “Particulate and Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Spray Guided Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine with Oxygenate Fuel Blends,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0472, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alkidas, A. and El Tahry, S., “Contributors to the Fuel Economy Advantage of DISI Engines Over PFI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3101, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cambustion. DMS-500 Fast Particulate Spectrometer User Manual Version 2.0. Available at: http://www.cambustion.com/products/dms500/aerosol [2003-20006, accessed 16 May 2011]</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Price, P., Stone, R., Collier, T., Davies, M. et al., “Dynamic Particulate Measurements from a DISI Vehicle: A Comparison of DMS500, ELPI, CPC and PASS,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1077, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, F., Chen, L. and Stone, R. Effects of a Catalytic Volatile Particle Remover (VPR) on the Particulate Matter Emissions from a Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine. Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 2011, 45, 9036-9043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cambustion. DMS-03 Cambustion Application Note - Sampling Engine Exhaust with the DMS500. Available from: http://www.cambustion.com/applications/appinst/DMS500%20%2526amp %3B%20DMS50 [2005-2008, accessed 06 June 2011]</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Symonds, J.P.R., Reavell, K. St.J., Olfert, J.S., Campbell, B.W. and Swift, S.J. Diesel soot mass calculation in real-time with a differential mobility spectrometer. Aerosol Science, 2007, 38, 52-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Symonds, J.P.R., Price, P., Williams, P.I. and Stone, R. Density of particles emitted from a gasoline direct injection engine. Cambustion. Available from: http://www.cambustion.com/sites/default/files/downloads/papers/2008/EAC-2008-SYMONDS.pdf, [June 2008, accessed 15 September 2011].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Virtanen, A., Ristimäki, J., Marjamäki, M., Vaaraslahti, K. et al., “Effective Density of Diesel Exhaust Particles as a Function of Size,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0056, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizuno, T. and Suzuki, J., “Development of a New DPNR Catalyst,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0578, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0578.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giugliano, M., Cernuschi, S., Lonati, G., Ozgen, S., Sghirlanzoni, G.A., Tardivo, R., Mascherpa, A. and Migliavacca, G. Ultrafine particles from combustion sources: sampling and measurement. Chemical Engineering Transactions, 2008, 16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burtscher, H. Physical characterization of particulate emissions from diesel engines: a review. Aerosol Science, 2005, 36, 896-932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lipsky, E., Stanier, C.O., Pandis, S.N. and Robinson, A.L. Effects of Sampling Conditions on the Size Distribution of Fine Particulate Matter Emitted from a Pilot-Scale Pulverized-Coal Combustor. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2002, 16, 302-310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
