<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23024777</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>EXTENDING CREDIT TO SMALL-SCALE FARMERS: THE CASE OF AGRICULTURAL FINANCE CORPORATION IN THE CENTRAL RIFT AREA OF KENYA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>J.N.</given-names>
                  <surname>Mbata</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23024723</issue-id>
         <fpage>57</fpage>
         <lpage>73</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23024777"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The Agricultural Finance Corporation (AFC) was established to provide credit to small-scale farmers, among others who cannot produce adequate collateral to qualify for loans from the commercial banks. How well the corporation has performed in extending credit to small-scale farmers in the Central Rift Area of Kenya and the impact of the credit on this group of farmers during the 1989/90 are the basis for this study. The results of the study revealed that about 20 per cent of the total amount of credit granted to the farmers in the area went to the small-scale farmers, an indication that most of the loans from AFC still go to the large scale producers. Empirically, it was observed that there is a need to increase the amount of credit granted to the small-scale farmers in the area. This is because the results of the budgetary analysis showed that small-scale farming with the use of credit was profitable whereas the results of the production function analysis indicated that credit as an input was under-utilized as the ratio of its marginal value product to marginal cost was statistically greater than 1. In addition, it was observed that the high rate of default among the farmers as a result of the lax collection procedures of the AFC has seriously affected the liquidity and performance of the corporation, while the complicated procedures in loan application, approval and disbursement have contributed to the inefficient utilization of the credit extended to the farmers. Based on the findings of the study, it is recommended that the amount of credit available to small-scale farmers should be increased and disbursed promptly to ensure an optimal utilization of the input. Also, for increased liquidity and for the corporation to become self-sufficient, it should improve its loan recovery procedure and make desperate efforts to stem the high rate of default that has seriously affected the performance of the corporation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d15e172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e176" publication-type="other">
Adams, D.W and Graham, D.H. (1981). "A Critique of Traditional Agricultural Credit Projects and Policies". Journal
of Development Economics. Vol. 8 pp. 347-366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e190" publication-type="other">
Baker, C.B. (1973). "Role of Credit in the Economic Development of Small-Farm Agriculture". AID Spring Review
of Small Farmer Credit. Vol. V No. XIX. Washington, USAID.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e200a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e204" publication-type="other">
Donaldson, G.F. and von Pischke, J.D. (1973). "A Survey of Small Farmers Credit in Kenya". AID Spring Review
of Small Farmer Credit. Vol. VII No. IX. Washington, USAID.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e218" publication-type="other">
Dwivedi, R.C. (1972). New Strategy for Agricultural Development in India. Meerut Loyal Book Depot. 536p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e226a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e230" publication-type="other">
FAO, (1965). "Agricultural Credit through Cooperatives and other Institutions". FAO Agricultural Studies, No. 68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e237a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e241" publication-type="other">
Godfrey, M. (1986). "The Agricultural Sector in Kenya to 1990". Special Report; Economist Intelligence Unit.
No. 1052 pp. 53-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e251a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e255" publication-type="other">
Grosh, B. (1987). "Performance of Financial Parastatals in Kenya, 1964-1984". Working Paper No. 449. Insti-
tute for Development Studies, University of Nairobi, Kenya. 70p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e265a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e269" publication-type="other">
Kenya, (1989). Sixth National Development Plan 1989-1993. Government Printers, Nairobi, Kenya. 262p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e276a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e280" publication-type="other">
Kenya, Agricultural Finance Corporation (1990). Statistical Digest, December, 1990, Nairobi. 13 p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e287a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e291" publication-type="other">
Koutsoyiannis, A. (1977). Theory of Econometrics. Second Edition. MacMillan Education, London. 681p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e299a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e303" publication-type="other">
Ladipo, O.O. (1977). "The Variance of Marginal Productivity Estimates Using the Cobb-Douglas Function". Journal
of Rural Economics and Development Vo. II No. 1 pp. 57- 68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e313a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e317" publication-type="other">
Lugogo, J.A. (1983). "A Polyperiod Risk Programming Analysis of Small-Holder Farm Management in Kenya".
An Unpublished PhD Dissertation, Department of Agricultural Economics, Virginia Polytechnic and State
University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e330a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e334" publication-type="other">
Mbata, J.N. (1991). "An Evaluation of Institutional Credit and its Role in Agricultural Production in Rivers State,
Nigeria". African Review of Money, Finance and Banking. No. 1 - 1991. pp 5-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e344a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e348" publication-type="other">
Olodimu. O.L. and Fabiyi, Y.L. (1984). "Providing and Utilizing Credit for Agricultural Development in Nigeria:
A Case Study of the Cross River State". Savings and Development. No. 2 - 1984 - VIII. pp. 175 - 188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e358a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e362" publication-type="other">
Osuntogun, A. (1980). "A Study of Resource Productivity in Co-operative Farming in Imo State in Nigeria". Cana-
dian Journal of Agricultural Economics. Vol. 28, No. 2 pp 80 - 84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e372a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e376" publication-type="other">
Paulson, Jo. Ann (1984). "The Structure and Development of Financial Markets in Kenya. An Example of Agricul-
tural Finance Corporation". An Unpublished PhD Dissertation, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e387a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e391" publication-type="other">
Rukandema, F.M. (1978). "Resource Availability, Utilization and Productivity on Small-Scale Farms in Kakame-
ga District, Western Kenya". An Unpublished PhD Dissertation, Cornell University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e401a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e405" publication-type="other">
World Bank, (1982). Agricultural Credit Sector Policy Analysis. Washington DC. pp 21 - 36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
