<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">reviespafinacont</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50009991</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administarción de Empresas</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02102412</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23320753</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26597706</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The differential effect of revenue rises and cost savings on investors' valuation of growth options. Evidence from a comparative case in the electricity business / El efecto diferencial de los aumentos de ingresos y los ahorros de costes en la valoración de las opciones de crecimiento por parte de los inversores. Evidencia aportada por un caso comparativo en el sector eléctrico</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bonis</surname>
                  <given-names>Susana Alonso</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universidad de Valladolid</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Palenzuela</surname>
                  <given-names>Valentín Azofra</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universidad de Valladolid</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>de la Fuente Herrero</surname>
                  <given-names>Gabriel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universidad de Valladolid</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>July-September 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>42</volume>
         <issue>159</issue>
         <issue-id>e26597697</issue-id>
         <fpage>319</fpage>
         <lpage>340</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2001 Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administración de Empresas</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26597706"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper seeks to analyze the way investors consider growth option values when pricing equity. To achieve this objective we study the effect on stock prices of a comparative case of direct foreign investment involving acquisition of two different growth options, whose valuation has already been well-documented in prior literature. The case consists of the two sequential investment stages carried out in the Chilean group Enersis by the Spanish electricity company Endesa in the second half of the 1990s. The effect of growth option values on investors' expectations is analyzed on the basis of the abnormal returns in the period around the time of the investment announcement. Our results show that a growth option which value comes from future rise in sales has a greater impact on stock returns than that of a growth option whose value is based on cost savings.</p>
         </abstract>
         <abstract xml:lang="spa">
            <p>En este trabajo se analiza la forma en que los inversores consideran los valores de las opciones de crecimiento al establecer los precios de las acciones. Para conseguir este objetivo estudiamos el efecto en los precios de los títulos de un caso comparativo de inversión directa en el extranjero, que implica la adquisición de dos opciones de crecimiento diferentes, cuya valoración está bien documentada en la literatura previa. El caso se refiere a las dos etapas secuenciales de la inversión llevada a cabo por la eléctrica española Endesa en el grupo chileno Enersis, en la segunda mitad de los años 90. Se analiza el efecto de los valores de la opción de crecimiento en las expectativas de los inversores sobre la base de las rentabilidades anormales en el intervalo de tiempo alrededor del anuncio de inversión. Nuestros resultados muestran que una opción de crecimiento cuyo valor procede de los futuros incrementos de los ingresos tiene un impacto mayor en las rentabilidades de los títulos que la opción cuyo valor se basa en los ahorros de costes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS</label> 
            <kwd>Real options</kwd> 
            <kwd>Corporate valuation</kwd> 
            <kwd>Abnormal returns</kwd> 
            <kwd>Case study</kwd> 
            <kwd>Capital budgeting</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>PALABRAS CLAVE</label> 
            <kwd>Opciones reales</kwd> 
            <kwd>Valoración de empresas</kwd> 
            <kwd>Rentabilidades anormales</kwd> 
            <kwd>Estudio de casos</kwd> 
            <kwd>Presupuesto de capital</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkas, N.; de Bodt, E., and Roll, R. 2007. Is European M&amp;A regulation protectionist?. The Economic Journal 117: 1,096-1,121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albertí, M.; León A., and Llobet G. 2003. Evaluation of a taxi sector reform: A real options approach. CEMFI Working Paper, n.º 2003_0312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alessandri, T.M.; Lander, D.M., and Bettis, R.A. 2007. Strategic implications of valuation: Evidence from valuing growth options. In: Reuer, J. J., and Tong, T. W. (eds.), Real Options Theory, Advances in Strategic Management 24: 459-484.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alonso, S.; Azofra, V., and De la Fuente, G. 2009a. Las opciones reales en el sector eléctrico. El caso de la expansión de Endesa en Latinoamérica. Cuadernos de Economía y Dirección de Empresas 38: 65-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alonso, S.; Azofra, V., and De la Fuente, G. 2009b. The value of Real Options: The case of Endesa's takeover of Enersis. Journal of Finance Case and Research 10 (1): 1-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alonso, S.; Azofra, V., and De la Fuente, G. 2005. Real options as a component of the market value of stocks: Evidence from the Spanish Stock Market. Applied Economics 37 (14): 1,673-1,691.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alonso, S.; Azofra, V., and De la Fuente, G. 2006. The real options component of fi rm market value: The case of the technological corporation. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting 33 (1&amp;2): 133-149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold, M., and Parker, D. 2007. UK Competition policy and shareholder value: The impact of merger inquiries. British Journal of Management 18: 27-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Azofra, V.; De la Fuente, G., and Fortuna, J. M. 2004. Las opciones reales en la industria de componentes del automóvil: una aplicación a la valoración de una inversión directa en el exterior. Cuadernos de Economía y Dirección de Empresas 18: 97-120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berger, P. G. 2003. Discussion of differential market reactions to revenue and expense surprises. Review of Accounting Studies 8: 213-220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berger, P.G.; Ofek, E., and Swary, I. 1996. Investor valuation of the abandonment option. Journal of Financial Economics 42: 257-287.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Binder, J. 1998. The Event Study Methodology Since 1969. Review of Quantitative Finance and Accounting 11: 111-137</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell, J.Y.; Lo, A., and MacKinlay, A. C. 1997. The econometrics of fi nancial markets. Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cox, A., and Portes, J. 1998. Mergers in regulated industries: The uses and abuses of event studies. Journal of Regulatory Economics 14 281-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Danbolt, J.; Hirst, I., and Jones, E. 2002. Measuring Growth Opportunities. Applied Financial Economics 12: 203-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eckbo, E., and Wier, P. 1985. Antimerger Policy under the hart-scott-rodino act: A reexamination of the market power hypothesis. Journal of Law and Economics 28 (1): 119-149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ertimur, Y.; Livnat, J., and Martikainen, M. 2003. Differential market reactions to revenue and expense surprises. Review of Accounting Studies 8: 185-211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fama, E.; Fisher, L.; Jensen M., and Roll, R. 1969. The adjustment of stock prices to new information. International Economic Review 10: 1-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forbes, W. 1994. The shareholder wealth effects of MMC decisions. Journal of Business Finance and Accounting 21: 763-790.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gervais, S. 2010. Capital Budgeting and Other Investments Decisions. In Behavioral Finance, H. Kent Baker and John Nofsinger, eds. (Hoboken:Wiley).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hou, K.; Peng, W. and Xiong, L., 2006. R2 Return and Price Ineffi ciency, Fisher College of Business Working Paper No. 2006-03-007. Charles A. Dice Center Working Paper No. 2006-23. Available at SSRN: http://ssrn.com/abstract=954559 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.954559 (accesed 1 July 2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kellog, D., and Charnes, J. M. 2000. Real-options valuation for a biotechnology company. Financial Analysts Journal 56: 76-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kester, W. C. 1984. Today's options for tomorrow's growth. Harvard Business Review 62 (2): 153-160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">León, A., and Piñeiro, D. 2004. Valuation of a Biotech Company: a Real Options Approach, Revista Bolsa de Madrid 133: 66-68. The extended version of this work can be found in CEMFI Working Paper Nº 2004-0420.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Longstaff, F. A., and Schwartz, E. S. 2001. Valuing American options by simulation: A simple leastsquares approach. Review of Financial Studies 14 (1): 113-147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MacKinlay, A. 1997. Event Studies in Economics and Finance. Journal of Economic Literature 35: 13-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Micalizzi, A. 1999. The fl exibility for discontinuing product development and market expansion: The Glaxo Wellcome Case. In Trigeorgis, L. (ed.): Real options and Business Strategy: Applications to decision making, Risk Books, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oxera 2006. Blocking the deal: How do merger decisions affect share prices? Agenda, March 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rocha, K.; Salles, L.; Augusto, F.; Sandinha, J. A., and Teixeira, J. P. 2007. Real estate and real options. A case study. Emerging Markets Review 8 (1): 67-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rubio, G., and Lamothe, P. 2006. Real Options in biotechnological fi rms valuation. An empirical analysis of European fi rms, Journal of Technology Management &amp; Innovation, 1, 2: 27-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sáenz-Diez, R.; Gimeno, R., and Abajo, C. 2008. Real options valuation: A case study of an E-commerce Company. Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 20 (2): 129-143</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sick, G. 1989. Capital budgeting with real options. Monograph Series in Finance and Economics n.º 3, Salomon Brothers Center for the Study of Financial Institutions, New York University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stark, A. 2001. DixPin Biotech Plc. A Simple example of a binary option. In Howell, S. (ed.): Real Options, Evaluating Corporate Investment Opportunities in a Dynamic World, Financial Times-Prentice Hall, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trillas, F. 2001. The takeover of Enersis: the control of privatized utilities. Utilities Policy 10: 25-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swaminathan, S., and Weintrop, J. 1991. The Information Content of Earnings, Revenues, and Expenses. Journal of Accounting Research 24 (supplement): 165-200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
