<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23027452</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE IMPACT OF SPECIALISED SMALL-HOLDER CREDIT PROGRAMMES ON FARMER-BENEFICIARIES: A CASE STUDY OF THE FIRST BANK OF NIGERIA COMMUNITY LOAN SCHEME IN OYO STATE OF NIGERIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Osuntogun</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>B.O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Oramah</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>J.O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Olusi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23027445</issue-id>
         <fpage>75</fpage>
         <lpage>87</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23027452"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This study attempted an evaluation of a smallholder loans scheme on farmer beneficiaries. Seventy-one farmer beneficiaries in Ilesa and Obokun Local Government Areas of Oyo State Nigeria were interviewed between September, 1988 and January, 1989 using a structured questionnaire. Results indicate that the credit programme probably increased farm income and the use of labour and modern technology inputs. However, the programme seems to have increased capital intensity in the production process. Another consequence of the project appears to be increased commercialisation of agriculture in the area. Cette étude tente d'évaluer un programme de prêts accordés à des petits agriculteurs. Soixante-et-onze agriculteurs bénéficiaires de ces prêts dans les zones des gouvernements locaux de Ilesa et Obokun (Etat d'Oyo au Nigeria) ont été interviewés entre septembre 1988 et janvier 1989 en utilisant un questionnaire detaillé. Les résultats indiquent que le programme de crédit a augmenté le revenu et l'emploi en même temps que les instruments de technologie moderne. Toutefois le programme semble avoir augmenté l'intensité du capital dans le processus de production. Une autre conséquence de ce projet semble être une commercialisation accélerée de l'agriculture dans cette région.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>Footnotes</title>
         <ref id="d22e159a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d22e166" publication-type="other">
5th annual conference of the Farm Management Association of Nigeria
held in the University of Agriculture, Abeokuta, Nigeria in September, 1966.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d22e185a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e189" publication-type="other">
Adeyeye, V.A. (1989): Health and Nutrition Factors in Labour Productivity amongst Tobacco and Non-tobacco
Farmers in Oyo State, Nigeria, Niser Monograph series, No. 7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e199a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e203" publication-type="other">
Batterham, R.L. and A.A. Majid (1987): "The Demand for seasonal credit under conditions of risk: A case study
in Bangladesh". Savings and Development Vol XI, No. 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e213a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e217" publication-type="other">
Braun, J.V.D. Hotchkiss and M. Immink (1989): Non Traditional Export Crops in Guatemala: Effects on Produc-
tion, Income and Nutrition. Research Report 73, International Food Policy Research Institute, Washington
D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e230a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e234" publication-type="other">
CBN (1988): Annual Report and Statement of Account for the Year Ended December, 1987. Central Bank of
Nigeria, Lagos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e245a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e249" publication-type="other">
Kennedy, E (1989): The Effects of Sugarcane Production on Food Security, Health and Nutrition in Kenya: A
Longitudinal Analysis. Research Report 78, International Food Policy Research Institute, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e259a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e263" publication-type="other">
Kennedy, E.T. and B Cogill (1987): Income and Nutritional Effects of the Commercialisation of Agriculture in
Southwestern Kenya. Research Report 63, International Food Policy Research Institute Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e273a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e277" publication-type="other">
Koutsoyiannis (1977): Econometrics McMillan Book Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e284a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e288" publication-type="other">
Oramah; B.O. (1991): "An Evaluation of Economic Impact of Irrigation Projects in the Lower Anambra River
Basin on the Farming Community". Unpublished Ph.D thesis, Dept. of Agric. Economics, Obafemi Awolowo
University, lie - Ife, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e305" publication-type="other">
Osuntogun; C.A. (1983): Cooperatives and Nigeria's Agricultural Development. Inaugural Lecture Series, Obafemi
Awolowo University, lie - Ife.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d22e315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d22e319" publication-type="other">
Shultz; T.W. (1964): Transforming Traditional Agriculture, New Haven.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
