<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830170</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830172</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CROP AND LIVESTOCK INSURANCE SCHEMES IN LESS DEVELOPED COUNTRIES: SOME ISSUES OF DESIGN / LES SCHÉMAS D'ASSURANCE DANS LE SECTEUR DE L'ÉLEVAGE ET DES CULTURES MARCHANDES: PROBLÈMES D'ENCADREMENT DANS LES PAYS EN VOIE DE DÉVELOPPEMENT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
                  <surname>Mosley</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>21</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830172"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Recent literature has expressed considerable pessimism about the practical feasibility of reducing risks for small Third World farmers by means of agricultural insurance schemes, and argued that such schemes, if implemented, should confine themselves to insurance against acts of God such as hail and hurricane damage. This paper argues, on the basis of an empirical examination of the costs and benefits of a number of insurance schemes, that this pessimism is overdone, and that the extension of insurance beyond mere acts of God to cover breakdown or loss of capital assets and non-repayment of loans to agricultural banks might well compensate for the extra costs involved. However, to work well such schemes need to be compulsory, to be properly reinsured and to be integrated with existing schemes of agricultural credit and extension, since the functions of technical advice, loan supervision and checking of insurance claims can with advantage be seen as part of the same job. The agency which provides insurance need not be, and ideally should not, be part of the state apparatus; but the collaboration of the state as lawmaker, loan guarantor and provider of complementary services will be necessary at all times. Les analyses récentes sont assez pessimistes quant'à la possibilité concrète des pays du Tiers Monde de réduire le risque pour les exploitations agricoles de petite dimension qui recourent au système des assurances. Ces assurances, même si faisables, devraient se limiter à des phénomènes spéciaux qui ne sont pas contrôlables par l'homme comme, par exemple, le risque de grêle et d'orage. Sur la base d'une analyse empirique des coûts et des bénéfices de nombreux schémas d'assurance, cet article arrive à la conclusion que le pessimisme n'est pas justifié. On peut élargir le cadre des assurances bien au de là des phénomènes non contrôlables par l'homme comme dans le cas de perte de capital ou de non remboursement de prêts aux banques agricoles. Dans ce cas, les bénéfices d'un recours à l'assurance dépasseront de loin les coûts supplémentaires. Toutefois, pour assurer l'efficacité des schémas d'assurance, il est nécessaire de les rendre obligatoires, de les réassurer de façon adéquate et de les intégrer dans le contexte des systèmes de crédit agricole. De cette façon, plusieurs activités (conseil technique, supervision des prêts et contrôle des demandes de dommages) peuvent être très utilement concentrées et beaucoup plus efficacement effectuées. Les compagnies d'assurance ne doivent pas normalement (et du point de vue théorique ne devraient jamais) être rattachées aux organismes étatiques. Toutefois, la collaboration avec les pouvoirs publics (comme pouvoir législatif, comme garants de prêts et comme fournisseurs de services complémentaires) est indispensable à chaque étape de leurs activités.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d29e144a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e151" publication-type="other">
Hazell
et ai (1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e161a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e168" publication-type="other">
Weeks (1971)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e174" publication-type="other">
Binswanger and Sillers (1983), table 2, p 8</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e181a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e188" publication-type="other">
Eg Ahsan (1985), p 12</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e195a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e202" publication-type="other">
Hazell et al. 1986: 154</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e210a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e217" publication-type="other">
Hazell et al.: 244</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e224a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e231" publication-type="other">
Hazell et al. 1986: 266</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e238a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e245" publication-type="other">
Mosley 1986: 316</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e252a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e259" publication-type="other">
Ahsan (1985: 141).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d29e275a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e279" publication-type="other">
Ahsan, Syed M 1985 Agricultural insurance: a new policy for developing countries, Aldershot: Glower Publishers</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e290" publication-type="other">
Ajayi, G A, O L Oludimu and S A Oni 1986 «A financial appraisal of the Nigerian Agricultural Credit Guarantee
Scheme Fund*, International Journal of Development Banking, Vol. 4, No 2 (July 1986), 13-20</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e304" publication-type="other">
Binswanger, Hans P and Donald A Sillers 1983 «Risk aversion and credit constraints in farmers' decision-making:
a reinterpretation*, Journal of Development Studies, Vol. 20 (1983), 5-20</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e318" publication-type="other">
Commonwealth Secretariat 1982 Report of the workshop on poverty-focussed rural development and small farm
credit, Comilla, Bangladesh, 2 vols.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e333" publication-type="other">
Hazell, Peter, Carlos Pomareda and Alberto Valdes 1986 Crop insurance for agricultural development: issues
and experience, Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e343a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e347" publication-type="other">
Mosley, Paul 1986 «Risk, insurance and small farm credit in developing countries*, Public Administration and
Development, Vol 6, 309-319.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e357a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e361" publication-type="other">
Mosley, Paul and Dahal, Rudra Prasad 1987 «Credit for the poorest: a comparison of two policy experiments
in Nepal and Bangladesh*, Manchester Papers on Development, Vol 3, No 2, pp 45-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e375" publication-type="other">
Okorie, A 1987 ^Agricultural insurance in Nigeria: mirage or reality*, Development Policy Review, Vol 5, No 2
(June), 149-165</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e385a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e389" publication-type="other">
Pauly, M V1974 «Overinsurance and public provision of insurance: the roles of moral hazard and adverse selec-
tion*, Quarterly Journal of Economics Vol 88, pp 44-62</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e403" publication-type="other">
Rothschild, M and Stiglitz, J 1976, "Equilibrium in competitive insurance markets: an essay on the economics
of imperfect imformation*, Quarterly Journal of Economics, Vol 90, 629-649</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e414a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e418" publication-type="other">
Sanderatne, Nimal 1986 «The political economy of small farmer loan delinquency*, Savings and Development,
No 4, 343-354</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e428a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e432" publication-type="other">
Scikovsky, T 1954, «Two concepts of external economics*, Journal of Political Economy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e443" publication-type="other">
von Pischke, J D 1983 «The pitfalls of specialised farm credit institutions in low income countries*. In J D von
Pischke, Dale W Adams and Gordon Donald (eds) Rural financial markets in developing countries,
Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press for World Bank Economic Development Institute</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e456a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e460" publication-type="other">
Weeks, John 1971 Uncertainty*, risk and wealth and income distribution in peasant agriculture*, Journal of
Development Studies, vol 7</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e470a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e474" publication-type="other">
World Bank 1975 Agricultural credit: sector policy paper, Washington DC: World Bank</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


