<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794431</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>The Efficacy of State and Local Fiscal Policy in Promoting Economic Growth</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Temporal and Spatial Effects of State Taxes on Economic Growth</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Anderson</surname>
                  <given-names>John E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bernard</surname>
                  <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>22</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794431"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In this paper we estimate the relationship between the economic growth of states and taxes, modeling both the effects of states own taxes on growth over time and the fiscal spillover effects of taxes in neighboring states on their economic growth. Our research goes beyond the usual temporal tax-growth analysis in the literature to incorporate spatial spillovers. Using annual data for the states over the period 1999-2013 our estimation strategy divides the data into five-year periods to analyze the effect of both differences and levels of state taxes on state gross state product (GSP) growth. We specify a state production function for output and derive estimating equations that are empirically estimable. Our analysis includes consideration of each of the major state tax revenue sources: income (both personal and corporate), property, and sales taxes. While some previous studies have found strong inverse relationships between state taxes and economic growth, our results indicate that the temporal tax-growth relationship is sensitive to model specification and the time period of analysis. We extend the model to include spatial spillover effects using a spatial Durbin model in order to determine how neighboring states taxes may affect a states economic growth. Our results indicate that negative spillover effects are present in some cases, which we analyze for policy implications.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abreu, M., De Groot, H. L. and Florax, R. J. (2004), Space and growth: a survey of empirical evidence and methods, Technical report, Tinbergen Institute Working Paper No. TI 04-123/3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Anselin, L. (1988), ‘Model validation in spatial econometrics: a review and evaluation of alternative approaches’, International Regional Science Review 11(3), 279-316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Atems, B. (2015), ‘Another look at tax policy and state economic growth: The long-run and short-run of it’, Economics Letters 127, 64-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Belotti, F., Hughes, G. and Piano Mortari, A. (2016), ‘Spatial panel data models using stata’.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bureau of Economic Analysis (2015), ‘National economic accounts, Table 3.1ES Current-Cost Net Stock of Private Fixed Assets by Industry’, U.S. Department of Commerce.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Döring, T. and Schnellenbach, J. (2006), ‘What do we know about geographical knowledge spillovers and regional growth?: A survey of the literature’, Regional Studies 40(03), 375-395.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Elhorst, J. P. (2010), ‘Applied spatial econometrics: raising the bar’, Spatial Economic Analysis 5(1), 9-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Elhorst, J. P. (2017), ‘Spatial Panel Data Analysis’, pp. 2050-2058. URL: https://spatial-panels.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Elhorst-Spatial-Panel-Data-Analysis-Encyclopedia-GIS-2nd-ed-Working-Paper-Version.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Gale, W. G., Krupkin, A. and Rueben, K. (2015), ‘The relationship between taxes and growth at the state level: New evidence’, National Tax Journal68(4), 919-942.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Garofalo, G. A. and Yamarik, S. (2002), ‘Regional convergence: Evidence from a new state-by-state capital stock series’, Review of Economics and Statistics 84(2), 316323.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Garrett, T. A., Wagner, G. A. and Wheelock, D. C. (2005), Regional Disparities in the Spatial Correlation of State Income Growth, Technical report, The Federal Reserve Bank of St Louis. URL: http://research.stlouisfed.org/wp/2005/2005-061.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Goff, B., Lebedinsky, A. and Lile, S. (2012), ‘A matched pairs analysis of state growth differences’, Contemporary Economic Policy 30(2), 293-305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Kao, Y.-H. and Bera, A. K. (2013), Spatial regression: The curious case of negative spatial dependence, in ‘VII World Conference of The Spatial Econometric Association’.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Kopczewska, K., Kudla, J. and Walczyk, K. (2017), ‘Strategy of Spatial Panel Estimation: Spatial Spillovers Between Taxation and Economic Growth’, Applied Spatial Analysis and Policy 10(1), 77-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">LeSage, J. P. and Fischer, M. M. (2008), ‘Spatial growth regressions: Model specification, estimation and interpretation’, Spatial Economic Analysis 3(3), 275-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">LeSage, J. and Pace, R. K. (2009), Introduction to Spatial Econometrics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Ljungqvist, A. and Smolyansky, M. (2014), ‘To cut or not to cut? on the impact of corporate taxes on employment and income’, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Mazerov, M. (2013), ‘Academic research lacks consensus on the impact of state tax cuts on economic growth’, Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, June 17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">McBride, W. (2012), ‘What is the evidence on taxes and growth?’, Tax Foundation 207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Ojede, A. and Yamarik, S. (2012), ‘Tax policy and state economic growth: The long-run and short-run of it’, Economics Letters 116(2), 161-165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Reed, W. R. (2008), ‘The robust relationship between taxes and us state income growth’, National Tax Journal pp. 57-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Reed, W. R. (2009), ‘The determinants of us state economic growth: A less extreme bounds analysis’, Economic Inquiry 47(4), 685-700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Reed, W. R. and Rogers, C. L. (2004), ‘Tax cuts and employment in new jersey: Lessons from a regional analysis’, Public Finance Review 32(3), 269-291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Segura, J. (2017), ‘The effect of state and local taxes on economic growth: A spatial dynamic panel approach’, Papers in Regional Science 96(3), 627-645. URL: http://doi.wiley.com/10.1111/pirs.12221</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">U.S. Census Bureau (2010), ‘Centers of population by state’, https://www.census.gov/geo/reference/centersofpop.html. (accessed March 27, 2017).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Wasylenko, M. (1999), ‘Taxation and economic development: The state of the economic literature’, Public Administration and Public Policy 72, 309-328.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Yu, J., De Jong, R. and Lee, L.-f. (2008), ‘Quasi-maximum likelihood estimators for spatial dynamic panel data with fixed effects when both n and t are large’, Journal of Econometrics 146(1), 118-134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Regression Results – Non-Spatial Panel</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Spatial Effects – Total Tax Burden</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Spatial Effects – Decomposed Tax Burden</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Clustering of 5-year differences in growth throughout the US.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>List of Control Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Global spatial autocorrelation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Summary of Spatial Weight Matrices</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8 :</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Tests for Specification Issues</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
