<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000451</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008410</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Lexicon for Knowledge-Based MT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Boyan</given-names>
                  <surname>Onyshkevich</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Sergei</given-names>
                  <surname>Nirenburg</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>57</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1995 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008410"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>In knowledge-based machine translation (KBMT), the lexicon can be specified and acquired only in close connection with the specification and acquisition of the world model (ontology) and the specification of the text meaning representation (interlingua) language. The former supplies the atoms for the specification of text meaning and provides world knowledge to support the inference processes necessary for a variety of disambiguation and meaning assignment operations. The latter is necessary for the formulation of the semantic zone of the lexicon entries, which can be viewed as containing the static building blocks of the text meaning representation. This is the view taken in the Mikrokosmos KBMT project.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>knowledge-based machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>lexicon</kwd>
            <kwd>semantic analysis</kwd>
            <kwd>ontology</kwd>
            <kwd>text meaning representation</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d908456e208a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e212" publication-type="other">
Apresjan, Y.D. 1974. Regular Polysemy. Linguistics, 142:5-32.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e219a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e223" publication-type="other">
Bresnan, J., editor. 1982. The Mental Representation of Grammatical Relations.
MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e233a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e237" publication-type="other">
Brown, R. 1994. FRAMEPAC. Technical report, Center for Machine Translation,
Carnegie Mellon University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e247a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e251" publication-type="other">
Carbonell, J., T. Mitamura, and E. Nyberg. 1992. The KANT Perspective: A Cri-
tique of Pure Transfer (and Pure Interlingua, Pure Statistics, ...). In Proceedings
of the Fourth International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues
in Machine Translation, Montreal.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e268a1310">
               
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e274" publication-type="other">
Carlson, L., E. Cooper, R. Dolan, and S. Maiorano. 1994. Representing Text
Meaning for Multilingual Knowledge- Based Machine Translation. In Proceedings
of the First AMTA Conference, Columbia, MD.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e287a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e291" publication-type="other">
Carlson, L. and S. Nirenburg. 1990. World Modeling for NLP. Technical Report
CMU-CMT-90-121, Center for Machine Translation, Carnegie Mellon University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e301a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e305" publication-type="other">
Cullingford, R. and B. Onyshkevych. 1987. An Experiment in Lexicon-Driven
Machine Translation. In S. Nirenburg, editor, Machine Translation: Theoretical
and Methodological Issues. Cambridge University Press, New York.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e318a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e322" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B.J. 1993. Machine Translation: A View from the Lexicon. MIT Press,
Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e332a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e336" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B.J. and C.R. Voss. 1993. Machine Translation of Spatial Expressions:
Defining the Relation between an Interlingua and a Knowledge Representation
System. In Proceedings of Twelfth Conference of the American Association for
Artificial Intelligence, pages 374-379, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e352a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e356" publication-type="other">
Farwell, D., L. Guthrie, and Y. Wilks. 1993. Automatically Creating Lexical
Entries for ULTRA, a Multilingual MT System. Machine Translation, 8(3): 127-
146.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e370a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e374" publication-type="other">
Hobbs, J. 1985. Ontological Promiscuity. In Proceedings of the 23rd Annual
Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e384a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e388" publication-type="other">
Hovy, E. 1988. Generating Natural Language under Pragmatic Constraints. Ph.D.
thesis, Yale University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e398a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e402" publication-type="other">
Hovy, E., J. Lavid, E. Maier, V. Mittal, and C. Paris. 1992. Employing Knowledge
Resources in a New Text Planner. In Dale, Hovy, Rosner, and Stock, editors,
Aspects of Automated NL Generation. Springer Verlag, Heidelberg. Lecture Notes
in AI no. 587.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e418a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e422" publication-type="other">
Hovy, E. and E. Maier. 1993. Parsimonious or Profligate: How Many and Which
Discourse Structure Relations? Discourse Processes, to appear.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e432a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e436" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, R., editor. 1983. Semantics and Cognition. MIT Press, Cambridge,
MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e446a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e450" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, R., editor. 1990. Semantic Structures. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e458a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e462" publication-type="other">
Kamp, H. 1981. A Theory of Truth and Semantic Representation. In J. Groenedijk,
J. Janssen, and M. Stokhof, editors, Formal Methods in the Study of Language.
Mathematical Center Tracts, Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e475a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e479" publication-type="other">
Levin, B. 1989. English Verbal Diathesis. Technical Report Lexicon Project Work-
ing Papers #32, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e489a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e493" publication-type="other">
Levin, B. 1991. Building a Lexicon: The Contribution of Linguistics. International
Journal of Lexicography, 4(3):205-226.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e503a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e507" publication-type="other">
Levin, L. and S. Nirenburg. 1994. Construction-Based MT Lexicons. In A. Zam-
polli, N. Calzolari, and M. Palmer, editors, Current Issues in Computational
Linguistics: In Honour of Don Walker. Kluwer Academic and Giardini Editori E
Stampatori in Pisa.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e523a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e527" publication-type="other">
McDermott, D. 1978. Tarskian Semantics, or No Notation Without Denotation!
Cognitive Science, 2(3).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e537a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e541" publication-type="other">
Mel'chuk, I. 1984. Explanatory Combinatorial Dictionary of Modern Russian (in
Russian). Wiener Slawistischer Almanach, Vienna.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e552a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e556" publication-type="other">
Mitamura, T. 1990. The Hierarchical Organization of Predicate Frames for In-
terpretive Mapping in Natural Language Processing. Ph.D. thesis, Center for
Machine Translation, Carnegie Mellon University. CMU-CMT-90-117.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e569a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e573" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S., J. Carbonell, M. Tomita, and K. Goodman, editors. 1992. Machine
Translation: A Knowledge-Based Approach. Morgan Kaufmann Publishers, San
Mateo, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e586a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e590" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S. and C. Defrise. 1991. Practical Computational Linguistics. In
R. Johnson and M. Rosner, editors, Computational Linguistics and Formal Se-
mantics. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e603a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e607" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S. and K. Goodman. 1990. Treatment of Meaning in MT Systems.
In Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Theoretical and Method-
ological Issues in Machine Translation of Natural Language, Linguistic Research
Center, University of Texas at Austin.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e623a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e627" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S. and L. Levin. 1992. Syntax-Driven and Ontology-Driven Lexical
Semantics. In J. Pustejovsky, editor, Lexical Semantics and Knowledge Repre-
sentation. Springer Verlag, Heidelberg.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e640a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e644" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S., V. Raskin, and A. Tucker. 1987. The Structure of Interlingua in
TRANSLATOR. In S. Nirenburg, editor, Machine Translation: Theoretical and
Methodological Issues. Cambridge University Press, New York.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e658a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e662" publication-type="other">
Nyberg, E. 1988. The FRAMEKIT User's Guide, Version 2.0. Technical Report
CMU-CMT-MEMO, Center for Machine Translation, Carnegie Mellon University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e672a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e676" publication-type="other">
Nyberg, E. and T. Mitamura. 1992. The KANT System: Fast, Accurate, High-
Quality Translation in Practical Domains. In Proceedings of COLING-92, Trento.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e686a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e690" publication-type="other">
Ostler, N. and B.T.S. Atkins. 1992. Predictable Meaning Shift: Some Linguis-
tic Properties of Lexical Implication Rules. In J. Pustejovsky, editor, Lexical
Semantics and Knowledge Representation. Springer Verlag, Heidelberg.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e703a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e707" publication-type="other">
Pustejovsky, J. 1991. The Generative Lexicon. Computational Linguistics, 17(4).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e714a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e718" publication-type="other">
Schank, R. 1973. Identification of Conceptualizations Underlying Natural Lan-
guage. In R. Schank and K. Colby, editors, Computer Models of Thought and
Language. W.H. Freeman Co, San Francisco, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e731a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e735" publication-type="other">
Small, S. and C. Rieger. 1982. Parsing and Comprehending with Word Experts
(A Theory and Its Realization). In W. Lehnert and M. Ringle, editors, Strategies
for Natural Language Processing. Lawrence Earlbaum Associates, Hillsdale, NJ.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e749a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e753" publication-type="other">
Tulving, E. 1985. How Many Memories Are There? American Psychologist,
40:385-398.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e763a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e767" publication-type="other">
Voss, C.R. and B.J. Dorr. 1995. Toward a Lexicalized Grammar for Interlinguas.
Machine Translation, 9(3-4).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e777a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e781" publication-type="other">
Wilks, Y. 1973. An Artificial Intelligence Approach to Machine Translation. In
R. Schank and K. Colby, editors, Computer Models of Thought and Language.
W.H. Freeman Co., San Francisco, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e794a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e798" publication-type="other">
Wilks, Y. 1975. Preference Semantics. In E.L. Keenan, editor, Formal Semantics
of Natural Language. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908456e808a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e812" publication-type="other">
Wilks, Y. 1992. Review of Ray Jackendoff's Semantic Structures. Computational
Linguistics, 18(l):95-97.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d908456e831a1310">
               <label>2</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908456e838" publication-type="other">
(Nirenburg et al., 1992).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
