<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440134</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Economic Cost of Growing Up Poor: Estimating the GDP Loss Associated with Child Poverty</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Jo</given-names>
                  <surname>Blanden</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Kirstine</given-names>
                  <surname>Hansen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Stephen</given-names>
                  <surname>Machin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">31</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440131</issue-id>
         <fpage>289</fpage>
         <lpage>311</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyritht © 2010 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440134"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>One of the motivations for the UK government's target to reduce (and eventually eliminate) child poverty is the perception of a significant long-term economic cost of growing up in poverty. This perception arises from the observation that individuals who experience poverty in their childhood earn less as adults, are less likely to be in employment, are more likely to engage in criminal or anti-social activities and are more likely to experience poor health and lower life satisfaction. This paper quantifies these effects, and expresses them in terms of GDP losses to the nation. We begin by focusing on lost earnings that arise from poorer skills and reduced employment opportunities, and then move on to the wider costs associated with the higher crime rates, poorer health and reduced well-being that are linked with growing up poor. We find a sizeable economic cost, with the cost of growing up in poverty amounting to at least 1 per cent of GDP.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d50e229a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e236" publication-type="other">
Submitted September 2009.
This paper emanated from research funded by the Joseph Rowntree Foundation as part of its
■Estimating the Costs of Child Poverty' project. The authors would like to thank Donald Hirsch for
helpful comments on the original working paper and an Editor and referees for many useful suggestions.
They are also grateful to Mike Brewer of the Institute for Fiscal Studies for providing data on child
poverty rates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e259a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e266" publication-type="other">
See HM Treasury (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e273a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e280" publication-type="other">
See Brewer et al. (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e287a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e294" publication-type="other">
See HM Treasury (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e302a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e309" publication-type="other">
Holzer et al. obtain their figures by manipulating estimates of the impact of poverty from existing
studies, insisting throughout that they take a 'conservative' approach. We believe our methodology is
more transparent; using original analysis enables us to better reveal the impact of different assumptions
on the aggregate figures.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e325a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e332" publication-type="other">
The 'less than £100 a week' cut-off is chosen for simplicity as it corresponds to the bottom two
categories of the income variable contained in the survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e342a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e349" publication-type="other">
This is in large part because there are few categories to choose from in the age 10 income question, so
it is difficult to get a good definition of poverty.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e359a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e366" publication-type="other">
There may be some concern that the poverty rate for 16-year-olds will differ from the rate for all
children. Investigation of the Family Expenditure Survey indicates that this problem is not too severe as
the poverty rate for 14- to 16-year-olds is 18.1 per cent in 1986, only a little below the overall rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e379a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e386" publication-type="other">
See Blanden and Gregg (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e393a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e400" publication-type="other">
Blanden and Gregg (2004) review and explore even more stringent tests to identify the causal impact
of parental income on children's educational attainment. One way of approaching this is to try to look at
within-family or within-individual changes in income. For example, we can look at how children's
outcomes evolve between ages 10 and 16 as the level of family income changes. If children's
performance deteriorates when their relative income position declines, then we can think of this as a
causal effect. When this approach is applied, Blanden and Gregg find that the impacts of family income
are still significant but are about one-third of the size of those where family characteristics and test scores
are controlled for. However, this approach is likely to be downward biased for two reasons: first, the
abolition of child poverty would lead to higher family incomes throughout childhood; and second, these
estimates rely on income changes which tend to include a great deal of measurement error.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e436a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e443" publication-type="other">
We have also explored these models using alternative measures of deprivation. Using the same
sample, having free school meals at age 16 has a coefficient of -0.187 in the model including test scores,
and parent reporting financial difficulties has a coefficient of -0.095. Fewer children report having free
school meals than report income of less than £100 a week.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e459a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e466" publication-type="other">
We are also unable to take account of how the impacts of poverty vary according to the length of
time poverty is experienced for. This is unavoidable given the nature of our data sources.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e476a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e483" publication-type="other">
The proportion of high-skilled workers is roughly equal to the proportion of workers with degrees in
the population, while the LS group is the proportion of workers growing up in poverty (assuming current
rates).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e496a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e503" publication-type="other">
The elasticity of substitution is estimated for those leaving school at 18 or below compared with
those leaving school at 19 or above.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e513a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e520" publication-type="other">
A third scenario is also possible where not all the LS workers are transformed; this would again limit
the increase in GDP that would result from ending child poverty - see Blanden, Hansen and Machin
(2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e533a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e540" publication-type="other">
Calculated as 0.071x3.3x£24,668x5.4m = £31 billion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e548a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e555" publication-type="other">
See, among others, Layard, Mayraz and Nickell (2008), who relate life satisfaction to income and
find that a 1-log-point increase in income increases happiness by 0.52 points on a 0-10 scale. This
coefficient is the mean of those reported in table 3 of Layard et al., which includes estimates from a
variety of studies and approaches. The estimates range from 0.25 to 0.7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e571a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e578" publication-type="other">
Results for regressions based on life satisfaction at age 29/30 are strikingly similar, and imply a slight
increase of the effect of child poverty on well-being as individuals age.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d50e597a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e601" publication-type="other">
Belfield, C. R., Nores, M., Barnett, S. and Schweinhart, L. (2006), 'The High/Scope Perry
Preschool Program: cost-benefit analysis using data from the age-40 followup', Journal of
Human Resources, vol. 41, pp. 162-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e614a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e618" publication-type="other">
Blanden, J. (2006), "'Bucking the trend": what enables those who are disadvantaged in
childhood to succeed in later life?', Department for Work and Pensions, Working Paper
no. 31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e631a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e635" publication-type="other">
— and Gibbons, S. (2006), The Persistence of Poverty: A View from Two British Cohorts,
Joseph Rowntree Report, Bristol: Policy Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e645a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e649" publication-type="other">
— and Gregg, P. (2004), 'Family income and educational attainment: a review of approaches
and evidence for Britain', Oxford Review of Economic Policy, Special Issue on Education,
vol. 20, pp. 245-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e663a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e667" publication-type="other">
—, Hansen, K. and Machin, S. (2008), The GDP Cost of the Lost Earning Potential of Adults
who Grew Up in Poverty, York: Joseph Rowntree Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e677a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e681" publication-type="other">
Blau, D. (1999), 'The effect of income on child development', Review of Economics and
Statistics, vol. 81, pp. 261-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e691a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e695" publication-type="other">
Brewer, M., Browne, J., Joyce, R. and Sutherland, H. (2009), Micro-Simulating Child Poverty
in 2010 and 2020, Commentary no. 108, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://
www.ifs.org.uk/publications/4434).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e708a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e712" publication-type="other">
—, Muriel, A., Phillips, D. and Sibieta, L. (2008), Poverty and Inequality in the UK: 2008,
Commentary no. 105, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/
publications/4258).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e725a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e729" publication-type="other">
Duncan, G., Yeung, W., Brooks-Gunn, J. and Smith, J. (1998), 'How much does childhood
poverty affect children's life chances?', American Sociological Review, vol. 63, pp. 406-
23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e742a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e746" publication-type="other">
Goodman, A., Gregg, P. and Macmillan, L. (2008), 'Intergenerational mobility and education
in the next generation: forecasting intergenerational mobility for current cohorts of
youths', University of Bristol, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e760a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e764" publication-type="other">
Haveman, R. and Wolfe, B. (1995), 'The determinants of children's attainments: a review of
methods and findings', Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 33, pp. 1829-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e774a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e778" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (2008), Ending Child Poverty: Everybody's Business, London (http://www.hm-
treasury.gov.uk/bud_bud08_child.htm).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e788a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e792" publication-type="other">
Holzer, H., Whitmore Schanzenbach, D., Duncan, G. and Ludwig, J. (2007), The Economic
Costs of Poverty in the United States : Subsequent Effects of Children Growing Up Poor,
Washington, DC: Center for American Progress.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e805a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e809" publication-type="other">
Home Office (2005), The Economic and Social Costs of Crime, Home Office Research Study
no. 217, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e819a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e823" publication-type="other">
Katz, L. and Murphy, K. (1992), 'Changes in relative wages, 1963-87: supply and demand
factors', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 107, pp. 35-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e833a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e837" publication-type="other">
Layard, R., Clark, D., Knapp, M. and Mayraz, G. (2007), 'Cost-benefit analysis of
psychological therapy', National Institute Economic Review, no. 202, pp. 90-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e848a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e852" publication-type="other">
—, Mayraz, G. and Nickell, S. (2008), 'The marginal utility of income', Journal of Public
Economics, vol. 92, pp. 1846-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e862a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e866" publication-type="other">
Manacorda, M., Manning, A. and Wadsworth, J. (2006), 'The impact of immigration on the
structure of male wages: theory and evidence from Britain', Centre for Economic
Performance (CEP), Discussion Paper no. 754.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e879a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e883" publication-type="other">
Mayer, S. (1997), What Money Can't Buy: Family Income and Children's Life Chances,
Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e893a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e897" publication-type="other">
Solon, G. (1999), 'Intergenerational mobility in the labor market', in O. Ashenfelter and D.
Card (eds), Handbook of Labor Economics, vol. 3 A, Amsterdam: North Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
