<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939360</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Optimal Tax 1</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Preference Difference, Generalized Social Marginal Welfare Weights, and the Two Approaches for Optimal Tax Theory</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>An</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhiyong</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>14</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939360"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Many reasons can result in that the government’s and individuals’ preferences differ. We make two key contributions in this paper. First, we parameterize the relationship between the preference difference and the generalized social marginal welfare weights (Saez and Stantcheva, 2016) by following the definition of the latter. Second, we use an optimal tax example with a simple preference difference to demonstrate that one can take the traditional approach for optimal tax theory (Mirrlees, 1971) to derive the optimal marginal income tax as a function of the preference difference. Our work suggests that the traditional and the new approaches for optimal tax theory, pioneered by Mirrlees (1971) and Saez and Stantcheva (2016), respectively, are essentially dual.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">An, Z., “On the Sufficiency of Using the Elasticity of Taxable Income to Calculate Deadweight Loss: The Implications of Charitable Giving and Warm Glow,” International Tax and Public Finance, 2015, 22, 1040-1047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">An, Z., “When Preferences Differ: ETI Insufficient to Calculate DWL,” Tax Notes, 2017, 155(6), 825-827.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Andreoni, J., “Giving with Impure Altruism: Applications to Charity and Ricardian Equivalence,” Journal of Political Economy, 1989, 97(6), 1447-1458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Andreoni, J., “Impure Altruism and Donations to Public Goods: A Theory of Warm-Glow Giving,” Economic Journal, 1990, 100(401), 464-477.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Andreoni, J. “Philanthropy.” In Handbook of the Economics of Giving, Altruism and Reciprocity. Edited by Serge-Christophe Kolm and Jean Mercier Ythier, 1201-1269. 2006. Amsterdam: Elsevier/North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Besley, T., “A Simple Model for Merit Good Arguments,” Journal of Public Economics, 1988, 35, 371-383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bierbrauer, F., A. Tsyvinski, and N. D. Werquin, “Taxes and Turnout,” NBER Working Paper No. 24123, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Blomquist, S., and L. Micheletto, “Optimal Redistributive Taxation when Government’s and Agents’ Preferences Differ,” Journal of Public Economics, 2006, 90(6), 1215-1233.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Chetty, R., “Is the Taxable Income Elasticity Sufficient to Calculate Deadweight Loss? The Implications of Evasion and Avoidance,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2009, 1(2), 31-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Diamond, P., “Optimal Income Taxation: An Example with a U-Shaped Pattern of Optimal Marginal Tax Rates,” American Economic Review, 1998, 88(1), 83-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Diamond, P., “Optimal Tax Treatment of Private Contributions for Public Goods with and without Warm Glow Preferences,” Journal of Public Economics, 2006, 90, 897-919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Farhi, E., and X. Gabaix, “Optimal Taxation with Behavioral Agents,” NBER Working Paper No. 21524, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Feldstein, M., “Tax Avoidance and the Deadweight Loss of the Income Tax,” Review of Economics and Statistics, 1999, 81(4), 674-680.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Gerritsen, A., “Optimal Taxation when People Do Not Maximize Well-Being,” Journal of Public Economics, 2016, 144, 122-139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Kanbur, R., J. Pirttila, and M. Tuomala, “Non-welfarist Optimal Taxation and Behavioral Public Economics,” Journal of Economic Surveys, 2006, 20(5), 849-868.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Lockwood, B. B., “Optimal Income Taxation with Present Bias,” Working Paper, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Lockwood, B. B., C. G. Nathanson, and E. G. Weyl, “Taxation and the Allocation of Talent,” Journal of Political Economy, 2017, 125(5), 1635-1682.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Mirrlees, J. A., “An Exploration in the Optimal Theory of Income Taxation,” Review of Economic Studies, 1971, 38(2), 175-208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Musgrave, R. A. The Theory of Public Finance. 1959. New York: McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">O’Donoghue, T., and M. Rabin, “Optimal Sin Taxes,” Journal of Public Economics, 2006, 90, 1825-1849.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Piketty, T., E. Saez, and S. Stantcheva, “Optimal Taxation of Top Labor Incomes: A Tale of Three Elasticities,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2014, 6(1), 230-271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Rothschild, C., and F. Scheuer, “Optimal Taxation with Rent-Seeking,” Review of Economic Studies, 2016, 83(3), 1225-1262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Saez, E., and S. Stantcheva, “Generalized Social Marginal Welfare Weights for Optimal Tax Theory,” American Economic Review, 2016, 106(1), 24-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Sandmo, A., “Ex Post Welfare Economics and the Theory of Merit Goods,” Economica, 1983, 50, 19-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Stiglitz, J. E., “Self-selection and Pareto Efficient Taxation,” Journal of Public Economics, 1982, 17(2), 213-240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Thaler, R. H., and C. R. Sunstein, “Libertarian Paternalism,” American Economic Review, 2003, 93, 175-179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Tobin, J., “On Limiting the Domain of Inequality,” Journal of Law and Economics, 1970, 13, 263-277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Weinzierl, M., “The Promise of Positive Optimal Taxation: Normative Diversity and a Role for Equal Sacrifice,” Journal of Public Economics, 2014, 118, 128-142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Preference Difference vs. GSMWW and Traditional vs. New Approach</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
