<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438356</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Inequality and Two Decades of British Tax and Benefit Reforms</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>TOM</given-names>
                  <surname>CLARK</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>ANDREW</given-names>
                  <surname>LEICESTER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2004</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">25</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438343</issue-id>
         <fpage>129</fpage>
         <lpage>158</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2004</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438356"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Microsimulation methods are used to identify the contribution of tax and benefit reforms to the significant growth in UK income inequality since 1979. The total effect turns out to depend crucially on the counterfactual against which the reforms are assessed: compared with the alternative of pure price-indexation, the total effect of reform is small; by contrast, compared with a counterfactual in which benefits rose in line with national income (historically the case before 1979), the effect is substantial — approximately half the total rise in income inequality is explained. The impact of reforms on inequality has varied significantly over time: income tax cuts in the late 1970s and late 1980s increased inequality; direct tax rises in the early 1980s and 1990s, together with increases in means-tested benefits in the late 1990s, reduced it. The robustness of the results to sampling variation and to the measure of inequality used is also investigated.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d43e245a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e252" publication-type="other">
Gottschalk and Smeeding (2000) looked at data from 16 industrial countries and found the rise in British
inequality the greatest in both actual and relative terms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e262a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e269" publication-type="other">
'Regressive' in this sense means that the rich gained relative to the poor, increasing post-tax-and-benefit
income inequality.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e279a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e286" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Clark and Taylor (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e293a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e300" publication-type="other">
The Gini coefficient is a number between 0 and 1, where 0 represents total income equality (everyone in the
economy has the same income) and 1 represents total inequality (all income is owned by just one person).
Thus, the higher the value of the Gini coefficient, the higher is inequality.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e314a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e321" publication-type="other">
Thorough details of the major reforms are available from the authors on request. Information on the current
and historical tax and benefit systems can be found in Adam and Shaw (2003) and Leicester and Shaw (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e331a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e338" publication-type="other">
Source: HM Treasury, 2001a and 2001b. Whilst general government receipts are not identical to the total tax
burden (owing to non-tax government incomes), the two are similar and follow similar trends.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e348a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e355" publication-type="other">
Sources: 1978-79 figures from Adam and Shaw (2003); 2000-01 figures from HM Treasury (2001b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e362a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e369" publication-type="other">
The latest official attempt to do this is Lakin (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e376a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e383" publication-type="other">
For example, Jenkins (1995) and Goodman, Johnson and Webb (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e390a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e397" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Johnson and Webb (1993) or Giles and Johnson (1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e405a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e412" publication-type="other">
For more information about TAXBEN, see Giles and McCrae (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e419a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e426" publication-type="other">
The most recent edition is Department for Work and Pensions (2004b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e433a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e440" publication-type="other">
The analysis of the income distribution and data underlying Figure 1 is also based on incomes constructed
using HB AI methodology.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e450a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e457" publication-type="other">
Excise duties are uprated so as to keep the real value of tax on excisable items constant. The interaction of
specific duty with VAT and ad valorem taxes means that this is achieved by increasing the specific duties by
less than inflation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e470a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e477" publication-type="other">
In particular, the Family Expenditure Survey does not contain sufficient information for us to estimate the
pre-1990 system of domestic rates. Given the omission of local taxes, corresponding benefit rates are
automatically excluded.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e490a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e497" publication-type="other">
See Clark, Giles and Hall (1999, p. 9). Greater variation in a tax should be expected to increase measured net
income inequality.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e508a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e515" publication-type="other">
See Giles and Ridge (1993).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e522a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e529" publication-type="other">
For details of how TAXBEN attempts to model these, see Giles and McCrae (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e536a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e543" publication-type="other">
For attempts to assess the redistributive implications of such transfers in kind, see Lakin (2003) and Sefton
(2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e553a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e560" publication-type="other">
For consistency with the net income measures, we use gross income that is equivalised and expressed at the
household level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e570a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e577" publication-type="other">
Official estimates of non-take-up of the main means-tested benefits are available in Department for Work and
Pensions (2004a). The bias that overlooking benefit non-take-up imposes on our results might be expected to
change over time, especially as the proportion of social security expenditure that is means-tested has increased
over time (Brewer, Clark and Wakefield, 2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e593a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e600" publication-type="other">
The disequalising effect of the 1988 tax changes was actually slightly stronger than the 0.7 percentage point
rise in the Gini shown in Table 1. This is because the Fowler reforms, which mildly reduced inequality, also
came into effect that year. See footnote 26.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e614a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e621" publication-type="other">
A point that received renewed attention in April 2002 when the Budget increased employee National
Insurance rates less than a year after the government had been re-elected pledging not to increase income tax
rates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e634a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e641" publication-type="other">
Of course, there is a legitimate position that argues that the appropriate dimension in which to measure
inequality is individual, not family, income. We focus on family income because of the data available rather
than because we take a particular position on whether it is individual or family income that matters.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e654a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e661" publication-type="other">
The start of this trend in NICs pre-dates 1979 by some way. It can certainly be dated back to 1961, when
contributions graduated with earnings were introduced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e671a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e678" publication-type="other">
We estimate that the Fowler reforms reduced the Gini coefficient by 0.1 percentage points. For more on these
reforms, see Dilnot and Webb (1988). Progressive features included an increase in means-tested benefits for
families with children, although these were at least partially offset by other regressive changes, such as the
introduction of the Social Fund, a cash-limited pool of money available as loans to those in need rather than the
payments for exceptional need system that operated under the supplementary benefit system which was
abolished as part of the reforms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e701a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e708" publication-type="other">
As we indicated in Section ID, we are not able to model all the changes to non-means-tested benefits.
Important reforms that we will not have captured with accuracy (owing to data paucity) include the increased
work conditionality for unemployment benefit, reductions in the value of state earnings-related pensions and
the stricter medical conditionality of incapacity benefit compared with the invalidity benefit it replaced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e724a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e731" publication-type="other">
This result matches the findings of Brewer et al. (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e739a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e746" publication-type="other">
Changes to indirect taxes — such as VAT or excise duties — do, of course, feed into price indices which are
used to uprate benefits and tax thresholds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e756a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e763" publication-type="other">
Budget changes to National Insurance are effective with a delay, so the effect does not show up until the April
1986 system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e773a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e780" publication-type="other">
For more on bootstrapping techniques, see Davison and Hinkley (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e787a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e794" publication-type="other">
From 1993 onwards, the data are on a financial-year basis, so the April 1996 reforms, for example, are
modelled on the 1995-96 data-set. Before 1993, the data are on a calendar-year basis, so data from the calendar
year before the April in question are used — for example, the April 1988 reforms are modelled on 1987 data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e807a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e814" publication-type="other">
When run on 1997-98 data, we saw that the overall effect of the full 22 years of reform was to reduce
inequality relative to the counterfactual 'no change' by 0.1 percentage points. When run on 1979 data
throughout, the effect is to reduce inequality by 0.8 percentage points; on 1986 data, the effect is a reduction of
0.5 percentage points; and when run on 1999-2000 Family Resources Survey data — which have been more
rigorously checked for consistency than the 1999-2000 FES data — we see an increase in inequality of 0.6
percentage points. These are all small changes which follow the intuition suggested earlier: given the
underlying increase in the dispersion of income since 1979, the effect of the reforms to the tax and benefit
system is to increase inequality less the earlier the data we use.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e843a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e850" publication-type="other">
However, it is important to note that in the early 1980s, the tax and benefit systems were largely separate
entities such that differential uprating is fairly easy to justify and implement. Over the 1990s and particularly
since the election of the Labour government in 1997, the tax and benefit systems have become much more
closely aligned, with many 'benefits', such as the various tax credits, being administered by the Inland
Revenue. Thus it may be that the further we wish to take this analysis, the less straightforward it would be to
have separate uprating factors for taxes and benefits. It should be noted, though, that in some cases, these new
benefits are explicitly income-linked — the child tax credit has been linked to earnings for the lifetime of the
second Labour Parliament, for example, and the pension credit is also earnings-linked. Of course, the further
from the repeal of the earnings ratchet the analysis begins, the harder it is to use historical justification for an
earnings uprating index for benefits — the legislation itself created a new historical precedent for price-
uprating. This is why studies such as Brewer et al. (2004), which looked at reforms from 1997 only, did not
consider this counterfactual.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e893a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e900" publication-type="other">
This follows the earlier results in Table 3, where including indirect taxes raised the inequality-promoting
effects of reforms and including employer NICs reduced them by around 1 percentage point. The results for all
years including indirect taxes and employer NICs are not reported here but are available from the authors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e913a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e920" publication-type="other">
We do not look at changes to employer National Insurance in this simulation. Since this raised significant
amounts of revenue, were we to include it the fiscal effects of the reforms would be to improve the government
finances substantially relative to the 'do-nothing' counterfactuals. Indirect tax reforms are, however, included.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e933a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e940" publication-type="other">
This is the 'constant progressivity' counterfactual we discussed earlier. Using this counterfactual, the effects
of reforms to the tax and benefit system have been to increase inequality as measured by the Gini by 4
percentage points. This is a similar result to that under our historical counterfactual where benefits were
increased by nominal GDP but tax thresholds by prices. However, the overall effect of the reforms under the
constant progressivity counterfactual turns out to be slightly lower. This is because if tax thresholds had
increased with nominal GDP, fiscal drag would not have happened, meaning that there would be fewer people
paying tax and fewer higher-rate taxpayers. This reduces the amount of redistribution being done relative to
price-indexing of tax thresholds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e969a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e976" publication-type="other">
0f course, one can argue that governments over time have different aims with regard to overall levels of
taxation and spending and the 'size' of government. Our results suggest that relative to full price-indexation,
tax and benefit reforms have made the government significantly worse off. This does not mean that price-
indexation is not a credible counterfactual, since this loss comes mainly from large cuts in tax rates which were
probably implemented with the aim of making the government sector smaller.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e995a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e1002" publication-type="other">
The effect on inequality of tax and benefit reforms compared with this counterfactual is to increase it by 3
percentage points. This constant uprating factor was also applied to duties — see footnote 14.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d43e1021a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1025" publication-type="other">
Adam, S. and Shaw, J. (2003), A Survey of the UK Tax System, Briefing Note no. 9, London:
Institute for Fiscal Studies (www.ifs.org.uk/taxsystem/taxsurvey.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1035a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1039" publication-type="other">
Brewer, M., Clark, T. and Wakefield, M. (2002), 'Social security under New Labour: what did the
Third Way mean for welfare reform?', paper presented to conference at the Institute for Fiscal
Studies, 22 May (www.ifs.org.uk/conferences/socsec/clark.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1052a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1056" publication-type="other">
—, Goodman, A., Myck, M., Shaw, J. and Shephard, A. (2004), Poverty and Inequality in Britain:
2004, Commentary no. 96, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (www.ifs.org.uk/inequality/
comm96.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1069a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1073" publication-type="other">
Clark, T., Giles, C. and Hall, J. (1999), Does Council Tax Benefit Work?, London: Institute for
Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1084a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1088" publication-type="other">
— and Taylor, J. (1999), 'Income inequality: a tale of two cycles?', Fiscal Studies, vol. 20, pp.
387-408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1098a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1102" publication-type="other">
Davison, A. C. and Hinkley, D. V. (1997), Bootstrap Methods and Their Application, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1112a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1116" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions (2004a), Income-Related Benefits Estimates of Take-Up in
2001/2002, London: Office for National Statistics (www.dwp.gov.uk/asd/income_analysis/
V2pubfinal0102.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1129a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1133" publication-type="other">
-— (2004b), Households Below Average Income, 1994/95 to 2002/03, Leeds: Corporate Document
Services.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1143a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1147" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A. and Webb, S. (1988), 'The 1988 social security reforms', Fiscal Studies, vol. 9, no. 3,
pp. 26-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1157a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1161" publication-type="other">
Giles, C. and Johnson, P. (1994), Taxes Down, Taxes Up: The Effects of a Decade of Tax Changes,
Commentary no. 41, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1176" publication-type="other">
— and McCrae, J. (1995), 'TAXBEN: the IFS microsimulation tax and benefit model', Institute for
Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. 95/19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1190" publication-type="other">
— and Ridge, M. (1993), 'The impact on households of the 1993 Budget and the council tax',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 14, no. 3, pp. 1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1200a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1204" publication-type="other">
Goodman, A., Johnson, P. and Webb, S. (1997), Inequality in the UK, Oxford: Oxford University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1218" publication-type="other">
Gottschalk, P. and Smeeding, T. (2000), 'Empirical evidence on income inequality in industrial
countries', in A. B. Atkinson and F. Bourguignon (eds), Handbook of Income Distribution,
Volume 1, Amsterdam: North Holland-Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1231a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1235" publication-type="other">
Hills, J. (2000), 'Taxation for the enabling state', in N. Fraser and J. Hills (eds), Making Economic
Policy in the 21s' Century: Essays in Memory of Henry Neuburger, Bristol: Policy Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1245a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1249" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (2001a), Budget 2001 — Investing for the Long Term: Building Opportunity and
Prosperity for All, HC 279, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1260a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1264" publication-type="other">
— (2001b), Public Finance Databank, March 2001, London: HM Treasury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1271a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1275" publication-type="other">
-— (2001c), Pre-Budget Report — Building a Stronger, Fairer Britain in an Uncertain World, Cm.
5318, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1285a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1289" publication-type="other">
Jenkins, S. (1995), 'Accounting for inequality trends: decomposition analyses for the UK, 1971—
86', Economica, vol. 62, pp. 29-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1299a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1303" publication-type="other">
Johnson, P. and Webb, S. (1993), 'Explaining the growth in UK income inequality: 1979-1988',
Economic Journal, vol. 103, pp. 429-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1313a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1317" publication-type="other">
Lakin, C. (2003), The Effects of Taxes and Benefits on Household Income, 2001-02, London:
Office for National Statistics (www.statistics.gov.uk/articles/economic_trends/effects_taxes_
benefits_household_income_01-02/revised/l akin_revised_final.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1330a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1334" publication-type="other">
Leicester, A and Shaw, J. (2003), A Survey of the UK Benefit System, Briefing Note no. 13,
London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (www.ifs.org.uk/taxsystem/benefitsurvey.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1345a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1349" publication-type="other">
McClements, L. (1977), 'Equivalence scales for children'. Journal of Public Economics, vol. 8, pp.
191-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1359a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1363" publication-type="other">
Redmond, G., Sutherland, H. and Wilson, M. (1998), The Arithmetic of Tax and Social Security
Reform: A User's Guide to Microsimulation Methods and Analysis, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1376a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1380" publication-type="other">
Sefton, T. (2002), Recent Changes in the Distribution of the Social Wage, CASEpaper no. 62,
London: Centre for Analysis of Social Exclusion (sticerd.lse.ac.uk/dps/case/cp/
CASEpaper62.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1393a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1397" publication-type="other">
Vording, H. (1999), 'Indexed social security benefits: what have we learned?', University of
Magdeburg, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
