<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909675</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fractals:</article-title>
            <subtitle>From Physical Science to Military Science</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lauren</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr Michael Lauren is a Research Leader in the Human Systems Group for the Defence Technology Agency, New Zealand. He has a PhD in physics from the University of Auckland. Dr Lauren is one of the original developers of the MANA agent-based combat model.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>McIntosh</surname>
                  <given-names>Gregory C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr Gregory McIntosh works with the Operations Analysis section at Defence Technology Agency in New Zealand where his recent work has focused on developing the MANA agent-based model for combat simulation. He has a PhD in physics from Victoria University in Wellington.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Moffat</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Professor Jim Moffat is a Senior Fellow of the Defence Science and Technology Laboratory, UK, and a Fellow of both the Operational Research Society, and the Institute of Mathematics and its Applications. He has worked for the past 30 years on defence related operational analysis problems, and aerospace technology research. His most recent works include the Dept of Defense CCRP publications “Complexity Theory and Network Centric Warfare‚” and “The Agile Organisation.”</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2007</year>
            <string-date>December 2007</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>40</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909669</issue-id>
         <fpage>8</fpage>
         <lpage>11</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909675"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. L. Helmbold. 1995. Personnel Attrition Rates in Historical Land Combat Operations. US Army Concepts Analysis Agency, Bethesda, MD, Report CAARP- 95-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. K. Lauren, J. M. Smith and J. Moffat. 2005. Using the Fractal attrition Equation to Construct a Metamodel of the MANA Cellular Automaton Combat Model, TTCP JSA TP3 report.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. S. Hartley III. 2001. Predicting Combat Effects. INFORMS, Linthicum Md.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. K. Lauren. 1999. Characterising the Difference Between Complex Adaptive and Conventional Combat Models (DOTSE Report 169, New Zealand Defence Force).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. N. Kolmogorov. Local Structure of Turbulence in an Incompressible Fluid at Very High Reynolds Numbers. Dokl. Akad. Nauk SSSR 30, No 4, pp 299-303 (1941).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. C. McIntosh. 2006. Using Agent-Based Models to Derive Equations of Attrition for Military Combat. DTA report, in press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. I. Barenblatt. 1996. Scaling, Self-similarity and Intermediate Asymptotics, CUP.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. D. Perry. 2006. Verification and Validation of the Fractal Attrition Equation, DSTO Report DSTO-TR-1822, Australian Government (available at www.dsto.defence.gov.au/publications/4372/).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
