<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285092</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Miller Cycle Engine without Compromise - The Magma Concept</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Osborne</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ricardo UK Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Downes</surname>
                  <given-names>Trevor</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ricardo Innovations</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>O'Brien</surname>
                  <given-names>Simon</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ricardo UK Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pendlebury</surname>
                  <given-names>Ken</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ricardo UK Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Christie</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ricardo Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>846</fpage>
         <lpage>857</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285092"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The Magma engine concept is characterised by a high compression ratio, central injector combustion system employed in a downsized direct-injection gasoline engine. An advanced boosting system and Miller cycle intake-valve closing strategies are used to control combustion knock while maintaining specific performance. A key feature of the Magma concept is the use of high CR without compromise to mainstream full-load performance levels. This paper focuses on development of the Magma combustion system using a single-cylinder engine, including valve event, air motion and injection strategies.</p>
            <p>Key findings are that Early Intake Valve Closing (EIVC) is effective both in mitigating knock and improving fuel consumption. A Net Indicated Mean Effective Pressure (NIMEP) equivalent to 23.6 bar Brake Mean Effective Pressure (BMEP) on a multi-cylinder engine has been achieved with a geometric compression ratio of 13:1.</p>
            <p>Comparison of weighted key point cycle predictions for the downsized Magma concept vs a contemporary baseline engine, indicates fuel consumption savings over WLTC and FTP-75 of 12.5% and 16.4% respectively.</p>
            <p>The cost / benefit trade-off is currently being refined, but the position in terms of cost per gram per mile of CO₂ benefit appears to favour a Magma solution over other options. Part of the benefit arises from the current assumption that a 2.0 litre L4 engine is replaced with a 1.5 litre L3 which is enabled by the higher specific rating of the Magma concept. The reduction in base engine cost offsets some of the additional air handling equipment.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Osborne, R. J., Pendlebury, K. J., Stokes, J., Dalby, J. and Rouaud, C.: “The Magma Engine Concept,” JSAE Annual Congress 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pendlebury, K. J., Osborne, R. J., Downes, T. A. and O’Brien, S., “Development of the Magma Combustion System,” JSAE Annual Congress 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, R. ‘High Expansion, Spark Ignited, Gas Burning, Internal Combustion Engines’, USA Patent No. 2773490 (1956)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schutting, E., Dumböck, O., Kraxner, T. and Eichlseder, H., “Thermodynamic Consideration of the Miller Cycle on the Basis of Simulation and Measurements”, ATZ Live 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, J. “Research and application of over-expansion cycle (Atkinson and Miller) engines - A review”, Applied Energy, Volume 185, Part 1, 1 January 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watanabe, I., Kawai, T., Yonezawa, K. and Ogawa, T.: “The New Toyota 2.0-Liter Inline 4-Cylinder ESTEC D-4ST Engine - Turbocharged Direct Injection Gasoline Engine”, 23rd Aachen Colloquium Automobile (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hikichi, K., Watanabe, I., Shinagawa, K., and Kudo, M.: “The New Toyota Inline 4 Cylinder 1.2L ESTEC D-4T Engine”, 36. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium (2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aiyoshizawa, E., Hori, K.: “The New Nissan High Efficient 4-Cylinder 1.6L GDI turbocharged engine with low pressure EGR - Evolution for Lower Fuel Consumption combined with High Output Performance”, 35. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium (2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurms, R., Budack, R., Grigo, M., Mendl, G., Heiduk, T., Knirsch, S., “The New Audi 2.0l Engine with Innovative Rightsizing - A Further Milestone in the TFSI Technology”, 36. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium (2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“1Optimization of the Combustion Process as Demonstrated on the New Audi 2.0L TFSI,” 24th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichler, F., Demmelbauer-Ebner, W., Theobald, J., Stiebels, B., “The New EA211 TSI evo from Volkswagen”, Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demmelbauer-Ebner, W., Middendorf, H., Birkigt, A., Ganzer, M., Hagelstein, D., Persigehl, K., “EA211 TSI evo -The New 4-Cylinder Gasoline Engines from Volkswagen”, 25th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kishi, K., Satou, T.: “The New Nissan High Efficient 1.2L 3cyl GDI Supercharged Engine Enables 95 g/km CO2 Emissions and High Driving Performance”, 33. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pendlebury, K. J., Osborne, R. J., Stokes, J., Dalby, J. “The Gasoline Engine at 2020,” 23rd Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sandoval, D. and Heywood, J., "An Improved Friction Model for Spark-Ignition Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0725, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0725.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patton, K., Nitschke, R., and Heywood, J., "Development and Evaluation of a Friction Model for Spark-Ignition Engines," SAE Technical Paper 890836, 1989, doi:10.4271/890836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, B., “Path to High Efficiency Gasoline Engine”, DEER 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
