<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277686</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Hot Exhaust Gas Recirculation on the Combustion Characteristics and Particles Emissions of a Pilot-Ignited Natural Gas Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhou</surname>
                  <given-names>Lei</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Liu</surname>
                  <given-names>Yifu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sun</surname>
                  <given-names>Lu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hou</surname>
                  <given-names>Haixiao</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zeng</surname>
                  <given-names>Ke</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Huang</surname>
                  <given-names>Zuohua</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Xi'an Jiaotong University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1116</fpage>
         <lpage>1125</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277686"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Natural gas has become an attractive alternative for diesel fuel due to its higher octane number, richer reserves and lower price. It has been utilized in compression ignition engines to obtain a higher thermal efficiency compared with spark ignition engines. However, its relatively higher auto-ignition temperature increases the difficulty of compression-ignition based on present hardware devices. One optimal ignition method is that a very small quantity of diesel fuel as the only ignition resource pilot-ignites the lean natural gas-air mixture. This micro diesel pilot-ignited natural gas premixed charge compression ignition (DPING-PCCI) combustion strategy is easy to implement without major hardware modifications, and can significantly reduce the NOₓ and particle mass emissions from diesel engines. Although the DPING-PCCI has so many advantages, it suffers from poor engine stability and high ultrafine particles emissions at part loads. In the present paper, the hot exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) strategy was employed in a single-cylinder DPING-PCCI engine at part loads. The aim is to investigate influences of hot EGR on combustion and emissions characteristics of the DPING-PCCI engine, especially ultrafine particles emissions. The results show that, when increasing the hot EGR rate, the ignition delay period is prolonged progressively, however the total combustion duration is shortened gradually. With the increase of hot EGR rate, the shape of particle size distribution curve appears unimodal and the peak of particle number concentration gradually shifts downwards and towards the larger particle size. The total ultrafine particle number concentration was reduced up to 57 percent. While the particle mass concentration is reduced and the coefficient of variation in indicated mean effective pressure (COV<sub>IMEP</sub>) decreased 5 percent. Meanwhile, CO, HC and NOₓ emissions are decreased simultaneously. The results indicate that the hot EGR has the merits to fulfill lower emissions and improve the engine stability.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dorfman Ira, Dual fuel conversion systems for heavy duty trucks. EcoDual, http://www.cleanvehicle.org/workshop/portland/NielsonEcoDual.pdf. 2012.3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westport Corporate, Westport corporate update presentation. http://www.westport.com/media/presentations/corporate-update/corporateupdate. pdf. 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saleri, N. G., Our man-made energy crisis. Wall Street Journal, http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703386704576186622682563228.html.2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qi Y, Srinivasa, K. K., Krishnan, S. R., Yang, H. Effect of hot exhaust gas recirculation on the performance and emissions of an advanced injection low pilot-ignited natural gas engine. International Journal Engine Research 2007, 8, 289-305, doi: 10.1243/14680874jer02306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Papagiannakis, R. G., Hountalas, D. T. combustion and exhaust emission characteristics of a dual fuel compression ignition engine operated with pilot diesel fuel and natural gas. Energy Conversion Management 2004, 45, 2971-2987, doi: 10.1016/j.enconman. 2004.01.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Selim, M., “Combustion Noise Measurements and Control from Small Diesel and Dual Fuel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-32-0072, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-32-0072.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Srinivasan, K. K., Krishnan, S. R., Midkiff, K. C. Improving low load combustion, stability and emissions in pilot-ignited natural gas engines. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers Part D-Journal of Automobile Engineering 2006, 220, 229-239, doi: 10.1243/09544070jauto104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlucci, A. P., de Risi, A., Laforgia, D., Naccarato, F. Experimental investigation and combustion analysis of a direct injection dual-fuel diesel-natural gas engine. Energy 2008, 33, 256-263, doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2007.06.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Selim, M. Y. E. Pressure-time characteristics in diesel engine fueled with natural gas. Renewable Energy 2001, 22, 473-489.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Srinivasan, K. K., Krishnan, S. R., Qi, Y., Midkiff, K. C., Yang, H. Analysis of diesel pilot-ignited natural gas low-temperature combustion with hot exhaust gas recirculation. Combustion Science and Technology 2007, 179, 1737-1776, doi: 10.1080/00102200701259882.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlucci, A. P., Laforgia, D., Saracino, R., Toto, G. Combustion and emissions control in diesel-methane dual fuel engines: The effects of methane supply method combined with variable in-cylinder charge bulk motion. Energy Conversion Management 2011, 52, 3004-3017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saanum, I., Bysveen, M., Tunestål, P., and Trajkovic, S., “HCCI Combustion of Natural Gas and Hydrogen Enriched Natural Gas Combustion Control by Early Direct Injection of Diesel Oil and RME,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1657, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korakianitis, T., Namasivayam, A. M., Crookes, R. J. Natural-gas fueled spark-ignition (SI) and compression-ignition (CI) engine performance and emissions. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 2011, 37, 89-112, doi: 10.1016/j.pecs.2010.04.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abd-Alla, G. H. Using exhaust gas recirculation in internal combustion engines: a review. Energy Conversion Management 2002, 43, 1027-1042, doi:10.1016/s0196-8904(01)00091-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abd-Alla, G., Soliman, H., and Abd-Rabbo, M., “The Effects of Diluent Admissions and Intake Temperature in Exhaust Gas Recirculation on the Emissions of an Indirect-Injection Dual Fuel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2796, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2796.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope, C. A. Epidemiology of fine paniculate air pollution and human health: Biologic mechanisms and who's at risk?. Envirnment Health Perspectives 2000, 108, 713-723, doi: 10.2307/3454408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donaldson, K., Li, X. Y. &amp; MacNee, W. Ultrafine (nanometre) particle mediated lung injury. Journal of Aerosol Science 1998, 29, 553-560, doi:10.1016/s0021-8502(97)00464-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McTaggart-Cowan, G. P., Jones, H. L., Rogak, S. N., Bushe, W. K. &amp; Hill, P. G. The effects of high-pressure injection on a compressionignition, direct injection of natural gas engine. Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power-transactions of the ASME 2007, 129, 579-588, doi: 10.1115/1.2432894.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V., Curran, S., Barone, T., Lewis, S. et al., “Emission Characteristics of a Diesel Engine Operating with In-Cylinder Gasoline and Diesel Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):946-955, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cha, J. P., Heo, J. Y. &amp; Lee, C. S. Nanoparticle emissions of partial premixed charge compression ignition (PPCCI) engines at dieselgasoline dual fuel combustion. Proceedings of the 14th Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systerms-Asia 2010, 47-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Y. F., Liu B, Zeng K, Huang, Z. H., Zhou L, Sun L. Performance and emission characteristics of a hydrogen-enriched compressednatural- gas direct-injection spark ignition engine diluted with exhaust gas recirculation. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers Part D-Journal of Automobile Engineering 2012, 226, 123-132, doi: 10.1177/0954407011413047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsolakis, A., Hernandez, J. J., Megaritis, A., Crampton, M. Dual fuel diesel engine operation using H-2 center dot effect on particulate emissions. Energy Fuel 2005, 19, 418-425, doi: 10.1021/ef0400520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Y. F., Liu, B., Liu, L., Zeng, K., Huang, Z. H. Combustion characteristics and paniculate emission in a natural-gas direct-injection engine: effects of the injection timing and the spark timing. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers Part D-Journal of Automobile Engineering 2010, 2224, 1071-1080, doi: 10.1243/09544070jauto1532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, G., Yu, W., Li, Q., and Huang, Z., “Effects of n-Butanol Addition on the Performance and Emissions of a Turbocharged Common-Rail Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0852, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0852.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, JB. Internal combustion engine fundamentals. McGraw-Hill book Company, 1988: 383-390.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G. A. Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine, doi: 10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gordon, S., McBride, B. J., Aeronautics, U. S. N., Scientific, S. A. Program, T. I. computer program for calculation of complex chemical equilibrium compositions and applications I. 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McBride, B. J., Gordon, S. Computer Program for Calculation of Complex Chemical Equilibrium Compositions and Applications II; Users Manual and Program Description. 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Misztal, J., Xu, H. M., Tsolakis A., et al. Influence of Inlet Air Temperature on Gasoline HCCI Particulate Emissions. Combustion Science Technology 2009, 181, 695-709, doi: 10.1080/00102200902851610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tan, P. Q. et al. Particulate matter emission modelling based on soot and SOF from direct injection diesel engines. Energy Conversion Management 2007, 48, 510-518, doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2006.06.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
