<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812159</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Issues in Property Taxation</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Paying for Property Tax Assessment Quality</article-title>
            <subtitle>An Experiment</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Delaney</surname>
                  <given-names>Jason</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sjoquist</surname>
                  <given-names>David L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wallace</surname>
                  <given-names>Sally</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>4</lpage>
         <page-range>1-18, 1-3, 1-4, 1-4</page-range>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812159"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>At the local government level, the property tax is a major source of funding for public goods. The process by which property taxes are assessed involves establishing a fair market value of the property. In many jurisdictions, tight budgets for tax administration have led to complaints of highly inaccurate valuation of properties. The result may be property taxes that are “too high” or “too low.” In this research, a laboratory experiment is conducted to determine the willingness of taxpayers to pay for improved assessment. In this experiment, the choice that is modeled is a reduction in risk, which people value, as predicted by economic theory and confirmed by experimental evidence and the existence of insurance markets. In principle this benefit can be provided as a private good, meaning that an individual pays a private firm to reduce risk and is the sole beneficiary of the risk reduction. An example would be a warranty or collision insurance for an automobile. It might also be provided as a public good, in which a group acts collectively to reduce risk and the group benefits from the reduction in risk. Examples of this kind of collective risk reduction include the establishment and maintenance of fire departments or investments in watershed management. This research will produce new knowledge on the ways in which human behavior responds to these two types of risk reduction, and the similarities and differences between them with a practical application in the case of property tax assessment.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Ackerman, Hagen, Martin Fochmann, Benedikt Mihm. 2013. “Biased Effects of Taxes and Subsidies on Portfolio Choices.” Economic Letters 120 (1): 23-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Ackert, Lucy, Jorge Martinez-Vazquez, and Mark Rider. 2007. “Social Preferences and Tax Policy Design: Some Experimental Evidence.” Economic Inquiry 45 (3): 487-501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bolton, Gary E. and Alex Ockenfels. 2000. ERC-A Theory of Equity, Reciprocity, and Competition.” American Economic Review 90(1): 166-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Dohmen, Thomas, Armin Falk, David Huffman, Uwe Sunde, Jürgen Schupp, and Gert G. Wagner. 2011. “Individual Risk Attitudes: Measurement, Determinants, and Behavioral Consequences. Journal of the European Economic Association 9(3): 522-550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Durham, Yvonne, Tracy S. Manly, Christina Ritsema. 2014. “The Effects of Income Source, Context, and Income Level on Tax Compliance Decisions in a Dynamic Experiment.” Journal of Economic Psychology 40: 220-233.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Einav, Liran, Amy Finkelstein, Iuliana Pascu, and Mark R. Cullen. 2012. “How General are Risk Preferences? Choices under Uncertainty in Different Domains.” American Economic Review 102(6): 2606-2638.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Engelmann, Dirk and Martin Strobel. 2004. “Inequality Aversion, Efficiency, and Maximin Preferences in Simple Distribution Experiments.” American Economic Review 94(4): 857-869.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Esarey, Justin, Timothy C. Salmon, and Charles Barrilleaux. 2012. “Social Insurance and Income Redistribution in a Laboratory Experiment.” Political Research Quarterly 65(3): 685-698.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Fehr, Ernst and Klaus M. Schmidt. 1999. “A Theory of Fairness, Competition, and Cooperation.” The Quarterly Journal of Economics 114 (3): 817-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Gerau, Vincent J. and James L. Plourde. 1976. “The Determinants of Uniform Property Tax Assessment.” Assessor’s Journal 11: 235-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Hardisty, David J., Eric J. Johnson, and Elke U. Weber. 2010. “A Dirty Word or a Dirty World: Attribute Framing, Political Affiliation, and Query Theory.” Psychological Science 21 (1): 86-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Holt, Charles A. and Susan K. Laury. 2002. “Risk Aversion and Incentive Effects.” The American Economic Review 92 (5): 1644-1655</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Isaac, R. Mark and James M. Walker. 1988. “Group Size Effects in Public Goods Provision: The Voluntary Contributions Mechanism.” Quarterly Journal of Economics 103 (1): 179-199</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Kitchler, Erich. 2007. The Economic Psychology of Tax Behavior. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Sjoquist, David and Mary Beth Walker. 1999. "Economics of Scale in Property Tax Assessment." National Tax Journal 52(2): 207-220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Sussman, Abigail and Christopher Y. Olivola. 2011. “Axe the Tax: Taxes Are Disliked More Than Equivalent Costs.” Journal of Marketing Research 58 (Special Issue): S91-S101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
