<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">16</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000456</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008637</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Methodology for a Semi-Automatic Evaluation of the Lexicons of Machine Translation Systems</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ahmed</given-names>
                  <surname>Guessoum</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Rached</given-names>
                  <surname>Zantout</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2001</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>127</fpage>
         <lpage>149</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2002 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008637"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>The lexicon is a major part of any Machine Translation (MT) system. If the lexicon of an MT system is not adequate, this will affect the quality of the whole system. Building a comprehensive lexicon, i.e., one with a high lexical coverage, is a major activity in the process of developing a good MT system. As such, the evaluation of the lexicon of an MT system is clearly a pivotal issue for the process of evaluating MT systems. In this paper, we introduce a new methodology that was devised to enable developers and users of MT Systems to evaluate their lexicons semi-automatically. This new methodology is based on the idea of the importance of a specific word or, more precisely, word sense, to a given application domain. This importance, or weight, determines how the presence of such a word in, or its absence from, the lexicon affects the MT system's lexical quality, which in turn will naturally affect the overall output quality. The method, which adopts a black-box approach to evaluation, was implemented and applied to evaluating the lexicons of three commercial English-Arabic MT systems. A specific domain was chosen in which the various word-sense weights were determined by feeding sample texts from the domain into a system developed specifically for that purpose. Once this database of word senses and weights was built, test suites were presented to each of the MT systems under evaluation and their output rated by a human operator as either correct or incorrect. Based on this rating, an overall automated evaluation of the lexicons of the systems was deduced.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Arabic</kwd>
            <kwd>coverage</kwd>
            <kwd>evaluation</kwd>
            <kwd>lexicons</kwd>
            <kwd>translation quality</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d1134923e190a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e194" publication-type="other">
Anon: 1996, المترجم الالي: الوافي [The Machine Translator: Al-Wafy], عربيوتر (Arabuter) 8,
27-28.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e204a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e208" publication-type="other">
Arnold, Doug, R. Lee Humphreys and Louisa Sadler (eds): 1993, 'Special Issue on Evaluation of
MT Systems', Machine Translation 8(1-2).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e218a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e222" publication-type="other">
Dorr, Bonnie J. and Judith Klavans: 1994/5, 'Special Issue: Building Lexicons for Machine
Translation', Machine Translation 9(3-4), 10(1-2).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e232a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e236" publication-type="other">
Dyson, Mary C. and Jean Hannah: 1987, 'Towards a Methodology for the Evaluation of Machine-
Assisted Translation Systems', Computers and Translation 2, 163-176.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e247a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e251" publication-type="other">
EAGLES (Expert Advisory Group on Language Engineering Standards): 1995, 'Evaluation of Natural
Language Processing Systems', EAGLES Document EAG-EWG-PR.2.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e261a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e265" publication-type="other">
EAGLES: 1998, Proceedings of the Second Eagles II Workshop on Evaluation in Human Language
Technology, Geneva.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e275a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e279" publication-type="other">
Hutchins, W. John and Harold L. Somers: 1992, An Introduction to Machine Translation, London:
Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e289a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e293" publication-type="other">
Jihad, A. جهاد عبد اللاه: 1996, هل بداعصر الترجمةالالية عربيا [Has the Arabic Machine
Translation Era Started?], بايت الشرق الاوسط (Byte Middle East), November 1996, pp.
36-48.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e306a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e310" publication-type="other">
King, M. and K. Falkedal: 1990, 'Using Test Suites in Evaluation of Machine Translation Sys-
tems', in COLING-90: Papers presented to the 13th International Conference on Computational
Linguistics, Helsinki, Finland, Vol. 2, pp. 211-216.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e323a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e327" publication-type="other">
Klein, J., S. Lehmann, K. Netter and T. Wegst: 1999, 'DiET in the Context of MT Evaluation', in
Rita Nübel and Uta Seewald-Heeg (eds), Evaluation of the Linguistic Performance of Machine
Translation Systems, Proceedings of the Konvens'98, St. Augustin: Gardezi Verlag, pp. 107-126.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e341a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e345" publication-type="other">
Lehmann, Sabine, Stephan Oepen, Sylvie Regnier-Prost, Klaus Netter, Veronika Lux, Judith
Klein, Kirsten Falkedal, Frederik Fouvry, Dominique Estival, Eva Dauphin, Herv, Compagnion,
Judith Baur, Lorna Balkan and Doug Arnold: 1996, 'TSNLP - Test Suites for Natural Language
Processing', COLING-96: The 16th International Conference on Computational Linguistics,
Copenhagen, Denmark, pp. 711-716.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e364a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e368" publication-type="other">
Lehrberger, John and Laurent Bourbeau: 1987, Machine Translation: Linguistic Characteristics of
MT Systems and General Methodology of Evaluation, Amsterdam: John Benjamins.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e378a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e382" publication-type="other">
Mason Jane and Adriane Rinsche: 1995, Ovum Evaluates: Translation Technology Products,
London: OVUM Ltd.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e392a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e396" publication-type="other">
Melby, A. K.: 1988, 'Lexical Transfer: Between a Source Rock and a Hard Target', Coling Budapest:
Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Budapest, pp.
411-419.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e409a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e413" publication-type="other">
Nagao, M.: 1985, 'Evaluation of the Quality of Machine-Translated Sentences and the Control of
Language', Journal of the Information Processing Society of Japan 26, 1197-1202.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e423a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e427" publication-type="other">
Nyberg, Eric H. and Teruko Mitamura: 1992, 'The KANT System: Fast, Accurate, High-Quality
Translation in Practical Domains', Proceedings of the fifteenth [sic] International Conference on
Computational Linguistics, COLING-92, Nantes, pp. 1069-1073.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e441a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e445" publication-type="other">
Nyberg, Eric H., Teruko Mitamura and Jaime G. Carbonell: 1994, 'Evaluation Metrics for
Knowledge-Based Machine Translation', COLING 94: The 15th International Conference on
Computational Linguistics, Kyoto, Japan, pp. 95-99.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e458a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e462" publication-type="other">
Qendelft, G. جورج قندلفت: 1997, مستقبل المترجمين لا يزال مضمونا: برنامج الوافي للترجمة
مفيد لفھم المعنى العام من رسالة انكليزية [The Translation Program Al-Wafy Is
Useful for Getting a General Understanding of a Letter Written in English], الحياة (Al-Hayat)
الحياة الاقتصدية (Saturday, 25 October).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e478a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e482" publication-type="other">
Sinaiko, H. W. and G. R. Klare: 1972, 'Further Experiments in Language Translation: Readability of
Computer Translations', ITL 15, 1-29.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e492a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e496" publication-type="other">
Sinaiko, H. W. and G. R. Klare: 1973, 'Further Experiments in Language Translation: A Second
Evaluation of the Readability of Computer Translations', ITL 19, 29-52.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e506a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e510" publication-type="other">
van Slype, G.: 1979, 'Systran: Evaluation of the 1978 Version of the Systran English-French Auto-
matic System of the Commission of the European Communities', The Incorporated Linguist 18,
86-89.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e523a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e527" publication-type="other">
Vasconcellos, Muriel (ed.): 1988. Technology as Translation Strategy, Binghamton, NY: State
University of New York at Binghamton (SUNY).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e538a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e542" publication-type="other">
White, John S., Theresa O'Connell and Francis O'Mara: 1994, 'The ARPA MT Evaluation Meth-
odologies: Evolution, Lessons, and Future Approaches', Technology Partnerships for Crossing
the Language Barrier: Proceedings of the First Conference of the Association for Machine
Translation in the Americas, Columbia, Maryland, pp. 193-205.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1134923e558a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1134923e562" publication-type="other">
Wilks Y.: 1992, 'Systran: It Obviously Works, But How Much Can It Be Improved?', in John
Newton (ed.), Computers and Translation: A Practical Appraisal, London: Routledge, pp. 166-
188.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
