<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">107</volume>
         <issue-id>i40195325</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44668183</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Landing Forces Resulting from Exiting Tractors and Trailers</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Cotnam</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Fadi A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Fathallah</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>431</fpage>
         <lpage>434</lpage>
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1999 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44668183"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Tractors are generally provided with step and grab rail systems to facilitate driver entrance and exit from the cab. However, many of these systems are not designed based on human factors engineering principles, particularly anthropometry and thus are not always used. Some examples include steps or rails that are too high for a cross-section of the population to reach or steps that are difficult to see as the occupant descends from the cab. Trailers frequently do not have any "designed steps/grab rails" to aid the driver or material handler in safely climbing up or down from the rear of the unit. As a result, squat jumping from the trailer floor down to the ground is a common method of exit from commercial trailers. Injuries resulting from exiting commercial vehicles could represent a substantial cost to businesses operating these equipment. The purpose of this study was to quantify landing forces experienced during various tractor and trailer exit methods ranging from making optimal use of hand rails and steps to jumping. The study investigated landing forces sustained by ten male subjects while exiting two tractors and a box trailer. Steps were retrofitted onto the back of the box trailer in order to show reductions in landing forces achievable from trailers that are retrofitted with improved access systems. The results showed squat jumping down from the back of a box trailer generated landing forces as high as 11 times body weight. On the other hand, using the trailer's retrofitted step and grab system while exiting resulted in landing forces reduced by over 66%. Jumping from the cab-level of a cab-over-engine tractor resulted in landing forces as high as 12 times the subject's body weight; whereas, fully utilizing the existing steps and grab-rails kept the landing forces under two times their body weight. An approach that emphasizes optimal entry/exit aids design based on human factors engineering, coupled with driver training is expected to minimize vehicle-related musculoskeletal injuries.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d610e153a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e160" publication-type="other">
Miller, J. M. 1976, Efforts to reduce truck and bus operator
hazards, Human Factors, 18(6), 533-550.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d610e170a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e177" publication-type="other">
Nicholson, A. S. and David, G. C. 1985, Slipping, tripping
and falling accidents to delivery drivers, Ergonomics, 28(7),
977-991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d610e190a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e197" publication-type="other">
Heglund, R. E. 1987, SAE Technical Paper Series: Falls
entering and exiting heavy truck cabs, Proceedings of the
Truck and Bus Meeting and Exposition, Dearborn, Ml.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d610e210a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e217" publication-type="other">
U.S. Army, 1988 Anthropometric Survey of U.S. Army Per-
sonnel: Methods and Summary Stastics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d610e228a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e235" publication-type="other">
Roebuck, J.A., Kroemer, K.H.E., and, Thompson, W.G.,
1975, Engineering Anthropometry Methods (New York:
John Wiley &amp; Sons).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d610e248a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e255" publication-type="other">
Wootton, B.H., 1997, Gender differences in occupational
employment, U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor
Statistics, Monthly Labor Review, April 1 997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d610e268a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e275" publication-type="other">
Federal Motor Carrier Safety Regulations, 1979, Step,
Handhold, and Deck Requirements for Commercial Motor
Vehicles, Part 399, Employee Safety and Health Stan-
dards, Subpart L - Section 399.201-399.211.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d610e291a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d610e298" publication-type="other">
The Maintenance Council of the American Trucking Associ-
ation. 1989, Truck and Truck Tractor Access Systems, TMC
Recommended Practice, RP404B-1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


