<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284933</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Design of Catalytic Devices by Means of Genetic Algorithm</article-title>
            <subtitle>Comparison between Open-Cell Foam and Honeycomb Type Substrates</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Falfari</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefania</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Micci</surname>
                  <given-names>Giacomo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bianchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Gian Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brusiani</surname>
                  <given-names>Federico</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Montenegro</surname>
                  <given-names>Gianluca</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Torre</surname>
                  <given-names>Augusto Della</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Onorati</surname>
                  <given-names>Angelo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>September 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284904</issue-id>
         <fpage>1686</fpage>
         <lpage>1695</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284933"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Metallic foams or sponges are materials with a cell structure suitable for many industrial applications, such as reformers, heat catalytic converters, etc. The success of these materials is due to the combination of various characteristics such as mechanical strength, low density, high specific surface, good thermal exchange properties, low flow resistance and sound absorption. Different materials and manufacturing processes produce different type of structure and properties for various applications. In this work a genetic algorithm has been developed and applied to support the design of catalytic devices. In particular, two substrates were considered, namely the traditional honeycomb and an alternative open-cell foam type. CFD simulations of pressure losses and literature based correlations for the heat and mass transfer were used to support the genetic algorithm in finding the best compromise between flow resistance and pollutant abatement. The CFD analysis was conducted by means of numerical simulations carried out on a geometry sample obtained by the micro-tomography technique to investigate the flow regime type and to extract pressure drop information. The result of this analysis was used to set guideline for the design of foam type substrate and to provide a first estimation of cost effectiveness of new type of substrates.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thiel, M., Klingbeil, A., and Reitz, R., "Experimental Optimization of a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Using Automated Genetic Algorithms," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0960, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Risi, A., Donateo, T., and Laforgia, D., "Optimization of the Combustion Chamber of Direct Injection Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1064, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, T., Miki, M., Kim, M., Watanabe, S. et al., "Reduction of Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Emission and Fuel Economy with Multi- Objective Genetic Algorithm and Phenomenological Model," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0531, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusca, S., Lanzafame, R., and Messina, M., "The Evaluation of Gross Heat Release in Internal Combustion Engines by Means of Genetic Algorithms," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0657, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dimopoulos Eggenschwiler P., Tsinoglou D. N., Seyfert J., Bach C., Vogt U. F., and Gorbar M.. Ceramic foam substrates for automotive catalyst applications. Fluid mechanic analysis. Experiments in Fluids, (47, 2):209-222, 2009. doi:10.1007/s00348-009-0653-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bach, C. and Dimopoulos Eggenschwiler, P., "Ceramic Foam Catalyst Substrates for Diesel Oxidation Catalysts: Pollutant Conversion and Operational Issues," SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0179, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucci F., Della Torre A., Montenegro G., and Dimopoulos Eggenschwiler P.. On the catalytic performance of open cell structures versus honeycombs. Chemical Engineering Journal, 264:514-521, 2015. doi:10.1016/j.cej.2014.11.080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deb K., Agarwal S., Pratap A., and Meyarivan T.. A fast elitist nondominated sorting genetic algorithm for multi-objective optimization: NSGA-II. Technical report, Kampur Genetic Algorithms Laboratory (Kam-GAL), Indian Institute of Technology Kampur - Kan-GAL Report No. 200001, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deb K., Pratap A., Agarwal S., and Meyarivan T.. A fast and elitist multiobjective genetic algorithm: NSGA-II. IEEE Transactions on Evolutionary Computation, 6(2):182-197, 2002. doi:10.1109/4235.996017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wickman, D., Senecal, P., and Reitz, R., "Diesel Engine Combustion Chamber Geometry Optimization Using Genetic Algorithms and Multi- Dimensional Spray and Combustion Modeling," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0547, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shrivastava, R., Hessel, R., and Reitz, R., "CFD Optimization of DI Diesel Engine Performance and Emissions Using Variable Intake Valve Actuation with Boost Pressure, EGR and Multiple Injections," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0959, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanner F.X. and Srinivasan S.. Cfd-based optimization of fuel injection strategies in a diesel engine using an adaptive gradient method. Applied Mathematical Modelling, 33(3):1366-1385, 2009. doi:10.1016/j.apm.2008.01.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Costa M., Bianchi G.M., Forte C., and Cazzoli G.. A numerical methodology for the multiobjective optimization of the di diesel engine combustion. volume 45, pages 711-720, 2014. doi:10.1016/j.egypro.2014.01.076.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mancin S., Zilio C., Cavallini A., and Rossetto L.. Heat transfer during air flow in aluminum foams. International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, 53(21-22):4976-4984, 2010. doi:10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2010.05.033.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edouard D., Lacroix M., Huu C.P., and Luck F.. Pressure drop modeling on solid foam: State-of-the art correlation. Chemical Engineering Journal, 144(2):299-311, 2008. doi:10.1016/j.cej.2008.06.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Della Torre A., Montenegro G., Tabor G.R., and Wears M.L.. CFD characterization of flow regimes inside open cell foam substrates. International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow, 50:72-82, 2014. doi:10.1016/j.ijheatfluidflow.2014.05.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giani L., Groppi G., and Tronconi E.. Mass-transfer characterization of metallic foams as supports for structured catalysts. Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Research, 44(14):4993-5002, 2005. doi:10.1021/ie0490886.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Groppi G., Giani L., and Tronconi E.. Generalized correlation for gas/solid mass-transfer coefficients in metallic and ceramic foams. Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Research, 46(12):3955-3958, 2007. doi:10.1021/ie061330g.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patcas F. C., Incera Garrido G., and Kraushaar-Czarnetzki B.. CO oxidation over structured carriers: A comparison of ceramic foams, honeycombs and beads. Chemical Engineering Science, 62(15):3984- 3990, August 2007. doi:10.1016/j.ces.2007.04.039.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucci F., Della Torre A., von Rickenbach J., Montenegro G., Poulikakos D., and Dimopoulos Eggenschwiler P.. Performance of randomized kelvin cell structures as catalytic substrates: Mass-transfer based analysis. Chemical Engineering Science, 112:143-151, 2014. doi:10.1016/j.ces.2014.03.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weller H. G., Tabor G., Jasak H., and Fureby C.. A Tensorial Approach to CFD using Object Orientated Techniques. Computers in Physics, Vol. 12(No. 6):620, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Versteeg H. K. and Malalasekera W.. An introduction to computational fluid dynamics. Longman Scientific &amp; Technical, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Menter F. and Esch T.. Elements of Industrial Heat Transfer Prediction. 16th Brazilian Congress of Mechanical Engineering (COBEM), 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Della Torre A., Montenegro G., Onorati A., and Tabor G.. CFD characterization of pressure drop and heat transfer inside porous substrates. Energy Procedia, 81:836 - 845, 2015. doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.egypro.2015.12.093, 69th Conference of the Italian Thermal Engineering Association, ATI 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhattacharya A., Calmidi V.V., and Mahajan R.L.. Thermophysical properties of high porosity metal foams. International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, 45(5):1017-1031, 2002. doi:10.1016/S0017- 9310(01)00220-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marsh, P., Acke, F., Konieczny, R., Brück, R. et al., "Application Guideline to Define Catalyst Layout for Maximum Catalytic Efficiency," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0929, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
