<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i23321971</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23321974</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis, preparation, and optimization of statistical sign language machine translation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
                  <surname>Stein</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Christoph</given-names>
                  <surname>Schmidt</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hermann</given-names>
                  <surname>Ney</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>325</fpage>
         <lpage>357</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Springer Science+Business Media Dordrecht 2012</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23321974"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Sign languages represent an interesting niche for statistical machine translation that is typically hampered by the scarceness of suitable data, and most papers in this area apply only a few, well-known techniques that are not adapted to small-sized corpora. In this article, we analyze existing data collections and emphasize their quality and usability for statistical machine translation. We also offer findings in the proper preprocessing of a sign language corpus, by introducing sentence end markers, splitting compound words and handling parallel communication channels. Then, we focus on optimization procedures that are tailored to scarce resources, such as scaling factor optimization, alignment optimization and system combination. All methods are evaluated on two of the largest sign language corpora available.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d63200e378a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d63200e385" publication-type="other">
Rexroat 1997</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d63200e392a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d63200e399" publication-type="other">
http://www.htlpr.rwth-aachen.de/-och/software/GIZA++.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d63200e406a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d63200e413" publication-type="other">
Bellugi and Fischer (1972)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d63200e419" publication-type="other">
Speers 2002</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d63200e426a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d63200e433" publication-type="other">
http://mastarpj.nict.go.jp/IWSLT2009/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d63200e441a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d63200e448" publication-type="other">
www.bu.edu/asllrp.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d63200e455a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d63200e462" publication-type="other">
http://nip.Stanford.edu/software/lex- parser.shtml.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d63200e478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e482" publication-type="other">
Bauer B, Kraiss KF (2001) Towards an automatic sign language recognition system using subunits. In:
Gesture and sign language in human-computer interaction. International gesture workshop GW 2001,
Springer, London, pp 64-75</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e495a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e499" publication-type="other">
BeckerC (2010) Lesen und Schreiben Lernen mit einer Hörschädigung. Unterstützte Kommunikation 1:17-
21</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e509a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e513" publication-type="other">
Bellugi U, Fischer S (1972) A comparison of sign language and spoken language. Cognition 1:173-200</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e520a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e524" publication-type="other">
Bertoldi N, Tiotto G, Prinetto P, Piccolo E, Nunnari F, Lombardo V, Mazzei A, Damiano R, Lesmo L,
Principe AD (2010) On the creation and the annotation of a large-scale Italian-LIS parallel corpus.
In: 4th workshop on the representation and processing of sign languages: corpora and sign language
technologies, Valletta, Malta, pp 19-22</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e541a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e545" publication-type="other">
Brown PF, Delia Pietra SA, Delia Pietra VJ, Mercer RL (1993) The mathematics of statistical machine
translation: parameter estimation. Comput Linguist 19(2):263-311</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e559" publication-type="other">
Bungeroth J, Ney H (2004) Statistical sign language translation. In: LREC 2004, workshop proceedings:
representation and processing of sign languages, Lisbon, Portugal, pp 105-108</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e573" publication-type="other">
Bungeroth J, Stein D, Dreuw P, Ney H, Morrissey S, Way A, van Zijl L (2008) The ATIS sign language
corpus. In: International conference on language resources and evaluation, Marrakech, Morocco, p 4</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e587" publication-type="other">
Chiu Y, Wu C, Su H, Cheng C (2007) Joint optimization of word alignment and epenthesis generation for
Chinese to taiwanese sign synthesis. IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intel 29( 1 ):28—39</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e601" publication-type="other">
Crasborn O, Zwitserlood I (2008) The corpus NGT: an online corpus for professionals and laymen. In:
Crasborn O, Hanke T, Efthimiou E, Zwitserlood I, Thoutenhoofd E (eds) Construction and exploita-
tion of sign language corpora. 3rd workshop on the representation and processing of sign languages
at LREC 2008, ELDA, Paris, France, pp 44-49</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e621" publication-type="other">
Crasborn O, van der Kooij E, Nonhebel A, Emmerik W (2004) ECHO data set for sign language of the
Netherlands (NGT). Department of Linguistics, Radboud University Nijmegen, Nijmegen</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e632a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e636" publication-type="other">
Dreuw P, Forster J, Gweth Y, Stein D, Ney H, Martinez G, Verges Llahi J, Crasborn O, Ormel E, Du W,
Hoyoux T, Piater J, Moya Lazaro JM, Wheatley M (2010a) Signspeak—understanding, recognition,
and translation of sign languages. In: 4th Workshop on the representation and processing of sign
languages: corpora and sign language technologies, Malta</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e652a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e656" publication-type="other">
Dreuw P, Ney H, Martinez G, Crasborn O, Piater J, Miguel Moya J, Wheatley M (2010b) The signspeak
project—bridging the gap between signers and speakers. In: International conference on language
resources and evaluation, Valletta, Malta, pp 476-481</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e669a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e673" publication-type="other">
Efthimiou E, Fotinea SE, Vogler C. Hanke T, Glauert J, Bowden R, Braffort A, Collet C, Maragos P, Segouat
J (2009) Sign language recognition, generation, and modelling: a research effort with applications in
deaf communication. In: Stephanidis C (ed) Universal access in human-computer interaction. Address-
ing diversity, lecture notes in computer science, vol 5614, Springer. Berlin, pp 21-30</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e689a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e693" publication-type="other">
Fiscus JG (1997) A post-processing system to yield reduced word error rates: recognizer output voting error
reduction (rover), pp 347-352</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e703a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e707" publication-type="other">
Hermans D, Knoors H, Ormel E, Verhoeven L (2008a) Modeling reading vocabulary learning in deaf chil-
dren in bilingual education programs. J Deaf Stud Deaf Edu 13(2): 155-174</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e717a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e721" publication-type="other">
Hermans D, Knoors H, Ormel E, Verhoeven L (2008b) The relationship between the reading and signing
skills of deaf children in bilingual education programs. J Deaf Stud Deaf Edu 13(4):519-530</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e732a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e736" publication-type="other">
Huenerfauth M (2004) Spatial representation of classifier predicates for machine translation into american
sign language. In: Workshop on representation and processing of sign language, 4th intemationnal
conference on language ressources and evaluation, LREC 2004, pp 24-31</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e749a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e753" publication-type="other">
Johnston T (2001) The lexical database of auslan (Australian sign language). Sign Lang Linguist 4(25): 145-
169</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e763a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e767" publication-type="other">
Kanis J, Müller L (2009) Advances in Czech—signed speech translation. In: Lecture notes in computer
science, vol 5729. Springer, New York, pp 48-55</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e777a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e781" publication-type="other">
Kanis J, Zahradil J, Jurc/cek F, Müller L (2005) Czech-sign speech corpus for semantic based machine
translation. In: Lecture notes in artificial intelligence, vol. 4188, pp 613-620</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e791a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e795" publication-type="other">
Koehn P (2005) Europarl: a parallel corpus for statistical machine translation. In: Machine translation
summit X, Phuket, Thailand, pp 79-86</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e805a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e809" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Och FJ, Marcu D (2003) Statistical Phrase-Based Translation. In: Proceedings of the human lan-
guage technology, North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics, Edmonton,
Canada, pp 54-60</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e823a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e827" publication-type="other">
Kramer F (2007) Kulturfaire Berufseignungsdiagnostik bei Gehörlosen und daraus abgeleitete Untersuch-
ungen zu den Unterschieden der Rechenfertigkeiten bei Gehörlosen und Hörenden. PhD thesis, RWTH
Aachen University, Aachen, Germany</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e840a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e844" publication-type="other">
Massó G, Badia T (2010) Dealing with sign language morphemes for statistical machine translation. In:
4th workshop on the representation and processing of sign languages: corpora and sign language
technologies, Valletta, Malta, pp 154-157</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e857a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e861" publication-type="other">
Matusov E, Leusch G, Banchs RE, Bertoldi N, Dechelotte D, Federico M, Kolss M, Lee YS, Marino JB,
Paulik M, Roukos S, Schwenk H, Ney H (2008) System combination for machine translation of spoken
and written language. IEEE Trans Audio Speech Lang Process 16(7): 1222-1237</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e874a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e878" publication-type="other">
Mauser A, Hasan S, Ney H (2009) Extending statistical machine translation with discriminative and trigger-
based lexicon models. In: Conference on empirical methods in natural language processing, Singapore,
pp 210-218</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e891a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e895" publication-type="other">
Morissey S (2008) Data-driven machine translation for sign languages. PhD thesis, School of Computing,
Dublin City University, Dublin City University. Ireland</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e905a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e909" publication-type="other">
Morrissey S, Way A (2006) Lost in translation: the problems of using mainstream MT evaluation metrics
for sign language translation. In: Proceedings of the 5th SALTMIL workshop on minority languages
at LREC'06, Genoa, Italy, pp 91-98</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e923a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e927" publication-type="other">
Morrissey S, Way A, Stein D, Bungeroth J, Ney H (2007) Towards a hybrid data-driven MT system for sign
languages. In: Machine translation summit, Copenhagen, Denmark, pp 329-335</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e937a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e941" publication-type="other">
Och FJ, Ney H (2003) A systematic comparison of various statistical alignment models. Comput Linguist
29(1): 19-51</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e951a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e955" publication-type="other">
Papineni K, Roukos S, Ward T, Zhu WJ (2002) Bleu: a method for automatic evaluation of machine trans-
lation. In: Proceedings of the 41st annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics,
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA, pp 311-318</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e972" publication-type="other">
Pizzuto E, Rossini P, Russo T (2006) Representing signed languages in written form: questions that need
to be posed. In: Proceedings of the workshop on the representation and processing of sign languages:
"lexicographic matters and didactic scenarios", international conference on language resources and
evaluation LREC 2006, Genoa, Italy—28th May 2006, pp 1-6</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e988a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e992" publication-type="other">
Popovic M, Stein D, Ney H (2006) Statistical machine translation of German compound words. In: 5th
international conference on natural language processing, FinTal, Turku, Finland, pp 616-624</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1002a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1006" publication-type="other">
Prillwitz S (1989) HamNoSys, Version 2.0; Hamburg notation system for sign language. An introductory
guide. Signum, Hamburg</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1017a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1021" publication-type="other">
Rexroat N (1997) The colonization of the deaf community. Soc Work Perspect 7(1):18—26</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1028a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1032" publication-type="other">
Sáfár É, Marshall I (2001) The architecture of an English-text-to-sign-languages translation system. In:
et al GA (ed) Recent advances in natural language processing (RANLP), Tzigov Chark, Bulgaria,
pp 223-228</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1045a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1049" publication-type="other">
San-Segundo R, Pardo JM, Ferreiras J, Sama V, Barra-Chicote R, Lucas JM, Snchez D, Garca A (2010) Spo-
ken spanish generation from sign language. Interact Comput 22(2): 123-139, URL http://linkinghub.
elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S095354380900099X</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1062a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1066" publication-type="other">
Snover M, Dorr B, Schwartz R, Micciulla L, Makhoul J (2006) A study of translation edit rate with targeted
human annotation. In: Proceedings of the 7th conference of the association for machine translation in
the Americas, Cambridge, MA, USA, pp 223-231</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1079a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1083" publication-type="other">
Speers AL (2002) Representation of American sign language for machine translation. PhD thesis, George-
town University, Washington, DC</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1093a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1097" publication-type="other">
Stein D, Bungeroth J, Ney H (2006) Morpho-syntax based statistical methods for sign language translation.
In: Conference of the European association for machine translation, Oslo, Norway, pp 169-177</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1108a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1112" publication-type="other">
Stein D, Forster J, Zelle U, Dreuw P, Ney H (2010a) Analysis of the German sign language weather forecast
corpus. In: 4th workshop on the representation and processing of sign languages: corpora and sign
language technologies, Valletta, Malta, pp 225-230</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1125a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1129" publication-type="other">
Stein D, Schmidt C, Ney H (2010b) Sign language machine translation overkill. In: Proceedings of the
international workshop on spoken language translation (IWSLT), Paris, France, pp 337-334</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1139a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1143" publication-type="other">
Veale T, Conway A, Collins B (1998) The challenges of cross-modal translation: English to sign language
translation in the zardoz system. J Mach Trans 13(1):81—106</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1153a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1157" publication-type="other">
Venugopal A, Zollmann A, Smith N, Vogel S (2009) Preference grammars: softening syntactic constraints
to improve statistical machine translation. In: Proceedings of human language technologies: the 2009
annual conference of the north American chapter of the association for computational linguistics,
Boulder, Colorado, USA, pp 236-244</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1177" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Stein D, Ney H (2008) Analysing soft syntax features and heuristics for hierarchical phrase based
machine translation. In: Proceedings of the international workshop on spoken language translation
(IWSLT), Waikiki, Hawaii, pp 190-197</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1194" publication-type="other">
Vilar D, Stein D, Huck M, Ney H (2010) Jane: open source hierarchical translation, extended with reor-
dering and lexicon models. In: ACL 2010 joint fifth workshop on statistical machine translation and
metrics MATR, Uppsala, Sweden, pp 262-270</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1208a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1212" publication-type="other">
Wauters LN, van Bon WHJ, Tellings AEJM (2006) Reading comprehension of Dutch deaf children. Read
Writ Interdiscip J 19:49-76</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1222a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1226" publication-type="other">
Zens R, Ney H (2008) Improvements in dynamic programming beam search for phrase-based statistical
machine translation. In: Proceedings of the international workshop on spoken language translation
(IWSLT), Honolulu, Hawaii, pp 195-205</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d63200e1239a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d63200e1243" publication-type="other">
Zielinski A, Simon C (2008) Morphisto: an open-source morphological analyzer for German. In: Proceed-
ings of the international workshop on finite-state methods and natural language processing, Ispra,
Italy, pp 177-184</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


