<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277775</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Negative Valve Overlap Reforming Chemistry in Low-Oxygen Environments</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Szybist</surname>
                  <given-names>James P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Lab.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Steeper</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Labs.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Splitter</surname>
                  <given-names>Derek</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Lab.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kalaskar</surname>
                  <given-names>Vickey B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Lab.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pihl</surname>
                  <given-names>Josh</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Lab.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Daw</surname>
                  <given-names>Charles</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Lab.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>418</fpage>
         <lpage>433</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277775"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Fuel injection into the negative valve overlap (NVO) period is a common method for controlling combustion phasing in homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) and other forms of advanced combustion. When fuel is injected into O₂-deficient NVO conditions, a portion of the fuel can be converted to products containing significant levels of H₂ and CO. Additionally, other short chain hydrocarbons are produced by means of thermal cracking, water-gas shift, and partial oxidation reactions. The present study experimentally investigates the fuel reforming chemistry that occurs during NVO. To this end, two very different experimental facilities are utilized and their results are compared. One facility is located at Oak Ridge National Laboratory, which uses a custom research engine cycle developed to isolate the NVO event from main combustion, allowing a steady stream of NVO reformate to be exhausted from the engine and chemically analyzed. The other experimental facility, located at Sandia National Laboratories, uses a dump valve to capture the exhaust from a single NVO event for analysis. Results from the two experiments are in excellent trend-wise agreement and indicate that the reforming process under low-O₂ conditions produces substantial concentrations of H₂, CO, methane, and other short-chain hydrocarbon species. The concentration of these species is found to be strongly dependent on fuel injection timing and injected fuel type, with weaker dependencies on NVO duration and initial temperature, indicating that NVO reforming is kinetically limited. Further, NVO reforming does not require a large energy input from the engine, meaning that it is not thermodynamically expensive. The implications of these results on HCCI and other forms of combustion are discussed in detail.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L., Ogink, R., and Denbratt, I., “Direct Gasoline Injection in the Negative Valve Overlap of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01- 1854, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A., and Itoh, T., “Expansion of HCCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, Negative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0749, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Waldman, J., Nitz, D., Aroonsrisopon, T., Foster, D. et al., “Experimental Investigation into the Effects of Direct Fuel Injection During the Negative Valve Overlap Period in an Gasoline Fueled HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0219, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arning, J., Ramsander, T., and Collings, N., “Analysis of In-Cylinder Hydrocarbons in a Multi-Cylinder Gasoline HCCI Engine Using Gas Chromatography,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):141-149, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2698.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Wermuth, N., and Najt, P., “High Load HCCI Operation Using Different Valving Strategies in a Naturally-Aspirated Gasoline HCCI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1190-1201, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall, A., Szybist, J., Edwards, K., Foster, M. et al., “HCCI Load Expansion Opportunities Using a Fully Variable HVA Research Engine to Guide Development of a Production Intent Cam-Based VVA Engine: The Low Load Limit,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1149- 1162, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fitzgerald, R. and Steeper, R., “Thermal and Chemical Effects of NVO Fuel Injection on HCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):46-64, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szybist, J., Edwards, K., Foster, M., Confer, K. et al., “Characterization of Engine Control Authority on HCCI Combustion as the High Load Limit is Approached,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):553-568, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1665.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berntsson, A. and Denbratt, I., “Optical study of HCCI Combustion using NVO and an SI Stratified Charge,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0012, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szybist, J., Nafziger, E., and Weall, A., “Load Expansion of Stoichiometric HCCI Using Spark Assist and Hydraulic Valve Actuation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):244-258, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Wermuth, N., and Najt, P., “Extending the High Load Operating Limit of a Naturally-Aspirated Gasoline HCCI Combustion Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):681-699, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0847.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall A. J., and Szybist J. P., 2012, “The Effects of Fuel Characteristics on Stoichiometric Spark-Assisted HCCI,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 134(7).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manofsky, L., Vavra, J., Assanis, D., and Babajimopoulos, A., “Bridging the Gap between HCCI and SI: Spark-Assisted Compression Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1179, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olesky L. M., Martz J. B., Lavoie G. a., Vavra J., Assanis D. N., and Babajimopoulos A., 2013, “The effects of spark timing, unburned gas temperature, and negative valve overlap on the rates of stoichiometric spark assisted compression ignition combustion,” Applied Energy, 105, pp. 407-417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T. and Mangold, B., “Dedicated EGR: A New Concept in High Efficiency Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):620-631, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Topinka, J., Gerty, M., Heywood, J., and Keck, J., “Knock Behavior of a Lean-Burn, H2 and CO Enhanced, SI Gasoline Engine Concept,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0975, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoffmann, W., Wong, V., Cheng, W., and Morgenstern, D., “A New Approach to Ethanol Utilization: High Efficiency and Low NOx in an Engine Operating on Simulated Reformed Ethanol,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2415, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2415.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Song H., and Edwards C., 2009, “Understanding chemical effects in low-load-limit extension of homogeneous charge compression ignition engines via recompression reaction,” International Journal of Engine Research, 10(4), pp. 231-250.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wermuth, N., Yun, H., and Najt, P., “Enhancing Light Load HCCI Combustion in a Direct Injection Gasoline Engine by Fuel Reforming During Recompression,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):823- 836, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steeper, R. and Davisson, M., “Analysis of Gasoline Negative- Valve-Overlap Fueling via Dump Sampling,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7():in press, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J. B., 1988, Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw Hill Book Co., New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yanowitz J., Christensen E., and McCormick R. L., 2011, “Utilization of Renewable Oxygenates as Gasoline Blending Components,” NREL Technical Report, NREL/TP-4500-50791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Daw, C., Szybist, J., Pihl, J., Splitter, D., Kalaskar, V., Xie, C., and Gao, Z., “Stretch Efficiency for Combustion Engines: Exploiting New Combustion Regimes,” U.S. Department of Energy, Washington D.C., 2013, Vehicle Technologies Annual Merit Review, Advanced Combustion Engines ACE-015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalaskar, V., Szybist, J., Splitter, D., Pihl, J., Gao, Z., and Daw, C.S., “In-cylinder Reaction Chemistry and Kinetics during Negative Valve Overlap Fuel Injection under Low-oxygen Condition,” Proceedings of the ASME Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, ICEF2013-19230, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lawson, J., “Some Criteria for a Power Producing Thermonuclear Reactor,” Proceedings of the Physical Society. Section B, 70(1):6- 10, 1957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
