<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023224</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Measuring Inequality</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Changes in the Distribution of After-Tax Wealth</article-title>
            <subtitle>Has Income Tax Policy Increased Wealth Inequality?</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Looney</surname>
                  <given-names>Adam</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">*</xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Moore</surname>
                  <given-names>Kevin B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">**</xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">*Brookings Institution.</aff>
            <aff id="a2">**Federal Reserve Board of Governors.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>35</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023224"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>A substantial share of the wealth of Americans is held in tax-deferred form such as in retirement accounts or as unrealized capital gains. Most data and statistics on assets and wealth is reported on a pre-tax basis, but pre-tax values include an implicit tax liability and may not provide as accurate a measure of the financial position or material well-being of families. In this paper, we describe the distribution of tax-deferred assets in the SCF from 1989 to 2013, provide new estimates of the income tax liabilities implicit in those assets, and present new statistics on the level and distribution of after-tax net worth. The results of our analysis suggest that, relative to published statistics on pre-tax net worth, the distribution of after-tax wealth is slightly less concentrated in the early years of our sample period, but the effectiveness of the income tax system in reducing wealth inequality has decreased during the last decade. We find the reduction in the long-term capital gains rate is the primary reason for the muted effectiveness of the current income tax system in reducing wealth inequality.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>Wealth</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Taxation</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Inequality</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Argento, Robert, and Kevin B. Moore. 2013. “Evaluating Tax Data Generated Using the Survey of Consumer Finances and TAXSIM,” Papers and Proceedings of the 2013 Joint Statistical Meetings.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Armour, Philip, Richard V. Burkhauser, and Jeff Larrimore. 2014. “Levels and Trends in U.S. Income and its Distribution: A Crosswalk from Market Income towards a Comprehensive Haig-Simons Income Approach,” Southern Economic Journal, 81(2): 271-293.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, Anthony B. and Bourguignon, F. Handbook of Income Distribution. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, Anthony B., Thomas Piketty, and Emmanuel Saez. 2011. “Top Incomes in the Long Run of History,” Journal of Economic Literature. 49(1): 3-71. (March)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and Kevin Hassett. 2015. “Capital Taxation in the 21<sup>st</sup> Century,” Working Paper, University of California, Berkeley and American Enterprise Institute. (January)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Avery, Robert B., Daniel Grodzicki and Kevin B. Moore. 2013 “Estate vs. Capital Gains Taxation: An Evaluation of Prospective Policies for Taxing Wealth at the Time of Death.” FEDS working paper, 2013-28. http://www.federalreserve.gov/pubs/feds/2013/201328/201328pap.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Avery, Robert B, and Michael S Rendall. 2002. “Lifetime Inheritances of Three Generations of Whites and Blacks.” American Journal of Sociology, 107(5): 1300–1346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bordo, Michael D., and Christopher M. Meissner. 2012. “Does Inequality Lead to a Financial Crisis?” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 17896. (March)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bricker, Jesse, Lisa J. Dettling, Alice Henriques, Joanne W. Hsu, Kevin B. Moore, John Sabelhaus, Jeffrey Thompson, and Richard A. Windle. 2014. “Changes in U.S. Family Finances from 2010 to 2013: Evidence from the Survey of Consumer Finances,” Federal Reserve Bulletin, 100(4): 1-40. (September)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bricker, Jesse, Alice Henriques, Jacob Krimmel, and John Sabelhaus. 2015. “Measuring Income and Wealth at the Top Using Administrative and Survey Data,” Federal Reserve Board.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, Meta, Andrew Haughwout, Donghoon Lee, and Wilbert van der Klaauw. 2015. “Do We Know What We Owe? Consumer Debt as Reported by Borrowers and Lenders,” FRBNY Economic Policy Review (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bucks, Brian, and Kevin Moore. 2012. “The Great Recession’s Varied Effects on Household Well-being and Its Consequences for Inequality,” Paper Prepared for the 32nd General Conference of The International Association for Research in Income and Wealth. http://www.iariw.org/papers/2012/BucksPaper.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burkhauser, Richard V., Jeff Larrimore, and Kosali I. Simon. 2012. “A ‘Second Opinion’ on the Economic Health of the American Middle Class.” National Tax Journal, 65(1): 7-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burkhauser, Richard V., Shuaizhang Feng, Stephen P. Jenkins, and Jeff Larrimore. 2012. “Recent Trends in Top Income Shares in the United States: Reconciling Estimates from March CPS and IRS Tax Return Data.” Review of Economics and Statistics, 94(2): 371-388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Castaneda, Ana, Javier Diaz-Gimenez, and Jose-Victor Rios-Rull. 2003. “Accounting for the U.S. Earnings and Wealth Inequality.” Journal of Political Economy, 111(4): 818-857.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office. 2014. “The Distribution of Household Income and Federal Taxes, 2011,” Washington, DC: Congress of the United States, Congressional Budget Office. (November)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davies, James. 2009. “Wealth and Economic Inequality,” in The Oxford Handbook of Economic Inequality, Salverda, W., Nolan, B., &amp; Smeeding, T. M. (eds).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dettling, Lisa, Sebastian Devlin-Foltz, Jacob Krimmel, Sarah Pack and Jeffrey Thompson. 2015. “Comparing Micro and Macro Sources for Household Accounts in the United States: Evidence from the Survey of Consumer Finances,” FEDS working paper 2015-086. (October)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devlin-Foltz, Sebastian, Alice Henriques, and John Sabelhaus. 2015. “The Evolution of Retirement Wealth,” FEDS working paper 2015-009. (February)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donovan, Sarah A. 2015. “A Guide to Describing the Income Distribution,” Washington, DC: Congressional Research Office. (February)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feenberg, Daniel, and Elisabeth Coutts. 1993. An introduction to the TAXSIM model. Journal of Policy Analysis and management, 12(1), 189-194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gale, William G., James R. Hines Jr., and Joel Slemrod. 2001. Rethinking Estate and Gift Taxation. Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenwood, Daphne. 1983. “An Estimation of US Family Wealth and its Distribution from Microdata” Review of Income and Wealth (March) pp 23-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henriques, Alice M., and Joanne W. Hsu. 2014. “Analysis of Wealth using Micro and Macro Data: A Comparison of the Survey of Consumer Finances and Flow of Funds Accounts,” in Jorgenson, Dale W., J. S. Landefeld and Paul Schreyer eds., Measuring Economic Sustainability and Progress, Studies in Income and Wealth, Volume 72. Cambridge, MA: National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hungerford, Thomas L. 2010 “The Economic Effects of Capital Gains Taxation,” Washington, DC: Congressional Research Office. (June)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jones, Charles I. 2015. “Pareto and Piketty: The Macroeconomics of Top Income and Wealth Inequality,” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 29(1): 29-46. (Winter) 2009.” FEDS working paper 2011-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kennickell, Arthur B. 2012. “The Other, Other Half: Changes in the Finances of the Least Wealthy 50 Percent, 2007–2009.” FEDS working paper 2012-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klass, Oren S., Ofer Biham, Moshe Levy, Ofer Malcai, and Sorin Solomon. 2006. “The Forbes 400 and the Pareto Wealth Distribution.” Economics Letters, 90(2): 290-295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kopczuk, Wojciech. 2015. “What Do We Know About the Evolution of Top Wealth Shares in the United States?” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 29(1): 47-66. (Winter)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kopczuk, Wojciech. 2012. “Taxation and Intergenerational Transfers of Wealth.” NBER Working Paper 1854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kopczuk, Wojciech, and Emmanuel Saez. 2004. “Top Wealth Shares in the United States, 1916-2000” Evidence from Estate Tax Returns,” National Tax Journal, 52:445-487.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piketty, Thomas. 2014. Capital in the 21<sup>st</sup> Century. Harvard University Press. (April)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piketty, Thomas. 2015. “Putting Distribution Back at the Center of Economics: Reflections on Capital in the Twenty-First Century” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 29(1): 67-88. (Winter)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piketty, Thomas, Emmanuel Saez, and Stefanie Stantcheva. 2014. “Optimal Taxation of Top Labor Incomes: A Tale of Three Elasticities.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 6(1): 230-271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piketty, Thomas, and Emmanuel Saez. 2013. “A Theory of Optimal Inheritance Taxation.” Econometrica, 81(5): 1851-1886.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piketty, Thomas, and Emmanuel Saez. 2003. “Income Inequality in the United States, 1913-1998,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 118(1): 1-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piketty, Thomas, and Gabriel Zucman. 2014. “Capital Is Back: Wealth-Income Ratios in Rich Countries 1700-2010.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 129(3): 1255-1310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roine, Jesper, and Daniel Waldenström. 2015. “Long-Run Trends in the Distribution of Income and Wealth,” in Handbook of Income Distribution, Atkinson, A.B. and Bourguignon, F. (eds). Sabelhaus, John. 2000. “Modeling IRA Accumulation and Withdrawals,” National Tax Journal, vol. 53, no. 4, pp. 865-875.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saez, Emmanuel, and Gabriel Zucman. 2014. “Wealth Inequality in the United States since 1913: Evidence from Capitalized Income Tax Data,” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 20625. (October)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smeeding, T. M., &amp; Thompson, J. P. 2011. “Recent trends in income inequality: labor, wealth and more complete measures of income,” Research in Labor Economics, 32, 1-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stein, Harry. 2014. “How the Government Subsidies Wealth Inequality,” Center for American Progress. (June)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stiglitz, Joseph E. 2012. The Price of Inequality: How Today’s Divided Society Endangers Our Future, W.W. Norton. (June)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vermeulen, Phillip. 2014. “How Fat is the Top Tail of the Wealth Distribution?” Directorate General Research, Monetary Policy Research Division, European Central Bank. (September)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weil, David N. 2015. “Capital and Wealth in the 21<sup>st</sup> Century,” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 20919. (January)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolff, Edward. 2014. “Household Wealth Trends in the United States, 1962-2013: What Happened Over the Great Recession?” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 20733. (December)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
