<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169210</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Prediction of Dynamic Progressive Buckling Behaviors of Single-Hat and Double-Hat Steel Components under Axial Loading</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Haorongbam</surname>
                  <given-names>Bisheshwar</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Deb</surname>
                  <given-names>Anindya</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Indian Institute Of Science</aff>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chou</surname>
                  <given-names>Clifford</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169200</issue-id>
         <fpage>114</fpage>
         <lpage>126</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169210"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Hat sections, single and double, made of steel are frequently encountered in automotive body structural components such as front rails, B-Pillar, and rockers of unitized-body cars. These components can play a significant role in terms of impact energy absorption during collisions thereby protecting occupants of vehicles from severe injury. Modern vehicle safety design relies heavily on computer-aided engineering particularly in the form of explicit finite element analysis tools such as LS-DYNA for virtual assessment of crash performance of a vehicle body structure. There is a great need for the analysis-based predictions to yield close correlation with test results which in turn requires well-proven modeling procedures for nonlinear material modeling with strain rate dependence, effective representation of spot welds, sufficiently refined finite element mesh, etc. Although hat sections subject to axial loading have been studied widely in published literature, it is difficult to come across detailed information on modeling that can lead to sound correlation of CAE predictions with experimental results even for quasi-static conditions. In the current study, both single-hat and double-hat components made of mild steel are at first tested under axial loading in a UTM and the resulting load-displacement responses are predicted accurately through explicit finite element analysis carried out with LS-DYNA. Mean loads from theoretical predictions are then compared with the experimentally obtained results. Furthermore, studies are conducted for different impact conditions and the modeling procedures such as for definition of elasto-plastic material behavior are discussed in detail. The simulation-based impact dynamic responses including crash performance parameters such as mean load and total crush are found to compare well with corresponding experimental results. For generality and for relevance to practical impact scenarios, eccentrically loaded double hat-sections are tested and reasonably good numerical predictions of their behaviors are presented, perhaps for the first time in published literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahmood, H. and Paluszny, A., “Design of Thin Walled Columns for Crash Energy Management - Their Strength and Mode of Collapse,” SAE Technical Paper 811302, 1981, doi: 10.4271/811302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">White M.D., Jones N. and Abramowicz W., “A theoretical analysis for the quasi-static axial crushing of top-hat and double-hat thin-walled sections”, International Journal of Mechanical Sciences 41, 209-233 (1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">White M.D. and Jones N., “A theoretical analysis for the dynamic axial crushing of top-hat and double-hat thin-walled sections”, Proc Instn Mech Engrs Vol 213 Part D, 307-325 (1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schneider F. and Jones N., “Impact of thin-walled high-strength steel structural sections, Proc. Instn Mech. Engrs Vol. 218 Part D: J. Automobile Engineering, 131-158 (2004).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peixinho N., Jones N. and Pinho A., “Experimental and numerical study in axial crushing of thin walled sections made of high-strength steels”, J. Phys. IV France, 110, 717-722 (2003).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tarigopula V., Langseth M., Hopperstad O.S. and Clausen A.H., “Axial crushing of thin-walled high-strength steel sections”, International Journal of Impact Engineering, 32, 847-882 (2006).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sato, K., Yoshitake, A., Hosoya, Y., and Mikami, H., “FEM Simulation to Estimate Crashworthiness of Automotive Parts,” SAE Technical Paper 982356, 1998, doi: 10.4271/982356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stander N., Roux W., Giger M., Redhe M., Fedorova N., Haarhoff J., “Crashworthiness Optimization in LS-OPT: Case Studies in Metamodeling and Random Search Techniques”, J-1-11:26, 4th European LS-DYNA Users Conference (2003).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lanzi Luca, Bisagni Chiara and Ricci Sergio, “Neural network systems to reproduce crash behavior of structural components”, Computers &amp; Structures, 82(1), 93-108 (2004).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Du Bois Paulo et al., “Vehicle Crashworthiness and Occupant Protection”, Automotive Applications Committee, American Iron and Steel Institute, Southfield, Michigan (2004).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deb, A., Haorongbam, B., Diwakar, J., and Chou, C., “Efficient Approximate Methods for Predicting Behaviors of Steel Hat Sections Under Axial Impact Loading,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 3(1):695-703, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sugimoto Tomiji, Kadotani Yoshiji and Ohmura Shigeru, “The Offset Crash Test-A comparative analysis of test methods”. Honda R &amp; D Co., Ltd. Japan Paper Number 98-S1-O-08.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
