<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">36/49</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186568</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44438845</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Characteristics of EXHAUST-GAS ANALYZERS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>J. L.</given-names>
                  <surname>DILWORTH</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1941</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>234</fpage>
         <lpage>239</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44438845"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>CONFLICTING views of experienced maintenance men on the accuracy of exhaust-gas analyzers in determining air-fuel ratio, Mr. Dilworth explains, stimulated a critical study and numerous actual tests of various exhaust-gas analyzers with a view toward securing some dependable information on the actual performance of these instruments. The tests were all conducted at Virginia Polytechnic Institute on a single-cylinder, variable-compression test engine in order to eliminate, or permit the control of, as many variables as possible. The laboratory set-up and the method of conducting the tests are explained in this paper. Six exhaust-gas analyzers were tested: two of the widely used thermal-conductivity type, one of the hot-wire catalytic type, one of the relative-density type, and two employing the Orsat principle. Mr. Dilworth points out that, while these do not represent all the makes on the American market, they represent every general type which is applicable to automotive service. Probably the most striking thing shown, he reports, is that every instrument practically ceased to function when the air-fuel ratio became leaner than 14: 1. From the results of these tests it is concluded that exhaust-gas analyzers are not precision instruments, being likely to err as much as one-half of one airfuel ratio, even under favorable conditions; and that all exhaust gas analyzers are calibrated for regular commercial gasolines, requiring special calibration for any fuel with a different chemical composition.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1065e190a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1065e197" publication-type="other">
SAE Transactions, March, 1936, pp. 90-98. 116: Relation of
Exhaust-Gas Composition to Air-Fuel Ratio," by B. A. D'Alleva and
W. G. Lovell;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1065e209" publication-type="other">
Engineering Experiment Station Bulletin Series
No. 4, May, 1934, Oregon State Agricultural College, by Graf, Gleason,
and Paul;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1065e221" publication-type="other">
NACA Technical Report No. 616. 1938; "Interrela-
tion of Exhaust-Gas Constituents," by H. C. Gerrish and F. Voss.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


