<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812222</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Tax Distortions in Firm Mobility, Local Employment, and Finance</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Employment Effects of Local Business Taxes</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siegloch</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>31</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812222"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This is the first paper to thoroughly investigate the employment effects of corporate taxation. Higher taxes are theoretically shown to have a negative impact on employment through reduced investments, if labor is regionally mobile. I test this prediction by exploiting the specific setting of local business taxation in Germany, where on average 10% of the 11,441 municipalities change their tax rate each year. Relying on rich administrative linked employer-employee panel data, I provide non-parametric and parametric evidence that employment declines if business tax rates increase. For given wages, a one euro increase in an establishment's tax bill leads to a reduction in the wage bill by 20 cents over two years. I empirically show that the negative employment effect is triggered by reduced (net) investments and leads to lower production levels.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Alda, H., S. Bender, and H. Gartner (2005). European Data Watch: The Linked Employer-Employee Dataset Created from the IAB Establishment Panel and the Process-Produced data of the IAB (LIAB). Schmollers Jahrbuch: Journal of Applied Social Science Studies 125 (2), 327{336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Andrews, M., T. Schank, and R. Upward (2006). Practical axed-e ects estimation methods for the three-way error-components model. Stata Journal 6 (4), 461{481.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Angrist, J. D. and J.-S. Pischke (2009). Mostly Harmless Econometrics. Princeton, New Jersey: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Arulampalam, W., M. P. Devereux, and G. Maani (2012). The Direct Incidence of Corporate Income Tax on Wages. European Economc Review 56 (6), 1038{1054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bender, S., A. Haas, and C. Klose (2000). The IAB Employment Subsample 1975- 1995. Schmollers Jahrbuch: Journal of Applied Social Science Studies 120 (4), 649{662.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bertrand, M., E. Duo, and S. Mullainathan (2004). How Much Should we Trust Di erence-in-Di erence Estimates? Quarterly Journal of Economics 119 (1), 249{ 275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bond, S. and J. Van Reenen (2007). Microeconometric Models of Investment and Employment. In J. J. Heckman and E. E. Leamer (Eds.), Handbook of Econometrics, Volume 6, Chapter 65, pp. 4417{4498. Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bradford, D. F. (1978). Factor prices may be constant but factor returns are not.Economics Letters 1 (3), 199{203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Burda, M. C. and J. Hunt (2001). From reuniacation to economic integration: productivity and the labor market in East Germany. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 2, 1{92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Carroll, R., D. Holtz-Eakin, M. Rider, and H. S. Rosen (2000). Income Taxes and Entrepreneurs' Use of Labor. Journal of Labor Economics 18 (2), 324{351.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Chirinko, R. S. (1993). Business Fixed Investment Spending: Modeling Strategies, Empirical Results, and Policy Implications. Journal of Economic Literature 31 (4), 1875{1911.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Dwenger, N., P. Rattenhuber, and V. Steiner (2011). Sharing the burden: Empirical evidence of corporate tax incidence. Preprint of the Max Planck Institute for Tax Law and Public Finance 2011-14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Eckey, H.-F., R. Kosfeld, and M. Taa&gt;½rck (2006). Delineation of German labour market regions. Raumforschung und Raumordnung 64 (4), 299{309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Elhorst, J. P. (2003). The Mystery of Regional Unemployment Di erentials: Theoretical and Empirical Explanations. Journal of Economic Surveys 17 (5), 709{748.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Felix, R. A. and J. R. Hines Jr. (2009). Corporate Taxes and Union Wages in the United States. NBER Working Paper No. 15263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Foremny, D. and N. Riedel (2014). Business Taxes and the Electoral Cycle. Journal of Public Economics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Fuest, C., A. Peichl, and S. Siegloch (2013). Do Higher Corporate Taxes Reduce Wages? Micro Evidence from Germany. IZA Discussion Paper No. 7390.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gebhardt, H. and L.-H. R. Siemers (2011). The relative tax burden of medium-sized corporations in Germany. MPRA Paper No. 28894.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gravelle, J. C. (2013). Corporate Tax Incidence: Review of General Equilibirum Estimates and Analysis. National Tax Journal 66 (1), 185{214.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Harberger, A. C. (1962). The incidence of the corporation income tax. Journal of Political Economy 70, 215{240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Harju, J. and T. Kosonen (2013). The Impact of Tax Incentives on the Economic Activity of Entrepreneurs. CESifo Working Paper No. 4259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Hassett, K. A. and R. G. Hubbard (2002). Tax policy and business investment. In A. J. Auerbach and M. Feldstein (Eds.), Handbook of Public Economics, Volume 3, pp. 1293{1343. Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Jones, D. W. (1982). The Interregional Incidence of Local Taxes with Migration and a Nontradable Good. Geographical Analysis 14 (2), 109{123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Kaolling, A. (2000). The IAB-Establishment Panel. Schmollers Jahrbuch: Journal of Applied Social Science Studies 120 (2), 291{300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Kotliko , L. J. (2014). Abolish the Corporate Income Tax. New York Times, January 4, 2014, http://www.nytimes.com/2014/01/06/opinion/abolishthe- corporate-income-tax.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Kotliko , L. J. and L. H. Summers (1987). Tax Incidence. In A. J. Auerbach and M. Feldstein (Eds.), Handbook of Public Economics, Volume 2, pp. 1043{1092.Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Liu, L. and R. Altshuler (2013). Measuring the burden of the corporate income tax under imperfect competition. National Tax Journal 66 (1), 215{237.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">McLure, C. E. (1969). The Interregional Incidence of General Regional Taxes. Public Finance 24 (3), 457{483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">McLure, C. E. (1970). Taxation, Substitution, and Industrial Location. Journal of Political Economy 78 (1), 112{132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Niebuhr, A., N. Granato, A. Haas, and S. Hamann (2012). Does Labour Mobility Reduce Disparities between Regional Labour Markets in Germany? Regional Studies 46 (7), 841{858.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Obama, B. (2014). State of the Union Address 2014. http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-oace/2014/01/28/president-barackobamas- state-union-address.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">OECD (2013). Addressing Base Erosion and Proat Shifting. Paris: OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Peichl, A. and S. Siegloch (2012). Accounting for Labor Demand E ects in Structural Labor Supply Models. Labour Economics 19 (1), 129{138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Suaarez Serrato, J. C. and O. Zidar (2014). Who Beneats from State Corporate Tax Cuts? A Local Labor Markets Approach with Heterogeneous Firm. mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Cross-sectional and time variation in local tax rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Time variation in local tax rates, 1992-2008</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Descriptive statistics, 1998-2008</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Event study estimates: baseline model</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Event study estimates: sensitivity</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Effect on ln median municipal employees: event study estimates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Effect on ln employees: baseline estimates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Effect on ln employees: heterogeneous establishment effects</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Effect on ln employees: heterogeneous worker groups</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Effects on ln employees, ln (net) investments and ln output</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Effect on ln net mean regional employment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Effect on ln employees: timing</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Effect on ln employees: clustering</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Effect on employees: level vs. log</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Effects on ln employees and ln total hours</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
