<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">5</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465733</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465738</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Informational Role of Stock and Bond Volume</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Kerry</given-names>
                  <surname>Back</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Kevin</given-names>
                  <surname>Crotty</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1381</fpage>
         <lpage>1427</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465738"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In a Kyle (1985) model, the sign of the correlation between a firm's debt and equity returns is the same as the sign of the cross-market Kyle's lambda. The sign is positive (negative) if private information concerns the mean (risk) of the firm's assets. We show empirically that information conveyed by order flows is primarily about asset means. The cross-market lambdas are quite large; consequently, the portions of bond and stock returns explained by order flows are highly correlated, even though the order flows themselves are virtually uncorrelated.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d2157577e254a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e261" publication-type="other">
Such regressions are run by Collin-Dufresne, Goldstein, and Martin (2001), Campbell and Taksler (2003), and
Cremers et al. (2008), using the VIX, idiosyncratic volatility, and implied volatilities, respectively, as the volatility
measure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e274a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e281" publication-type="other">
We provide empirical evidence that this is true, and as far as we know, we are the first to show this in any markets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e288a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e295" publication-type="other">
Our assumption that market makers observe order flow in both markets is not extreme. In the model, market
makers can infer orders from price changes, so the assumption that we actually need is post-trade transparency.
See Section 3.3 for a discussion of transparency in these markets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e308a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e315" publication-type="other">
It is without loss of generality to assume that the informed trades are of order df (dX=0dt for some 0), because
Back (1992) shows that jumps and Brownian motion components are suboptimal.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e326a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e333" publication-type="other">
A previous version of this paper used data from 2008 through 2011. FINRA publicly disclosed trade direction
indicators starting in November 2008. In this version, we employ the Enhanced TRACE database, which includes
trade direction indicators back to 2002. The Enhanced TRACE also does not top-censor volume for investment-
grade (high-yield) trades of $5 million ($1 million).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e349a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e356" publication-type="other">
Round-trip trades have been used to estimate transactions costs by Bessembinder, Maxwell, and Venkataraman
(2006), Goldstein, Hotchkiss, and Sirri (2007), and Feldhiitter (2012) for corporate bonds and Green, Hollifield,
and Schürhoff (2007) for municipal bonds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e369a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e376" publication-type="other">
We obtain similar results using excess returns rather than raw returns, suggesting that the relationship we study
is capturing the firm-specific information that is the focus of our study. Excess returns are calculated using an
equal-weighted index of returns in each market.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e389a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e396" publication-type="other">
In the model, price impacts are stochastic; that is, A is time varying and depends on cumulative order flow. We
estimate the empirical equivalent of dPt = A(/, Yt)dYt where dP is sampled at the daily or hourly frequency and
normalized by price. Our estimates represent an average price impact across firms and time. The (untabulated)
results are similar if we include quadratic signed order-flow terms in the return regressions to account for the
fact that we sample at a lower frequency than continuous time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e415a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e422" publication-type="other">
As discussed in Section 2, the matrix A is singular when there is binary information, but this is special to the case
of binary information. In a previous version of this paper with continuous information, we verified the theoretical
positive definiteness of A for trading a company's debt and equity. Other research on multisecurity Kyle models
also establishes positive definiteness (Back, 1993, Caballé and Krishnan, 1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e438a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e445" publication-type="other">
Specifically, the variance-covariance matrix is estimated as Vpirm&amp;Time = ^Firm + ^Time ~ ^Robust' as proposed
by Cameron, Gelbach, and Miller (2011) and Thompson (2011) and discussed in Petersen (2009). As a practical
matter, within-firm serial correlation has the largest effect on standard errors, which are largely unchanged when
additionally clustered by time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e462a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e469" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Breen, Hodrick, and Korajczyk (2002), Hasbrouck (2009), and Goyenko, Holden, and Trzcinka
(2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e479a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e486" publication-type="other">
We have also verified the positive definiteness of A without assuming symmetry. In the absence of symmetry,
A is positive definite if and only if A +A' is symmetric and positive definite. This is equivalent to Ybb &gt; 0 and
4pW?p,ss &gt; [ßTbs+y^ps6^ jn our sampie5 the ratio ^ has a median value of about 3. We can also
reject the null
' -(3°-5ri,s+3~a5rs6V |=o.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e505a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e512" publication-type="other">
We classify financial firms as those with SIC codes between 6000 and 6999.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e519a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e526" publication-type="other">
We thank an anonymous referee for suggesting this analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e533a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e540" publication-type="other">
Results are qualitatively similar for different lag lengths.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e547a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e554" publication-type="other">
This is the filter used by Rossi (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d2157577e562a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d2157577e569" publication-type="other">
This is the filter used by Han and Zhou (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d2157577e585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e589" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V. V., and T. C. Johnson. 2007. Insider trading in credit derivatives. Journal of Financial Economics
84:110-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e603" publication-type="other">
. 2010. More insiders, more insider trading: Evidence from private-equity buyouts. Journal of Financial
Economics 98:500-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e613a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e617" publication-type="other">
Alexander, G J., A. K. Edwards, and M. G Ferri. 2000. What does Nasdaq's high-yield bond market reveal about
bondholder-stockholder conflicts? Financial Management 29:23-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e627a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e631" publication-type="other">
Andrade, S. C., C. Chang, and M. S. Seasholes. 2008. Trading imbalances, predictable reversals, and cross-stock
price pressure. Journal of Financial Economics 88:406-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e642a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e646" publication-type="other">
Back, K. 1992. Insider trading in continuous time. Review of Financial Studies 5:387^409.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e653a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e657" publication-type="other">
. 1993. Asymmetric information and options. Review of Financial Studies 6:435-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e668" publication-type="other">
Back, K., K. Crotty, and T. Li. 2014. Can information asymmetry be identified from order flows alone? Working
Paper, Rice University and City University of Hong Kong.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e678a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e682" publication-type="other">
Bai, J., and P. Collin-Dufresne. 2013. The determinants of the CDS-bond basis during the financial crisis of
2007-2009. Working Paper, Georgetown University and Swiss Finance Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e692a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e696" publication-type="other">
Bessembinder, H., W. Maxwell, and K. Venkataraman. 2006. Market transparency, liquidity externalities, and
institutional trading costs in corporate bonds. Journal of Financial Economics 82:251-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e706a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e710" publication-type="other">
Bodnaruk, A., and M. Rossi. 2013. Dual ownership, returns, and voting in mergers. Working Paper, University
of Notre Dame and Texas A&amp;M University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e721a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e725" publication-type="other">
Boot, A., and A. Thakor. 1993. Security design. Journal of Finance 48:1349-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e732a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e736" publication-type="other">
Boulatov, A., T. Hendershott, and D. Livdan. 2013. Informed trading and portfolio returns. Review of Economic
Studies 80:35-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e746a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e750" publication-type="other">
Breen, W. J., L. S. Hodrick, and R. A. Korajczyk. 2002. Predicting equity liquidity. Management Science 48:
470-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e760a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e764" publication-type="other">
Caballé, J., and M. Krishnan. 1994. Imperfect competition in a multi-security market with risk neutrality.
Econometrica 62:695-704.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e774a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e778" publication-type="other">
Cameron, A. C., J. B. Gelbach, and D. L. Miller. 2011. Robust inference with multiway clustering. Journal of
Business and Economic Statistics 29:238-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e788a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e792" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and G B. Taksler. 2003. Equity volatility and corporate bond yields. Journal of Finance 58:
2321-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e803a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e807" publication-type="other">
Chan, K., Y. P. Chung, and W.-M. Fong. 2002. The informational role of stock and option volume. Review of
Financial Studies 15:1049-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e817a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e821" publication-type="other">
Chan, K., A. Menkveld, and Z. Yang. 2007. The informativeness of domestic and foreign investors' stock trades:
Evidence from the perfectly segmented Chinese market. Journal of Financial Markets 10:391-415.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e831a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e835" publication-type="other">
Chang, C., and X. Yu. 2010. Informational efficiency and liquidity premium as the determinants of capital
structure. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 45:401-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e845a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e849" publication-type="other">
Chordia, T., A. Sarkar, and A. Subrahmanyam. 2005. An empirical analysis of stock and bond market liquidity.
Review of Financial Studies 18:85-129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e859a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e863" publication-type="other">
Collin-Dufresne, P., R. S. Goldstein, and J. S. Martin. 2001. The determinants of credit spread changes. Journal
of Finance 56:2177-207.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e873a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e877" publication-type="other">
Cremers, M., J. Driessen, P. Maenhout, and D. Weinbaum. 2008. Individual stock-option prices and credit spreads.
Journal of Banking and Finance 32:2706-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e888a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e892" publication-type="other">
Dick-Nielsen, J. 2009. Liquidity biases in TRACE. Journal of Fixed Income 19:43-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e899a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e903" publication-type="other">
Downing, C., S. Underwood, and Y. Xing. 2009. The relative informational efficiency of stocks and bonds: An
intraday analysis. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 44:1081-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e913a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e917" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., N. Garleanu, and L. H. Pedersen. 2005. Over-the-counter markets. Econometrica 73:1815-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e928" publication-type="other">
Edwards, A. K., L. E. Harris, and M. S. Piwowar. 2007. Corporate bond market transaction costs and transparency.
Journal of Finance 62:1421-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e942" publication-type="other">
Feldhiitter, P. 2012. The same bond at different prices: Identifying search frictions and selling pressures. Review
of Financial Studies 25:1155-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e952a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e956" publication-type="other">
Fulghieri, P., and D. Lukin. 2001. Information production, dilution costs, and optimal security design. Journal
of Financial Economics 61:3-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e967a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e971" publication-type="other">
Goldstein, M. A., E. S. Hotchkiss, and E. R. Sirri. 2007. Transparency and liquidity: A controlled experiment on
corporate bonds. Review of Financial Studies 20:235-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e985" publication-type="other">
Goyenko, R. Y., C. W. Holden, and C. A. Trzcinka. 2009. Do liquidity measures measure liquidity? Journal of
Financial Economics 92:153-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e995a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e999" publication-type="other">
Green, R. C., B. Hollifield, and N. Schürhoff. 2007. Financial intermediation and the costs of trading in an opaque
market. Review of Financial Studies 20:275-314.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1009a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1013" publication-type="other">
Han, S., and H. Zhou. 2008. Effects of liquidity on the nondefault component of corporate yield spreads: Evidence
from intraday transactions data. Working Paper, Federal Reserve Board.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1023a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1027" publication-type="other">
Han, S., and X. Zhou. 2014. Informed bond trading, corporate yield spreads, and corporate default prediction.
Management Science 60:675-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1037a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1041" publication-type="other">
Hasbrouck, J. 1991. Measuring the information content of stock trades. Journal of Finance 46:179-207.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1049a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1053" publication-type="other">
. 1995. One security, many markets: Determining the contributions to price discovery. Journal of Finance
50:1175-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1067" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Trading costs and returns for U.S. equities: Estimating effective costs from daily data. Journal of
Finance 64:1445-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1077a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1081" publication-type="other">
He, Z., and K. Milbradt. 2014. Endogenous liquidity and defaultable bonds. Econometrica 82:1443-508.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1088a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1092" publication-type="other">
Hilscher, J., J. M. Pollet, and M. Wilson, forthcoming. Are credit default swaps a sideshow? Evidence that
information flows from equity to CDS markets. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1102a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1106" publication-type="other">
Hotchkiss, E. S., and T. Ronen. 2002. The informational efficiency of the corporate bond market: An intraday
analysis. Review of Financial Studies 15:1325-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1116a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1120" publication-type="other">
Jones, C. M., G Kaul, and M. L. Lipson. 1994. Transactions, volume, and volatility. Review of Financial Studies
7:631-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1131a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1135" publication-type="other">
Kapadia, N., and X. Pu. 2012. Limited arbitrage between equity and credit markets. Journal of Financial
Economics 105:542-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1145a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1149" publication-type="other">
Karatzas, I., and S. E. Shreve. 1988. Brownian motion and stochastic calculus. New York: Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1156a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1160" publication-type="other">
Kedia, S., and X. Zhou. 2014. Informed trading around acquisitions: Evidence from corporate bonds. Journal of
Financial Markets 18:182-205.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1170a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1174" publication-type="other">
Korajczyk, R. A., D. J. Lucas, and R. L. McDonald. 1991. The effect of information releases on the pricing and
timing of equity issues. Review of Financial Studies 4:685-708.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1188" publication-type="other">
Kwan, S. H. 1996. Firm-specific information and the correlation between individual stocks and bonds. Journal
of Financial Economics 40:63-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1202" publication-type="other">
Kyle, A. S. 1985. Continuous auctions and insider trading. Econometrica 53:1315-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1210a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1214" publication-type="other">
Lee, C. M., and M. J. Ready. 1991. Inferring trade direction from intraday data. Journal of Finance 46:733-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1221a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1225" publication-type="other">
Lesmond, D. A., R F. O'Connor, and L. W. Senbet. 2008. Capital structure and equity liquidity. Working Paper,
University of Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1235a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1239" publication-type="other">
Mao, Y. 2013. Price discovery in the stock and corporate bond markets. Working Paper, Indiana University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1250" publication-type="other">
McCracken, J. 2008. Delphi recovery hits snag; bankruptcy-court exit sidetracked by disputes with investor
groups. Wall Street Journal, March 13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1260a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1264" publication-type="other">
O'Hara, M., C. Yao, and M. Ye. 2014. What's not there: Odd lots and market data. Journal of Finance 69:
2199-236.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1278" publication-type="other">
Pasquariello, P., and C. Vega, forthcoming. Strategic cross-trading in the U.S. stock market. Review of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1290" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M. A. 2009. Estimating standard errors in finance panel data sets: Comparing approaches. Review of
Financial Studies 22:435-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1304" publication-type="other">
Ronen, T., and X. Zhou. 2013. Trade and information in the corporate bond market. Journal of Financial Markets
16:61-103.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1318" publication-type="other">
Rossi, M. 2009. Realized volatility, liquidity, and corporate yield spreads. Working Paper, University of Notre
Dame.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1332" publication-type="other">
Rourke, T. 2014. The delta- and vega-related information content of near-the-money option market trading
activity. Journal of Financial Markets 20:175-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1346" publication-type="other">
Schultz, P. 2001. Corporate bond trading costs: A peek behind the curtain. Journal of Finance 56:677-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1357" publication-type="other">
Szockyj, E. 1993. Insider trading: The SEC meets Carl Karcher. Annals of the American Academy of Political
and Social Science 52:46-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1372" publication-type="other">
Thompson, S. B. 2011. Simple formulas for standard errors that cluster by both firm and time. Journal of Financial
Economics 99:1-10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1386" publication-type="other">
Tookes, H. E. 2008. Information, trading, and product market interactions: Cross-sectional implications of
informed trading. Journal of Finance 63:379-413.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1400" publication-type="other">
Veronesi, P. 1999. Stock market overreaction to bad news in good times: A rational expectations equilibrium
model. Review of Financial Studies 12:975-1007.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1410a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1414" publication-type="other">
Wei, J., and X. Zhou. 2012. Informed trading in corporate bonds prior to earnings announcements. Working
Paper, University of Toronto and Rutgers University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2157577e1424a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2157577e1428" publication-type="other">
Zhu, H. 2012. Finding a good price in opaque over-the-counter markets. Review of Financial Studies 25:
1255-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


