<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">9</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466905</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466908</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Capital Structure, Investment, and Fire Sales</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Douglas</given-names>
                  <surname>Gale</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Piero</given-names>
                  <surname>Gottardi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2502</fpage>
         <lpage>2533</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466908"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We study a dynamic general equilibrium model in which firms choose their investment level and capital structure, trading off the tax advantages of debt against the risk of costly default. Bankruptcy costs are endogenous, as bankrupt firms are forced to liquidate their assets, resulting in a fire sale if the market is illiquid. When the corporate income tax rate is positive, firms have a unique optimal capital structure. In equilibrium, firms default with positive probability and their assets are liquidated at fire-sale prices. The equilibrium features underinvestment and is constrained inefficient. In particular there is too little debt and default.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d726333e126a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e133" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Barnea, Haugen, and Senbet (1981), Bradley, Jarrell, and Kim (2011), Brennan and Schwartz
(1978), Dammon and Green (1987), Fischer, Heinkel, and Zechner (1989), Kim (1982), Leland and Toft (1996),
Miller (1977), Titman (1984), and Titman and Wessels (1988).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e146a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e153" publication-type="other">
To be precise, for each individual firm any combination of debt and equity is optimal. There is however a
constraint on the aggregate amount of debt in the economy, that has to be small enough that fire sales do not
occur.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e166a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e173" publication-type="other">
We do not wish to claim too much for this result, of course. The optimal capital structure is unique only within a
given (symmetric) equilibrium. In general, the capital structure depends on the equilibrium, which in turn depends
on the model parameters, including policy parameters, such as the tax rate. But note that the Modigliani-Miller
theorem also holds for a given equilibrium of a given model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e189a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e196" publication-type="other">
The cost of increasing the firm's debt level has two components. First, the probability of going bankrupt and
having to liquidate assets in a fire sale increases. Second, the probability of making capital gains when solvent
by buying assets of other firms in a fire sale is reduced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e210a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e217" publication-type="other">
The data that Eisfeldt and Rampini (2006) use to measure capital reallocation is deflated using the CPI. Since the
price of capital may vary over the cycle and would be expected to be lower in distress sales than in non-distressed
sales, the figures are likely to understate capital reallocation resulting from fire sales.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e230a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e237" publication-type="other">
The finance constraint takes the form of a liquidity constraint similar to the familiar cash-in-advance constraint
used in macroeconomic and monetary models. We prefer the term finance constraint, first, because there is no
money in the model and, second, because we interpret the constraint as merely ruling out the possibility of
borrowing to fund the purchase of asset trades due to the urgency of these transactions, rather than requiring
"cash on the barrelhead."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e256a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e263" publication-type="other">
In the dynamic environment considered, at any t both the resale price qt and the full value vt are endogenous.
As further discussed in Section 5.2, we could allow for an additional, deadweight cost of bankruptcy, with no
substantial change in the results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e276a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e283" publication-type="other">
A model of this process is found in Shleifer and Vishny (1992).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e290a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e297" publication-type="other">
Here, and in what follows, it is convenient to denote the face value of the debt issued per unit of capital acquired
by dt.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e307a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e314" publication-type="other">
Because a fraction of firms default each period, the surviving firms who acquire their capital may grow in size
in sub-period B but are then indifferent between buying or selling capital at vt in sub-period C. Hence, we can
always consider a situation in which the mass of active firms remains unchanged over time, whereas their size
varies with kt.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e331a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e338" publication-type="other">
The level of z determines the face value of the debt as in (8).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e345a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e352" publication-type="other">
In the Online Appendix we show formally the equivalence between a proportional tax on corporate earnings and
a proportional tax on the value of equity in a slightly simpler specification of the environment, where depreciation
is nonstochastic.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e365a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e372" publication-type="other">
When vt+i =qt+, the solution is clearly full debt financing, zt+ = 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e379a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e386" publication-type="other">
The (average) value of firms owning the initial endowment of capital equals the value of the output Ak$
produced with this capital in sub-period A, plus the value of the capital left after depreciation in sub-period C,
ÖkQVQ. Because they are, as we said, financed entirely with equity, this coincides with their equity value. Also,
while producers of capital good operate and hence distribute profits in every period t &gt; 0, the first equity issue is
at the end of date 0, and hence the first tax revenue on equity earnings is at date / = 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e405a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e412" publication-type="other">
As explained above, the returns on diversified equity and debt are deterministic. Thus, vf* and vf* must be such
that the one-period expected returns on debt and equity are equal to the risk free-rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e422a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e429" publication-type="other">
The term on the denominator, is obtained from the expression of the pretax value of the equity of the firm, when
solvent, obtained in (11). This is then subtracted from the overall value of the firm, in (13), to obtain the value
of debt.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e443a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e450" publication-type="other">
Condition 2 above is in fact stated for this case.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e457a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e464" publication-type="other">
Because there is no aggregate uncertainty, risk aversion is not an issue. The only role played by the curvature of
the utility function is to determine the intertemporal marginal rate of substitution (IMRS). By assuming that the
utility function is linear, one imposes a constant IMRS. This restricts somewhat the adjustment of endogenous
variables along the transition path but is otherwise innocuous.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e480a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e487" publication-type="other">
When the initial capital stock k^=kFB the unique Pareto-efficient allocation of the economy is the Pareto-efficient
steady state. Because the equilibrium allocation is different, it is clearly Pareto inefficient. For other values of k$,
the transitional dynamics of the Pareto-efficient allocation needs also to be considered to claim the inefficiency
of the equilibrium. This can be shown formally by proceeding along similar lines to the ones of the next section.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e503a1310">
            <label>2®</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e510" publication-type="other">
See in particular the proof of Proposition 6 in the Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e517a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e524" publication-type="other">
We focus attention on a permanent intervention, but it is fairly easy to verify that the same welfare result holds
in the case of a temporary intervention.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e534a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e541" publication-type="other">
See footnote 18 for a discussion of this specification of consumers' preferences.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e549a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e556" publication-type="other">
We used here (9) and the property 1+r,+; = 1 /&lt;$, following from the specification of consumers' preferences, to
simplify the expression.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e566a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e573" publication-type="other">
Note that expressions (21) and (22) give us the new equilibrium levels of q and v also for any discrete change
Az, as long as we have v &gt;q, that is, as long as z + Az is not too close to zero.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e583a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e590" publication-type="other">
Note that the equilibrium condition (21) has an admissible solution for all z + Az&lt;, but not in the limit for
z+Az = l.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e600a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e607" publication-type="other">
In contrast, we see from (12), that when firms act as price takers their optimal decision when q -&gt; 0 is z ~0.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e614a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e621" publication-type="other">
Also, in Lorenzoni (2008) and some of the other papers mentioned in the Introduction the capital of bankrupt
firms can only be sold to different types of firms who operate a less productive technology, hence there is;
deadweight cost attached to fire sales.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e634a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e641" publication-type="other">
See the Online Appendix for a formal analysis of this case and the derivation of some properties of equilibria.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d726333e649a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d726333e656" publication-type="other">
The details are in the Online Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d726333e672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e676" publication-type="other">
Aghion, P., O. Hart, and J. H. Moore. 1992. The economics of bankruptcy reform. Journal of Law, Economics
and Organization 8:523-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e686a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e690" publication-type="other">
Allen, F., and D. Gale. 2004a. Financial intermediaries and markets. Econometrica 72:1023-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e701" publication-type="other">
. 2004b. Financial fragility, liquidity, and asset prices. Journal of the European Economic Association
2:1015-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e715" publication-type="other">
Arnott, R., and J. E. Stiglitz. 1986. Moral hazard and optimal commodity taxation. Journal of Public Economics
29:1-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e726a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e730" publication-type="other">
Barnea, A., R. A. Haugen, and L. W. Senbet. 1981. An equilibrium analysis of debt financing under costly tax
arbitrage and agency problems. Journal of Finance 36:569-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e740a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e744" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L. A. 1988. A new approach to corporate reorganizations. Harvard Law Review 101:775-804.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e751a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e755" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B. S., and M. Gertler. 1989. Agency costs, net worth, and business fluctuations. American Economic
Review 79:14—31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e765a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e769" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B. S., M. Gertler, and S. Gilchrist. 1999. The financial accelerator in a quantitative business cycle
framework. In Handbook of macroeconomics, 1341-93, vol. 1, part C. Ed. J. B. Taylor and M. Woodford.
Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e786" publication-type="other">
Bianchi, J. 2011. Overborrowing and systemic externalities in the business cycle. American Economic Review
101:3400-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e796a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e800" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., H. Chen, and N. Wang. 2013. A unified theory of Tobin's q, corporate investment, financing, and risk
management. Journal of Finance 66:1545-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e811a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e815" publication-type="other">
Bradley, M., G A. Jarrell, and E. H. Kim. 2011. On the existence of an optimal capital structure: Theory and
evidence. Journal of Finance 39:857-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e829" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M. J., and E. S. Schwartz. 1978. Corporate income taxes, valuation, and the problem of optimal capital
structure. Journal of Business 51:103-14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e843" publication-type="other">
Dammon, R. M., and Richard C. Green. 1987. Tax arbitrage and the existence of equilibrium prices for financial
assets. Journal of Finance 42:1143-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e857" publication-type="other">
Eberly, J., S. Rebelo, and N. Vincent. 2008. Investment and value: A neoclassical benchmark. Working Paper,
NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e871" publication-type="other">
Eisfeldt, A., and A. Rampini. 2006. Capital reallocation and liquidity. Journal of Monetary Economics 53:369-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e878a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e882" publication-type="other">
Fischer, E. O., R. Heinkel, and J. Zechner. 1989. Dynamic capital structure choice: Theory and tests. Journal of
Finance 44:19-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e893a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e897" publication-type="other">
Gale, D., and R Gottardi. 2011. Bankruptcy, finance constraints and the value of the firm. American Economic
Journal: Micro 3:1-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e911" publication-type="other">
Geanakoplos, J., and H. Polemarchakis. 1986. Existence, regularity, and constrained suboptimality of competitive
allocations when the asset market is incomplete. In Essays in honor of Kenneth J. Arrow: Uncertainty, information
and communication, 65-95, vol. 3. Ed. W. Heller, R. Starr, and D. Starret. Cambridge: Cambridge University
Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e927a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e931" publication-type="other">
Gersbach, H., and J.-C. Rochet. 2012. Aggregate investment externalities and macroprudential regulation. Journal
of Money, Credit and Banking 44:73-109.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e941a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e945" publication-type="other">
Gertler, M., and N. Kiyotaki. 2010. Financial intermediation and credit policy in business cycle analysis. In
Handbook of monetary economics, 547-99, vol. 3 A. Ed. B. M. Friedman and M. Woodford. Amsterdam: North-
Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e962" publication-type="other">
Gomes, J., and L. Schmid. 2010. Equilibrium credit spreads and the macroeconomy. Paper presented at the
American Financial Association Meetings, Atlanta, GA, January 3-5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e972a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e976" publication-type="other">
Greenwald, B. C., and J. E. Stiglitz. 1986. Externalities in economies with imperfect information and incomplete
markets. Quarterly Journal of Economics 101:229-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e987a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e991" publication-type="other">
Hackbarth, D., and D. C. Mauer. 1979. Optimal priority structure, capital structure, and investment. Review of
Financial Studies 25:747-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1001a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1005" publication-type="other">
Hart, O. D. 1979. On shareholder unanimity in large stock market economies. Econometrica 47:1057-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1012a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1016" publication-type="other">
Kim, E. H. 1982. Miller's equilibrium, shareholder leverage clienteles, and optimal capital structure. Journal of
Finance 37:301-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1026a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1030" publication-type="other">
Kiyotaki, N., and J. Moore. 1997. Credit cycles. Journal of Political Economy 105:211-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1037a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1041" publication-type="other">
Korinek, A. 2012. Systemic risk-taking: Amplification effects, externalities, and regulatory responses.
Manuscript, University of Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1051a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1055" publication-type="other">
Kuehn, L.-A., and L. Schmid. 2014. Investment-based corporate bond pricing. Journal of Finance 69:2741-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1067" publication-type="other">
Leland, H. E., and K. B. Toft. 1996. Optimal capital structure, endogenous bankruptcy, and the term structure of
credit spreads. Journal of Finance 51:987-1019.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1077a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1081" publication-type="other">
Lorenzoni, G 2008. Inefficient credit booms. Review of Economic Studies 75:809-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1088a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1092" publication-type="other">
Miao, J., and P Wang. 2010. Credit risk and business cycles. Manuscript, Boston University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1099a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1103" publication-type="other">
Miller, M. H. 1977. Debt and taxes. Journal of Finance 32:261-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1110a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1114" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F., and M. H. Miller. 1958. The cost of capital, corporation finance and the theory of investment.
American Economic Review 48:261-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1124a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1128" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A., and R. W. Vishny. 1992. Liquidation values and debt capacity: A market equilibrium approach.
Journal of Finance 47:1343-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1139a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1143" publication-type="other">
Sundaresan, S., N. Wang, and J. Yang. 2014. Dynamic investment, capital structure, and debt overhang. Available
at http://www0.gsb.columbia.edu/faculty/nwang/papers/Sundaresan_Wang_Yang_2014.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1153a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1157" publication-type="other">
Titman, S. 1984. The effect of capital structure on a firm's liquidation decision. Journal of Financial Economics
13:137-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1167a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1171" publication-type="other">
Titman, S., and Roberto Wessels. 1988. The determinants of capital structure choice. Journal of Finance 43:1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d726333e1178a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d726333e1182" publication-type="other">
Wagner, W. 2011. Systemic liquidation risk and the diversity—diversification trade-off. Journal of Finance
66:1141-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


