<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422619</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Kinetic Modelling Study of Alcohols Operating Regimes in a HCCI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pelucchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Matteo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bissoli</surname>
                  <given-names>Mattia</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rizzo</surname>
                  <given-names>Cristina</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yingjia</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>National University of Ireland Galway</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Somers</surname>
                  <given-names>Kieran</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>National University of Ireland Galway</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Frassoldati</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Curran</surname>
                  <given-names>Henry</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>National University of Ireland Galway</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Faravelli</surname>
                  <given-names>Tiziano</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422609</issue-id>
         <fpage>2354</fpage>
         <lpage>2370</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422619"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Pursuing a sustainable energy scenario for transportation requires the blending of renewable oxygenated fuels such as alcohols into commercial hydrocarbon fuels. From a chemical kinetic perspective, this requires the accurate description of both hydrocarbon reference fuels (<italic>n</italic>-heptane, <italic>iso</italic>-octane, toluene, etc.) and oxygenated fuels chemistry. A recent systematic investigation of linear C₂-C₅ alcohols ignition in a rapid compression machine at p = 10-30 bar and T = 650-900 K has extended the scarcity of fundamental data at such conditions, allowing for a revision of the low temperature chemistry for alcohol fuels in the POLIMI mechanism. Heavier alcohols such as <italic>n</italic>-butanol and <italic>n</italic>-pentanol present ignition characteristic of interest for application in HCCI engines, due to the presence of the hydroxyl moiety reducing their low temperature reactivity compared to the parent linear alkanes (i.e. higher octane number). The promising performances of ethanol in a HCCI engine have been recently discussed by Bissoli et al. (<italic>Energy &amp; Fuels, 2017, Submitted</italic>), observing wider stable operability conditions in terms of fuel/air load (λ) and exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) extent compared to PRF80 and PRF100. The aim of this study is to present briefly the reliability of the updated POLIMI mechanism for heavier alcohols and to investigate the fundamental role of chemical kinetics on the performance maps of HCCI engines fueled with <italic>n</italic>-butanol and <italic>n</italic>-pentanol, in terms of operability limits and engine efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Exxonmobil, The Outlook for Energy: A View to 2040, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C2ES, Outcomes of the UN climate change conference in Paris. http://www.c2es.org/docUploads/cop-21-paris-summary-02-2016-final.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coniglio L., Bennadji H., Glaude P.A., Herbinet O., Billaud F., Combustion chemical kinetics of biodiesel and related compounds (methyl and ethyl esters): experiments and modeling-advances and future refinements, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 39 (2013) 340-382.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahabuddin M., Liaquat A., Masjuki H., Kalam M., Mofijur M., Ignition delay, combustion and emission characteristics of diesel engine fueled with biodiesel, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 21 (2013) 623-632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sarathy S.M., Oßwald P., Hansen N., Kohse-Höinghaus K., Alcohol combustion chemistry, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 44 (2014) 40-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sudholt A., Cai L., Heyne J., Haas F.M., Pitsch H., Dryer F.L., Ignition characteristics of a bio-derived class of saturated and unsaturated furans for engine applications, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 35 (2015) 2957-2965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atsumi S., Hanai T., Liao J.C., Non-fermentative pathways for synthesis of branched-chain higher alcohols as biofuels, Nature 451 (2008) 86-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peralta-Yahya P.P., Keasling J.D., Advanced biofuel production in microbes, Biotechnology journal 5 (2010) 147-162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA, Federal Register Environmental Protection Agency Federal Register, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos D., Rakopoulos C., Giakoumis E., Dimaratos A., Kyritsis D., Effects of butanol-diesel fuel blends on the performance and emissions of a high-speed DI diesel engine, Energy Conversion and Management 51 (2010) 1989-1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siwale L., Kristóf L., Adam T., Bereczky A., Mbarawa M., Penninger A., Kolesnikov A., Combustion and emission characteristics of n-butanol/diesel fuel blend in a turbo-charged compression ignition engine, Fuel 107 (2013) 409-418.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Valentino G., Corcione F.E., Iannuzzi S.E., Serra S., Experimental study on performance and emissions of a high speed diesel engine fuelled with n-butanol diesel blends under premixed low temperature combustion, Fuel 92 (2012) 295-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campos-Fernandez J., Arnal J.M., Gomez J., Lacalle N., Dorado M.P., Performance tests of a diesel engine fueled with pentanol/diesel fuel blends, Fuel 107 (2013) 866-872.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei L., Cheung C., Huang Z., Effect of n-pentanol addition on the combustion, performance and emission characteristics of a directinjection diesel engine, Energy 70 (2014) 172-180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li L., Wang J., Wang Z., Xiao J., Combustion and emission characteristics of diesel engine fueled with diesel/biodiesel/pentanol fuel blends, Fuel 156 (2015) 211-218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi G.T., The outlook for fuels for internal combustion engines, International Journal of Engine Research, (2014) 1468087414526189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergthorson J.M., Thomson M.J., A review of the combustion and emissions properties of advanced transportation biofuels and their impact on existing and future engines, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 42 (2015) 1393-1417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morgan N., Smallbone A., Bhave A., Kraft M., Cracknell R., Kalghatgi G., Mapping surrogate gasoline compositions into RON/MON space, Combustion and Flame 157 (2010) 1122-1131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao M., Zheng Z., Liu H., Progress and recent trends in homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engines, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 35 (2009) 398-437.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Epping, K., Aceves, S., Bechtold, R., and Dec, J., "The Potential of HCCI Combustion for High Efficiency and Low Emissions," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1923, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Komninos N., Rakopoulos C., Modeling HCCI combustion of biofuels: A review, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 16 (2012) 1588-1610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu M.-B., He B.-Q., Zhao H., Effect of air dilution and effective compression ratio on the combustion characteristics of a HCCI (homogeneous charge compression ignition) engine fuelled with n-butanol, Energy 85 (2015) 296-303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, X., Wang, M., and Zheng, M., "An Enabling Study of Neat n-Butanol HCCI Combustion on a High Compression-ratio Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0001, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xie, K., Yanai, T., Yang, Z., Reader, G. et al., "Emission Analysis of HCCI Combustion in a Diesel Engine Fueled by Butanol," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0749, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mack J.H., Schuler D., Butt R.H., Dibble R.W., Experimental investigation of butanol isomer combustion in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) engines, Applied Energy 165 (2016) 612-626.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martinez-Frias, J., Aceves, S., Flowers, D., Smith, J. et al., "HCCI Engine Control by Thermal Management," SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2869, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2869.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yelvington, P. and Green, W., "Prediction of the Knock Limit and Viable Operating Range for a Homogeneous-Charge Compression-Ignition (HCCI) Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1092, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1092.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., Sjöberg, M. et al., "Partial Fuel Stratification to Control HCCI Heat Release Rates: Fuel Composition and Other Factors Affecting Pre-Ignition Reactions of Two-Stage Ignition Fuels," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1903-1920, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aichlmayr H., Kittelson D., Zachariah M., Miniature free-piston homogeneous charge compression ignition engine-compressor concept-Part II: modeling HCCI combustion in small scales with detailed homogeneous gas phase chemical kinetics, Chemical Engineering Science 57 (2002) 4173-4186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pinheiro, A., Vuilleumier, D., Kozarac, D., and Saxena, S., "Simulating a Complete Performance Map of an Ethanol-Fueled Boosted HCCI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0821, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortiz-Soto E., Assanis D., Babajimopoulos A., A comprehensive engine to drive-cycle modelling framework for the fuel economy assessment of advanced engine and combustion technologies, International Journal of Engine Research 13 (2012) 287-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bissoli M., Frassoldati A., Cuoci A., Ranzi E., Mehl M., Faravelli T., A new predictive multi-zone model for HCCI engine combustion, Applied Energy 178 (2016) 826-843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agbro E., Tomlin A.S., Lawes M., Park S., Sarathy S.M., The influence of n-butanol blending on the ignition delay times of gasoline and its surrogate at high pressures, Fuel 187 (2017) 211-219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frassoldati A., Cuoci A., Faravelli T., Niemann U., Ranzi E., Seiser R., Seshadri K., An experimental and kinetic modeling study of n-propanol and iso-propanol combustion, Combustion and Flame 157 (2010) 2-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grana R., Frassoldati A., Faravelli T., Niemann U., Ranzi E., Seiser R., Cattolica R., Seshadri K., An experimental and kinetic modeling study of combustion of isomers of butanol, Combustion and Flame 157 (2010) 2137-2154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nativel D., Pelucchi M., Frassoldati A., Comandini A., Cuoci A., Ranzi E., Chaumeix N., Faravelli T., Laminar flame speeds of pentanol isomers: An experimental and modeling study, Combustion and Flame 166 (2016) 1-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pelucchi M., Cavallotti C., Ranzi E., Frassoldati A., Faravelli T., Relative Reactivity of Oxygenated Fuels: Alcohols, Aldehydes, Ketones, and Methyl Esters, Energy &amp; Fuels 30 (2016) 8665-8679.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heufer K.A., Sarathy S.M., Curran H.J., Davis A.C., Westbrook C.K., Pitz W.J., Detailed kinetic modeling study of n-pentanol oxidation, Energy &amp; Fuels 26 (2012) 6678-6685.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carstensen H.-H., Dean A.M., Development of detailed kinetic models for the thermal conversion of biomass via first principle methods and rate estimation rules, Computational Modeling in Lignocellulosic Biofuel Production, Oxford University Press, Oxford, UK 201 (2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumar K., Zhang Y., Sung C.-J., Pitz W.J., Autoignition response of n-butanol and its blends with primary reference fuel constituents of gasoline, Combustion and Flame 162 (2015) 2466-2479.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranzi E., Frassoldati A., Stagni A., Pelucchi M., Cuoci A., Faravelli T., Reduced kinetic schemes of complex reaction systems: fossil and biomass-derived transportation fuels, International Journal of Chemical Kinetics 46 (2014) 512-542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pelucchi M., Bissoli M., Cavallotti C., Cuoci A., Faravelli T., Frassoldati A., Ranzi E., Stagni A., Improved kinetic model of the low-temperature oxidation of n-heptane, Energy &amp; Fuels 28 (2014) 7178-7193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pelucchi M., Development of Kinetic Mechanisms for the Combustion of Renewable Fuels, Department of Chemistry, Materials and Chemical Engineering "G. Natta", Politecnico di Milano, 2017, pp. 406.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranzi E., Dente M., Goldaniga A., Bozzano G., Faravelli T., Lumping procedures in detailed kinetic modeling of gasification, pyrolysis, partial oxidation and combustion of hydrocarbon mixtures, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 27 (2001) 99-139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranzi E., Frassoldati A., Granata S., Faravelli T., Wide-range kinetic modeling study of the pyrolysis, partial oxidation, and combustion of heavy n-alkanes, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research 44 (2005) 5170-5183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Darcy D., Nakamura H., Tobin C., Mehl M., Metcalfe W., Pitz W., Westbrook C., Curran H., A high-pressure rapid compression machine study of n-propylbenzene ignition, Combustion and Flame 161 (2014) 65-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burke S., Simmie J., Curran H., Critical Evaluation of Thermochemical Properties of C1-C4 Species: Updated Group-Contributions to Estimate Thermochemical Properties, Journal of Physical and Chemical Reference Data 44 (2015) 013101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou C.-W., Simmie J.M., Curran H.J., Rate constants for hydrogenabstraction by from n-butanol, Combustion and Flame 158 (2011) 726-731.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhou C.W., Simmie J.M., Curran H.J., Rate constants for hydrogen abstraction by HO˙2 from n-butanol, International Journal of Chemical Kinetics 44 (2012) 155-164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katsikadakos D., Zhou C.-W., Simmie J., Curran H., Hunt P., Hardalupas Y., Taylor A., Rate constants of hydrogen abstraction by methyl radical from n-butanol and a comparison of CanTherm, MultiWell and Variflex, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 34 (2013) 483-491.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranzi E., Dente M., Faravelli T., Pennati G., Prediction of kinetic parameters for hydrogen abstraction reactions, Combustion science and technology 95 (1993) 1-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran H., Rate constant estimation for C1 to C4 alkyl and alkoxyl radical decomposition, International journal of chemical kinetics 38 (2006) 250-275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran H., Gaffuri P., Pitz W.J., Westbrook C.K., A comprehensive modeling study of n-heptane oxidation, Combustion and flame 114 (1998) 149-177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zádor J., Fernandes R.X., Georgievskii Y., Meloni G., Taatjes C.A., Miller J.A., The reaction of hydroxyethyl radicals with O 2: A theoretical analysis and experimental product study, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 32 (2009) 271-277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">da Silva G., Bozzelli J.W., Liang L., Farrell J.T., Ethanol oxidation: Kinetics of the α-hydroxyethyl radical+ O2 reaction, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A 113 (2009) 8923-8933.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Welz O., Klippenstein S.J., Harding L.B., Taatjes C.A., Zádor J., Unconventional peroxy chemistry in alcohol oxidation: the water elimination pathway, The journal of physical chemistry letters 4 (2013) 350-354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pelucchi M., Ranzi E., Frassoldati A., Faravelli T., Alkyl radicals rule the low temperature oxidation of long chain aldehydes, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, (2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pelucchi M., Somers K.P., Yasunaga K., Burke U., Frassoldati A., Ranzi E., Curran H.J., Faravelli T., An experimental and kinetic modeling study of the pyrolysis and oxidation of n-C 3 C 5 aldehydes in shock tubes, Combustion and Flame 162 (2015) 265-286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cuoci A., Frassoldati A., Faravelli T., Ranzi E., OpenSMOKE++: An object-oriented framework for the numerical modeling of reactive systems with detailed kinetic mechanisms, Computer Physics Communications 192 (2015) 237-264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vranckx S., Heufer K., Lee C., Olivier H., Schill L., Kopp W., Leonhard K., Taatjes C., Fernandes R., Role of peroxy chemistry in the high-pressure ignition of n-butanol-Experiments and detailed kinetic modelling, combustion and flame 158 (2011) 1444-1455.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber B.W., Kumar K., Zhang Y., Sung C.-J., Autoignition of n-butanol at elevated pressure and low-to-intermediate temperature, Combustion and Flame 158 (2011) 809-819.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Black G., Curran H.J., Pichon S., Simmie J.M., Zhukov V., Bio-butanol: Combustion properties and detailed chemical kinetic model, Combustion and Flame 157 (2010) 363-373.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stranic I., Chase D.P., Harmon J.T., Yang S., Davidson D.F., Hanson R.K., Shock tube measurements of ignition delay times for the butanol isomers, Combustion and Flame 159 (2012) 516-527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heufer K., Bugler J., Curran H., A comparison of longer alkane and alcohol ignition including new experimental results for n-pentanol and n-hexanol, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 34 (2013) 511-518.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tang C., Wei L., Man X., Zhang J., Huang Z., Law C.K., High temperature ignition delay times of C5 primary alcohols, Combustion and Flame 160 (2013) 520-529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dagaut P., Togbé C., Experimental and modeling study of the kinetics of oxidation of butanol-n-heptane mixtures in a jet-stirred reactor, Energy &amp; Fuels 23 (2009) 3527-3535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>67.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bissoli, M., Cuoci, A., Frassoldati, A., Faravelli, T. et al., "Detailed Kinetic Analysis of HCCI Combustion Using a New Multi-Zone Model and CFD Simulations," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1594-1609, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>68.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Komninos, N., Hountalas, D., and Kouremenos, D., "Development of a New Multi-Zone Model for the Description of Physical Processes in HCCI Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0562, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0562.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>69.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oakley A.J., Experimental investigations on controlled autoignition combustion in a four-stroke gasoline engine, Brunel University School of Engineering and Design PhD Theses, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>70.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oakley A., Zhao H., Ma T., Ladommatos N., Dilution effects on the controlled auto-ignition (CAI) combustion of hydrocarbon and alcohol fuels, (2001).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <label>71.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oakley, A., Zhao, H., Ladommatos, N., and Ma, T., "Experimental Studies on Controlled Auto-ignition (CAI) Combustion of Gasoline in a 4-Stroke Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1030, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <label>72.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhave, A., Kraft, M., Mauss, F., Oakley, A. et al., "Evaluating the EGR-AFR Operating Range of a HCCI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0161, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0161.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
