<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278323</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Investigation into the Wake Structure of Square Back Vehicles and the Effect of Structure Modification on Resultant Vehicle Forces</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Littlewood</surname>
                  <given-names>Rob</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Loughborough University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Passmore</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Loughborough Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wood</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Loughborough University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278288</issue-id>
         <fpage>2629</fpage>
         <lpage>2637</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278323"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A large contribution to the aerodynamic drag of a vehicle (30% or more depending on vehicle shape) arises from the low base pressure in the wake region, especially on square-back configurations. A degree of base pressure recovery can be achieved through careful shape optimization, but the flow structures and mechanisms within the wake that cause these base pressure changes are not well understood. A more complete understanding of these mechanisms may provide opportunities for further drag reductions from both passive shape changes and in the future through the use of active flow control technologies.</p>
            <p>In this work surprisingly large changes in drag and lift coefficients of a square-back style vehicle have been measured as a result of physically small passive modifications. Tests were performed at quarter scale using a simplified vehicle model (Windsor Model) and at full scale using an MPV. The full scale vehicle was tested with and without a flat floor. During both tests the vehicle base region was fitted with a series of low profile, horizontal slats to disrupt any steady wake structures acting close to the vehicle base surface. Force balance, static pressure and PIV measurements have been used to investigate the flow structures in the vehicle wake.</p>
            <p>This paper summarizes the results and relates the global drag and lift changes that arise from the horizontal slats to the base pressure from both model and full scale and to the PIV measurements from the model tests.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golke, M. “Drag reduction by flow control at PSA Peugeot-Citroen” KATnetII Separation and Control Workshop, Toulouse, France 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schultz, S. “Aerodynamics of Modern Sport Utility Vehicles” 8th MIRA International Vehicle Aerodynamics Conference 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hucho, W.-H. “Aerodynamics of Road Vehicles,” SAE International, Warrendale, PA, ISBN 978-0-7680-0029-0, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ribaldone, E. et al, “Application of mulit-objective optimization to the aerodynamic development of passenger vehicles at FIAT” 8th MIRA International Vehicle Aerodynamics Conference 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schrefl, M. “The Audi A1 - Aerodynamics and Aeroacoustics” MIRA International Vehicle Aerodynamics Conference 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Littlewood, R.P., Passmore, M. A. “Aerodynamic drag reduction of a simplified squareback vehicle using steady blowing” Submission for Journal of Experiments in Fluids 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Littlewood, R. and Passmore, M., “The Optimization of Roof Trailing Edge Geometry of a Simple Square-Back.,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0510, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roshko, A. “Perspective on Bluff Body Aerodynamics” Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics, 49 (1993) 79-100</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roumeas, A, Gillieron, Azeddine, K. “Analyse and Control of the Near-Wake Flow over a Square Back Geometry” 3rd AIAA Flow Control Conference 5-8 June 2006, San Francisco, California, AIAA 2006-3336</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le Good, G. and Garry, K., “On the Use of Reference Models in Automotive Aerodynamics,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1308, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duell, E. and George, A., “Measurements in the Unsteady Near Wakes of Ground Vehicle Bodies,” SAE Technical Paper 930298, 1993, doi: 10.4271/930298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le Good, G., Howell, J., Passmore, M., and Garry, K., “On-Road Aerodynamic Drag Measurements Compared with Wind Tunnel Data,” SAE Technical Paper 950627, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950627.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
