<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023198</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>The Law and Macroeconomics of Fiscal Policy</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>How Income Taxes Should Change during Recessions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Liscow</surname>
                  <given-names>Zachary</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>Yale Law School, J.D. Expected 2015; Ph.D., University of California, Berkeley 2012.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>40</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023198"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper offers recommendations for how the design of labor income taxes should change during recessions, based on a simple model of a recessionary economy in which jobs are rationed and some employees value working more than others do. The paper draws two counter-intuitive conclusions for maximizing social welfare. First, subsidize non-employment. This draws marginal workers out of the labor force, creating “space” for those who really need jobs. Second, subsidize employers for hiring, not the employees themselves. The problem during recessions is having too few jobs; subsidizing employers creates more jobs, while subsidizing employees confers benefits on those who already won the job lottery. Tax policy in the recent recession has done a poor job of following these recommendations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <fn id="fn1">
            <label>2</label> 
            <p>See <mixed-citation publication-type="other">David Romer, Advanced Macroeconomics 242-44 (2006) (for a modern rendition of the Keynesian model)</mixed-citation>. Keynesian theory was originally developed in <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John Maynard Keynes, The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money (1936)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn2">
            <label>3</label> 
            <p>For prominent explanations of the literature on matching in unemployment, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Shimer, The Cyclical Behavior of Equilibrium Unemployment and Vacancies, 95 Am. Econ. Rev. 25 (2005)</mixed-citation> and <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arthur J. Hosios, On the Efficiency of Matching and Related Models of Search and Unemployment, Rev. Econ. Stud. 279 (1990)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn3">
            <label>4</label> 
            <p>Economists believe that jobs are rationed because wages do not fall during recessions, even though demand for workers falls, generating more workers willing to work than employers wish to employ. For economics papers arguing why rationing is an important feature of recessionary economies because wages do not change quickly enough to stop the rationing, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Truman Bewley Why Wages Don’t Fall During a Recession (1999) (suggesting, based upon interviews with workers and management, that workers strongly dislike decreases in their “nominal”—that is, non-inflation-adjusted—wage and that these decreases would decrease moral and therefore productivity)</mixed-citation> and <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John Taylor, Staggered Wage Setting in a Macro Model, 80 Am. Econ. Rev. 37 (1979) (with wage stickiness, both upward and downward, resulting from the fact that firms cannot fully adjust its wages if its competitors are not adjusting theirs at the same time because of staggered wage-setting)</mixed-citation>. Bewley’s work builds in part on that of <mixed-citation publication-type="other">George Akerlof, Labor Contracts as a Partial Gift Exchange, 97 Q. J. Econ. 543 (1982) (suggesting that norms may matter in wage-setting)</mixed-citation>. For recent prominent macroeconomic models which include these “wage rigidities,” see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Hall, Employment Fluctuations with Equilibrium Wage Stickiness, 95 Am. Econ. Rev. 50 (2005) (incorporating sticky wages into a search model, but assuming that the sticky wages merely adjust the division of surplus and do not generate layoffs, contrary to our model)</mixed-citation> and <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Shimer, The Consequences of Rigid Wages in Search Models, 2 J. Eur. Econ. Ass’n 469 (2004) (adding wage rigidities to a search model with stochastic shocks and finding that, if all wages are inflexible, the model does a better of predicting the dynamics of employment throughout business cycles, but still finding that the welfare costs of the business cycle are still low)</mixed-citation>. See also <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Shimer, Convergence in Macroeconomics: The Labor Wedge, 1 Am. Econ. J.: Macroeconomics 280 (2009) (arguing that wage rigidities, combined with search frictions, are a promising possible explanation for unemployment during recessions)</mixed-citation>. But see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christopher Pissarides, The Unemployment Volatility Puzzle: Is Wage Stickiness the Answer?, Walras-Bowley Lecture (2007) (arguing that wage rigidities cannot explain unemployment during recessions)</mixed-citation>. This literature does not include heterogeneous reservation wages, which I explore. Finally, for econometric evidence of nominal rigidities, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">James Poterba, Julio Rotemberg &amp; Lawrence Summers, A Tax-Based Test for Nominal Rigidities, 74 Am. Econ. Rev. 659 (1986)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn4">
            <label>5</label> 
            <p>The implications of heterogeneous worker surplus have been explored in other contexts. See, e.g., <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bontemps, et al. An Empirical Equilibrium Job Search Model with Search on the Job and Heterogeneous Workers and Firms, 40 Int’l Econ. Rev. 1039 (1999) (studying the implications of heterogeneous worker surplus on “equilibrium wage dispersion,” that is how wages for similar jobs vary)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn5">
            <label>6</label> 
            <p>There are many reasons that individuals may vary in their surplus from work. For example, some may particularly fear long-term earnings losses due to long-term unemployment resulting from being unemployed (related to “hysteresis,” or increased unemployment resulting from prolonged periods of unemployment during economic shocks). For evidence on long-term earning losses resulting from being laid off, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Till von Wachter et al., Long-Term Earnings Losses due to Mass Layoffs During the 1982 Recession: An Analysis Using U.S. Administrative Data from 1974 to 2004, http://www.columbia.edu/~vw2112/papers/mass_layoffs_1982.pdf</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn6">
            <label>7</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Douglas W. Elmendorf, Policies for Increasing Economic Growth and Employment in 2012 and 2013, Congressional Budget Office 28, Nov. 15, 2011, http://www.cbo.gov/sites/default/files/cbofiles/attachments/11-15-Outlook_Stimulus_Testimony.pdf</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn7">
            <label>8</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alan J. Auerbach, Implementing the New Fiscal Policy Activism, 99 Am. Econ. Rev. 543, 548 (2009) (“[I]f we are going to practice fiscal discretionary policy on a large scale, then more attention to policy design is sorely needed.”)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn8">
            <label>9</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yair Listokin, Equity, Efficiency, and Stability: The Importance of Macroeconomics for Evaluating Income Tax Policy, 29 Yale J. on Reg. 45 (2012)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn9">
            <label>10</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brian Galle &amp; Jonathan Klick, Recessions and the Social Safety Net: The Alternative Minimum Tax as a Countercyclical Fiscal Stabilizer, 63 Stan. L. Rev. 187 (2010)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn10">
            <label>11</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Camille Landais, Pascal Michaillat &amp; Emmanuel Saez, Optimal Unemployment Insurance over the Business Cycle, NBER Working Paper No. 16526 (2013) (also finding that unemployment insurance should be more generous during recessions, but based on a model which assumes that all workers value work the same amount and also not studying the choice between taxing employees or subsidizing employers or other forms of subsidizing non-employment)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn11">
            <label>12</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kyle D. Logue &amp; Joel Slemrod, Of Coase, Calabresi, and Optimal Tax Liability, 63 Tax. L. Rev. 797 (2010)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn12">
            <label>13</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wojciech Kopczuk, Justin Marion, Erich Muehlegger &amp; Joel Slemrod, Do the Laws of Tax Incidence Hold? Point of Collection and the Pass-through of State Diesel Taxes (2013), http://www.ire.eco.usi.ch/presentazione/paper-muehlegger-203467.pdf</mixed-citation>. This builds on earlier work of <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba et al., supra note 4</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn13">
            <label>14</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milton Friedman &amp; George Stigler, Roofs or Ceilings? The Current Housing Problem, 2 Popular Essays on Current Probs. 1 (1946)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn14">
            <label>15</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John R. Lott, Non-transferable Rents and an Unrecognized Social Cost of Minimum Wage Laws, 11 J. Labor Research 453 (1990)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn15">
            <label>16</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Empirical evidence of misallocation due to regulation is reviewed in Erzo Luttmer, Does the Minimum Wage Cause Inefficient Rationing?, 7 B.E. J. Econ. Analysis &amp; Pol’y (Contributions) 49 (2007)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn16">
            <label>17</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edward Glaeser &amp; Erzo Luttmer, The Misallocation of Housing under Rent Control, 93 Am. Econ. Rev. 1027 (2003)</mixed-citation>. A later paper by Luttmer develops a test for the efficiency of rationing in the minimum wage labor market using a test which is conceptually similar; he studies how the demographics of the workforce change as the minimum wage changes, under the principle that a higher minimum wage leads to more rationing and that some demographics are correlated with reservation wage. Luttmer, supra note 16.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn17">
            <label>18</label> 
            <p>David Lee and Emmanuel Saez explore optimal minimum wage policy if the social planner values redistribution, where rationing is efficient and inefficient. <mixed-citation publication-type="other">David Lee &amp; Emmanuel Saez, Optimal Minimum Wage in Competitive Labor Markets, 96 J. Pub. Econ. 739 (2012)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn18">
            <label>19</label> 
            <p>See, e.g., <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christine Jolls, Cass R. Sunstein &amp; Richard Thaler, A Behavioral Approach to Law and Economics, 50 Stan. L. Rev. 1471 (1998) (describing how behavioral economics should change policy recommendations in law and economics generally)</mixed-citation>, <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edward McCaffery &amp; Joel Slemrod, Behavioral Public Finance (2006) (reviewing recent developments in behavioral economics and their implications for public finance)</mixed-citation>, and <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacob Goldin &amp; Yair Listokin, Tax Expenditure Salience, Am. L. &amp; Econ. Rev. (forthcoming) (describing issues that arise in tax when tax expenditures may be less salient than other expenditures)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn19">
            <label>20</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Glaeser &amp; Luttmer, supra note 17</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn20">
            <label>21</label> 
            <p>As noted above, this assumption is common in the economics literature. It is also supported by the interviews conducted by <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bewley, supra note 4 at 241-243 (noting that no companies offered “choice between layoff and continued work on the same job at lower pay” and “[m]ost managers were astonished by the idea of offering as an alternative to layoff continued work on the same job at reduced pay.”)</mixed-citation>. As more time passes after the beginning of the recession and wages have time to adjust, the wage rigidities which motivate this paper become less relevant—and, therefore, so do its implications.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn21">
            <label>22</label> 
            <p>See <mixed-citation publication-type="other">David Romer, Real Rigidities, New Palgrave Dictionary of Economics, 2nd edition (2007) and Shimer, supra note 3</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn22">
            <label>23</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bewley, supra note 4</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn23">
            <label>24</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, supra note 4</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn24">
            <label>25</label> 
            <p>Note that the problem of sticky wages persists even as many people come and go from jobs. See <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steven J. Davis &amp; John Haltiwanger, Gross Job Flows, in 3 Handbook of Labor Economics 2711 (Orley Ashenfelter &amp; David Card, ed. 1999) (on the large flows of people into and out of jobs, even with the total number of jobs is stable)</mixed-citation>. New hires are also affected by sticky wages, both to maintain intra-firm equity in wages between old and new hires, and because firms offering new jobs are competing with employers offering high “sticky” wages. See <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, supra note 4</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn25">
            <label>26</label> 
            <p>This is the case with “quasi-linear utility functions” conventionally used in economic models. This means that utility is linear in income. In other words, there are no income effects.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn26">
            <label>27</label> 
            <p>The result requires the additional natural assumption that the sticky wage is not so high that the market evaporates or so low that there is in fact no sticky wage (i.e., 𝜃 = 0).</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn27">
            <label>28</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold C. Harberger, The Measurement of Waste, 43 Am. Econ. Rev. 58 (1964) (deriving the triangle method of analyzing deadweight loss)</mixed-citation> and <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold C. Harberger, Taxation, Resource Allocation, and Welfare, in The Role of Direct and Indirect Taxes in the Federal Revenue System 25 (John F. Due ed., 1964) (applying the triangle method to estimate deadweight losses due to income taxes in the United States)</mixed-citation>. See also <mixed-citation publication-type="other">James R. Hines, Three Sides of Harberger Triangles, 13 J. Econ. Persp. 167 (1999) (providing additional and more contemporary explanations of Harberger triangles)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn28">
            <label>29</label> 
            <p>Technically, the DWL is first-order in θ for uniform rationing and second-order in θ for efficient rationing. See infra note 34 for an explanation of “first-order” and “second-order.”</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn29">
            <label>30</label> 
            <p>More technically, <inline-formula>
                  <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline">
                     <mml:semantics>
                        <mml:mrow>
                           <mml:munder>
                              <mml:mrow>
                                 <mml:mtext>lim</mml:mtext>
                              </mml:mrow>
                              <mml:mrow>
                                 <mml:mo>θ</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mo>→</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mn>0</mml:mn>
                              </mml:mrow>
                           </mml:munder>
                           <mml:mrow>
                              <mml:mo>(</mml:mo>
                              <mml:mrow>
                                 <mml:mfrac>
                                    <mml:mrow>
                                       <mml:mtext>DWL under uniform rationing – DWL under efficient rationing</mml:mtext>
                                    </mml:mrow>
                                    <mml:mrow>
                                       <mml:mtext>DWL under efficient rationing</mml:mtext>
                                    </mml:mrow>
                                 </mml:mfrac>
                              </mml:mrow>
                              <mml:mo>)</mml:mo>
                           </mml:mrow>
                           <mml:mo>=</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mtext>∞</mml:mtext>
                        </mml:mrow>
                     </mml:semantics>
                  </mml:math>
               </inline-formula>. That is, the limit as θ approaches 0 of the ratio of 1) the extra DWL from uniform rationing relative to efficient rationing and 2) the DWL from efficient rationing alone is infinite. For small amounts of rationing, all that matters is the inefficient rationing, not the jobs shortage. 31 In particular, for subsidy W, the welfare gain is <inline-formula>
                  <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline">
                     <mml:semantics>
                        <mml:mrow>
                           <mml:mfrac>
                              <mml:mn>1</mml:mn>
                              <mml:mn>2</mml:mn>
                           </mml:mfrac>
                           <mml:mrow>
                              <mml:mo>(</mml:mo>
                              <mml:mrow>
                                 <mml:mtext>P</mml:mtext>
                                 <mml:mo>*</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mo>+</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mo>θ</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mo>−</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mrow>
                                    <mml:mo>(</mml:mo>
                                    <mml:mrow>
                                       <mml:msub>
                                          <mml:mtext>b</mml:mtext>
                                          <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                       </mml:msub>
                                       <mml:mo>+</mml:mo>
                                       <mml:msub>
                                          <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                          <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                       </mml:msub>
                                       <mml:mfrac>
                                          <mml:mrow>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">(</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:mo>θ</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:mo>−</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:mtext>W</mml:mtext>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">)</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">(</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo>+</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>D</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">)</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:mo>+</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">(</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>b</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>D</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo>−</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>b</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">)</mml:mo>
                                          </mml:mrow>
                                          <mml:mrow>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">(</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo>+</mml:mo>
                                             <mml:msub>
                                                <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                                <mml:mtext>D</mml:mtext>
                                             </mml:msub>
                                             <mml:mo stretchy="false">)</mml:mo>
                                          </mml:mrow>
                                       </mml:mfrac>
                                    </mml:mrow>
                                    <mml:mo>)</mml:mo>
                                 </mml:mrow>
                              </mml:mrow>
                              <mml:mo>)</mml:mo>
                           </mml:mrow>
                           <mml:mtext>Q</mml:mtext>
                           <mml:mo>*</mml:mo>
                        </mml:mrow>
                     </mml:semantics>
                  </mml:math>
               </inline-formula>. The welfare</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn30">
            <label/> 
            <p>gain is “large” in the sense of being a “first-order” welfare gain; that is, W appears in the equation without being multiplied by itself. Since economic welfare analysis is done “on the margin” (i.e., for the first infinitesimally small unit of W) and when W is less than 1, multiplying W by itself (i.e., a “second-order” welfare gain) yields a product less than W itself, the welfare gain is considered large for first-order welfare gains. An additional technical (and sensible) assumption for the marginal welfare gain to be positive is that the subsidy is not so gigantic that it reduces the number of workers willing to work to less than 𝒬<sup>D</sup>, the level of employment with no intervention.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn31">
            <label>32</label> 
            <p>20 C.F.R. § 604.5. For additional discussion, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Redefining “Suitable-Work” and Job-Search Rules for Unemployment Insurance, National Employment Law Project 1 (2012)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn32">
            <label>33</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Federal Unemployment Tax Act, § 3304(a)(5)(B)</mixed-citation>. See also <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Unemployment Insurance Program Letter No. 41-98, U.S. Department of Labor, Aug. 17, 1998</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn33">
            <label>34</label> 
            <p>In particular, the welfare gain for subsidizing an employer is <inline-formula>
                  <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline">
                     <mml:semantics>
                        <mml:mrow>
                           <mml:mfrac>
                              <mml:mn>1</mml:mn>
                              <mml:mn>2</mml:mn>
                           </mml:mfrac>
                           <mml:mo stretchy="false">(</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mtext>P</mml:mtext>
                           <mml:mo>*</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mo>+</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mo>θ</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mo>−</mml:mo>
                           <mml:msub>
                              <mml:mtext>b</mml:mtext>
                              <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                           </mml:msub>
                           <mml:mo>−</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mtext>W</mml:mtext>
                           <mml:mo stretchy="false">)</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mfrac>
                              <mml:mtext>W</mml:mtext>
                              <mml:mrow>
                                 <mml:msub>
                                    <mml:mtext>m</mml:mtext>
                                    <mml:mtext>D</mml:mtext>
                                 </mml:msub>
                              </mml:mrow>
                           </mml:mfrac>
                        </mml:mrow>
                     </mml:semantics>
                  </mml:math>
               </inline-formula>. While still positive, the welfare gain starts decreasing when the subsidy is greater than half the surplus of the highest-surplus worker (that is, the total welfare benefits start declining when <inline-formula>
                  <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline">
                     <mml:semantics>
                        <mml:mrow>
                           <mml:mtext>W</mml:mtext>
                           <mml:mo>&gt;</mml:mo>
                           <mml:mfrac>
                              <mml:mrow>
                                 <mml:mtext>P</mml:mtext>
                                 <mml:mo>*</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mo>+</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mo>θ</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:mo>−</mml:mo>
                                 <mml:msub>
                                    <mml:mtext>b</mml:mtext>
                                    <mml:mtext>S</mml:mtext>
                                 </mml:msub>
                              </mml:mrow>
                              <mml:mn>2</mml:mn>
                           </mml:mfrac>
                        </mml:mrow>
                     </mml:semantics>
                  </mml:math>
               </inline-formula>. Put another way, for large employer-side subsidies, in which the marginal dollar in employer subsidy causes little decrease in quantity DWL, a marginal increase in the subsidy can increase total DWL, so employer subsidies should be set below this point.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn34">
            <label>35</label> 
            <p>In particular, when the average reservation wage of workers willing to work is greater than that of the worker who would be rationed into employment under efficient rationing (the employee at 𝒬<sup>
                  <sub>2</sub>D</sup> along the supply curve), a marginal increase in the subsidy increases allocative DWL.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn35">
            <label>36</label> 
            <p>Thus, the welfare loss from subsidizing an employee is simply the negative of the welfare gain from subsidizing nonemployment. See the results in supra note 31.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn36">
            <label>37</label> 
            <p>Instead of subsidizing employees, the model actually implies that it is desirable to increase taxes on employees. Of course, raising taxes during recessions is a bad idea for macroeconomic reasons. If it were wise, though, taxing employees and subsidizing employers would effectively reduce the post-tax wage, removing the underlying source of inefficiency and therefore reducing both allocative and quantity DWLs. Although the market will not get the wage down, the government can effectively decrease it. Such a policy is an alternative to inflation when the Federal Reserve already has interest rates as low as they can go, which happened in the most recent recession.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn37">
            <label>38</label> 
            <p>Congress could partially respond to the concern about employers’ strategic behavior by promising during its deliberations to make the subsidy retroactive.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn38">
            <label>39</label> 
            <p>Measuring rationing efficiency is particularly challenging given the unobservability of surplus from work. One approach to measuring surplus from work is using the amount that individuals say that they value working (as in <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin Feldstein &amp; James Poterba, Unemployment Insurance and Reservation Wages, 23 J. Pub. Econ. 141 (1984)</mixed-citation>); however, economists tend to be skeptical of such stated values, versus those that are revealed by individuals’ behavior.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn39">
            <label>40</label> 
            <p>In principle, people who quit but do not find employment could also be a part of unemployment. However, evidence shows that the number of people quitting jobs actually went down substantially during the recession, so quits are unlikely to play an important role in cyclical unemployment. In contrast, layoffs increased substantially and the number of job opening and amount of hiring plummeted, making it harder to find jobs. See <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Job Opening and Labor Turnover Point to (Slow) Recovery, http://econompicdata.blogspot.com/2011/11/job-opening-and-labor-turnover-point-to.html (last visited Aug. 1, 2014)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn40">
            <label>41</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bewley, supra note 4, at 238-242</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn41">
            <label>42</label> 
            <p>See, e.g., <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Gibbons &amp; Lawrence Katz, Layoffs and Lemons, 9 J. Labor Econ. 351 (1991) (confirming empirical predictions of a model in which low-productivity workers are laid off when firms do not close whole plants and therefore have discretion over layoffs)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn42">
            <label>43</label> 
            <p>Of course, family circumstances and other things may be observed, but these are likely to be crude proxies.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn43">
            <label>44</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bewley, supra note 4, at 238</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn44">
            <label>45</label> 
            <p>Some firms also lay off in reverse seniority, which also is unlikely to closely correspond to workers surplus from work. Id.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn45">
            <label>46</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bewley, supra note 4, at Chp. 15</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn46">
            <label>47</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bewley, supra note 4 at 341 (“I asked whether people could find work quickly if they were sufficiently flexible and energetic in their job search. The answer was usually an emphatic ‘no.’ Respondents claimed that the general shortage of jobs and the overqualification problem made finding a job of any time a long, difficult process, though some job hunters were lucky. The shortage of jobs relative to the number of job seekers preoccupied advisers of the unemployed…. All but one of these 18 said it normally took a long time to find work, even if job searchers were energetic and completely flexible.”)</mixed-citation> See also <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alan B. Krueger &amp;Andreas Mueller, Job Search and Unemployment Insurance: New Evidence from Time Use Data, IZA DP No. 3667, 24 http://anon-ftp.iza.org/dp3667.pdf (2008) (finding in the most basic model that “increasing [job] search by one hour increases the probability of finding a job by 0.31 percentage points,” which the authors consider “small”)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn47">
            <label>48</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John McCall, Economics of Information and Job Search, 84 Q. J. Econ. 113 (1970)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn48">
            <label>49</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fabien Postel-Vinay &amp; Jean-Marc Robin, 2002, Equilibrium Wage Dispersion with Worker and Employer Heterogeneity, 70 Econometrica 2295 (2002) (taking into account worker and firm heterogeneity)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn49">
            <label>50</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Louis S. Jacobson, Robert J. LaLonde &amp; Daniel G. Sullivan. Earnings Losses of Displaced Workers, 83 Am. Econ. Rev. 685. (1993)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn50">
            <label>51</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Lucas, Models of Business Cycles (1987)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn51">
            <label>52</label> 
            <p>Lucas also implicitly assumes that every individual has perfect insurance against fluctuations in income. Combining heterogeneous surplus from work and inefficient rationing together provides a reason that imperfect insurance would yield particularly large welfare losses: some of those losing jobs (and therefore consumption) during recessions are those most in need.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn52">
            <label>53</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bewley, supra note 4</mixed-citation>,</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn53">
            <label>54</label> 
            <p>For a useful summary of recent theory on Keynesian economic policies, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jordi Gali, Modern Perspectives on Fiscal Stabilization Policies, 51 CESifo Econ. Stud. 587 (2005) (summarizing the New Keynesian perspective on increasing aggregate demand in recessions)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn54">
            <label>55</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elmendorf, supra note 7</mixed-citation>. The table actually gives ranges. I take the average of the top and bottom of the range.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn55">
            <label>56</label> 
            <p>Perhaps part of the reason that the CBO makes these findings is the significant amount of stress businesses were under, perhaps increasing the likelihood that they would spend the money rather than save it.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn56">
            <label>57</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoram Barzel, A Theory of Rationing by Waiting, 17 J.L. &amp; Econ. 73 (1974)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn57">
            <label>58</label> 
            <p>Note that this cost would be the same under efficient and inefficient sorting.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn58">
            <label>59</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">David Neumark, Spurring Job Creation in Response to Severe Recessions: Reconsidering Hiring Credits, 32 J. Pol’y Analysis &amp; Mgmt. 142 (2013)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn59">
            <label>60</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Julie M. Whittaker &amp; Katelin P. Isaacs, Extending Unemployment Compensation Benefits During Recessions, Congressional Research Service, May 2, 2013, http://www.fas.org/sgp/crs/misc/RL34340.pdf (listing the numerous extensions of unemployment insurance through May 2013) [hereinafter Whittaker &amp; Isaacs, Extending Unemployment Compensation]</mixed-citation>; <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Julie M. Whittaker &amp; Katelin P. Isaacs, Unemployment Insurance: Programs and Benefits, Congressional Research Service, Feb. 12, 2014, https://www.fas.org/sgp/crs/misc/RL33362.pdf (on unemployment insurance extension through nearly the end of 2013) [hereinafter, Whittaker &amp; Isaacs, Unemployment Insurance]</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn60">
            <label>61</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, Pub. L. No. 111-5, Division B, Title II, Subtitle A</mixed-citation>. For a description, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clinton T. Brass, et al., American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (P.L. 111-5): Summary and Legislative History, Congressional Research Service 29, Apr. 20, 2009, http://waxman.house.gov/sites/waxman.house.gov/files/documents/UploadedFiles/ARRA.pdf</mixed-citation>, and <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whittaker &amp; Isaacs, Extending Unemployment Compensation, supra note 59, at 24</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn61">
            <label>62</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whittaker &amp; Isaacs, Unemployment Insurance, supra note 59</mixed-citation>. On the expiration of benefits at the end of 2013, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ed O’Keefe, Unemployment benefits dominate the agenda, Wash. Post, Jan. 31, 2014, http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/unemployment-benefits-dominate-the-agenda/2014/01/31/3a63a70a-8659-11e3-b85b-b305db87fb90_story.html</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn62">
            <label>63</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jesse Rothstein, Unemployment Insurance and Job Search in the Great Recession, 2011 Brookings Papers on Econ. Activity 143 (2011)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn63">
            <label>64</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (COBRA). Pub.L. 99–272, 100 Stat. 82</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn64">
            <label>65</label> 
            <p>Pub. L. No. 111-5, Division B, Title III. For a description, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brass et al., supra note 61, at 29 &amp; 32-33</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn65">
            <label>66</label> 
            <p>Pub. L. No. 111-5, Division A, Title I. For a description, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brass et al., supra note 61, at 14</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn66">
            <label>67</label> 
            <p>Pub. L. No. 111-5, Division B, Title II, Subtitle B. For a description, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brass et al., supra note 61, at 31</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn67">
            <label>68</label> 
            <p>Pub. L. No. 111-5, Division B, Title V. For a description, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brass et al., supra note 61, at 35 &amp; 45</mixed-citation>. See also <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cliff Binder et al., American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA, P.L. 111-5): Title V, Medicaid Provisions, Congressional Research Service, Mar. 17, 2009, http://assets.opencrs.com/rpts/R40223_20090317.pdf</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn68">
            <label>69</label> 
            <p>The first was a campaign promise that “[d]uring 2009 and 2010, existing businesses will receive a $3,000 refundable tax credit for each additional full-time employee hired.” The Obama-Biden Plan, http://change.gov/agenda/economy_agenda/, accessed Feb. 24, 2014. Second, in January 2010, President Obama proposed the Small Business Jobs and Wages Tax Cut, which would provide business with “a $5,000 tax credit for every net new employee that they employ in 2010,” capped at $500,000 per firm and with half the tax credit allowed for start-ups. It also would have reimbursed “[s]mall businesses that increase[d] wages or hours for their existing employees … for the Social Security payroll taxes they pa[id] on real increases in their payrolls.” Firms would have been “able to claim the credit on a quarterly basis, … [to get] money out to businesses quickly and provides and [sic] early incentive to hire and increase payrolls.” <mixed-citation publication-type="other">President Obama to Propose New Small Business Jobs and Wages Tax Cut, White House, Jan. 28, 2010, http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/president-obama-propose-new-small-business-jobs-and-wages-tax-cut</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn69">
            <label>70</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009: Full Summary of Provisions from Senate Finance, House Ways &amp; Means Committees, U.S. House of Representatives Ways and Means Committee 4, Feb. 12, 2009, http://waysandmeans.house.gov/media/pdf/111/arra.pdf</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn70">
            <label>71</label> 
            <p>Pub. L. No. 111-5, Division B, Title I, § 1221. For a description of the provision, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IRS Offers Tax Credit Guidance to Businesses Hiring Unemployed Veterans and Certain Youth, Internal Revenue Service, May 28, 2009, http://www.irs.gov/uac/IRS-Offers-Tax-Credit-Guidance-to-Businesses-Hiring-Unemployed-Veterans-and-Certain-Youth</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn71">
            <label>72</label> 
            <p>H.R. 2847. The Act provided two benefits to employers: “The first, referred to as the payroll tax exemption, provides employers with an exemption from the employer’s 6.2 percent share of social security tax on wages paid to qualifying employees, effective for wages paid from March 19, 2010 through December 31, 2010. In addition, for each qualified employee retained for at least 52 consecutive weeks, businesses will also be eligible for a general business tax credit, referred to as the new hire retention credit, of 6.2 percent of wages paid to the qualified employee over the 52 week period, up to a maximum credit of $1,000.” <mixed-citation publication-type="other">HIRE Act: Questions and Answers for Employers, http://www.irs.gov/Businesses/Small-Businesses-&amp;-Self-Employed/HIRE-Act:--Questions-and-Answers-for-Employers</mixed-citation>. See also <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baucus Hails Final Passage of Job-Creation Legislation, https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=12&amp;cad=rja&amp;ved=0CDIQFjABOAo&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.finance.senate.gov%2Fdownload%2F%3Fid%3D4dfdaafa-7eaa-4e49-903ace6f45159fd8&amp;ei=aNhdUtHAKve34APvsYDgCQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNHMXF3CMiaHUsApOzPcq1Xe1gkLQ&amp;sig2=Ikoo5tTen2hCEVciemGEvQ</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn72">
            <label>73</label> 
            <p>Pub. L. No. 111-5, Division B, Title I, Subtitle A; <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brass et al., supra note 61</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn73">
            <label>74</label> 
            <p>In particular, it “phase[d] out for taxpayers with modified adjusted gross income in excess of $75,000, or in the case of married couples filing jointly, $150,000.” <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brass et al., supra note 61, at 36</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn74">
            <label>75</label> 
            <p>Id.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn75">
            <label>76</label> 
            <p>Tax Relief, Unemployment Insurance Reauthorization, and Job Creation Act of 2010, P.L. 111-312. For a description of the 2011 payroll tax reduction, see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dawn Nuschler, Social Security: Temporary Payroll Tax Reduction, Congressional Research Service, January 9, 2012, http://assets.opencrs.com/rpts/R41648_20120109.pdf</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn76">
            <label>77</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tax Relief, Unemployment Insurance Reauthorization, and Job Creation Act of 2010: Information Center, http://www.irs.gov/uac/Tax-Relief,-Unemployment-Insurance-Reauthorization,-and-Job-Creation-Act-of-2010:-Information-Center</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn77">
            <label>78</label> 
            <p>The payroll tax cut was first extended two months, through February 2012. H.R. 3630, Temporary Payroll Tax Cut Continuation Act of 2011. For description see <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payroll Tax Cut Temporarily Extended into 2012, http://www.irs.gov/uac/Payroll-Tax-Cut-Temporarily-Extended-into-2012</mixed-citation>. Then, in February 2012, it was extended for the rest of the year with the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012, Pub. L. No. 112–96. The estimated cost of the 10-month extension was $93.2 billion. <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Summary of The Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012, Feb. 16, 2012, http://www.finance.senate.gov/newsroom/chairman/release/?id=c42a8c8a-52ad-44af-86b2-4695aaff5378</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn78">
            <label>79</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jeffrey M. Perloff &amp; Michael L. Wachter, The New Jobs Tax Credit: An Evaluation of the 1977-78 Wage Subsidy Program, 69 Am. Econ. Rev. 173 (1979)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
