<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437357</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Public Debt and Pension Policy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>LANS</given-names>
                  <surname>BOVENBERG</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>CAREL</given-names>
                  <surname>PETERSEN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>1992</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437354</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>14</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1992</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437357"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e147a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e154" publication-type="other">
Future pension benefits are not contractual obligations in the same way as regular debt instruments are and feature
distinct risk characteristics. Hence, these two types of liability are not perfectly substitutable (see also Section IV).
One can therefore argue that, rather than adding the pension liabilities to their regular debt, governments should
provide supplemental information regarding the potential future liabilities on account of the pensions payments to
their own employees and social security old-age pensions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e173a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e180" publication-type="other">
Strictly speaking, pensions are taxed on a consumption-tax basis only if benefits are consumed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e187a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e194" publication-type="other">
Some countries, such as Australia, New Zealand, Denmark, Sweden and Belgium, do not really tax pension saving
on a consumption-tax basis because they collect tax also on (part of) the returns of pension funds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e204a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e211" publication-type="other">
When the population ages, large funded supplementary pension schemes benefit the public finances on two
accounts. First, they yield a broader base for income and consumption taxes. Second, they tend to imply lower
public spending on pay-as-you-go public pensions. High private pensions are also likely to reduce the demand for
other types of public spending, such as health and social security spending.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e228a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e235" publication-type="other">
The public sector bears a substantial share of the costs of environmental damage because 'the polluter pays'
principle cannot be applied in all circumstances.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e245a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e252" publication-type="other">
Methods for the valuation of assets in pension funds differ across countries, in part due to differences in regulatory
regimes. These differences complicate an international comparison of the size of pension funds and life assurance
companies. In particular, the assets in pension and life assurance funds in countries that adopt conservative valuation
methods may be underestimated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e268a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e275" publication-type="other">
By levying a one-off wealth tax on pension funds, countries with mature pension systems can alleviate the
transitional problems associated with moving from the cash-flow to the prepayment system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e285a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e292" publication-type="other">
In examining the incentives to shift consumption through pension saving, one may also have to explore how
effective marginal tax rates during the working life and retirement period are affected by income-dependent prices
and public transfers or own contributions that depend on income. There are also tax arbitrage opportunities if
individuals expect the government to reduce the income tax rate or the tax rates on consumption (such as VAT)
before or during their retirement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e311a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e318" publication-type="other">
This illustrates that tax incentives for private saving that defer taxes may not be successful in raising national
saving. This is especially so if the combination of these tax incentives with the deductibility of mortgage interest
provides opportunities for tax arbitrage. See also Stiglitz ( 1985). National saving may also fall if households feature
short time horizons so that they heavily discount future tax payments on retirement benefits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e334a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e341" publication-type="other">
Unless falling indirect consumption tax rates accompany rising personal income taxes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e349a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e356" publication-type="other">
An unexpected increase in indirect consumption taxes amounts to the expropriation of a part of all assets, including
non-pension assets. See Auerbach and Kotlikoff (1987).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e366a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e373" publication-type="other">
In fact, pension benefits (consumption) exceeding pension premiums (saving) is a condition for the dynamic
efficiency of funded schemes. See, e.g., Abel et al. (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e383a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e390" publication-type="other">
Assuming that the public sector is a net debtor.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e397a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e404" publication-type="other">
This will be the case if the government has set targets for its financial balance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d15e420a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e424" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. B., Mankiw, N. G., Summers, L. H. and Zeckhauser, R. J. (1989), 'Assessing dynamic
efficiency: theory and evidence', Review of Economic Studies, vol. 56, pp. 1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e434a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e438" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. J. and Kotlikoff, L. J. ( 1987), Dynamic Fiscal Policy, Cambridge: Cambridge University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e448a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e452" publication-type="other">
Blanchard, O. J., Chouraqui, J., Hagemann, R. P. and Sartor, N. (1990), 'The sustainability of fiscal
policy: new answers to an old question', OECD Economic Studies, no. 15, pp. 7-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e462a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e466" publication-type="other">
Blejer, M. and Cheasty, A. (1991), 'The measurement of fiscal deficits: analytical and methodological
issues', Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 29, pp. 1644-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e477a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e481" publication-type="other">
Hagemann, R. P. and Nicoletti, G. (1989), 'Population ageing: economic effects and some policy
implications for financing public pensions', OECD Economic Studies, no. 12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e491a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e495" publication-type="other">
Heller, P., Hemming, R. and Konhert, P. W. (1986), 'Aging and social expenditure in the major
industrial countries, 1980-2025', IMF Occasional Paper, no. 47, September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e505a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e509" publication-type="other">
Hubbard, R. G. and Judd, K. L. (1986), 'Liquidity constraints, fiscal policy, and consumption',
Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, pp. 1-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e519a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e523" publication-type="other">
Kay, J. (1990), 'Consumption and income taxation: horizontal equity and life cycle issues', in M. Rose
(ed.), Heidelberg Congress on Taxing Consumption, Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e533a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e537" publication-type="other">
Munnell, A. H. and Ernsberger, C. N. (1989), 'Public pension surpluses and national saving: foreign
experience', New England Economic Review, March/April, pp. 16-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e547a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e551" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J. (1985), 'The general theory of tax avoidance', National Tax Journal, vol. 38, pp. 325-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e559a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e563" publication-type="other">
van Loo, P. D. (1990), 'De beleggingen van pensioenfondsen', in C. Petersen (ed.), Pensioenen,
Uitkeringen, Financiering en Beleggingen, Leiden.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
