<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466885</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466888</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Board Structure and Monitoring: New Evidence from CEO Turnovers</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Lixiong</given-names>
                  <surname>Guo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ronald W.</given-names>
                  <surname>Masulis</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2770</fpage>
         <lpage>2811</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466888"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We use the 2003 NYSE and NASDAQ listing rules for board and committee independence as a quasinatural experiment to examine the causal relations between board structure and CEO monitoring. Noncompliant firms forced to raise board independence or adopt a fully independent nominating committee significantly increased their forced CEO turnover sensitivity to performance relative to compliant firms. Nominating committee independence is important even when firms had an independent board, and the effect is stronger when the CEO is on the committee. We conclude that greater board independence and full independence of nominating committees lead to more rigorous CEO monitoring and discipline.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d4823893e245a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e252" publication-type="other">
See the surveys by Bhagat and Black (1999), Hermalin and Weisbach (2003), and Adams, Hermalin, and Weisbach
(2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e262a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e269" publication-type="other">
According to the NYSE's new exchange listing requirements, the nominating committee must, at a minimum, be
responsible for identifing individuals qualified to become board members, selecting, or recommending that the
board select the director nominees for the next annual meeting of shareholders, and developing and recommending
to the board a set of corporate goverance guidelines applicable to the corporation and overseeing the evaluation
of the board and management.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e288a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e295" publication-type="other">
Shivdasani and Yermack (1999) find that when the CEO is on the nominating committee, a firm appoints fewer
outside directors and more gray directors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e305a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e312" publication-type="other">
According to Berle and Means (1932, 87): "... control will tend to be in the hands of those who select the
proxy committee and by whom, the election of directors for the ensuing period will be made. Since the proxy
committee is appointed by existing management, they can virtually dictate their own successors."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e326a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e333" publication-type="other">
Core, Holthausen, and Larcker (1999) find that CEO compensation is higher when the CEO is involved in the
nomination of new directors. Grinstein and Hribar (2004) find that the merger bonus given to acquiring firm
CEOs is higher when the CEO is involved in the nomination of new directors. However, the causality is not clear
in these studies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e349a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e356" publication-type="other">
These exchange listing rules also require non-management directors to hold regular meetings that exclude
management. NASDAQ allows a majority of independent directors to nominate directors or set CEO
compensation if a firm lacks a nominating or compensation committee. "Controlled" firms, in which an individual,
group, or another firm holds a majority of voting rights, are exempt from the independent board, nominating,
and compensation committee requirements.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e375a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e382" publication-type="other">
The official name of Sarbanes-Oxley Act is the Public Company Accounting Reform and Investor Protection
Act, whose objective is to ensure the accuracy and credibility of corporate financial reports. With two exceptions,
the provisions of SOX affect almost all U.S. public firms and compliance was required by the 2003 year-end
(which precedes the compliance dates of the exchange listing requirements, occurring in 2004 and 2005). The
first exception is Section 301, which required all public firms to have a fully independence audit committee.
This is the only board structure requirement in SOX that was implemented in the new exchange listing rules
we study. The second exception is Section 404. Section 404 (a) required companies to include an assessment
of internal control for financial reporting (ICFR) in their annual reports, and Section 404(b) required companies
to provide an independent auditor's attestation. For smaller public companies, defined as those with a public
float below $75 million, compliance with Section 404(a) was postponed until after December 15, 2007, while
the implementation of Section 404(b) was initially postponed for these firms and later became an exemption
under the Dodd-Frank Act. We find that our noncompliant samples are not dominated by these smaller public
companies. In fact, the mean market capitalization of firms noncompliant in 2001 with any of the four rules is
above $6 billion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e430a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e437" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Weisbach ( 1988), Huson, Parrino, and Starks (2001 ), Lei and Miller (2008), Jenter and Lewellen
(2010), Kaplan and Minton (2011), Mobbs (2013), and Coles, Daniel, and Naveen (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e447a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e454" publication-type="other">
As noted by Hermalin and Weisbach (1998), the same prediction can be generated by assuming independent
directors attribute less value to retaining the incumbent CEO than do non-independent directors because of their
reputation concerns, better alignment with shareholder interests, or lack of other ties to the CEO.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e467a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e474" publication-type="other">
Chhaochharia and Grinstein (2009) exploit the same natural experiment to study the effect of board independence
on CEO compensation. Guthrie, Sokolowsky, and Wan (2010) revisit these results and find that board
independence has no effect on CEO total pay, while firms forced to adopt an independent compensation committee
raise CEO total pay. While higher CEO pay can indicate weaker monitoring, it can also reflect more intensive
monitoring. For example, in Hermalin (2005), a rise in board monitoring reduces CEO job stability, which
requires higher pay to compensate for higher CEO risk bearing. In robustness analysis, we found that controlling
for CEO pay-for-performance sensitivity leaves our major findings unchanged.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e501a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e508" publication-type="other">
Dahya, McConnell, and Travlos (2002) note that compliance with the Cadbury Code is not totally voluntary
because London Stock Exchange requires listed companies to "comply or explain." However, to the extent that
some firms did choose not to adhere to the Code, their interpretation of the results is still contaminated by
endogeneity concerns. Furthermore, it is unclear whether their evidence is applicable to firms in other countries
that differ in terms of board powers and other governance mechanisms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e527a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e534" publication-type="other">
Rather than using a difference-in-differences method, Dahya, McConnell, and Travlos (2002) run separate
regressions for compliant and noncompliant firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e544a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e551" publication-type="other">
Our model choice is also consistent with the recommendation of Adams, Hermalin, and Weisbach (2010), who
observe that few existing CEO turnover studies control for firm-specific heterogeneity and this approach would
provide a valuable contribution to the understanding of the CEO turnover process.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e564a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e571" publication-type="other">
See also Coles, Daniel, and Naveen (2008) and Linck, Netter, and Yang (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e578a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e585" publication-type="other">
As a robustness check, we also repeat our analysis on sample that uses board structure on the last meeting date
of fiscal year 2002 to classify firms into treatment and control groups. The results are qualitatively unchanged.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e595a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e602" publication-type="other">
Although noncompliant firms should be determined based on the exchange definitions, this is not practical
since the size of business relations between directors and firms are generally unobservable. We conducted a
robustness check on this issue and found that our results are not affected by the misclassification of compliant
and noncompliant firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e619a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e626" publication-type="other">
This noise in the classifications should in general bias against our finding a significant difference between
treatment and control groups. To the extent that we do find differences, they do not affect our conclusions. We
explicitly check the robustness of our results to these issues and find that our results are not affected by the
misclassification of compliant and noncompliant firms and the inclusion of controlled companies as shown in
the Internet Appendix sections E and F.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e645a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e652" publication-type="other">
For information on how our sample firms complied with the new rules, please refer to Internet Appendix section A.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e659a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e666" publication-type="other">
We also decompose a firm's stock returns into an industry-induced component and an idiosyncratic component
following Jenter and Kanaan (2015) and measure stock performance by its idiosyncratic component. In unreported
results, we find our conclusions to be robust to this alternative stock performance measure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e679a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e686" publication-type="other">
To save space, we only report the results for the board and nominating committee independence rules because
we only expect them to have significant impact on turnover-performance sensitivity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e696a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e703" publication-type="other">
We estimated Equation ( 1 ) without the DiD terms to establish a baseline relation between forced CEO turnover and
firm performance in the full sample by varying performance, while setting all other variables to their respective
sample means.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e716a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e723" publication-type="other">
We did not consider the audit and compensation committee independence rules here because we already showed
in Table 5 that they did not affect CEO turnover decisions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e734a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e741" publication-type="other">
Given that the actual compliance date can be endogenous, one should be careful to not interpret these results
independently of those in Columns 1 and 2 of Table 5.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e751a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e758" publication-type="other">
Warner, Watts, and Wruck (1988) find regressing firm performance on CEO turnover in a logit model does not
capture the relation well, although it does better at extreme performance levels. Jenter and Lewellen (2010)
note that economic theory does not predict corporate governance has the same effect on turnover performance
sensitivity across all performance levels.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d4823893e774a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d4823893e781" publication-type="other">
This evidence is consistent with Jenter and Lewellen (2010), who find that the difference in rate of CEO
turnover between firms with high-quality and low-quality boards is most significant in the bottom quintile
of firm performance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d4823893e803a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e807" publication-type="other">
Adams, R. B., and D. Ferreira. 2007. A theory of friendly board. Journal of Finance 62:217-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e818" publication-type="other">
Adams, R., B. E. Hermalin, and M. S. Weisbach. 2010. The role of boards of directors in corporate governance:
a conceptual framework and survey. Journal of Economic Literature 48:58-107.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e828a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e832" publication-type="other">
Ai, C., and E. C. Norton. 2003. Interaction terms in logit and probit models. Economic Letters 80:123-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e843" publication-type="other">
Bebchuk, L., A. Cohen, and A. Ferrell. 2009. What matters in corproate governance? Review of Financial Studies
22:783-827.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e854a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e858" publication-type="other">
Berle, A. A., and G C. Means. 1932. The modern corporattion and private property. New York: MacMillan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e865a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e869" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., E. Duflo, and S. Mullainathan. 2004. How much should we trust difference in difference estimates?
Quarterly Journal of Economics 119:249-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e879a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e883" publication-type="other">
Bhagat, S., and B. Black. 1999. The uncertain relationship between board composition and firm performance.
Business Lawyer 54:921-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e893a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e897" publication-type="other">
Boone, A. L., L. C. Field, J. M. Karpoff, and C. G Raheja. 2007. The determinants of corporate board size and
independence: an empirical analysis. Journal of Financial Economics 85:66-101.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e911" publication-type="other">
Chhaochharia, V., and Y. Grinstein. 2009. CEO compensation and board structure. Journal of Finance 64:231-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e918a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e922" publication-type="other">
Coles, J. L., N. D. Daniel, and L. Naveen. 2008. Boards: Does one size fit all? Journal of Financial Economics
87:329-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e933a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e937" publication-type="other">
. 2014. Co-opted boards. Review of Financial Studies 27:1751-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e944a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e948" publication-type="other">
Core, J. E., R. W. Holthausen, and D. F. Larcker. 1999. Corporate governance, CEO compensation, and firm
performance. Journal of Financial Economics 51:371-406.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e962" publication-type="other">
Cornelli, F., Z. Kominek, and A. Ljungqvist. 2012. Monitoring managers: Does it matter? Journal of Finance
68:431-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e972a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e976" publication-type="other">
Dahya, J., J. J. McConnell, and N. G Travlos. 2002. The Cadbury committee, corporate performance, and top
management turnover. Journal of Finance 67:461-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e986a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e990" publication-type="other">
Dehejia, R. H., and S. Wahba. 2002. Propensity score matching methods for nonexperimental causal studies.
84:151-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1000a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1004" publication-type="other">
Denis, D. J., D. K. Denis, and A. Sarin. 1997. Ownership structure and top executive turnover. Journal of
Financial Economics 45:193-221.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1015a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1019" publication-type="other">
Duchin, R., J. G Matsusaka, and O. Ozbas. 2010. When are outside directors effective? Journal of Financial
Economics 96:195-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1029a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1033" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F. 1980. Agency problems and the theory of the firm. Journal of Political Economy 88:288-307.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1040a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1044" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1997. Industry costs of equity. Journal of Financial Economics 43:153-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1051a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1055" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and M. C. Jensen. 1983. Separation of ownership and control. Journal of Law &amp; Economics
26:301-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1065a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1069" publication-type="other">
Fracassi, C., and G Tate. 2012. External networking and internal firm governance. Journal of Finance 67:
153-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1079a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1083" publication-type="other">
Goyal, V. K., and C. W. Park. 2002. Board leadership structure and CEO turnvoer. Journal of Corporate Finance
8:49-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1094a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1098" publication-type="other">
Grinstein, Y., and P. Hribar. 2004. CEO compensation and incentives: Evidence from M&amp;A bonuses. Journal of
Financial Economics 73:119-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1108a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1112" publication-type="other">
Guo, L., P. Lach, and S. Mobbs. 2015. Tradeoffs between internal and external governance: evidence from
exogenous regulatory shocks. Financial Management 44:81-114.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1122a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1126" publication-type="other">
Guthrie, K., J. Sokolowsky, and K.-M. Wan. 2010. CEO Compensation and board structure revisited. Journal of
Finance 67:1149-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1136a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1140" publication-type="other">
Harris, M., and A. Raviv. 2008. A theory of board control and size. Review of Financial Studies 21:1797-832.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1147a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1151" publication-type="other">
Hazarika, S., J. M. Karpoff, and R. Nahata. 2012. Internal corporate governance, CEO turnover, and earnings
management. Journal of Financial Economics 104:44-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1165" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E. 2005. Trends in corporate governance. Journal of Finance 60:2351-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1177" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E., and M. S. Weisbach. 2003. Boards of directors as an endogenously determined institution: a
survey of the economic literature. FRBNY Economic Policy Review 2003:7-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1187a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1191" publication-type="other">
. 1998. Endogenously chosen boards of directors and their monitoring of the CEO. American Economic
Review 88:96-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1201a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1205" publication-type="other">
Huson, M. R., P. H. Malatesta, and R. Parrino. 2004. Managerial succession and firm performance. Journal of
Financial Economics 74:237-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1215a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1219" publication-type="other">
Huson, M. R., R. Parrino, and L. T. Starks. 2001. Internal monitoring mechanisms and CEO turnover: A long-term
perspective. Journal of Finance 56:2265-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1229a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1233" publication-type="other">
Hwang, B.-H., and S. Kim. 2009. It pays to have friends. Journal of Financial Economics 93:138-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1244" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. C. 1993. The modern indsutrial revolution, exit, and the failure of internal control systems. Journal
of Finance 48:831-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1255a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1259" publication-type="other">
Jenter, D., and F. Kanaan. 2015. CEO turnover and relative performance evaluation. Journal of Finance. Advance
Access published May 1,2015, 10.1111/jofi. 12282.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1269a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1273" publication-type="other">
Jenter, D., and K. Lewellen. 2010. Performance-induced CEO turnover. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1280a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1284" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., and B. A. Minton. 2011. How has CEO turnover changed? International Review of Finance
12:57-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1298" publication-type="other">
Knyazeva, A., D. Knyazeva, and R. W. Masulis. 2013. The supply of corproate directors and board independence.
Review of Financial Studies 26:1561-605.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1312" publication-type="other">
Lei, U., and D. P. Miller. 2008. International cross-listing, firm performance and top management turnover: A
test of the bonding hypothesis. Journal of Finance 63:1897-937.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1326" publication-type="other">
Linck, J. S., J. M. Netter, and T. Yang. 2008. The determinants of board structure. Journal of Financial Economics
87:308-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1341" publication-type="other">
Masulis, R. W., and S. Mobbs. 2011. Are all inside directors the same? Do they entrench CEOs or enhance board
decision making? Journal of Finance 66:812-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1355" publication-type="other">
Mobbs, S. 2013. CEOs underfire: The effects of competition from inside directors on forced CEO turnover and
CEO compensation. Journal of Fianncial and Quantitative Analysis 48:669-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1365a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1369" publication-type="other">
Parrino, R. 1997. CEO turnover and outside succession: A cross-sectional analysis. Journal of Financial
Economics 46:165-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1379a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1383" publication-type="other">
Perry, T. 1999. Incentive compensation for outside directors and CEO turnover. Working Paper, Arizona State
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1393a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1397" publication-type="other">
Raheja, C. G 2005. Determinant of board size and composition: A theory of corporate boards. Journal of Financial
and Quantitative Analysis 40:283-306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1411" publication-type="other">
Romano, R. 2005. The Sarbanes-Oxley Act and the making of quack corporate governance. Yale Law Review
114:1521-611.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1422a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1426" publication-type="other">
Shivdasani, A, and D. Yermack. 1999. CEO involvement in the selection of new board members: An empirical
analysis. Journal of Finance 54:1829-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1440" publication-type="other">
Warner, J. B., R. L. Watts, and K. H. Wruck. 1988. Stock prices and top management changes. Journal of Financial
Economics 20:431-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d4823893e1450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d4823893e1454" publication-type="other">
Weisbach, M. S. 1988. Outside directors and CEO turnover. Journal of Financial Economics 20:431-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


