<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275555</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of Secondary Air Injection During Cold Start of SI Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Dongkun</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Heywood</surname>
                  <given-names>John B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>182</fpage>
         <lpage>196</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275555"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>An experimental study was performed to develop a more fundamental understanding of the effects of secondary air injection (SAI) on exhaust gas emissions and catalyst light-off characteristics during cold start of a modern SI engine. The effects of engine operating parameters and various secondary air injection strategies such as spark retardation, fuel enrichment, secondary air injection location and air flow rate were investigated to understand the mixing, heat loss, and thermal and catalytic oxidation processes associated with SAI. Time-resolved HC, CO and CO ₂ concentrations were tracked from the cylinder exit to the catalytic converter outlet and converted to time-resolved mass emissions by applying an instantaneous exhaust mass flow rate model. A phenomenological model of exhaust heat transfer combined with the gas composition analysis was also developed to define the thermal and chemical energy state of the exhaust gas with SAI.</p>
            <p>The study found that significant emissions reduction can be achieved with SAI by the thermal oxidation process prior to the catalyst, which results in higher exhaust gas temperatures and therefore enhances the chemical process inside the catalyst by faster catalyst light-off. The engine operation, with a relative air/fuel ratio 20% rich of stoichiometric and 100% secondary air, yielded the fastest catalyst light-off time of 4.2 sec. The SAI system reduced HC emissions by 46% to 88% and CO emissions by 37% to 93% compared with the normal operating conditions. The analysis showed that the post-catalyst HC emissions levels were optimized with secondary air flow rates corresponding to an overall exhaust lambda of 1.3. The improvement in the thermal oxidation reaction with the increased mixing rates upstream of the catalyst decreased the catalytic oxidation reaction due to the increased consumption of reactants upstream of the catalyst. Therefore, the post-catalyst HC emission levels were not strongly affected by the mixing rates.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eastwood, P., Critical Topics in Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment, Research Studies Press Ltd., UK, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santoso, H. and Cheng, W.K., “Mixture Preparation and Hydrocarbon Emissions Behaviors in the First Cycle of SI Engine Cranking,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2805, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2805.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takeda, K., Yaegashi, T., Sekiguchi, K., Saito, K. et al., “Mixture Preparation and HC Emissions of a 4-Valve Engine with Port Fuel Injection during Cold Starting and Warm-up,” SAE Technical Paper 950074, 1995, doi:10.4271/950074</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meyer, R. and Heywood, J.B., “Evaporation of In- Cylinder Liquid Fuel Droplets in an SI Engine: A Diagnostic- Based Modeling Study,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0567, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0567.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borland, M. and Zhao, F., “Application of Secondary Air Injection for Simultaneously Reducing Converter-In Emissions and Improving Catalyst Light-Off Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2803, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-2803.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, D., “Effects of Secondary Air Injection During Cold Start of SI Engines”, Ph.D. Thesis, MIT Department of Mechanical Engineering, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, J., “Heat Transfer, Mixing and Hydrocarbon Oxidation in an Engine Exhaust Port”, Ph.D. Thesis, MIT Department of Mechanical Engineering, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hallgren, B.E., “Impact of Retarded Spark Timing on Engine Combustion, Hydrocarbon Emissions, and Fast Catalyst Light-Off”, Ph.D. Thesis, MIT Department of Mechanical Engineering, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mills, A.F., Heat Transfer, Prentice Hall, New Jersey, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, J.A., “Comparisons of Thermocouple, Time- Averaged and Mass-Averaged Exhaust Gas Temperatures for a Spark-Ignited Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 820050, 1982, doi:10.4271/820050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
