<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440043</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Distributional Implications of Tax Relief on Voluntary Private Pensions in Spain</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>José-Ignacio</given-names>
                  <surname>Antón</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440040</issue-id>
         <fpage>171</fpage>
         <lpage>203</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2007</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440043"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Using taxation statistics, this paper explores the distributional implications of tax relief on private pensions in Spain in 2002. For this purpose, the author suggests a decomposition of the Kakwani index and its generalisations that allows us to distinguish between the regressivity caused by targeting and that due to benefits allocation among recipients. This paper finds that these tax incentives are regressive – mainly for the latter reason – and have negative although small distributional effects. Finally, this work presents several proposals for reform of the current system and simulates their implications for equity.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e214a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e221" publication-type="other">
Submitted June 2006.
The author thanks F. Javier Brana, Miguel Carrera, Rafael Munoz de Bustillo and Lina Salanauskaite
for their useful comments on an earlier draft. He is also grateful to the Instituto de Estudios Fiscales in
Spain for providing him with the data-set for this research. The usual disclaimer applies. Previous
versions of this paper have been presented at the Swedish Institute for Futures Studies, the Summer
School in Social Protection and Governance at the University of Maastricht, the University of the
Americas-Puebla (Mexico) and the Thirty-First Symposium on Economic Analysis (Spain). Referees'
comments contributed to substantially improve the paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e250a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e257" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Dilnot and Johnson (1993) and Yoo and De Serres (2004) on the cost of tax
incentives and Engen, Gale and Scholz ( 1996), Poterba, Venti and Wise ( 1996) and Löpez Murphy and
Musalem (2004) on the effects of voluntary pension funds on national saving.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e270a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e277" publication-type="other">
See OECD (2005) and European Commission (2006) for a detailed description of the Spanish
pension system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e287a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e294" publication-type="other">
Most countries in the world follow the 'Exempted, Exempted, Taxed' (EET) tax system. The EET
regime does not tax either contributions to pension funds or fund income, but it taxes the pension in
payment. However, the T of the EET system usually becomes a 't' (for partial taxation) because in
practice the state taxes private pensions in a softer way than it taxes other incomes. For instance, the US
government exempts from taxes any payment from Individual Retirement Accounts, and lump-sum
benefits - limited to 25 per cent of the fund - are tax-free in the UK. Whitehouse (1999) provides an
overview of the different possible tax treatments of private pensions around the world.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e321a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e328" publication-type="other">
There were no data on corporate tax relief on pensions before 2001. They have been available since
2002 but, in order to construct comparable time series of tax expenditure, this section does not consider
them. Of course, neither is there any source of micro-data on corporate tax relief or exemption from
payroll taxes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e344a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e351" publication-type="other">
See, among others, Björklund and Palme (2000) on Sweden, Atkinson and Salverda (2005) on the
Netherlands and the UK, Saez (2005) on Canada and the US, and Alvaredo and Saez (2006) on Spain.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e361a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e368" publication-type="other">
Burman et al. assume 6 per cent and Yoo and De Serres 6.5 per cent, which seems very high, at least
for a baseline scenario.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e378a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e385" publication-type="other">
Most payments in Spain (roughly two-thirds) were lump-sum benefits in 2005 (Directorate General
for Insurance and Pension Funds, 2005). It is unknown why exactly some individuals are withdrawing
benefits as annuities. The most probable reason for this is that these individuals started withdrawal
several years ago (before 1999), when private pensions were subject to a different tax treatment and
lump-sum benefits were not tax-favoured (see Dominguez Barrero and Lopez Laborda (2004) for a
survey of the pensions tax regime in Spain since the early 1980s). Other possible motives may be that
these people are very risk-averse or that their tax rates at retirement are very low - so they would not pay
taxes on pensions anyway - or even that they do not have to pay income tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e414a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e421" publication-type="other">
Most literature uses this assumption in order to explain why tax relief on pensions implies a cost for
the government (Agulnik and Le Grand, 1998; Whitehouse, 1999; Hughes and Sinfield, 2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e431a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e438" publication-type="other">
Other authors also follow similar ad hoc assumptions. For example, Burman et al. (2004) assume the
same marginal tax rate during the whole working life.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e449a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e458" publication-type="other">
ln order to determine who benefits from the tax relief, Agulnik and Le Grand (1998) use aggregate
income of taxpayers, while Burman et al. (2004) choose a concept of income (which they call 'cash'
income) that includes pension contributions. Neither of these methodological options is completely
appropriate, because they are not equivalent to a pre-tax-instrument income and are not coherent with the
present-value approach these authors use to estimate the tax relief. Anyway, the impact of these
methodological options is negligible and does not affect the results obtained, mainly because the value of
tax relief in relation to total income is very small, as we will see in Section V. In other situations, this
type of decision can seriously affect results. For example, when studying the incidence of a large public
pension scheme, taking as reference total income including pensions provides very different results from
carrying out the analysis excluding pensions from the reference income. In a distributional analysis,
pensions are much more progressive under the former approach than under the latter, since a large share
of elderly income comes from old-age pensions and, without pensions, elderly people would be - in a
non-behavioural scenario - in the bottom deciles.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e503a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e510" publication-type="other">
The concentration curve provides a means of assessing the degree of income-related inequality in the
distribution of a variable. It plots the cumulative percentage of the variable (y-axis) against the
cumulative percentage of the sample, ranked by income, beginning with the poorest and ending with the
richest (x-axis). See, for example, Lambert (1993) for details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e526a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e533" publication-type="other">
For instance, when the Spanish government was studying reforms to the current system last year, a
union leader suggested that tax relief was widely used across all income levels (El Mundo, 3 March
2006), and the chief of the association of pension funds made a similar statement downplaying its
possible regressivity (El Mundo, 2 February 2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e549a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e556" publication-type="other">
The reranking effect is the difference between the concentration index of after-tax-expenditure
income and the Gini index of the same variable. These indices are not equivalent if the transfer (the tax
relief in this paper) alters the relative position of tax units in the income distribution.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e569a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e576" publication-type="other">
The two regions not present in the database have been excluded from Spanish GDP. The result
obtained is very similar to the one reported by Yoo and De Serres (2004) using a representative
individual approach (0.22 per cent of GDP).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e589a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e596" publication-type="other">
The proportion of tax units receiving tax relief (17 per cent) is substantially lower than the ratio
between total contributors and workers presented in Table 1 (39 per cent in 2002). These figures are very
different but are making reference to different facts. The figure presented in Table 1 is a ratio between the
total number of contributors (according to administrative data provided by pension funds) and the total
number of workers (according to the Spanish Labour Force Survey), whose aim is to offer a rough picture
of the increasing importance of supplementary pensions rather than an accurate picture of coverage. The
figure presented in Table 3 refers to the proportion of tax units receiving the subsidy (17 per cent). Apart
from the discrepancy that exists between number of tax units and total population, it is clear that the
numerator and denominator are both different in these expressions. In the first one, the denominator is
smaller (it only contains workers) and the numerator is larger (it includes all kind of contributors, both
recipients and non-recipients of the tax relief) than in the second one. The contributions of contributors
not entitled to tax relief (because they have low labour incomes on which they do not pay income tax) do
not appear in the tax database.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e642a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e649" publication-type="other">
It should be mentioned that these figures only include tax relief on pension contributions. In the case
of Australia, the limited concentration of tax deductions is probably because coverage is almost
universal, since contributions to pension funds are mandatory for all workers except low-paid employees
and the self-employed (Rein and Turner, 2004), and because Australia taxes funded pensions at all three
possible points (contributions, fund income and withdrawal) (Yoo and De Serres, 2004), which can raise
some questions regarding efficiency - for example, issues related to triple taxation - that are not analysed
here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e675a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e682" publication-type="other">
The values for the parameter v usually chosen in the literature have been used in the analysis
presented in this section, though it is possible to select any value above unity. See, as examples, Lerman
and Yitzhaki (1985), Wodon and Yitzhaki (2002) and Angel-Urdinola and Wodon (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e695a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e702" publication-type="other">
In order to put these figures into context, it can be mentioned that the least progressive social
transfer in Spain in the mid-1990s - public spending on higher education - showed a Kakwani index of
0.009 (Calonge and Manresa, 2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e715a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e722" publication-type="other">
A programme of direct subsidies quite similar to the one suggested here is used in the Czech
Republic (Tomes, Koldinska and Nemec, 2003, p. 44).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e732a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e739" publication-type="other">
See Munnell, Sundén and Taylor (2001) for a survey of determinants of contributions to pension
funds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e749a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e756" publication-type="other">
ln the case of people considering the whole tax system when making pension contributions, it would
be necessary to assume that they would guess how much tax they would pay in the future on withdrawals
and to adopt a functional form for discounting and a specific discount rate. This would not be exempt
from problems. For instance, according to Rubinstein (2003), both standard discounting and hyperbolic
discounting are rejected by experimental evidence.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e776a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e783" publication-type="other">
Regarding redistribution, one has to bear in mind that under Proposal III, the amount of the tax relief
(i.e. the size of the transfer) is smaller, so its comparability to the first two proposals is limited.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d29e802a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e806" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. B. (2001), 'Will bequests attenuate the predicted meltdown in stock prices when
baby boomers retire?', Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 83, pp. 589-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e816a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e820" publication-type="other">
Agulnik, P. and Le Grand, J. (1998), 'Tax relief and partnership pensions', Fiscal Studies,
vol. 19, pp. 403-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e830a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e834" publication-type="other">
Altmann, R. (2003), 'Beyond tax relief: a new savings incentive framework', in W. Paxton
(ed.), Equal Shares? Building a Progressive and Coherent Asset-Based Welfare Policy,
London: Institute for Public Policy Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e847a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e851" publication-type="other">
Alvaredo, F. and Saez, E. (2006), 'Income and wealth concentration in Spain in a historical
and fiscal perspective', Centre for Economic Policy Research, Discussion Paper no. 5836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e862a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e866" publication-type="other">
Angel-Urdinola, D. F. and Wodon, Q. (2004), 'The impact on inequality of raising the
minimum wage', Labour, vol. 18, pp. 317-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e876a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e880" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. B. (2002), 'Data matter', revised version of Alfred Cowles Lecture given at the
Australasian Meetings of the Econometric Society, Auckland, July 2001. Available at
http://www.nuff.ox.ac.uk/users/atkinson/Data%20Matter.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e893a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e897" publication-type="other">
— and Salverda, W. (2005), 'Top incomes in the Netherlands and the United Kingdom over
the 20lh century', Journal of the European Economic Association, vol. 3, pp. 883-913.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e907a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e911" publication-type="other">
Barr, N. (1979), 'Myths my grandpa taught me', Three Banks Review, vol. 124, pp. 27-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e922" publication-type="other">
— (1992), 'Economic theory and the Welfare State: a survey and interpretation', Journal of
Economic Literature, vol. 30, pp. 741-803.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e932a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e936" publication-type="other">
— (2000), 'Reforming pensions: myths, truths, and policy choices', International Monetary
Fund, Working Paper no. 139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e947a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e951" publication-type="other">
— (2004), The Economics of the Welfare State, fourth edition, Oxford: Oxford University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e961a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e965" publication-type="other">
Basset, W. F., Fleming, M. J. and Rodrigues, A. P. (1998), 'How workers use 401(k) plans:
the participation, contribution and withdrawal decisions', Federal Reserve Bank of New
York, Working Paper no. 38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e978a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e982" publication-type="other">
Björklund, A. and Palme, M. (2000), 'The evolution of inequality during the rise of the
Swedish Welfare State 1951 to 1973', Nordic Journal of Political Economy, vol. 26, pp.
115-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e995a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e999" publication-type="other">
Börsch-Supan, A. and Lührmann, M. (2003), 'Retirement benefit and pension taxation
principles', in O. Castellino and E. Fornero (eds), Pension Policy in an Integrating
Europe, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1012a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1016" publication-type="other">
Bosworth, B. and Burtless, G. (2004), 'Pension reform and saving', National Tax Journal,
vol. 57, pp. 703-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1026a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1030" publication-type="other">
Brana, F. J. (1982), 'Las poh'ticas de beneficios tributarios: cuestiones técnicas', Hacienda
Publica Espanola, vol. 74, pp. 87-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1041a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1045" publication-type="other">
Burman, L. E., Gale, W. L., Hall, M. and Orszag, P. (2004), 'Distributional effects of defined
contribution plans and individual retirement arrangements', National Tax Journal, vol.
57, pp. 671-701.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1058a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1062" publication-type="other">
Calero, J. (2002), 'The distribution of public social expenditure in Spain: a general analysis
with special reference to age and social class', Social Policy and Administration, vol. 45,
pp. 443-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1075a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1079" publication-type="other">
Calonge, S. and Manresa, A. (2001), Incidencia Fiscal y del Gasto Publico Social sobre la
Distribution de la Renta en Espaha y sus C.C.A.A., Bilbao: Fundaciön BBVA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1089a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1093" publication-type="other">
Cesaratto, S. (2005), Pension Reform and Economic Theory: A Non-Orthodox Approach,
Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1103a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1107" publication-type="other">
Cowell, F. A. (2000), Measuring Inequality, third edition, Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1114a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1118" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A. and Johnson, P. (1993), 'Tax expenditures: the case of occupational pensions',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 14, no. 1, pp. 42-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1129a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1133" publication-type="other">
Directorate General for Insurance and Pension Funds (Direccion General de Seguros y
Fondos de Pensiones) (2005), 'Planes y fondos de pensiones: informe estadistico 2005',
http://www.dgsfp.mineco.es/docs/internet/Memoria_2005_Fondos/Memoria_2005.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1146a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1150" publication-type="other">
Dormnguez Barrero, F. and Lopez Laborda, J. (2004), '^Por qué ahorra la gente en planes de
pensiones individuals?', Instituto de Estudios Fiscales, Working Paper no. 27/04.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1160a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1164" publication-type="other">
Duclos, J-Y. (2000), 'Gini indices and the redistribution of income', International Tax and
Public Finance, vol. 7, pp. 141-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1174a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1178" publication-type="other">
Eatwell, J. (1999), 'The anatomy of pension crisis', Economic Survey of Europe, vol. 1999,
no. 3, Geneva: United Nations Economic Commission for Europe.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1188a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1192" publication-type="other">
Ebbinghaus, B. (2006), 'The better side of private pensions: collective and state regulation of
occupational pensions', paper presented at the Fifteenth International Conference of the
Council for European Studies, Chicago, 29 March - 2 April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1205a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1209" publication-type="other">
Engen, E. M. and Gale, W. G. (1997), 'Effects of social security reform on private and
national saving', in S. A. Sass and R. K. Triest (eds), Social Security Reform Conference
Proceedings: Links to Saving, Investment, and Growth, Boston: Federal Reserve of
Boston.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1226a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1230" publication-type="other">
—, — and Scholz, J. K. (1996), 'The illusory effects of saving incentives on saving', Journal
of Economic Perspectives, vol. 10, no. 4, pp. 113-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1240a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1244" publication-type="other">
European Commission (2006), Mutual Information System on Social Protection, Brussels:
European Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1254a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1258" publication-type="other">
Gale, W. G. and Dworsky, M. (2006), 'Effect of public policies on the disposition of lump
sum distributions: rational and behavioral influences', Center for Retirement Research at
Boston College, Working Paper no. 2006-15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1271a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1275" publication-type="other">
Geanakoplos, J., Magill, M. and Quinzii, M. (2002), 'Demography and the long-run
predictability of the stock markets', Cowles Foundation, Discussion Paper no. 1380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1285a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1289" publication-type="other">
Hemming, R. (1998), 'Should public pensions be funded?', International Monetary Fund,
Working Paper no. 35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1299a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1303" publication-type="other">
Holzmann, R. (2000), 'The World Bank approach to pension reform', International Social
Security Review, vol. 53, pp. 11-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1314a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1318" publication-type="other">
Hughes, G. (2001), 'The cost and distribution of tax expenditure on occupational pensions in
Ireland', Economic and Social Research Institute, Working Paper no. 139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1328a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1332" publication-type="other">
— (2002), 'Private pensions and equity in Ireland and the U.K.', Economic and Social
Research Institute, Working Paper no. 142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1342a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1346" publication-type="other">
— and Sinfield, A. (2004), 'Financing pensions by stealth: the Anglo-American model and
the cost and distribution of tax benefits for private pensions', in G. Hughes and J. Stewart
(eds), Reforming Pensions in Europe: Evolution of Pension Financing and Sources of
Retirement Income, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1362a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1366" publication-type="other">
International Labour Organisation (ILO) (2000), 'Perspectives: pension reform - what the
debate is about', International Labour Review, vol. 139, pp. 197-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1376a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1380" publication-type="other">
Kahneman, D., Odean, T. and Barber, B. (2005), 'Privatized pensions: an irrational choice',
Global Agenda Magazine, a publication of the World Economic Forum 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1390a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1394" publication-type="other">
Lambert, P. J. (1993), The Distribution and Redistribution of Income: A Mathematical
Analysis, Manchester: Manchester University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1405a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1409" publication-type="other">
Lerman, R. I. and Yitzhaki, S. (1985), 'Income inequality effects by income source: a new
approach and applications to the United States', Review of Economics and Statistics, vol.
67, pp. 151-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1422a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1426" publication-type="other">
Lopez Garcia, M. A. (2000), 'Pensiones privadas y ahorro agregado', Hacienda Publica
Espahola, Special Number 2000, pp. 279-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1436a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1440" publication-type="other">
Lopez Murphy, P. and Musalem, A. R. (2004), 'Pension funds and national saving', World
Bank, Working Paper no. 3410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1450a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1454" publication-type="other">
MacKellar, F. L. and Reisen, H. (1998), International Diversification of Pension Assets Is No
Panacea for Population Aging, IIASA Interim Report IR-98-034, Laxenburg, Austria:
International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1467a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1471" publication-type="other">
Madrian, B. C. and Shea, D. F. (2001), 'The power of suggestion: inertia in 401 (k)
participation and saving behavior', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 116, pp. 1149—
87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1484a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1488" publication-type="other">
Ministry of the Treasury (2002), Manual prâctico renta 2002, Madrid: Ministerio de
Econorma y Hacienda.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1499a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1503" publication-type="other">
Munnell, A. H., Sundén, A. and Taylor, C. (2001), 'What determines 401 (k) participation and
contributions?', Social Security Bulletin, vol. 64, no. 3, pp. 64—75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1513a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1517" publication-type="other">
OECD (2005), Pensions at a Glance 2005, Paris: Organisation for Economic Cooperation
and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1527a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1531" publication-type="other">
Orszag, P. R. and Orszag, J. (2000), 'Would raising IRA contribution limits bolster retirement
security for lower- and middle-income families or is there a better way?',
http://www.cbpp.org/4-12-00tax2.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1544a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1548" publication-type="other">
Pensions Policy Institute (2004), 'Tax relief and incentives for pension saving'. Research
Paper for Age Concern England, available at http://www.pensionspolicyinstitute.org.uk.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1558a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1562" publication-type="other">
Picos, F., Antiqueira, M., Pérez, C., Moreno, A., Marcos, C. and Diaz de Sarralde, S. (2005),
'La muestra de déclarantes del IRPF de 2002: descripciön general y principales
magnitudes', Instituto de Estudios Fiscales, Working Paper no. 20/05.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1579" publication-type="other">
Poterba, J. M., Venti, S. F. and Wise, D. A. (1996), 'How retirement saving programs
increase saving', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 10, no. 4, pp. 91-112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1590a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1594" publication-type="other">
Rein, M. and Turner, J. (2004), 'Pathways to pension coverage', in G. Hughes and J. Stewart
(eds), Reforming Pensions in Europe: Evolution of Pension Financing and Sources of
Retirement Income, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1607a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1611" publication-type="other">
Rubinstein, A. (2003), "'Economics and psychology"? The case of hyperbolic discounting',
International Economic Review, vol. 44, pp. 1207-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1621a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1625" publication-type="other">
Ruiz-Huerta, J. (2004), 'El déficit de servicios sociales. ^.Qué pasô con el gasto social en
Espana?', Circunstancia, vol. 4, http://www.ortegaygasset.edu/circunstancia/numero4/
art4.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1638a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1642" publication-type="other">
Saez, E. (2005), 'Top income in the United States and Canada over the twentieth century',
Journal of the European Economic Association, vol. 3, pp. 402-11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1652a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1656" publication-type="other">
Serrano, F., Garcia, M. A. and Bravo, C. (2004), El sistema espahol de pensiones. Un
proyecto viable desde un enfoque econömico, Barcelona: Ariel.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1666a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1670" publication-type="other">
Thompson, L. (1998), Older and Wiser: The Economics of Public Pensions, Aldershot:
Ashgate.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1681a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1685" publication-type="other">
Tomes, I., Koldinska, K. and Nemec, J. (2003), Czech Republic: Country Study, study
financed by the European Commission, http://europa.eu.int/comm/employment_social/
social_protection.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1698a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1702" publication-type="other">
Utkus, S. P. and Young, J. A. (2004), 'Lessons from behavioral finance and the autopilot
401(k) plan', Report for the Vanguard Center for Retirement Research, https://
institutional.vanguard.com/iip/pdf/crr_autopilot.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1715a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1719" publication-type="other">
Whitehouse, E. (1999), 'The tax treatment of funded pensions', World Bank, Social
Protection Discussion Paper no. 9910.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1729a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1733" publication-type="other">
Wodon, Q. and Yitzhaki, S. (2002), 'Evaluating the impact of government programs on social
welfare: the role of targeting and the allocation rules among program beneficiaries',
Public Finance Review, vol. 30, pp. 102-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1746a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1750" publication-type="other">
World Bank (1994), Averting the Old Age Crisis: Policies to Protect the Old and Promote
Growth, New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1760a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1764" publication-type="other">
— (1999), Taxation: The Tax Treatment of Funded Pensions, World Bank Pension Reform
Primer no. 06/99, Washington, DC: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1775a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1779" publication-type="other">
— (ed.) (2005), Old-Age Income Support in the 21s' Century. An International Perspective on
Pension Systems and Reform, Washington, DC: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1793" publication-type="other">
Yitzhaki, S. (1983), 'On an extension of the Gini index', International Economic Review, vol.
24, pp. 617-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e1803a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e1807" publication-type="other">
Yoo, K. and De Serres, A. (2004), 'Tax treatment of pension contribution savings in OECD
countries and the net tax cost per unit of contribution to tax-favoured schemes', OECD
Economics Department, Working Paper no. 406.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
