<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278142</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Diesel Emissions in Review</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Corning Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>143</fpage>
         <lpage>157</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278142"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This review summarizes the latest developments in diesel emissions regarding regulations, engines, NOx (nitrogen oxides) control, particulate matter (PM) reductions, and hydrocarbon (HC) and CO oxidation.</p>
            <p>Regulations are advancing with proposals for 70% tightening of fleet average light-duty (LD) criteria emissions likely to be proposed in California for ∼2016-22. CO ₂ regulations in both the heavy - and light-duty sectors will also tighten and impact diesel engines and emissions, probably long into the future.</p>
            <p>Engine technology is addressing these needs. Light-duty diesel engines are making incremental gains with combustion enhancements that allow downsizing for CO ₂ savings. Heavy-duty (HD) engine show trade-offs between hardware recipes, exhaust deNOx control, and fuel consumption.</p>
            <p>Much has recently been reported on optimized selective catalytic reduction (SCR) systems, with many reports on improving low temperature performance with proper reductant management and new catalyst formulations. Developments on HC-based deNOx are focused on lean NOx traps (LNTs) and the LNT+SCR systems, wherein the LNT is calibrated to generate ammonia for use in a downstream SCR.</p>
            <p>PM control with DPFs (diesel particulate filters) are very effective. DPF regeneration advances are reported in strategy, catalyst utilization, and substrate design. Biodiesel effects on DPF functions are becoming clearer.</p>
            <p>Finally, diesel oxidation catalysts (DOCs) are investigated in the context of impacting NO ₂ coming from a downstream catalyzed DPF for use in an SCR system. Hydrocarbon removal from the DOC is quite important in this regard.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T.V., “Review of Diesel Emissions and Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):16-29, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Public Workshop to Discuss Potential Technologies for 2017 and Later Model Year Passenger Vehicles - LEV III, May 18, 2010, El Monte, California, http://www.arb.ca.gov/msprog/levprog/leviii/leviii.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Public Workshop to Discuss Proposed Modifications to Criteria and Greenhouse Gas Emission Requirements for Light- and Medium-Duty Vehicles - Advanced Clean Cars, November 16, 2010, El Monte, California, http://www.arb.ca.gov/msprog/levprog/leviii/leviii.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cackette, T., “The Path to Low Carbon Passenger Vehicles”, US Department of Energy “Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference”, September 27-30, 2010, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Interim Joint Technical Assessment Report: Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards for Model Years 2017-2025, http://www.epa.gov/otaq/climate/regulations/ldvghg- tar.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">An, F., et al., “Passenger Vehicle Greenhouse Gas and Fuel Economy Standards: A Global Update”, the International Council on Clean Transportation, June 2008, updated November 2009. http://www.TheICCT.org</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lakshminarayanan, P.A., “The Introduction of Bharat Stage 4 into the Indian Market,” Presentation at the SAE 2010 Heavy Duty Diesel Emissions Control Symposium, September, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Proposed Rulemaking: Greenhouse Gas Emissions Standards and Fuel Efficiency Standards for Medium- and Heavy-Duty Engines and Vehicles (Published November 30, 2010), Federal Register/ Vol. 75, No. 229/ Tuesday, November 30, 2010/ Proposed Rules.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wani, K., “Fuel Efficiency Standard for Heavy-Duty Vehicles in Japan”, presentation at International Workshop: Fuel Efficiency Policies for Heavy-Duty Vehicles, International Energy Agency, Paris, June 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T. V., “Review of CO2 Emissions and Technologies in the Road Transportation Sector,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 1079-1098, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Körfer, T., Schnorbus, T., Kalenborn, M., Kolbeck, A., Bourgoin, G., Cecur, M., Raimondi, E., “Integrated Diesel Engine Concept for Lowest CO2-Emission Requirements”, Aachen Colloquium, October 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tatur, M., “Future Directions in Engines and Vehicles”, US Department of Energy “Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference”, September 27-30, 2010, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Körfer, T., Lamping, M., Kolbeck, A., Pischinger, S. et al., “Potential of Modern Diesel Engines with Lowest Raw Emissions - a Key Factor for Future CO2 Reduction,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-26-025, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-26-025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomoda, T., Ohki, H., Koyama, T., Fujiwara, K., “Study of Diesel Combustion Improvement for Ultra Low Compression Ratio”, Aachen Colloquium, October 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weißbäck, M., Sorger, H., Zieher, F., Howlett, M., Krapf, S., Gutmann, P., “Tomorrow's Diesel Engines: Layout and Achieved Results Examples from Current Development Projects in a Production Context”, Aachen Colloquium, October 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cisternino, M., “Influence of Mild Hybridization on Performance and Emission in a 4 Cylinder in-Line Common Rail Diesel Engine”, US Department of Energy “Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference”, September 27-30, 2010, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krüger, M., Cornetti, G., Greis, A., Weidmann, U., Schumacher, H., Ger, J., “Operational Strategies of a Diesel Hybrid Electric Vehicle with Focus on the Combustion Engine”, Aachen Colloquium, October 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Charlton, S. J., “Meeting the US Heavy-Duty EPA 2010 Standards and Providing Increased Value for the Customer”, AVL 6th International Exhaust Gas and Particulate Emissions Forum, March 2010, Ludwigsburg, Germany</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parche, M., Sassen, K. P., Leonhard, R., Alvarez-Avila, C., “Bosch 2000/2200 bar Common Rail System for Commercial Vehicles”, Vienna Motorsymposium, April 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sassen, K.P., “Optimized CV-Solutions for Low Emissions and High Performance,” Presentation at SAE 2010 Heavy Duty Diesel Emissions Control Symposium, September, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanton, D., “Technology Development for High Efficiency Clean Diesel Engines and a Pathway to 50% Thermal Efficiency”, presentation at US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference, Dearborn, Michigan, August 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ligterink, N., de Lange, R., Vermeulen, R., Dekker, H., “On-Road NOx Emissions of Euro-V Trucks”, TNO report MON-RPT-033-DTS-2009-03840, 2 December 2009, Assignor Ministerie van VROM, Den Haag.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dollmeyer, T., Grana, T., “Meeting The US Heavy-Duty EPA 2010 Standards”, 3rd International IAV MinNOx Conference, Berlin, 29 June 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Charlton, S.J., “Meeting the US Heavy-Duty EPA 2010 Standards and Providing Increased Value for the Customer,” Presentation at SAE 2010 Heavy Duty Diesel Emissions Control Symposium, September, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Conicella, F., “Low Particulate Combustion Development of Medium Duty Engines for Off-Highway Application”, MTZ Conference on On/Off Highway Engines, Friedrichshafen, November 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Unger, H.-M., “Modular Exhaust Gas Treatment System for Off - Highway Applications”, 3rd International CTI Conference, 12th - 13th Oct. 2010, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jaussi, F., “Emission Concepts for Off-Highway Applications”, 3rd International CTI Conference, 12th - 13th Oct. 2010, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Macaudiere, P., “SCR as a Technical Response to Automotive Environmental Challenges”, 3rd International IAV MinNOx Conference, Berlin, 29 June 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhan, R., Li, W., Eakle, S. T., Weber, P. A., “Development of a Novel Device to Improve Urea Evaporation, Mixing and Distribution to Enhance SCR Performance”, SAE 2010-01-1185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kröcher, O., Elsener, M., Mehring, M., Bernhard, A., “Highly-Developed Thermal Analysis Methods for the Characterization of Soot and Deposits in Urea SCR Systems”, AVL 6th International Exhaust Gas and Particulate Emissions Forum, March 2010, Ludwigsburg, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brück, R., Holz, O., Konieczny, R., “SCR Upgraded Aftertreatment System for EU VI Vehicles to Reduce Urban NOx Emissions”, 3rd International IAV MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johannessen, T., “Compact Ammonia Storage Systems for Fuel-Efficient NOX Emissions Reduction”, CTI Conference on SCR Systems Stuttgart, Germany, July 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, M., “Customised NOx Aftertreatment for Diesel Passenger Cars to Meet Worldwide Emission Standards”, International Quality and Productivity Center (IQPC) Conference, November 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamasamudram, K., Currier, N., Szailer, T., and Yezerets, A., “Why Cu- and Fe-Zeolite SCR Catalysts Behave Differently at Low Temperatures,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):664-672, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nova, I., Colombo, M., Tronconi, E., Schmeisser, V., Weibel, M., “Transient Kinetic Study and Modelling of the NO/NO2 NH3-SCR Reactions over Cu- and Fe-Zeolite Catalysts for Diesel Exhaust Aftertreatment”, 3rd International IAV MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ido, T., Yoshimura, K., Kunieda, M., Tamura, Y. et al., “Volume Reduction of SCR Catalyst Using Zeolite-Base Honeycomb Substrate,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):614-624, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forzatti, P., Nova, I., and Tronconi, E., “Removal of NOx from Diesel Exhausts: The New “Enhanced NH3-SCR” Reaction,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):654-663, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, X., Narala, C., “Simple Approach to Tuning Catalytic Activity of MFI-Zeolites for Low Temperature SCR of NOx”, poster at US Department of Energy “Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference”, September 27-30, 2010, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rohart, E., Marques, R., Kröcher, O., Elsener, M., Harris, D., Jones, C., “Progress on Acidic Zirconia Mixed Oxides for Efficient NH3-SCR Catalysis”, 3rd International IAV MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Casapu, M., Bernhard, A., Peitz, D., Mehring, M., Elsener, M., Kröcher, O., “New CeO2 - Based Catalysts for the SCR of NO with NH3”, ADAP Catalyst Conference, Krakow, September 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapman, D.M., Fu, G., Augustine, S., Watson, M. et al., “New Titania Materials with Improved Stability and Activity for Vanadia-Based Selective Catalytic Reduction of NOx,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):643-653, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, A.P., “Optimising Future Catalyst Systems,” Presentation at SAE 2010 Heavy Duty Diesel Emissions Control Symposium, September, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adelman, B., Santhanam, S., Strots, V., Miller, M., Derybowski, E., “Direct NH3 Addition to Exhaust Streams Employing a Combined PM/NOx Reduction Aftertreatment Device for US2010 and EURO VI Applications”, 3rd International IAV MinNOx Conference, Berlin, June 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Folić, M., Lemus, L., Gekas, I., Vressner, A., “Selective Ammonia Slip Catalyst Enabling Highly Efficient NOx Removal Requirements of the Future”, US Department of Energy “Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference”, September 27-30, 2010, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guo, G., Warner, J., Cavataio, G., Dobson, D. et al., “The Development of Advanced Urea-SCR Systems for Tier 2 Bin 5 and Beyond Diesel Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1183, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laroo, C.A., “EPA SCR Unregulated Emissions Test Program: Dioxin, Furan, PCB, and PAH Emissions from a Compression Ignition Engine Utilizing CuZ SCR,” Panel Presentation at SAE 2010 World Congress &amp; Exhibition, April, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qi, G., Kim, C., Li, W., “Pt-Free, Perovskite-Based LNT Catalyst”, US Department of Energy “Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference”, September 27-30, 2010, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bonzi, R., Lietti, L., Castoldi, L., Forzatti, P., “NOx Removal Over a Double-Bed NSR-SCR Reactor Configuration”, Catalysis Today 151 (2010) 376-385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kodama, Y. and Wong, V.W., “Study of On-Board Ammonia (NH3) Generation for SCR Operation,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):537-555, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1071.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, L., McCabe, R., Dearth, M., and Ruona, W., “Laboratory and Vehicle Demonstration of “2nd-Generation” LNT + in-situ SCR Diesel NOx Emission Control Systems,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):37-49, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forzatti, P., Lietti, L., Nova, I., Morandi, S., Prinetto, F., Ghiotti, G., “Reaction Pathway of the Reduction by CO under Dry Conditions of NOx Species Stored onto PtABa/A12O3 Lean NOx Trap Catalysts”, Journal of Catalysis 274 (2010) 163-175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Theis, J.R., Ura, J.A., and McCabe, R.W., “The Effects of Sulfur Poisoning and Desulfation Temperature on the NOx Conversion of LNT+SCR Systems for Diesel Applications,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):1-15, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H.-Y., Weigert, E.C., Fedeyko, J.M., Cox, J.P. et al., “Advanced Catalysts for Combined (NAC + SCR) Emission Control Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0302, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murayama, T., Aoyagi, Y., Kobayashi, M., Adachi, T. et al., “Effective Usage of LNT in High Boosted and High EGR Rate of Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1066, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warner, J.R., Dobson, D., and Cavataio, G., “A Study of Active and Passive Regeneration Using Laboratory Generated Soot on a Variety of SiC Diesel Particulate Filter Formulations,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1): 149-164, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0533.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Southward, B.W.L., Basso, S., and Pfeifer, M., “On the Development of Low PGM Content Direct Soot Combustion Catalysts for Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0558, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0558.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iretskaya, S., Golden, S., Tadrous, T., and Long, S.H., “PM Control with Low NO2 Tailpipe Emissions by Systems with Non-PGM Catalyzed DPF for Passive Soot Regeneration,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0563, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0563.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karin, P. and Hanamura, K., “Particulate Matter Trapping and Oxidation on a Catalyst Membrane,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):368-379, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0808.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizutani, T., Iwasaki, S., Miyairi, Y., Yuuki, K. et al., “Performance Verification of Next Generation Diesel Particulate Filter,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0531, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heibel, A., “Advancements in Substrate Technology,” Presentation at SAE 2010 Heavy Duty Diesel Emissions Control Symposium, September, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boger, T., Jamison, J. A., Warkins, J. L., Golomb, N. A., Warren, C. J., Heibel, A. K., “Next Generation Aluminum- Titanate Material to Meet Upcoming EU6 Emissions Legislation Requirements”, Aachen Colloquium, October 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weigl, M., C. Roduner, C., Lauer, T., “Particle-Filter- Onboard-Diagnosis by Means of a Soot-Sensor Downstream of the Particle-Filter”, AVL 6th International Exhaust Gas and Particulate Emissions Forum, March 2010, Ludwigsburg, Germany</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finch, S., Hnilicka, B., Sindano, H., “EURO6 Light- Duty Vehicle OBD Project - Evaluation and Assessment of Proposed EOBD Emission Thresholds”, ACEACommissioned Report RD. 10/320201.4, November 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kondo, A., Sakuma, T., Sakurai, T., Egami, T., Tokuda, M., Yokoi, S., “New Particulate Matter Sensor for On-Board Diagnostics”, Aachen Colloquium, October 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Besch, M. C., Thiruvengadam, A., Carder, D., Littera, D., Mulone, V., Tikkanen, J., Gautam, M., “In-Line, Real- Time Exhaust PM Emissions Sensor -OBD and DPF Control System Applications”, 20th CRC On-Road Vehicle Emissions Workshop, March 2010, San Diego, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zidat, S., “Diesel Particulate Filters On Board Diagnostic”, poster at US Department of Energy “Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference”, September 27-30, 2010, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Austin, G., Naber, J., Johnson, J., and Hutton, C., “Effects of Biodiesel Blends on Particulate Matter Oxidation in a Catalyzed Particulate Filter during Active Regeneration,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):194-218, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0557.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>68.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strzelec, A., Toops, T., Daw, S., Foster, D., Rutland, C, “Particulate Matter Oxidation Kinetics: Surface Area Dependence”, CLEERS Conference, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>69.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsushima, S., Nakamura, I., Sakashita, S., Hirai, S. et al., “Lattice Boltzmann Simulation on Particle Transport and Captured Behaviors in a 3D-Reconstructed Micro Porous DPF,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0534, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>70.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spurk, P., Frantz, S., Schütze, F. W., Noack, H. D., Müller, W., “NO2 Formation on the DOC/DPF System - a system thought”, AVL 6th International Exhaust Gas and Particulate Emissions Forum, March 2010, Ludwigsburg, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
