<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">98</volume>
         <issue-id>i40187949</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44471676</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Intelligent Fault Tolerant Systems for Thermal Control in Space Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Osella</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>746</fpage>
         <lpage>758</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1990 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44471676"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper describes two smart fault tolerant systems (EURECA TCU and Pump Package ECU) that have been studied by MICROTECNICA in the frame of European Space programs. EURECA TCU: The TCU is the electronic unit of the EURECA Thermal Control System and consists of two cold redundant sections each with the prime task of controlling the temperature of 127 points on the carrier. It does this by switching on and off the appropriate heater, according to the temperature measured by the dedicated thermistors. Each control loop (thermistor, TCU, heater) is dual redundant and can be activated individually in case of one failure. The system can tolerate one failure without the loss of the correspondent control function. PUMP PACKAGE ECU: This is a proposed system to act as the electronic unit for the control and regulation of the mass flow of a water and/or freon pump package. It consists of two redundant electronic control channels. Each channel is capable of fulfilling the control function autonomously, to diagnose a failure condition and then to self inhibit. Therefore, the combination of the two electronic control channels constitutes a single failure tolerant system.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


