<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277673</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comparison of PFI and DI Operation in a Downsized Gasoline Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Knop</surname>
                  <given-names>Vincent</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Essayem</surname>
                  <given-names>Eddie</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IFP Energies nouvelles</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>941</fpage>
         <lpage>952</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277673"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A 300 cc gasoline engine has been experimentally and numerically studied to compare PFI and DI operation on naturally-aspirated and turbocharged full load operating points. Experiment outlines the benefits from DI operation in terms of volumetric efficiency, fuel economy and knock propensity but also clearly indicates worse raw engine-out CO emissions. The latter is an indication of the survival of a large scale mixture heterogeneity in this downsized GDI engine even when early injection and intense induced fluid motion are combined.</p>
            <p>For such a full load operation, the application of optical diagnostics to study mixture heterogeneity cannot be considered because pressure and temperature exceed sustainable levels for transparent materials. Therefore, 3D CFD RANS computations of the intake, injection, combustion and pollutant formation processes including detailed chemistry information are performed to complement the experimental data. The results at the end of compression stroke confirm the existence of a large scale mixture stratification. Moreover, the degree of mixture stratification can be directly related to the measured CO emissions. Combustion and pollutant formation modelling with detailed chemistry information allows quantifying the influence of locally rich mixtures on flame propagation and post-flame chemistry (CO and NOₓ emissions).</p>
            <p>Computations for various injection timings on a unique operating point explain why the experimentally-chosen injection timing is optimal. The interaction of intake-induced fluid motion with injection-induced fluid motion gives rise to a trade-off between turbulence and mixture homogeneity near TDC. Increased turbulence favours combustion speed and reduces knock propensity, which should lead to a better efficiency. But the gain in turbulence is counter-balanced by an enlarged mixture heterogeneity producing larger CO emissions and therefore impeding global efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hentschel, W., Block, B., Hovestadt, T., Meyer, H. et al., “Optical Diagnostics and CFD-Simulations to Support the Combustion Process Development of the Volkswagen FSI® Direct-Injection Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3648, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-3648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mastrangelo, G., Micelli, D. and Sacco, D., “Extreme Downsizing by the Two-cylinder Gasoline Engine from FIAT”, MTZ 72(2):4-10, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heiduk, T., Kuhn, M., Stichlmeier, M. and Unselt, F., “The New 1.8 l TFSI Engine from Audi - Part 2: Mixture Formation, Combustion Method and Turbocharging”, MTZ 72(8):58-64, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedfeldt, R., Zenner, T., Ernst, R. and Fraser, A., “Three-Cylinder Gasoline Engine with Direct Injection”, MTZ 73(5):5-11, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Linse, D., Hasse, C. and Durst, B., “An experimental and numerical investigation of turbulent flame propagation and flame structure in a turbo-charged direct injection gasoline engine”, Combust. Theor. Model. 13(1):167-188, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mounaïm-Rousselle, C., Landry, L., Halter, F. and Foucher, F., “Experimental characteristics of turbulent premixed flame in a boosted Spark-Ignition engine”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 34:2941-2949, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baretzky, U., Andor, T., Diel, H., and Ullrich, W., “The Direct Injection System of the 2001 Audi Turbo V8 Le Mans Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-3357, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-3357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bohbot, J., Gillet, N. and Benkenida, A., “IFP-C3D: an unstructured parallel solver for reactive compressible gas flow with spray”, Oil Gas Sci. Technol. 64:309-335, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colin, O. and Truffin, K., “A spark ignition model for large eddy simulation based on an FSD transport equation (ISSIM-LES)”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 33:3097-3104, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knop, V., Michel, J.-B. and Colin, O., “On the use of a tabulation approach to model auto-ignition during flame propagation in SI engines”, Appl. Energy 88:4968-4979, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knop, V., Nicolle, A. and Colin, O., “Modelling and speciation of nitrogen oxides in engines”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 34:667-675, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z. and Reitz, R. D., “Turbulence modeling of internal combustion engines using RNG k-ε models”, Combust. Sci. Technol. 106:267-295, 1995</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kays, W. M. and Crawford, M. E., “Convective heat and mass transfer”, 3rd ed, McGraw-Hill, 1994</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R.D., “Modeling atomization processes in high pressure vaporizing sprays”, Atomization Spray Technol. 3, 309-337, 1987</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P. and Amsden, A., “A Particle Numerical Model for Wall Film Dynamics in Port-Injected Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 961961, 1996, doi: 10.4271/961961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P. and Amsden, A., “A Spray/Wall Interaction Submodel for the KIVA-3 Wall Film Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0271, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reveille, B., Kleemann, A., Knop, V., and Habchi, C., “Potential of Narrow Angle Direct Injection Diesel Engines for Clean Combustion: 3D CFD Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1365, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1365.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Velghe, A., Gillet, N. and Bohbot, J., “A high efficiency parallel unstructured solver dedicated to internal combustion engine simulation”, Comput. Fluids 45:116-121, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeldovitch, Y., “The oxidation of nitrogen in combustion and explosions”, Acta Physicochimica 21:577-628, 1946</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maas, U. and Pope, S., “Simplifying chemical kinetics: intrinsic lowdimensional manifolds in composition space”, Combust. Flame 88:239-264, 1992</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hélie, J. and Trouvé, A., “A modified coherent flame model to describe turbulent flame propagation in mixtures with variable composition”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 28:193-201, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, N., “Laminar flamelet concepts in turbulent combustion”, Proc. Combust. Inst. 21:1231-1250, 1986</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
