<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939391</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Debt, Equity, and International Taxation</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Debt Shifting Restrictions and Reallocation of Debt</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Habu</surname>
                  <given-names>Katarzyna</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Qi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yaxuan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xing</surname>
                  <given-names>Jing</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>26</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939391"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper analyses the effects of tax incentives on the location of debt for multinational firms. Using a difference-in-differences approach, we provide causal evidence on the effect of the UK worldwide debt cap reform in 2010. The reform restricted tax deductions available to the UK subsidiaries of multinational companies. We find that firms that were affected by the debt cap reduced the tested debt ratios. Multinationals headquartered in the UK have reduced the level of the UK net debt without changing their worldwide debt holdings. Foreign headquartered multinationals instead have increased their worldwide debt holdings without changing the level of the UK net debt. We find an increase in leverage ratios in non-UK subsidiaries of all affected multinationals after the reform. This increase is more pronounced in affiliates located in higher tax countries. We also find that the fraction of affected multinational affiliates located in high tax countries increases after the reform, while the fraction located in lower tax countries declines. This provides evidence for debt shifting.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Blouin, J., Huizinga, H., Laveven, L., and Nicodeme, G. (2014). “Thin Capitalization Rules and Multinational Firm Capital Structure,” IMF working paper 14/12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Buetnner, T., Overesch, M., Schreibe, U., and Wamser, G. (2012). “The impact of thin-capitalization rules on the capital structure of multinational firms”, Journal of Public Economics, Vol. 96: 930-938.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Davies, R. B., Martin, J., Parenti, M., &amp; Toubal, F. (2018). Knocking on Tax Haven's Door: Multinational Firms and Transfer Pricing. The Review of Economics and Statistics, forthcoming . doi:10.1162/REST_a_00673</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Desai, M. A., Foley, C. F., &amp; Hines, &amp;. (2004). A multinational perspective on capital structure choice and internal capital markets. The Journal of Finance, 59(6), 2451-2487.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Dharmapala, D. (2014). What Do We Know about Base Erosion and Profit Shifting? A Review of the Empirical Literature. Fiscal Studies, 35(4), 421-448.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Hanlon, M., &amp; Heitzman. (2010). A review of tax research. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 50(2), 127-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Huizinga, H., &amp; Laeven, L. (2008). International profit shifting within multinationals: A multi-country perspective. Journal of Public Economics, 92(5), 1164-11</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Time-series evolution of the average gateway test ratio net UK debt and worldwide gross debt of the treated and the control groups.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Time-series evolution of the average gateway test ratio net UK debt and worldwide gross debt of the treated and the control groups – UK headquartered and non-UK headquartered MNCs.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Impact of the worldwide debt cap on group-level debt holdings</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Impact of the worldwide debt cap on group-level debt holdings--headquarter heterogeneities</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Impact of the worldwide debt cap on non-UK subsidiaries’ leverage ratio</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Impact of the worldwide debt cap on organizational structure</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Cross check of the impact of worldwide debt cap on UK debt using Orbis data</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
