<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014363</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Leveraging a Large Learner Corpus for Automatic Suggestion of Collocations for Learners of Japanese as a Second Language</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pereira</surname>
                  <given-names>Lis</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Lis Pereira completed her PhD at Nara Institute of Science and Technology in 2016 working on how to address content word choice errors in L2 Japanese.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Manguilimotan</surname>
                  <given-names>Erlyn</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Erlyn Manguilimotan is a PhD candidate in the Graduate School of Information Science at Nara Institute of Science and Technology. She is working on part-of-speech and syntactic analysis of the Tagalog language.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Matsumoto</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuji</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Yuji Matsumoto is currently a Professor of Information Science at the Nara Institute of Science and Technology. He received his MSc and PhD degrees in information science from Kyoto University in 1979 and 1989 respectively. He joined the Machine Inference Section of the Electrotechnical Laboratory in 1979. He has been an academic visitor at the Imperial College of Science and Technology, a deputy chief of the First Laboratory at ICOT, and an associate professor at Kyoto University. His main research interests are natural language understanding and machine learning.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Nara Institute of Science and Technology.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>33</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014360</issue-id>
         <fpage>311</fpage>
         <lpage>333</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2016, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014363"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>One of the challenges of learning Japanese as a Second Language (JSL) is finding the appropriate word for a particular usage. To address this challenge, we developed a collocational aid designed to suggest more appropriate collocations in Japanese. In particular, we address the problem of generating and ranking noun and verb candidates for correcting potential collocation errors in the learners’ text. Given a noun–verb construction as input, our system generates possible noun or verb correction candidates based on noun and verb corrections extracted from a large Japanese learner corpus. We use this corpus to investigate the learner’s tendency to commit collocation errors, and to produce a smaller and more realistic set of candidates. After combining nouns or verbs with the generated candidates to form noun–verb pairs, the system uses the Weighted Dice coefficient as the association measure to filter out inappropriate noun–verb pairs and rank the proper collocations. We report the detailed evaluation and results on learner data. In addition, we show that our system statistically outperforms existing approaches to collocation error correction. Finally, we report a preliminary user study with JSL learners.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>Collocation</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Automatic Error Correction</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Language Learner</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Japanese</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, Y. C., Chang, J. S., Chen, H. J., &amp; Liou, H. C. (2008). An automatic collocation writing assistant for Taiwanese EFL learners: A case of corpus-based NLP technology. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 21(3), 283–299. Retrieved from: http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588220802090337</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, M.-H., Huang, C.-C., Huang, S.-T., Chang, J.S., &amp; Liou, H.C. (2014). An automatic reference aid for improving EFL learners’ formulaic expressions in productive language use. IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies, 7(1), 57–68. Retrieved from: http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TLT.2013.34</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cho, Y. S. (2013). Software review: Lang-8. CALICO Journal, 30(2), 293–299. Retrieved from: http://dx.doi.org/10.11139/cj.30.2.293-299</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Church, K. W., &amp; Hanks, P. (1990). Word association norms, mutual information, and lexicography. In Proceedings of the 27th Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics (pp. 76–83). Stroudsburg, PA: Association for Computational Linguistics. Retrieved from: http://dx.doi.org/10.3115/981623.981633</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahlmeier, D., &amp; Ng, H. T. (2011). Correcting semantic collocation errors with L1-induced paraphrases. In Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (pp. 107–117). Stroudsburg, PA: Association for Computational Linguistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dunning, T. (1993). Accurate methods for the statistics of surprise and coincidence. Computational Linguistics, 19(1), 61–74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Futagi, Y., Deane, P., Chodorow, M., &amp; Tetreault, J. (2008). A computational approach to detecting collocation errors in the writing of non-native speakers of English. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 21(4), 353–367. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09588220802343561</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harris. Z. (1954). Distributional structure. Word, 10(2–3), 146–162. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00437956.1954.11659520</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hill, J. (2000). Revising priorities: From grammatical failure to collocational success. In Michael Lewis (Ed.), Teaching Collocation: Further Developments in the Lexical Approach (pp. 88–117). Hove: Language Teaching Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jurafsky, D., &amp; Martin, J. H. (2009). Speech and Language Processing: An Introduction to Natural Language Processing, Computational Linguistics, and Speech Recognition (2nd ed.). Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall PTR.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitamura, M., &amp; Matsumoto, Y. (1997). Automatic extraction of translation patterns in parallel corpora. Information Processing Society of Japan Journal, 38(4), 727–735.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kudo, T., &amp; Matsumoto, Y. (2002). Japanese dependency analysis using cascaded chunking. In Proceedings of the 6th Conference on Natural Language Learning (pp. 1–7). Stroudsburg, PA: Association for Computational Linguistics. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.3115/1118853.1118869</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lea, D., &amp; Runcie, M. (Eds.) (2002). Oxford Collocations Dictionary for Students of English. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leacock, C., Chodorow, M., Gamon, M., &amp; Tetreault, J. (2010). Automated Grammatical Error Detection For Language Learners (Synthesis lectures on human language technologies 3(1), pp. 1–134). San Rafael, CA: Morgan &amp; Claypool.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, L. (1999). Measures of distributional similarity. In Proceedings of the 37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Computational Linguistics (pp. 25–32). Stroudsburg, PA: Association for Computational Linguistics. Retrieved from: http://dx.doi.org/10.3115/1034678.1034693</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewis, M. (2000). There is nothing as practical as a good theory. In Michael Lewis (Ed.), Teaching Collocation: Further Developments in the Lexical Approach (pp. 10–27). Hove: Language Teaching Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liou, H., Chang, J., Chen, H., Lin, C., Liaw, M., Gao, Z., … You, G. (2006). Corpora processing and computational scaffolding for a Web-based English learning environment: The CANDLE project. CALICO Journal, 24(1), 77–95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, A. L.-E.,Wible, D., &amp; Tsao, N.-L. (2009). Automated suggestions for miscollocations. In Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications (pp. 47–50). Stroudsburg, PA: Association for Computational Linguistics. Retrieved from: http://dx.doi.org/10.3115/1609843.1609850</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, L. E. (2002). A corpus-based lexical semantic investigation of verb-noun miscollocations in Taiwan learners’ English (Master’s thesis). Tamkang University, Taipei.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maekawa, K., Yamazaki, M., Ogiso, T., Maruyama, T.,Ogura, H., Kashino, W., … Den, Y. (2014). Balanced corpus of contemporary written Japanese. Language Resources and Evaluation, 48(2), 345–371. Retrieved from: http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10579-013-9261-0</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nesselhauf, N. (2003). The use of collocations by advanced learners of English and some implications for teaching. Applied Linguistics, 24(2), 223–242. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/applin/24.2.223</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oyama, H., Komachi, M., &amp; Matsumoto, Y. (2013). Towards automatic error type classification of Japanese language learners’ writings. In Proceedings of the 27th Pacific Asia Conference on Language, Information, and Computation (pp.163–172). Taipei, Taiwan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, T., Lank, E., Poupart, P., &amp; Terry, M. (2008). “Is the sky pure today?” AwkChecker: An assistive tool for detecting and correcting collocation errors. In Proceedings of the 21th Annual Association for Computing Machinery Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (pp. 121–130). Monterey, CA, USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pereira, L. (2013). Collocation suggestion for Japanese second language learners (Master’s thesis). Nara Institute of Science and Technology, Ikoma, Japan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seretan, V. (2011). Syntax-Based Collocation Extraction (Text, speech and language technology series, 44). New York: Springer-Verlag. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-0134-2_4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shei, C.-C., &amp; Pain, H. (2000). An ESL writer’s collocational aid. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 13(2), 167–182. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1076/0958-8221(200004)13:2;1-D;FT167</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smadja, F. (1993). Retrieving collocations from text: Xtract. Computational Linguistics, 19(1), 143–177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smadja, F., McKeown, K. R., &amp; Hatzivassiloglou, V. (1996). Translating collocations for bilingual lexicons: A statistical approach. Computational Linguistics, 22(1),1–38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Voorhees, E. M.(1999). The TREC-8 question answering track evaluation. In E. M. Voochees &amp; D. K. Harman (Eds.), Proceedings of the Text Retrieval Conference (TREC-8) (pp. 83–105). NIST Special Publication 500-246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wible, D., Kuo, C., Tsao, N., Liu, A., &amp; Lin, H. (2003). Bootstrapping in a language learning environment. Journal of Computer-Assisted Learning, 19(1), 90–102. Retrieved from http://dx.doi.org/10.1046/j.0266-4909.2002.00009.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, X., Gao, J., &amp; Dolan, W. (2008). A web-based English proofing system for English as a Second Language users. In Proceedings of the 3rd International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing (pp. 619–624). Stroudsburg, PA: Association for Computational Linguistics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
