<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277792</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis of Cyclic Variability and the Effect of Dilute Combustion in a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Matthias</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicholas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wallner</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Scarcelli</surname>
                  <given-names>Riccardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Argonne National Lab.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>633</fpage>
         <lpage>641</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277792"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The pressing need to improve U.S. energy independence and reduce climate forcing fossil fuel emissions continues to motivate the development of high-efficiency internal combustion engines. A recent trend has been to downsize and turbocharge automotive spark-ignited engines coupled with direct fuel injection to improve engine efficiency while maintaining vehicle performance. In-line with recent trends in state-of-the-art engine technology, the focus of this study is lean and EGR dilute combustion in a gasoline direct injection (GDI) engine.</p>
            <p>The lean and dilute operating limits are defined by combustion stability typically in terms of COV<sub>IMEP</sub>so experiments were carried out on an automotive size single-cylinder research engine to characterize combustion stability. From a 20,000 cycle sequence analysis, lean operating conditions exhibit binary high- to low-IMEP cycle sequences. This may be because the cycle-to-cycle feedback mechanisms are physically limited to one or two cycles. Longer sequences are observed with EGR likely because the EGR loop introduces a much longer transient feedback mechanism.</p>
            <p>Results from a sensitivity study with induced variability show that COV<sub>IMEP</sub>is far less sensitive to ignition perturbation than to injection perturbation while the sensitivity is similar in terms of efficiency. This is true for both lean and EGR dilute operation; however, one difference that stands out with EGR is the sensitivity of COV<sub>IMEP</sub>to ignition perturbation. Increased sensitivity to ignition perturbation is likely the result of longer ignition delay which is critical for early flame kernel development.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Energy Information Administration, “Annual Energy Outlook 2013 with Projections to 2040,” DOE/EIA-0383(2013), 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, H., Stein, R., and Leone, T., “Comparison of Dual Retard VCT to Continuously Variable Event Valvetrain,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1268, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1268.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Samuel, S., Morrey, D., Whelan, I., and Hassaneen, A., “Combustion Characteristics and Cycle-By-Cycle Variation in a Turbocharged-Intercooled Gasoline Direct-Injected Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0348, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0348.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaul, B., Wagner, R., and Green, J., “Analysis of Cyclic Variability of Heat Release for High-EGR GDI Engine Operation with Observations on Implications for Effective Control,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):132-141, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0270.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stevens, S., Shayler, P., and Ma, T., “The Impact of Combustion Phasing on Cycle-by-Cycle Performance of a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 950687, 1995, doi:10.4271/950687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scarcelli, R., Matthias, N., and Wallner, T., “Numerical Investigation of Combustion in a Lean Burn Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0029, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
