<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">31</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i40211883</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44987844</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Improving retrieval performance of translation memories using morphosyntactic analyses and generalized suffix arrays</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Melanie</given-names>
                  <surname>Weitz</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>117</fpage>
         <lpage>146</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Springer Science+Business Media B.V., part of Springer Nature 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44987844"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Since the 1990s, translation memory (TM) systems have been one of the most widely-used tools in the field of computer-aided translation. However, most of the commercially available systems still consider two segments to be compared similar if the sequence of characters is identical or differ only marginally in spelling. Instead, linguistic similarities are disregarded so that semantically identical or similar segments, which have different (morpho)syntactic structures, are retrieved with a lower similarity value as expected or not at all. The iMem (iMem is an abbreviation for Intelligent Translation Memories) research project aimed at improving the retrieval of those very segments by analyzing their (morpho)syntactic structure and identifying the longest common substrings (LCS) between two sentences by means of generalized suffix arrays. The results of the morphosyntactic analysis are stored in the so-called iMem-TM, an independent relational database which is connected to a commercial, non-linguistically enhanced TM via its API. Base words were used for building the suffixes to increase the probability of finding a larger number of LCS between both sentences. Furthermore, an existing algorithm for generalized suffix arrays was enhanced by an additional array in order to distinguish which suffixes derive from which sentence. In this way, identical repeating LCS within the same sentence are ignored, whereas identical repeating LCS between two different sentences are still considered. If more than one identical repeating LCS between the sentences exist, the best matching LCS is given by calculating positional differences for the identical repeating LCS and choosing the one with the minimal positional difference.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d3436e242a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3436e249" publication-type="other">
http://www.casmacat.eu/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3436e256a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3436e263" publication-type="other">
https://www.matecat.com/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3436e270a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3436e277" publication-type="other">
http://similis.org/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3436e284a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3436e291" publication-type="other">
http://www.omegat.org/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3436e299a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3436e306" publication-type="other">
http://www.opentm2.org/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3436e313a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3436e320" publication-type="other">
MPRO stands for Morphological Program (Maas 1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d3436e327a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3436e334" publication-type="other">
http://www.sqlite.org/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d3436e350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e354" publication-type="other">
Alum S (2004) Suffix trees and suffix arrays. In: Mehta DP, Sahni S (eds) Handbook of data structures and
applications. Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC, Boca Raton, pp 29-1-29-22</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e364a1310">
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e370" publication-type="other">
Azzano D (2009) CAT und MÜ—Getrennte Welten? In: Seewald-Heeg U, Stein, D (eds) Journal for
Language Technology and Computational Linguistics (JLCL). Maschinelle Übersetzung von der The-
one zur Anwendung—machine translation—theory and applications, vol 24(3). Hochschule Anhalt,
Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München, Kothen, München, pp 19-36</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e386a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e390" publication-type="other">
Azzano D, Reinke U, Sauer M (2011) Ansätze zur Verbesserung der Retrieval -Leistung kommerzieller
Translation-Memory-Systeme. In: Hedeland H, Schmidt T, Wörner K (eds) Multilingual resources
and multilingual applications, proceedings of the conference of the German Society for Computational
Linguistics and Language Technology (GSCL) 2011. Universität Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany, pp
123-128</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e413" publication-type="other">
Baisa V, Horák A, Medved M (2015) Increasing coverage of translation memories with linguistically moti-
vated segment combination methods. In: RANLP, proceedings of the workshop on Natural Language
Processing for Translation Memories (NLP4TM), Hissar, Bulgaria, pp 31-35</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e431" publication-type="other">
Bloodgood M, Strauss B (2014) Translation memory retrieval methods. In: EACL 2014, proceedings of the
14th conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Gothen-
burg, Sweden, pp 202-210</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e444a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e448" publication-type="other">
Bowker L (2002) Computer-aided translation technology: a practical introduction. University of Ottawa
Press, Ottawa</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e458a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e462" publication-type="other">
Bruckner C, Plitt M (2001) Evaluating the operational benefit of using machine translation output as
translation memory input. In: MT Summit VIII, proceedings of the 8th Machine Translation Summit,
workshop on MT evaluation, Santiago de Compostela, Spain, pp 61-65</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e475a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e479" publication-type="other">
Carl M, Schmidt-Wigger A (1998) Shallow post morphological processing with KURD. In: Powers DMW
(ed) NeMLaP3/CoNLL98, proceedings of the joint conferences on new methods in Language Pro-
cessing and Computational Natural Language Learning. Association for Computational Linguistics,
Stroudsburg, pp 257-265</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e495a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e499" publication-type="other">
Chatzitheodorou K (2015) Improving translation memory fuzzy matching by paraphrasing. In: RANLP,
proceedings of the workshop on Natural Language Processing for Translation Memories (NLP4TM),
Hissar, Bulgaria, pp 24-30</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e516" publication-type="other">
Dara A, Dandapat S, Groves D, van Genabith J (2013) TMTprime: a recommender system for MT and TM
integration. In: HLT-NAACL 2013, proceedings of the 2013 annual conference of the North American
Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Demonstration Session, Atlanta, Georgia,
USA, pp 10-13</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e533a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e537" publication-type="other">
Elita N, Gavrila M (2006) Enhancing translation memories with semantic knowledge. In: CESCL, proceed-
ings of the 1st central European Student Conference in Linguistics, Budapest, Hungary</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e551" publication-type="other">
Federico M, Bertoldi N, Cettolo M, Negri M, Turchi M, Tromebetti M, Cattelan A, Farina A, Lupinetti
D, Martines A, Massidda A, Schwenk H, Barrault L, Blain F, Koehn P, Buck C, Germann U (2014)
The Matecat Tool. In: Tounsi L, Rak R (eds) COLING 2014, proceedings of the 25th international
conference on computational linguistics: system demonstrations. Dublin, Ireland, pp 129-132</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e567a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e571" publication-type="other">
Flanagan K (2014) Filling in the gaps: what we need from TM subsegment recall, http://www.kftrans.co.
uk/lift/FillinglnTheGaps.pdf. Accessed 26 Feb 2015</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e581a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e585" publication-type="other">
Gordon I (1997) The TM revolution -what does it really mean? In: Translating and the computer 19: papers
from the Aslib conference, London</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e595a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e599" publication-type="other">
Gupta R, Oräsan C (2014) Incorporating paraphrasing in translation memory matching and retrieval. In:
Tadic M, Koehn P, Roturier J, Way A (eds) EAMT 2014, proceedings of the 17th annual conference
of the European Association for Machine Translation, Dubrovnik, Croatia, pp 3-10</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e616" publication-type="other">
He Y, Ma Y, van Genabith J, Way A (2010a) Bridging SMT and TM with translation recommendation.
In: Hajic J, Carberry S, Clark S (eds) ACL 2010, proceedings of the 48th annual meeting of the
Association for Computational Linguistics, Uppsala, Sweden, pp 622-630</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e630a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e634" publication-type="other">
He Y, Ma Y, Way A, van Genabith J (2010b) Integrating N-best SMT Outputs into a TM System. In: Huang
CR, Jurafsky D (eds) COLING 2010, 23rd international conference on computational linguistics,
Posters Volume, Beijing, China, pp 374-382</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e647a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e651" publication-type="other">
Henrich A (2008) Information retrieval 1—Grundlagen, Modelle, Anwendungen, version 1.2 (rev.: 5727,
status: 7 January 2008). Otto-Friedrich-Universität, Lehrstuhl für Medieninformatik, Bamberg, 2001-
2008. http://www.uni-bamberg.de/fileadmin/uni/fakultaeten/wiai_lehrstuehle/medieninformatik/
Dateien/Publikationen/2008/henrich-irl-1.2.pdf. Accessed 9 April 2014</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e667a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e671" publication-type="other">
IBM (2016) OpenTM2 for Windows—translator's reference, version 1.3.1, 5th edn, p 321. https ://github.
com/OpenTM2/opentm2-source/blob/master/Doc/Opentm2TranslatorsReference.pdf. Accessed 23
Sept 2016</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e684a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e688" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Senellart J (2010) Convergence of translation memory and statistical machine translation. In:
Zhechev V (ed) JEC 2010, proceedings of the 2nd joint EM+/CGNL workshop: bringing MT to the
user: research on integrating MT in the translation industry, Denver, Colorado, pp 21-31</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e701a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e705" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Alabau V, Carl M et al (2013) CASMACAT—Final Public Report, http://www.casmacat.eu/
uploads/Deliverables/final-public-report.pdf. Accessed 26 April 2016</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e715a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e719" publication-type="other">
Kuhns RJ (2007) Advanced leveraging—the new generation of TMs. TAUS Report. TAUS B.V., De Rijp</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e727a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e731" publication-type="other">
Lagoudaki E (2006) Translation Memories Survey 2006. Translation memory systems: enlightening users'
perspective. Imperial College London. http://www3.imperial.ac.Uk/pls/portallive/docs/l/7307707.
PDF. Accessed 19 July 2011</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e744a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e748" publication-type="other">
Maas HD (1998) Multilingualität in MPRO. Institut für Angewandte Informationswissenschaft, Saar-
brücken. http://iai.iai-sb.de/docs/mmpro.pdf. Accessed 7 Feb 2012</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e758a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e762" publication-type="other">
Maas HD, Rösener C, Theofilidis A (2009) Morphosyntactic and semantic analysis of text: The MPRO
tagging procedure. In: Mahlow C, Piotrowski M (eds) State of the art in computational morphol-
ogy: workshop on Systems and Frameworks for Computational Morphology (SFCM 2009), Zurich,
Switzerland, Proceedings. Communications in Computer and Information Science, vol 41. Springer,
Heidelberg, pp 76-87</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e781a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e785" publication-type="other">
Macklovitch E (2000) Two types of translation memory. In: Translating and the computer 22, proceedings
of the 22nd international conference on translating and the computer, London, England. Aslib, London</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e795a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e799" publication-type="other">
McTait K (2001) Linguistic knowledge and complexity in an EBMT system based on translation patterns.
In: MT Summit VIII, proceedings of the 8th machine translation summit, workshop on MT evaluation,
Santiago de Compostela, Spain, pp 23-34</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e812a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e816" publication-type="other">
Mitkov R, Corpas G (2008) Improving third generation translation memory systems through identification of
rhetorical predicates, http://www.ac2idemia.edu/744 1 422/Improving_Third_Generation_Translation_
Memory_Systems. Accessed 26 April 2016</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e830a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e834" publication-type="other">
Nielsen J (1993) Usability engineering. Morgan Kaufmann, San Francisco</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e841a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e845" publication-type="other">
Planas E (2005) SIMILIS Second-generation translation memory software. In: Translating and the computer
27, proceedings of the 27th international conference on translating and the computer, London, England.
Aslib, London</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e862" publication-type="other">
Planas E, Furuse O (1999) Formalizing translation memories. In: MT Summit VII, proceedings of the 7th
machine translation summit: MT in the great translation era, Kent Ridge Digital Labs, Singapore, pp
331-339</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e875a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e879" publication-type="other">
Planas E, Furuse O (2000) Multi-level similar segment matching algorithm for translation memories and
example-based machine translation. In: COLING 2000, proceedings of the 18th international confer-
ence on computational linguistics, Universität des Saarlandes, Saarbrücken, Germany, vol 2. Morgan
Kaufmann Publishers, San Francisco, pp 621-627</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e895a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e899" publication-type="other">
Rapp R (2002) A part-of-speech-based search algorithm for translation memories. In: LREC 2002, pro-
ceedings of the 3rd international conference on language resources and evaluation, Las Palmas de
Gran Canaria, Spain, pp 466-472</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e912a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e916" publication-type="other">
Reinke U (2004) Translation Memories: Systeme -Konzepte -Linguistische Optimierung. Peter Lang,
Frankfurt am Main</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e927a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e931" publication-type="other">
Reinke U (2013) State of the art in translation memory technology. In: Rehm G, Sasaki F, Stein D, Witt
A (eds) Translation: computation, corpora, cognition. Special issue on language technologies for a
multilingual Europe, vol 3(1), pp 27-48</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e944a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e948" publication-type="other">
Rösener C (2005) Die Stecknadel im Heuhaufen: Natürlichsprachiger Zugang zu Volltextdatenbanken.
Dissertation. Peter Lang, Frankfurt am Main</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e962" publication-type="other">
Schäler R (2001) Beyond translation memories. In: MT Summit VIII, proceedings of the 8th machine
translation summit, workshop on MT evaluation, Santiago de Compostela, Spain, pp 49-55</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e972a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e976" publication-type="other">
Schmitt I (2006) Ähnlichkeitssuche in Multimedia-Datenbanken -Retrieval, Suchalgorithmen, Abfrage-
behandlung. Oldenbourg Wissenschaftsverlag GmbH, Munich</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e986a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e990" publication-type="other">
Sikes R (2007) Fuzzy matching in theory and practice. Multiling Comput Technol 18(6):39-43</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e997a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e1001" publication-type="other">
Smolej V (n. d.) OmegaT 3.0—user guide. Documentation of the open-source TMS OmegaT. http://
ob.nubati.net/ditundat/omegat/docs/en30/appendix.TokenizerPlugin.inOmegaT.html#d0el0802.
Accessed 26 Apr 2016</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e1015a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e1019" publication-type="other">
Somers H, Fernandez Diaz G (2004) Translation memory vs. example-based MT: what's the difference?
Int J Transi 16(2):5-33</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e1029a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e1033" publication-type="other">
Timonera K, Mitkov R (2015) Improving translation memory matching through clause splitting. In: RANLP,
proceedings of the workshop on Natural Language Processing for Translation Memories (NLP4TM),
Hissar, Bulgaria, pp 17-23</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e1046a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e1050" publication-type="other">
Vanallemeersch T, Vandeghinste V (2014) Improving fuzzy matching through syntactic knowledge. In:
Translating and the computer 36, proceedings of the 36th international conference on translating and
the computer, London, England, AsLing, London, pp 90-99</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e1067" publication-type="other">
Zhechev V, van Genabith J (2010a) Maximising TM performance through sub-tree alignment and SMT.
In: AMTA 2010, proceedings of the 9th conference of the association for machine translation in the
Americas, Denver, Colorado</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3436e1080a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3436e1084" publication-type="other">
Zhechev V, van Genabith J (2010b) Seeding statistical machine translation with translation memory output
through tree-based structural alignment. In: SSST-4, proceedings of the 4th workshop on syntax and
structure in statistical translation, Beijing, China</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


