<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437417</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Public Investment, the Stability Pact and the 'Golden Rule'</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>FABRIZIO</given-names>
                  <surname>BALASSONE</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>DANIELE</given-names>
                  <surname>FRANCO</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437413</issue-id>
         <fpage>207</fpage>
         <lpage>229</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2000</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437417"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The fiscal rules set in the Treaty of Maastricht and in the Stability and Growth Pact have sometimes been criticised as an excessively binding constraint for appropriate counter-cyclical action. The risk that the rules may permanently reduce the public sector's contribution to capital accumulation has also been pointed out. In this framework, the adoption of a 'golden rule' has been suggested. Starting from the recent debate, this paper tackles two questions: (a) the implications of the Pact for public investment and (b) the pros and cons of introducing a golden rule in EMU's fiscal framework, given the objectives of low public debts and adequate margins for a stabilising budgetary policy. The analysis suggests that the rules set in the Treaty and in the Pact may negatively influence public investment spending. However, the golden rule, although intuitively appealing, does not seem to be an appropriate solution to the problem.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e181a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e188" publication-type="other">
This point of view is taken by Modigliani et al. (1998). Opinions in favour of some kind of golden rule have
also been expressed by European Commissioner Mario Monti. It should be noted that, when defining an
'excessive deficit', the Treaty does not discriminate between current and capital outlays; however, it provides
for the Commission's Report on Excessive Deficits to take into account a list of relevant factors and, among
those, 'whether government deficit exceeds government investment expenditure' (article 104c(3)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e207a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e214" publication-type="other">
See, for example, European Commission (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e221a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e228" publication-type="other">
The idea that investment is reduced more than other items during fiscal consolidations is largely shared in the
literature. For example. Oxley and Martin (1991) point to 'the political reality that it is easier to cut back or
postpone investment spending than it is to cut current expenditure' (p. 161); De Haan, Sturm and Sikken
(1996) argue that investment '[is] the least rigid component of expenditure' (p. 108).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e244a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e251" publication-type="other">
Let us express all variables in real terms and assume that the deficit is equal to investment expenditure (/) and
constant as a ratio to GDP (Y): I,/Y, = i, = i Vr. If i is such that the debt (D) to GDP ratio converges (i.e. if i =
{g/(l+#)}£/, where d = d, - DJY, V/ and g is the growth rate of GDP), then since taxes (7) must equal interest
outlays (rD,-, where r is the interest rate) plus primary current expenditure (C), we have TJY, = rD,,/Y, + CJY,
= /"D,_i/{(l+g)fn ) + C,IY,= (r/(l+g))&lt;f + £.7 Vf, where c, = CJY,. If the same level of i were to be financed by
taxes, we would have TJY, = i + c, = {#/( l+g))r/ + c,. The difference between the two cases once the debt ratio
is stable would then be negligible if r = g (i.e. if the real interest rate were close to the real GDP growth).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e278a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e285" publication-type="other">
See Kitterer (1994) for an analysis based on an overlapping-generations general-equilibrium model. The
Central Planning Bureau of the Netherlands estimates that the shift from deficit to tax finance would entail a
welfare loss for current generations equal to 34 per cent of GDP (van Ewijk, 1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e298a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e305" publication-type="other">
If capital expenditures were reduced, the burden of transition would be shifted on to future generations who
would suffer from the lower accumulated stock of public capital.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e315a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e322" publication-type="other">
Budgetary problems involved in this second transition are analysed in Holzmann (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e329a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e336" publication-type="other">
By 'lasting and significant improvement', we mean a reduction of the deficit ratio for at least two years and by
at least 1.5 percentage points of GDP. Luxemburg is not included in the analysis. Similar evidence is also
reported by Roubini and Sachs (1989) and by De Haan, Sturm and Sikken (1996) with reference to different
time-spans and using a sample of OECD countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e352a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e359" publication-type="other">
The implications of deficit financing of public investment also raise doubts from a theoretical point of view.
Among the relevant issues, the possibility of crowding-out should be mentioned. A review of the theory is
provided by Dalamagas (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e372a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e379" publication-type="other">
Cost function estimations have also been used (see the references in Dalenberg, Partridge and Rickman
(1998)). In Dalenberg et al. (1998). the analysis focuses on the relationship between public infrastructure and
private employment using a labour demand function: 'public highway capital is significantly related to state
employment growth in all specifications' (p. 46). Also, the effects of public investment on private investment
have been investigated: Erenburg (1993) finds a significant positive relationship between the two variables at
state level for the US. Overall, the results are ambiguous.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e403a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e410" publication-type="other">
The production function method is based on an aggregate production function where public capital (G) is a
factor of production (Q) together with private capital (AT) and labour (L):
Q = MFP x f(K,L.G)
where MFP (multifactor productivity) is the residual after subtracting from the growth in total output the direct
contributions from capital and labour. Subsequent to the specification of the function (usually a Cobb-
Douglas) and of the error term (a typical structure for a panel would be = /i+g,+w„ where / is a country-
specific effect, g is a time-specific component and m is an identically and independently distributed error), a
regression analysis is conducted to check whether the coefficient of G is positive and significant. The literature
shows that the results of the analysis are strongly dependent upon the assumptions concerning f and g
specifically, the presence of significant productivity effects from public capital seems to depend on the
hypothesis that/= 0 Vi.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e448a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e455" publication-type="other">
Coinparative analyses show that the stock of infrastructure in Italy is currently 10 per cent lower than the EU
average; a similar gap was estimated for the mid-1980s. See, for example, Pontolillo (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e465a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e472" publication-type="other">
De la Fuente (1997), using a sample of OECD countries, finds that the elasticity of GDP with respect to
investment expenditure decreases rapidly as outlays increase and can even assume negative values as a
consequence of distortions and crowding-out induced by public intervention.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e485a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e492" publication-type="other">
Proposals to exclude capital outlays from the operating budget and to include depreciation of government
capital stock date back at least to Musgrave (1939). The issue is reviewed, for example, in Goode and
Birnbaum ( 1955), Steve (1972), Premchand (1983), Poterba (1995) and Robinson ( 1998 and 1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e505a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e512" publication-type="other">
The inclusion in the capital account (which can be debt-financed) of all expenditures contributing to human
capital accumulation would imply high levels of deficits and pose serious classification problems. One should
also take into account that part of expenditures replaces existing capital. Modigliani and Padoa Schioppa
Kostoris (1998) estimate that, in Italy, gross public expenditure for 'development' amounts to 15 per cent of
GDP; the corresponding net figure would be 5 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e531a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e538" publication-type="other">
Tor a review of the justifications put forward for the Pact and for an analysis of its potential macroeconomic
implications, see European Commission (1997), Artis and Winkler (1997) and Eichengreen and Wyplosz
(1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e552a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e559" publication-type="other">
This inteqrretation is supported by the Council Resolution of 16-17 June 1997, by the Council Regulation no.
1466/97 of 7 July 1997 and by the Opinion of the Monetary Committee of 12 October 1998 as endorsed by the
Council.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e572a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e579" publication-type="other">
We follow the definitions of the IMF, the OECD and the European Commission: structural is synonymous
with cyclically adjusted and only automatic reactions to the cycle (i.e. those induced by existing legislation) are
considered (see Banca d'ltalia (1999) for a review of methodologies and practices). It is common in the
literature to term 'elasticity' rather than 'semi-elasticity' the relation between point changes in the deficit to
GDP ratio and percentage changes in output.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e598a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e605" publication-type="other">
Article 104c of the Treaty says that, when the ratio is above 60 per cent of GDP, it must 'diminish
sufficiently' and approach 60 per cent 'at a satisfactory pace'. If the ratio increases, the Excessive Deficits
Procedure begins. It should be noted that, while the Treaty allows exceptions to the 3 per cent deficit criterion,
it does not for the criterion concerning the debt ratio. The implications for stabilisation policy of the interaction
between the deficit and the debt rule are analysed in Balassone and Monacelli (1999). Other relevant issues
concerning the stabilisation function of fiscal policy in EMU are discussed in European Commission (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e628a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e635" publication-type="other">
'Borrowing cannot exceed the total investment expenditure in the budget; exceptions are only allowed to
avoid disturbances to the overall economic equilibrium'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e645a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e652" publication-type="other">
0n this, see HM Treasury (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e659a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e666" publication-type="other">
For example, how would one distinguish between maintenance and new investment?</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e674a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e681" publication-type="other">
In the procedure, investment is defined as 'gross fixed capital formation'</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e688a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e695" publication-type="other">
It would be different if all capital expenditure were excluded from the deficit. Among these expenditures,
payments aimed at covering current deficits of public enterprises or at settling past debts would be included.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e705a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e712" publication-type="other">
In several countries, general government accounts are only available on a yearly basis. Monitoring of overall
balances is often based on more readily available financial data (for example, borrowing requirement), which
do not provide indications concerning the composition of balances and, more specifically, investment
expenditure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e728a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e735" publication-type="other">
In Figure 4(b), fluctuation margins are always equal to 2 percentage points of GDP.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e742a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e749" publication-type="other">
In the UK, net investment to GDP is likely to be below 1 per cent (the gross ratio is just above 1 per cent).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e756a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e763" publication-type="other">
In HM Treasury (1997), a safeguard clause is included for Ihe stability of the debt to GDP ratio over the
economic cycle.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e774a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e781" publication-type="other">
These problems become more relevant when referring to the overall contribution of public sector outlays to
human and physical capital accumulation. Estimates by Modigliani and Padoa Schioppa Kostoris (1998)
clearly show how high the deficit could reach (see footnote 15) and the complexity of evaluating that
contribution; the latter would be further compounded at the EU level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e797a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e804" publication-type="other">
According to the Ecofm decision on 12 October 1998, the objective should be attained by 2002.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e811a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e818" publication-type="other">
it has been suggested that the effects of expansionary policies diminish with the level of debt and that an
increase in deficit may even have restrictive effects. See, for example, Bertola and Drazen (1993) and Giavazzi
and Pagano (1990 and 1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d15e840a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e844" publication-type="other">
Artis, M. J. and Winkler, B. (1997), 'The Stability Pact: safeguarding the credibility of the
European Central Bank', Centre for Economic Policy Research, Discussion Paper no. 1688.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e854a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e858" publication-type="other">
Aschauer, D. A. (1989), 'Is public expenditure productive?'. Journal of Monetary Economics, vol.
23, pp. 177-200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e868a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e872" publication-type="other">
Balassone, F. and Franco, D. (1999), 'Public investment in the Stability Pact framework", in M.
Bordignon and D. Da Empoli (eds), Concorrenza fiscale in un'economia internazionale
integrata, Milano: Franco Angeli.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e885a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e889" publication-type="other">
— and Monacelli, D. (1999), 'Politiche di stabilizzazione: quali margini nelle regole fiscali della
UE?', Politica Economica, vol. 15, pp. 309-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e900a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e904" publication-type="other">
Banca d' Italia (1999), Indicators of Structural Budget Balances, Roma.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e911a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e915" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J. (1979), 'On the determination of public debt'. Journal of Political Economy, vol. 87,
pp. 940-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e925a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e929" publication-type="other">
Bertola, G. and Drazen, A. (1993), 'Trigger points and budgetary cuts: explaining the effects of
fiscal austerity', American Economic Review, vol. 38, pp. 11-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e939a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e943" publication-type="other">
Buti, M., Franco, D. and Ongena, H. (1997), 'Budgetary policies during recessions: retrospective
application of the "Stability and Growth Pact" to the post-war period', Recherches
Economiques de Louvain, vol. 63, pp. 321-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e956a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e960" publication-type="other">
—, — and — (1998), 'Fiscal discipline and flexibility in EMU: the implementation of the Stability
and Growth Pact', Oxford Review of Economic Policy, vol. 14, no. 3, pp. 81-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e970a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e974" publication-type="other">
Colm, G. and Wagner, P. (1963), 'Some observation on the budget concept'. Review of Economic
Studies, vol. 45, pp. 122-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e985a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e989" publication-type="other">
Dalamagas, B. (1995), 'Growth, public investment and deficit financing', Australian Economic
Papers, vol. 65, pp. 244-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e999a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1003" publication-type="other">
Dalenberg, D. R., Partridge, M. D. and Rickman, D. S. (1998), 'Public infrastructure: pork or jobs
creator?', Public Finance Review, vol. 1, pp. 24-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1013a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1017" publication-type="other">
De Haan, J., Sturm, J. E. and Sikken, B. J. (1996), 'Government capital formation: explaining the
decline', Review of World Economics, vol. 132, pp. 55-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1027a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1031" publication-type="other">
de la Fuente, A. (1997), 'Fiscal policy and growth in the OECD', Centre for Economic Policy
Research, Discussion Paper no. 1755.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1041a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1045" publication-type="other">
Eberts, R. (1990), 'Public infrastructure and regional economic development', Economic Review of
the Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland, vol. 26, pp. 15-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1055a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1059" publication-type="other">
Eichengreen, B. and Wyplosz, C. (1998), 'Stability Pact: more than a minor nuisance?', Economic
Policy, vol. 26, pp. 67-104.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1070a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1074" publication-type="other">
Erenburg, S. J. (1993), 'The real effects of public investment on private investment', Applied
Economics, vol. 25, pp. 831-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1084a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1088" publication-type="other">
European Commission (1997), 'Economic policy in EMU', Economic Papers, issues 124-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1095a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1099" publication-type="other">
Evans, P. and Karras, G. (1994), 'Is government capital productive? Evidence from a panel of
seven countries', Journal of Macroeconomics, vol. 16, pp. 271-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1109a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1113" publication-type="other">
Franco, D. and Munzi, M. T. (1997), 'Ageing and fiscal policies in the European Union', in
European Commission, 'The welfare state in Europe: challenges and reforms', European
Economy: Reports and Studies, vol. 7, pp. 239-388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1126a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1130" publication-type="other">
Garcia-Milà, T., McGuire, T. J. and Porter, R. H. (1996), 'The effect of public capital in state-level
production functions reconsidered', Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 78, pp. 177-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1140a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1144" publication-type="other">
Giavazzi, F. and Pagano, M. (1990), 'Can severe fiscal contractions be expansionary? Tales of two
small European countries', Centre for Economic Policy Research, Discussion Paper no. 417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1155a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1159" publication-type="other">
— and — (1996), 'Non-Keynesian effects of fiscal policy change: international evidence and the
Swedish experience', Swedish Economic Policy Review, vol. 3, pp. 67-105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1169a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1173" publication-type="other">
Girard, J., Gruber, H. and Hurst, C. (1994), 'A discussion of the role of public investment in
economic growth'. Cahiers BEI-EIB Papers, no. 23, pp. 13-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1183a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1187" publication-type="other">
—. — and — (1995), 'Increasing public investment in Europe: some practical consideration',
European Economic Review, vol. 39, pp. 731-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1197a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1201" publication-type="other">
— and Hurst, C. (1994), 'Investment and growth: quality versus quantity', Cahiers BEI-EIB
Papers, no. 23, pp. 39-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1211a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1215" publication-type="other">
Goode, R. and Birnbaum, E. A. (1955), Government Capital Budgets, Washington. DC:
International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1225a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1229" publication-type="other">
Grämlich, E. M. (1994), 'Infrastructure investment: a review essay", Journal of Economic
Literature, vol. 32, pp. 1147-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1240a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1244" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (1997), A Code for Fiscal Stability, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1251a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1255" publication-type="other">
— (1998), The Public Sector Balance Sheet, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1262a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1266" publication-type="other">
Holtz-Eakin, D. (1994), 'Public sector capital and the productivity puzzle'. Review of Economics
and Statistics, vol. 76, pp. 12-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1276a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1280" publication-type="other">
Holzmann, R. (1997), 'On economic benefits and fiscal requirements of moving from unfunded to
funded pensions', European Economy, vol. 4, pp. 121-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1290a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1294" publication-type="other">
Hurst, C. (1994), 'Infrastructure and growth: a literature review', Cahiers BEI-EIB Papers, no. 23,
pp. 57-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1304a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1308" publication-type="other">
Kelejian, H. H. and Robinson. D. P. (1997), infrastructure productivity estimation and its
underlying econometric specification: a sensitivity analysis', Papers in Regional Science, vol.
72, pp. 297-312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1322a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1326" publication-type="other">
Kitterer, W. (1994), 'Tax- versus debt-financing of public investment: a dynamic simulation
analysis', Kredit und Kapital, vol. 2, pp. 163-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1336a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1340" publication-type="other">
Mera, K. (1973), 'Production functions and social overhead capital: an analysis of the Japanese
case', Regional and Urban Economics, vol. 3, pp. 297-312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1350a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1354" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F., Fitoussi, J. P., Moro, B., Snower, D., Solow, R., Steinherr, A. and Sylos Labini. P.
( 1998), 'Manifesto contro la disoccupazione nell'Unione Europea', Moneta e Crédita, vol. 51,
pp. 375-412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1367a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1371" publication-type="other">
— and Padoa Schioppa Kostoris, F. (1998), Sostenibilità e solvibilità del debito pubblico in Italia,
Bologna: II Mulino.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1381a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1385" publication-type="other">
Munnel, A. H. (1992), 'Infrastructure investment and economic growth', Journal of Economic
Perspectives, vol. 6, pp. 189-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1395a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1399" publication-type="other">
Musgrave, R. A. (1939), 'The nature of budgetary balance and the case for a capital budget",
American Economic Review, vol. 29, pp. 260-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1410a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1414" publication-type="other">
Oxley, H. and Martin, J. P. (1991), 'Controlling government spending and deficits: trends in the
80s and prospects for the 90s', OECD Economic Studies, vol. 17, pp. 145-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1424a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1428" publication-type="other">
Pontolillo, V. (1998), 'Aspetti economico-istituzionali del project financing: problematiche ed
esperienze in Italia', Banca d'Italia, Documenti, no. 589.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1438a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1442" publication-type="other">
Poterba, J. M. (1995), 'Capital budgets, borrowing rules and state capital spending', Journal of
Public Economics, vol. 56, pp. 165-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1452a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1456" publication-type="other">
Premchand, A. (1983), Government Budgeting and Expenditure Controls: Theory and Practice,
Washington, DC: International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1466a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1470" publication-type="other">
Ratner, J. B. (1983), 'Government capital and the production function for U.S. private output'.
Economics Letters, vol. 13, pp. 213-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1480a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1484" publication-type="other">
Robinson, M. (1998), 'Measuring compliance with the golden rule', Fiscal Studies, vol. 19, pp.
447-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1495a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1499" publication-type="other">
— (1999), 'The role and nature of public sector balance sheets', Queensland University of
Technology, Discussion Papers in Economics, Finance and International Competitiveness no.
49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1512a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1516" publication-type="other">
Roubini, N. and Sachs, J. D. (1989), 'Government spending and budget deficits in the industrial
countries', Economic Policy, vol. 8, pp. 99-132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1526a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1530" publication-type="other">
Sartor, N. (ed.) (1998), II risanamento mancato — La politico di bilancio italiana: 1986-90,
Roma: Carocci.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1540a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1544" publication-type="other">
Steve, S. (1972), Lezioni di scienza dellefinanze, Padova: Cedam.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1551a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1555" publication-type="other">
van Ewijk, C. (1997), 'Infrastructure, intergenerational conflict and the golden rule of finance', De
Economist, vol. 145, pp. 447-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
