<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437899</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Peculiar Institutions: A British Perspective on Tax Policy in the United States</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>MICHAEL</given-names>
                  <surname>KEEN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">18</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437894</issue-id>
         <fpage>371</fpage>
         <lpage>400</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1997</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437899"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>By both effect and example, tax policy in the United States has a huge impact on the rest of the world. This paper explores five features of the American tax system that seem, from a British and European perspective, to be both especially peculiar and potentially instructive. These are: the remarkably low overall level of taxation; the absence of a value added tax (or any other general national tax on consumption); the absence of any explicit interstate equalisation; the marginal subsidisation of low earnings under the Earned Income Tax Credit; and the fragmentation of power in policymaking, an important aspect of which is the role played by the Constitution.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e114a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e121" publication-type="other">
Sinn (1985) estimates, for example, that the encouragement to domestic investment in the Accelerated Cost
Recovery System induced capital inflows to the US in the order of $1 trillion (about seven times the current
account deficit of the time).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e134a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e141" publication-type="other">
Few British observers could resist remarking, however, that this strategy was anticipated in the 1984 reform of
corporation tax in the UK.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e151a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e158" publication-type="other">
An excellent account is in Stotsky and Sunley (1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e165a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e172" publication-type="other">
Revenue statistics are from OECD (1996) except where indicated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e180a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e187" publication-type="other">
All states other than Vermont have balanced budget rules, of some form, intended to ensure that current
expenditures are not financed by borrowing. Thus we focus here on federal borrowing. (Including state
borrowing, the ratios of deficit and debt to GDP in 1993 were around 5.3 and 84 per cent respectively.)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e200a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e207" publication-type="other">
Economic Report of the President, 1997.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e214a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e221" publication-type="other">
Steinmo (1993) refers to such evidence.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e228a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e235" publication-type="other">
Peltzman, 1980, Table 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e242a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e249" publication-type="other">
Lindert, 1996, Table 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e256a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e263" publication-type="other">
A classic treatment of this is in Meitzer and Richard (1981), and a recent variant in Persson and Tabellini
(1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e274a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e281" publication-type="other">
This result is in Keen (1996). The federal countries are taken in this exercise to be Australia, Canada,
Switzerland and the US; the centralisation of tax powers in Austria and Germany is so great that these countries
are regarded, for this purpose, as unitary.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e294a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e301" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Dahlby (1996), Flowers (1988) and Keen and Kotsogiannis (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e308a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e315" publication-type="other">
Keen, 1996.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e322a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e329" publication-type="other">
The lonely exception being business transfer tax in Michigan, which is essentially a subtraction form of VAT.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e336a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e343" publication-type="other">
Sales taxes are deployed by 45 states, the District of Columbia and 6,000 local governments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e350a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e357" publication-type="other">
See Aaron and Gale (1996a) and Auerbach (1996) for more detail.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e365a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e372" publication-type="other">
Gale, Houser and Scholz, 1996.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e379a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e386" publication-type="other">
Gentry and Hubbard, 1996.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e393a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e400" publication-type="other">
For simplicity, the arguments in this paragraph abstract from capital market imperfections, intergenerational
linkages and administrative issues.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e410a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e417" publication-type="other">
VIVAT works best on an invoice basis, it being necessary to distinguish sales by the identity of the purchaser.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e424a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e431" publication-type="other">
Bradford et al. (1984), originally published in 1977</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e438a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e445" publication-type="other">
See Auerbach and Slemrod (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e453a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e460" publication-type="other">
Production efficiency requires, in a competitive world, that there be no tax wedge between the producer
prices faced by different enterprises. Capital income taxes operate on a quite different wedge, between
consumer and producer prices (of deferred consumption).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e473a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e480" publication-type="other">
Arbitrage gains will be available, for example, if there are ways in which individuals facing high marginal
rates of tax can deduct interest payments made to those with low marginal rates. See Gordon and Slemrod
(1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e493a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e500" publication-type="other">
McLure (1997), for example, cites this as a sufficient reason for Kazakhstan not to have adopted cash-flow
taxation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e510a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e517" publication-type="other">
There is no explicit equalisation in Russia or (though not formally a federation) China, though, of course, one
does not usually think of these as natural comparators for the US.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e527a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e534" publication-type="other">
President Nixon did propose a thoroughgoing system of revenue-sharing that would have had a strong
equalising component. In the event, however, only relatively minor schemes of this kind were introduced. There
is now no general revenue-sharing at the federal level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e547a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e554" publication-type="other">
A fuller comparison, of course, would need to allow for possible interstate differences in the cost of service
provision.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e565a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e572" publication-type="other">
29Figures are calculated from US Bureau of the Census (1995, Tables 27 and 703), CANSIM of Statistics
Canada, Ruding Committee (1992, Table 9B.2) for Switzerland in 1989 and the Australian Bureau of Statistics
Time Series Service (gopher://gopher.statistics.gov.au).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e585a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e592" publication-type="other">
Indeed, there is no entirely clean economic distinction between equalisation payments — in the sense of
unconditional horizontal transfers — and conditional grants: the same pattern of transfers may be represented
in many different ways, with different 'equalisation' components. This reflects the familiar point that a
conditional block grant that is smaller than the amount that the recipient state would otherwise spend on the
item concerned is, in principle, equivalent to an unconditional grant of the same amount. The flypaper effect'
— the feature that grants do not seem as fungible in practice as this argument implies (for reasons that remain
unclear: see Hines and Thaler (1995)) — diminishes the force of the argument, but the point remains: the
concept of an equalisation payment is not well defined.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e621a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e628" publication-type="other">
One finds, for instance, the regression line
—-= 0,53 + 12.31 - 0.063 POP; R2 = 0.07, N = 49
where G denotes federal grants-in-aid in 1993 ($ million), GSP gross state product in 1991 — the most recent
year available — ($ billion) and POP population in 1993 (million) and the figures in parentheses are White
standard errors. Alaska is excluded, being a clear outlier; inclusion results in a strongly significant positive
coefficient on per capita GSP — that is, a strongly perverse distributional effect. The data are from US Bureau
of the Census (1995, Tables 27 (POP being column 10), 418 (G being column 6) and 703 (GSP being column
10)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e657a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e664" publication-type="other">
Bayoumi and Masson (1995) and MacDougall Committee (1977).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e671a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e678" publication-type="other">
Bayoumi and Masson (1995), who look instead at the stabilisation of state incomes net of federal taxes and
transfers, also find a more significant effect than in Canada.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e688a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e695" publication-type="other">
As shown by Myers (1990).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e703a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e710" publication-type="other">
Analytical Perspectives: The Budget of the US Government Fiscal Year 1997, Tables 3-1 and 5-6.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e717a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e724" publication-type="other">
Dickert, Houser and Scholz, 1995, p. 42.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e731a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e738" publication-type="other">
Budget speech, line 133.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e745a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e752" publication-type="other">
The scheme was initially restricted to taxpayers with children, but was extended to those without in 1993.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e759a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e766" publication-type="other">
The closest UK relative to the E1TC — family credit — operates by bringing earned income up towards some
target level that depends on family composition, and thus implies a strictly positive marginal tax rate. See
Walker and Wiseman (this issue) for an intriguing direct comparison between the EITC and family credit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e779a1310">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e786" publication-type="other">
On these, see, in particular, Dickert, Houser and Scholz (1995), Scholz (1994 and 1996) and Whitehouse
(1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e797a1310">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e804" publication-type="other">
This result, established by Kanbur, Keen and Tuomala (1994), requires that it be optimal for all to work.
Altruism defined over the consumption of the poor has similar implications, as is shown by Oswald (1983): it
is optimal to subsidise earnings, and hence consumption, because, when making their labour-supply decisions,
the poor neglect the benefit that their consumption conveys on others — an argument, interestingly, that runs
almost exactly counter to that of Persson ( 1995) discussed above.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e823a1310">
            <label>42</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e830" publication-type="other">
There are others that, for brevity, we do not develop here. Complementarities between skilled and unskilled
labour, for example, may create a case for subsidising the earnings of the unskilled: see Allen (1982). In an
efficiency wage setting, to give another example, it may be better to support the low-paid by means of a wage
subsidy than by a lump-sum transfer: for while the effect of the latter is to reduce the net income of the poor
(Ravallion, 1984), the effect of the former, it can be shown, is to increase it.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e849a1310">
            <label>43</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e856" publication-type="other">
Or, rather, the reciprocal of the elasticity of the marginal product of labour, which is the elasticity of labour
demand in the competitive case.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e866a1310">
            <label>44</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e873" publication-type="other">
An overall assessment of the incidence of the E1TC would also need to take account of the effect of the ranges
in which the subsidy is constant and then phased out; this lends a progressivity to the tax structure that one
might expect to encourage employment and depress net wages (there then being some advantage to having
several low-paid workers rather than a few high-paid ones): see Koskela and Vilmunen (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e889a1310">
            <label>45</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e896" publication-type="other">
The eligibility links between these and the EITC are complex.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e903a1310">
            <label>46</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e910" publication-type="other">
'See Dickert, Houser and Scholz (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e918a1310">
            <label>47</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e925" publication-type="other">
Holtzblatt, McCubbin and Gillette, 1994, Table 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e932a1310">
            <label>48</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e939" publication-type="other">
Andrew Smith MP, then Shadow Chief Secretary to the Treasury. I owe this quotation to Michael Devereux
and Malcolm Gammie.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e949a1310">
            <label>49</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e956" publication-type="other">
Budget speech, line 81.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e963a1310">
            <label>50</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e970" publication-type="other">
Quoted in Steinmo (1993, p. 145).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e977a1310">
            <label>51</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e984" publication-type="other">
On banks in 1981, and now on utilities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d15e1000a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1004" publication-type="other">
Aaron, H. J. and Gale, W. G. (1996a), 'Introduction', in H. J. Aaron and W. G. Gale (eds),
Economic Effects of F undamental Tax Reform, Washington DC: Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1014a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1018" publication-type="other">
Aaron, H. J. and Gale, W. G. (eds) (1996b), Economic Effects of Fundamental Tax Reform,
Washington DC: Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1028a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1032" publication-type="other">
Allen, F. (1982), 'Optimal linear income taxation with general equilibrium effects on wages',
Journal of Public Economics, vol. 17, pp. 135-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1042a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1046" publication-type="other">
Asdrubali, P., Sprensen, B. E. and Yosha, O. (1996), 'Channels of interstate risk sharing: United
States 1963-1990', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. Ill,pp. 1081-110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1057a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1061" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. J. (1996), 'Tax reform, capital allocation, efficiency and growth', in H. J. Aaron and
W. G. Gale (eds), Economic Effects of Fundamental Tax Reform, Washington DC: Brookings
Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1074a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1078" publication-type="other">
—, Gokhale, J. and Kotlikoff, L. J. (1994), 'Generational accounting: a meaningful way to evaluate
fiscal policy', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 8, pp. 73-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1088a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1092" publication-type="other">
— and Slemrod, J. (1997), 'The economic effects of the Tax Reform Act of 1986', Journal of
Economic Literature, vol. 35, pp. 589-632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1102a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1106" publication-type="other">
Barfield, C. E. (1981), Rethinking Federalism: Block Grants and Federal, State, and Local
Responsibilities, Washington DC: American Enterprise Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1116a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1120" publication-type="other">
Bayoumi, T. and Masson, P. R. (1995), 'Fiscal flows in the United States and Canada: lessons for
monetary union in Europe', European Economic Review, vol. 39, pp. 253-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1130a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1134" publication-type="other">
Bradford, D. F. et al. (1984), Blueprints for Basic Tax Reform, Arlington, Va.: Tax Analysts.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1142a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1146" publication-type="other">
Brennan. G. and Buchanan, J. (1980), The Power to Tax: Analytical Foundations of a Fiscal
Constitution, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1156a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1160" publication-type="other">
Chamley, C. (1986), 'Optimal taxation of capital income in general equilibrium with finite lives',
Econometrica, vol. 54, pp. 607-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1170a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1174" publication-type="other">
Dahlby, B. (1996), 'Fiscal externalities and the design of intergovernmental grants', International
Tax and Public Finance, vol. 3, pp. 397-412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1184a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1188" publication-type="other">
Diamond, P. and Mirrlees, J. (1971), 'Optimal taxation and public production', American
Economic Review, vol. 81, pp. 8-27 and 261-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1198a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1202" publication-type="other">
Dickert, S., Houser, S. and Scholz, J. K. (1995), 'The earned income tax credit and transfer
programs: a study of labor market and program participation', in J. M. Poterba (ed.), Tax
Policy and the Economy, vol. 9, pp. 1-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1215a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1219" publication-type="other">
Feenberg, D., Mitrusi, A. W. and Poterba, J. M. (1997), 'Distributional effects of adopting a
National Retail Sales Tax', Tax Policy and the Economy, vol. 11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1230a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1234" publication-type="other">
Flowers, M. (1988), 'Shared tax sources in a Leviathan model of federalism', Public Finance
Quarterly, vol. 16, pp. 67-77.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1244a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1248" publication-type="other">
Gale, W. G. (1997), 'What can America learn from the British tax system?', Fiscal Studies, this
issue, pp. 341-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1258a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1262" publication-type="other">
—, Houser, S. and Scholz, J. K. (1996), 'Distributional effects of fundamental tax reform', in H. J.
Aaron and W. G. Gale (eds), Economic Effects of Fundamental Tax Reform, Washington DC:
Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1275a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1279" publication-type="other">
Gentry, W. M. and Hubbard, R. G. (1996), 'Distributional implications of introducing a broad-
based consumption tax', Tax Policy and the Economy, vol. 11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1289a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1293" publication-type="other">
Gordon, R. and Slemrod, J. (1986), 'Do we collect any revenue from taxing capital income?', Tax
Policy and the Economy, vol. 2, pp. 88-130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1303a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1307" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. and Rabushka, A. (1983), Low Tax, Simple Tax, Flat Tax, New York: McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1319" publication-type="other">
Higson, C. (1995), 'The effectiveness of the tax reform process in the UK', mimeo, London
Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1329a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1333" publication-type="other">
Hines, J. R. Jr and Thaler, R. H. (1995), 'The flypaper effect', Journal of Economic Perspectives,
vol.9, pp. 217-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1343a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1347" publication-type="other">
HMSO (1972), Proposals for a Tax Credit System, Cmnd 5116, London: HMSO.
— (1982), Corporation Tax, Cmnd 8456, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1357a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1361" publication-type="other">
Holtzblatt, J., McCubbin, J. and Gillette, R. (1994), 'Promoting work through the EITC', National
Tax Journal, vol. 47, pp. 591-607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1371a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1375" publication-type="other">
Kanbur, R., Keen, M. J. and Tuomala, M. (1994), 'Optimal non-linear income taxation for the
alleviation of income-poverty', European Economic Review, vol. 38, pp. 1613-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1385a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1389" publication-type="other">
Kay, J. A. and King, M. A. (1978), The British Tax System, 1st edition, Oxford: Oxford University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1400a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1404" publication-type="other">
Keen, M. J. (1996), 'Vertical tax externalities in the theory of fiscal federalism', mimeo,
International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1414a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1418" publication-type="other">
— and Kotsogiannis, C. (1996), 'Federalism and tax competition', mimeo, University of Essex.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1425a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1429" publication-type="other">
— and Smith, S. (1996), 'The future of value-added tax in the European Union', Economic Policy,
no. 23, pp. 373-411 and 419-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1439a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1443" publication-type="other">
King, M. (1980), 'Savings and taxation', in G. M. Heal and G. A. Hughes (eds), Public Policy and
the Tax System, London: Allen and Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1453a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1457" publication-type="other">
Koskela, E. and Vilmunen, J. (1996), 'Tax progression is good for employment in popular models
of trade union behaviour', Labour Economics, vol. 3, pp. 65-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1467a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1471" publication-type="other">
Lindert, P. (1994), 'The rise of social spending, 1880-1930', Explorations in Economic History,
vol. 31, pp. 1-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1482a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1486" publication-type="other">
— (1996), 'What limits social spending?', Explorations in Economic History, vol. 33, pp. 1-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1493a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1497" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. E. Ir (1990), 'Supply-side economics: an analytical review', Oxford Economic Papers,
vol. 42, pp. 293-316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1507a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1511" publication-type="other">
MacDougall Committee (1977), Report of the Study Group on the Role of Public Finance in
European Integration, Brussels: Office for Official Publications of the European Communities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1521a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1525" publication-type="other">
McLure, C. E. Jr (1987), The Value-Added Tax: Key to Deficit Reduction?, Washington DC:
American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1535a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1539" publication-type="other">
— (1997), 'Tax reform in Kazakhstan', mimeo, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1546a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1550" publication-type="other">
Meade Committee (1978), The Structure and Reform of Direct Taxation, London: Allen and
Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1561a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1565" publication-type="other">
Meitzer, A. H. and Richard, S. F. (1981), 'A rational theory of the size of government', Journal of
Political Economy, vol. 89, pp. 914—27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1579" publication-type="other">
Mikesell, J. L. (1997), 'The American retail sales tax: considerations on their structure, operations
and potential as a foundation for a federal sales tax', National Tax Journal, vol. 50, pp. 149—
65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1592a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1596" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees, J. A. (1971), 'An exploration in the theory of optimum income taxation', Review of
Economic Studies, vol. 38, pp. 175-208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1606a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1610" publication-type="other">
Murray, M. N. (1997), 'Would tax evasion and tax avoidance undermine a national retail sales
tax?', National Tax Journal, vol. 50, pp. 167-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1620a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1624" publication-type="other">
Myers, G. (1990), 'Optimality, free mobility and the regional authority in a federation', Journal of
Public Economics, vol. 43, pp. 107-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1634a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1638" publication-type="other">
Oates, W. E. (1985), 'Searching for Leviathan', American Economic Review, vol. 79, pp. 578-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1646a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1650" publication-type="other">
OECD (1996), Revenue Statistics of OECD Member Countries, 1965-1995, Paris: Organisation for
Economic Co-operation and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1660a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1664" publication-type="other">
Oswald, A. J. (1983), 'Altruism, jealousy and the theory of optimal non-linear taxation'. Journal of
Public Economics, vol. 20, pp. 77-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1674a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1678" publication-type="other">
Peltzman, S. (1980), 'The growth of government', Journal of Law and Economics, vol. 23, pp.
209-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1688a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1692" publication-type="other">
Persson, M. (1995), 'Why are taxes so high in egalitarian societies?', Scandinavian Journal of
Economics, vol. 97, pp. 569-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1702a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1706" publication-type="other">
Persson, T. and Tabellini, G, (1994), 'Is inequality harmful for growth?', American Economic
Review, vol. 84, pp. 600-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1716a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1720" publication-type="other">
Ravallion, M. (1984), 'How much is a transfer payment worth to a rural worker?', Oxford
Economic Papers, vol. 36, pp. 478-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1731a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1735" publication-type="other">
Ruding Committee (1992), Report of the Committee of Independent Experts on Company Taxation,
Brussels: Commission of the European Communities.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1745a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1749" publication-type="other">
Sala-i-Martin, X. and Sachs, J. (1992), 'Fiscal federalism and optimum currency areas: evidence
for Europe from the United States', in M. Canzoneri, V. Grilli and P. R. Masson (eds),
Establishing a Central Bank: Issues in Europe and Lessons from the US, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1765a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1769" publication-type="other">
Scholz, J. K. (1994), 'The earned income tax credit: participation, compliance and antipoverty
effectiveness', National Tax Journal, vol. 47, pp. 63-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1779a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1783" publication-type="other">
— (1996), 'In-work benefits in the United States: the earned income tax credit', Economic Journal,
vol. 106, pp. 156-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1793a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1797" publication-type="other">
Sinn, H.-W. (1985), 'Why taxes matter: Reagan's accelerated cost recovery system and the US
trade deficit', Economic Policy, vol. 1, pp. 240-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1807a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1811" publication-type="other">
Slemrod, J. (1996), 'Which is the simplest tax system of them all?', in H. J. Aaron and W. G. Gale
(eds), Economic Effects of Fundamental Tax Reform, Washington DC: Brookings Institution
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1825a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1829" publication-type="other">
Smart, M. and Bird, R. (1996), 'Federal fiscal arrangements in Canada: an analysis of incentives',
University of Toronto, International Centre for Tax Studies, Discussion Paper no. 8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1839a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1843" publication-type="other">
Sprensen, P. B. (1994), 'From the global income tax to the dual income tax: recent tax reforms in
the Nordic countries', International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 1, pp. 57-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1853a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1857" publication-type="other">
— (ed.) (1997), Tax Policy in the Nordic Countries, London: Macmillan Press, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1864a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1868" publication-type="other">
Steinmo, S. (1993), Taxation and Democracy, New Haven: Yale University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1875a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1879" publication-type="other">
Stotsky, J. G. and Sunley, E. M. (1994), 'The tax system of the United States', Tax Notes
International, vol. 9, 5 December, pp. 1755-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1889a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1893" publication-type="other">
US Bureau of the Census (1995), Statistical Abstract of the United States: 1995, 115th edition,
Lanham, Md.: Bernan Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1904a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1908" publication-type="other">
Walker, R. and Wiseman, M. (1997), 'The possibility of a British Earned Income Tax Credit',
Fiscal Studies, this issue, pp. 401-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1922" publication-type="other">
Watson, W. G. (1986), 'An estimate of the welfare gain from fiscal equalization', Canadian
Journal of Economics, vol. 19, pp. 298-308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1932a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1936" publication-type="other">
Whitehouse, E. (1996), 'Designing and implementing in-work benefits'. Economic Journal, vol.
106, pp. 130-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
