<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812175</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Financing Higher Education</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Returns to the Federal Tax Credits for Higher Education</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bulman</surname>
                  <given-names>George B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hoxby</surname>
                  <given-names>Caroline M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>69</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812175"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Three tax credits benefit households who pay tuition and fees for higher education. The credits have been justified as an investment: generating more educated people and thus more earnings and externalities associated with education. The credits have also been justified purely as tax cuts to benefit the middle class. In 2009, the generosity of and eligibility for the tax credits expanded enormously so that their 2011 cost was $25 billion. Using selected, de-identified data from the population of potential return filers, we show how the credits are distributed across households with different incomes. We estimate the causal effects of the federal tax credits using two empirical strategies (regression kink and simulated instruments) which we show to be strong and very credibly valid for this application. The latter strategy exploits the massive expansion of the credits in 2009. We present causal estimates of the credits' effects on postsecondary attendance, the type of college attended, the resources experienced in college, tuition paid, and financial aid received. We discuss the implications of our findings for society's return on investment and for the tax credits' budget neutrality over the long term (whether higher lifetime earnings generate sufficient taxes to recoup the tax expenditures). We assess several explanations why the credits appear to have negligible causal effects.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Agrawal, D., 2013. Inter-federation competition: sales tax externalities with multiple federations. working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Agrawal, D., 2013. LOST in America: evidence on local sales taxes from national panel data. working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Altshuler, R., Goodspeed, T., 2002. Follow the leader? Evidence on European and US tax competition. Rutgers University Working Paper Number 2002-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Andersson, F., Forslid, R., 2003. Tax competition and economic geography. Journal of Public Economic Theory 5 (2), 279-303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Baldwin, R., Krugman, P., 2004. Agglomeration, integration and tax harmonisation. European Economic Review 48 (1), 1-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Besley, T., Rosen, H., 1998. Vertical externalities in tax setting: evidence from gasoline and cigarettes. Journal of Public Economics 70 (3), 383-398.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Brett, C., Pinkse, J., 2000. The determinants of municipal tax rates in British Columbia. Canadian Journal of Economics 33 (3), 695-714.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Brueckner, J., 2003. Strategic interaction among governments: an overview of empirical studies. International Regional Science Review 26 (2), 175-188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Brueckner, J., Saavedra, L., 2001. Do local governments enagage in strategic property tax competition? National Tax Journal 54 (2), 203-230.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Brunori, D., 2007. Local Tax Policy: A Federalist Perspective (Second Edition). The Urban Institute Press; Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Bucovetsky, S., 1991. Asymmetric tax competition. Journal of Urban Economics 30 (2), 67-181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Buettner, T., 2001. Local business taxation and competition for capital: the choice of the tax rate. Regional Science and Urban Economics 31 (2-3), 215-245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Burge, G., Rogers, C., 2011. Local option sales taxes and consumer spending patterns: fiscal interdependence under multi-tiered local taxation. Regional Science and Urban Economics 41 (1), 46-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">de Mello, L., 2008. The Brazilian ‘Tax War’: The case of value-added tax competition among the states. Public Finance Review 36 (2), 169-193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Esteller-More, Sole-Olle, A., 2001. Vertical income tax externalities and fiscal interdependence: evidence from the US. Regional Science and Urban Economics 31 (2-3), 247-272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Eugster, B., Parchet, R., 2011. Culture and taxes: towards identifying tax competition. DEEP Working Papers 11-05. University of Lausanne.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Fletcher, J., Murray, M., 2006. Competition over the tax base in the state sales tax,” Public Finance Review 34 (3), 258-281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Goodspeed, T., 2000. Tax structure in a federation. Journal of Public Economics 75 (3), 493-506.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Goodspeed, T., 2002. Tax competition and tax structure in open federal economies: evidence from OECD countries with implication for the European Union. European Economic Review 46 (2), 357-374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Haufler, A., Wooton, I., 1999. Country size and tax competition for foreign direct investment. Journal of Public Economics 71 (1), 121-139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Hayashi, M., Boadway, R., 2001. An empirical analysis of intergovernmental tax interaction: the case of business income taxes in Canada. Canadian Journal of Economics 34 (2), 481- 503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Heyndels, B., Vuchelen, J., 1998, Tax mimicking among Belgian municipalities. National Tax Journal 51, 89-101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hill, B., 2008. Agglomerations and strategic tax competition. Public Finance Review 36 (6), 651- 677.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Janeba, E., Osterloh, S., 2012. Tax and the city: a theory of local tax competition an evidence for Germany. ZEW Centre for European Economic Research Discussion Paper 12-005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Kempf, H., Rota-Graziosi, G., 2010. Endogenizing leadership in tax competition. Journal of Public Economics 94 (9), 768-776.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Kind, H., Midelfart-Knarvik, K., Schjelderup, G., 2000. Competing for capital in a ‘lumpy’ world. Journal of Public Economics</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Ladd, H., 1992. Mimicking of local tax burdens among neighboring counties. Public Finance Review 20 (4), 450-467.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Luna, L., Bruce, D., Hawkins, R., 2007. Maxing out: an analysis of local option sales tax rate increases. National Tax Journal 60 (1) 45-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Lyytikainen, T., 2012. Tax competition among local governments: evidence from a property tax reform in Finland. Journal of Public Economics 96 (7), 584-595.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Mintz, J., Tulkens, H., 1986. Commodity tax competition between member states of a federation: equilibrium and efficiency. Journal of Public Economics 29 (2), 133-172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Oklahoma Department of Commerce, 2013. Population estimates by place. http://www.okcommerce.gov.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Oklahoma Tax Commission, 2013. Local option sales tax rates and revenues by place. http://www.tax.ok.gov.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Peralta, S., van Ypersele, T., 2005. Factor endowments and welfare levels in an asymmetric tax competition game. Journal of Urban Economics 57 (2), 258-274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Shoup, C., 1936. The sales tax. Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science 183 (1), 104-110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Tiebout, C., 1956. A pure theory of local expenditures. Journal of Political Economy 64 (5), 416- 424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Wildasin, D., 1988. Nash equilibria in models of fiscal competition. Journal of Public Economics 35 (2), 229-240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Wildasin, D., 1989. Interjurisdictional capital mobility: fiscal externality and a corrective subsidy. Journal of Urban Economics 25 (2), 193-212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Wilson, J., 1986. A theory of interregional tax competition. Journal of Urban Economics 19 (3), 296-315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Wilson, J., 1999. Theories of tax competition. National Tax Journal 52 (2), 269-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Wu, Y., Hendrick, R., 2009. Horizontal and vertical tax competition in Florida local governments. Public Finance Review 37 (3), 289-311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Zodrow, G., 2010. Capital mobility and capital tax competition. National Tax Journal 63 (4) 865- 902.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Zodrow, G., Mieskowski, P., 1986. Pigou, Tiebout, property taxation, and the underprovision of local public goods. Journal of Urban Economics 19 (3), 356-370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Higher education tax credits in 2008 for a student with $10000 of qualifying tuition and fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Higher education tax credits in 2009 for a student with $10000 in qualifying tuition and fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Higher education tax credits in 2008 for a student with $4,000 of qualifying tuition and fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Higher education tax credits in 2009 for a student with $4,0000 in qualifying tuition and fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Higher education tax credits in 2008 for a student with qualifying tuition and fees of $2,400</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Higher education tax credits in 2009 for a student with $2,400 in qualifying tuition and fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Tax Expenditure on Higher Education Tax Credits, 1998 to 2015</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 14</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 15</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Change in higher education tax credits that could be taken, 2008 to 2009, for student with $10,000 in qualifying tuition and fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Change in higher education tax credits that could be taken, 2008 to 2009, for a student with $4,000 in qualifying tuition and fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Change in higher education tax credits that could be taken, 20118 to 2009, for a student with $ 2,400 in qualifying tuition &amp; fees</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>attending college at all by income group and year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>attending college at least half time by income group and year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>attending four-year college (conditional on attending)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>attending two-year college (conditional on attending)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>instructional resources (conditional on attending)w</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 23</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Outcomes of 19-year-olds by year and the degree to which they were potentially affected by the introduction of the AOTC</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Parameters of the Higher Education Tax Credits</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Tax Expenditure Consequences of the Higher Education Tax Credits</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 19- to 20-year-olds, 2008 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 19- to 20-year-olds, 2009 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Defining as Refundable Only Those Tax Credits That Filer Would Not Obtain If the Credit Were Nonrefundable Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 19- to 20-year-olds, 2009 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 22- to 23-year-olds, 2008 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 22- to 23-year-olds, 2009 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Defining as Refundable Only Those Tax Credits That Filer Would Not Obtain If the Credit Were Nonrefundable Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 22- to 23-year-olds, 2009 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 25- to 26-year-olds, 2008 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 25- to 26-year-olds, 2009 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 29- to 30-year-olds, 2008 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Potential and Actual Higher Education Tax Credits among 29- to 30-year-olds, 2009 Tax Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>First Stage of Regression Kink Estimation Changes in the Slope of the Credit-Income Relationship at the Edges of the Phase-Out Range</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Second Stage of Regression Kink Estimation Changes in the Slope of Outcome-Income Relationships at the Edges of the Phase-Out Range</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>First Stage of Simulated Instrumental Variable Estimation Effect of Policy-Based Tax Credit on Actual Tax Credit Taken</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>Second Stage of Simulated Instrumental Variable Estimation Effect of Tax Credits on Collegiate Outcomes, 19 and 22-Year-Olds, 3 Years Before and After the Introduction of the AOTC</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>College Assessment Taking and Scores by Household Income 19 and 20 Year Olds in 2008</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>Expenditures on Tax Credits that Coincide More and Less with Third Party Reports, tax filers of all ages in 2011, billions of $2011</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
