<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023194</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Firm Taxation and Investment</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Incorporation for Investment</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Devereux</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Centre for Business Taxation, University of Oxford</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Liu</surname>
                  <given-names>Li</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Centre for Business Taxation, University of Oxford</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>52</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023194"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We estimate the effect of corporation tax on small business incorporation and investment by exploring cross-sectional variation in the impact of a 2006/07 tax reform in a difference-in-differences design. Analyzing the population of UK corporation tax records from 2002/03 to 2008/09, we present three findings. First, a one percentage point increase in the tax gains to incorporation increases the number of newly incorporated companies by around 2 to 4.5%. Second, there is a strong cash flow effect of taxes on corporate investment. On average, a one percentage point increase in the average tax rate reduces investment rate by about 2.2 percentage points. Third, the cash flow effect of corporation taxes on investment is most pronounced for newly incorporated firms, and diminishes over time. This evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that incorporation lowers the cost of external finance for small businesses, and that the cost is further reduced the longer a business has been incorporated.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ang, James S., James Wuh Lin, and Floyd Tyler. 1995. “Evidence on the Lack of Separation between Business and Personal Risks among Small Businesses.” Journal of Small Business Finance, 4(2): 197 – 210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, Thorsten, and Asli Demirguc-Kunt. 2006. “Small and Medium-size Enterprises: Access to Finance as a Growth Constraint.” Journal of Banking and Finance, 30(11): 2931 – 2943.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, Thorsten, Asli Demirgüç-Kunt, and Vojislav Maksimovic. 2008. “Financing patterns around the world: Are small firms different?” Journal of Financial Economics, 89(3): 467 – 487.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berger, Allen N., and Gregory F. Udell. 1998. “The economics of small business finance: The roles of private equity and debt markets in the financial growth cycle.” Journal of Banking and Finance, 22(6): 613 – 673.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blanchard, Olivier Jean, Florencio Lopez de Silanes, and Andrei Shleifer. 1994. “What do firms do with cash windfalls?” Journal of Financial Economics, 36(3): 337 – 360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bond, Stephen, and Jing Xing. 2013. “Corporate Taxation and Capital Accumulation.” Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper 1015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caballero, Ricardo J., Eduardo M. R. A. Engel, and John C. Haltiwanger. 1995. “Plant-Level Adjustment and Aggregate Investment Dynamics.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 26(2): 1–54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cameron, A. Colin, and Pravin K. Trivedi. 2013. Regression Analysis of Count Data. 2nd Edition, Econometric Society Monograph ed., Cambridge University Press. Campello, Murillo, and Erasmo Giambona. 2012. “Real Assets and Capital Structure.” National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper 18147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chirinko, Robert S., Steven M. Fazzari, and Andrew P. Meyer. 1999. “How Responsive is Business Capital Formation to Its User Cost?: An Exploration with Micro Data.” Journal of Public Economics, 74(1): 53–80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cummins, Jason G., Kevin A. Hassett, R. Glenn Hubbard, Robert E. Hall, and Ricardo J. Caballero. 1994. “A Reconsideration of Investment Behavior Using Tax Reforms as Natural Experiments.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 1994(2): pp. 1–74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demirguc-Kunt, Asli, Inessa Love, and Vojislav Maksimovic. 2006. “Business Environment and the Incorporation Decision.” Journal of Banking and Finance, 30(11): 2967 – 2993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Mooij, Ruud A., and Gaëtan Nicodeme. 2008. “Corporate Tax Policy and Incorporation in the EU.” International Tax and Public Finance, 15(4): 478–498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devereux, Michael P., and Rachel Griffith. 2003. “Evaluating Tax Policy for Location Decisions.” International Tax and Public Finance, 10(2): 107–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devereux, Michael P., Li Liu, and Simon Loretz. 2014. “The Elasticity of Corporate Taxable Income: New Evidence from UK Tax Records.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 6(2): 19–53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edgerton, Jesse. 2010. “Investment Incentives and Corporate Tax Asymmetries.” Journal of Public Economics, 94(11): 936 – 952.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egger, Peter, Christian Keuschnigg, and Hannes Winner. 2009. “Incorporation and Taxation: Theory and Firm-level Evidence.” Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper 0908.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fama, Eugene F., and Michael C. Jensen. 1983. “Separation of Ownership and Control.” Journal of Law and Economics, 26(2): pp. 301–325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fazzari, Steven M., R. Glenn Hubbard, and Bruce C. Petersen. 1988. “Financing Constraints and Corporate Investment.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 19(1): 141–206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goolsbee, Austan. 1998. “Taxes, Organizational Form, and the Deadweight Loss of the Corporate Income Tax.” Journal of Public Economics, 69(1): 143 – 152.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goolsbee, Austan. 2004. “The Impact of the Corporate Income Tax: Evidence from State Organizational Form Data.” Journal of Public Economics, 88(11): 2283 – 2299.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gordon, Roger, and Joel Slemrod. 2000. “Are Real Responses to Taxes Simply Income Shifting between Corporate and Personal Tax Bases?” In Does Atlas Shrug: The Economic Consequences of Taxing the Rich., ed. Joel Slemrod, 240-79. Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gordon, Roger H٠, and Jeffrey K٠ MacKie-Mason. 1994. “Tax Distortions to the Choice of Organizational Form.” Journal of Public Economics, 55(2): 279 – 306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hassett, Kevin A., and R. Glenn Hubbard. 2002. “Tax Policy and Business Investment.” In Handbook of Public Economics. Vol. 3 of Handbook of Public Economics,, ed. A. J. Auerbach and M. Feldstein, Chapter 20, 1293–1343. Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jorgenson, Dale W. 1963. “Capital Theory and Investment Behavior.” American Economic Review, 53(2): 247–259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jorgenson, Dale W., and R.E. Hall. 1967. “Tax Policy and Investment Behavior.” American Economic Review, 57: 391–414.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lamont, Owen. 1997. “Cash Flow and Investment: Evidence from Internal Capital Markets.” The Journal of Finance, 52(1): 83–109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Li. 2014. “Income Taxes and Business Incorporation: Evidence from the Early 20th Century.” National Tax Journal, 67(2): 387–417.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mackie-Mason, Jeffrey K, and Roger H Gordon. 1997. “How Much Do Taxes Discourage Incorporation?” Journal of Finance, 52(2): 477–505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rauh, Joshua D. 2006. “Investment and Financing Constraints: Evidence from the Funding of Corporate Pension Plans.” The Journal of Finance, 61(1): 33–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Silva, J. M. C. Santos, and Silvana Tenreyro. 2006. “The Log of Gravity.” The Review of Economics and Statistics, 88(4): 641–658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Voordeckers, Wim, and Tensie Steijvers. 2006. “Business Collateral and Personal Commitments in SME Lending.” Journal of Banking and Finance, 30(11): 3067 – 3086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yagan, Danny. 2013. “Capital Tax Reform and the Real Economy: the Effects of the 2003 Dividend Tax Cut.” Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper 1322.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zwick, Eric, and James Mahon. 2014. “Do Financial Frictions Amplify Fiscal Policy? Evidence from Business Investment Stimulus.” Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper 1415.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
