<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816635</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Retirement Transition (Pensions)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Using Panel Tax Data to Examine the Transition to Retirement</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brady</surname>
                  <given-names>Peter J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bass</surname>
                  <given-names>Steven</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Holland</surname>
                  <given-names>Jessica</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pierce</surname>
                  <given-names>Kevin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>85</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816635"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Using panel data from the Internal Revenue Service’s Statistics of Income (SOI) Division, we find that most individuals do not experience a reduction in inflation-adjusted spendable income after claiming Social Security. We also examine the composition of income after claiming and find that both Social Security benefits and non-Social Security retirement distributions typically represent substantial shares of income. Examining the five-year period from one year before individuals first receive Social Security retirement benefits to three years after, 81 percent of individuals had income, either directly or through a spouse, from employer retirement plans, annuities, or IRAs; and another 8 percent had a Form 1099-R (indicating a retirement account transaction, such as a rollover, that did not generate income), a Form 5498 (indicating IRA ownership), or both. This study uses the SOI 1999 Edited Panel of individual income tax returns, with information through tax year 2010, supplemented with data from information returns. We structure the data to follow individual taxpayers—specifically, individuals who were the primary or secondary taxpayer on a joint return or the primary taxpayer on a non-joint return in 1999—rather than tax returns. Information returns and various schedules filed with Form 1040 allow us to allocate labor income, Social Security benefits, and retirement income (pension, annuity, and IRA distributions) to primary and secondary filers on joint returns. Information returns also allow us to measure the income of all 1999 taxpayers through 2010 regardless of whether they filed a tax return in a subsequent year or not. We focus on working individuals age 55 to 61 in 1999 who did not receive Social Security benefits in 1999. Comparison with U.S. population counts suggests that nearly all individuals in this category filed a tax return in 1999.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References (possibly incomplete, certainly inconsistently formatted)</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Aguiar, Mark and Eric Hurst. 2005. “Consumption vs Expenditure.” Journal of Political Economy, 113(5), 919-948.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Aguiar, Mark and Eric Hurst. 2007. “Lifecycle Production and Prices.” American Economic Review, 97(5), 1533-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Aguiar, Mark and Eric Hurst. 2013. “Deconstructing Lifecycle Expenditure.” Journal of Political Economy, 121(3), 437-492.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Armour, Philip and Angela A. Hung. 2017. “Drawing Down Retirement Wealth: Interactions between Social Security Wealth and Private Retirement Savings.” RAND Labor and Population Working Paper, no. 1165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Attanasio, Orazio. 1999. “Consumption.” Handbook of Macroeconomics</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bee, Adam C. and Joshua Mitchell. 2016. “The Hidden Resources of Women Working Longer: Evidence from Linked Survey-Administrative Data.” NBER Working Paper No. 22970</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Behaghel, Luc, and David M. Blau. 2012. "Framing social security reform: Behavioral responses to changes in the full retirement age." American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 41-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bernheim, Douglas, Jonathan Skinner, and Steven Weinberg. 2001. “What Accounts for the Variation in Retirement Wealth Among U.S. Households?” American Economic Review, 91(4), 832 – 857.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Brady, Peter J. 2010. "Measuring retirement resource adequacy." Journal of Pension Economics and Finance, 9(2):235–262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Brady, Peter J. 2016. How America Supports Retirement: Challenging the Conventional Wisdom on Who Benefits. Washington, DC: Investment Company Institute. Available at www.ici.org/pdf/rpt_16_america_supports_retirement.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Glickman, Mark M., and Sharon Hermes. 2015. "Why Retirees Claim Social Security at 62 and How It Affects Their Retirement Income: Evidence from the Health and Retirement Study." The Journal of Retirement 25-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Hurd, Michael, and Susann Rohwedder. 2006. “Some Answers to the Retirement-Consumption Puzzle.” RAND Labor and Population Working Paper, no. 342 (January). Available at www.rand.org/pubs/working_papers/WR342.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Hurd, Michael, and Susann Rohwedder. 2008. “The Retirement-Consumption Puzzle: Actual Spending Change in Panel Data.” RAND Labor and Population Working Paper, no. 563 (April). Available at www.rand.org/pubs/working_papers/WR563.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Erik Hurst. 2008. “The Retirement of a Consumption Puzzle.” NBER Working Paper No. 13789</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Goda, Gopi Shah, Shanthi Ramnath, John B. Shoven, and Sita Nataraj Slavov. 2015. “The Financial Feasibility of Delaying Social Security: Evidence from Administrative Tax Data.” NBER Working Paper No. 21544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Gustman, Alan L., Thomas L. Steinmeier, and Nahid Tabatabai. 2009. “How Do Pension Changes Affect Retirement Preparedness? The Trend to Defined Contribution Plans and the Vulnerability of the Retirement Age Population to the Stock Market Decline of 2008–2009.” University of Michigan Retirement Research Center Working Paper 2009-206 (October). Available at www.mrrc.isr.umich.edu/publications/papers/pdf/wp206.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Gustman, Alan L., Thomas L. Steinmeier and Nahid Tabatabai. 2010. Pensions in the Health and Retirement Study. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gustman, Alan L., Thomas L. Steinmeier and Nahid Tabatabai. 2012. “Mismeasurement of Pensions Before and After Retirement: The Mystery of the Disappearing Pensions with Implications for the Importance of Social Security as a Source of Retirement Support” University of Michigan Retirement Research Center Working Paper 2012-268</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Li, Xiaoyan, Michael Hurd, and David S. Loughran. 2008. “The characteristics of social security beneficiaries who claim benefits at the early entitlement age.” Vol. 19. AARP, Public Policy Institute</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Mastrobuoni, Giovanni. 2009. "Labor supply effects of the recent social security benefit cuts: Empirical estimates using cohort discontinuities." Journal of Public Economics 93(11): 1224-1233.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Meyer, Bruce D., Wallace K. C. Mok, and James X. Sullivan. 2009. “The Under-Reporting of Transfers in Household Surveys: Its Nature and Consequences.” NBER Working Paper no. 15181 (July). Cambridge, MA: National Bureau of Economic Research. Available at www.nber.org/papers/w15181.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Miller, Billie Jean, and Sylvester J. Schieber. 2014. “Contribution of Pension and Retirement Savings to Retirement Income Security: More Than Meets the Eye.” Journal of Retirement 1, no. 3: 14–29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Munnell, Alicia H. and Anqi Chen. 2015. “Trends in Social Security Claiming.” Center for Retirement Research Issue Brief no. 15-8 (May). Available at http://crr.bc.edu/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IB_15- 8.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Schieber, Sylvester J. 1995. “Why Do Pension Benefits Seem So Small?” Benefits Quarterly 11, no. 4 (December): 57–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Song, Jae, and Joyce Manchester. 2007. "Have people delayed claiming retirement benefits? Responses to changes in Social Security rules." Social Security Bulletin 67(2): 1-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Weber, Michael, Victoria L. Bryant. 2005. “The 1999 Individual Income Tax Return Edited Panel,” Proceedings of the American Statistical Association, Social Statistics Section. Government Statistics Section, Alexandria, VA: American Statistical Association.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Weber, Michael. 2006. “The Tax Year 1999-2003 Individual Income Tax Return Panel: A First Look at the Data,” Proceedings of the American Statistical Association, Social Statistics Section. Government Statistics Section, Alexandria, VA: American Statistical Association.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Dollar Ranges for Categories of 1999 Per Capita Total Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Age 62 and Age 66 Most Common Ages for Claiming Social Security Benefits</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Benefits Most Often Claimed at Full Benefit Retirement Age</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Higher-Income Workers More Likely to Have Claimed Social Security when Older</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>97 Percent Were Alive Three Years After Claiming Social Security</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Older Workers More Likely to Have Claimed Social Security by 2007</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Lower-Income Workers More Likely to Have Claimed Social Security by 2007</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Higher-Income Workers More Likely to Have Filed a Tax Return After Claiming Social Security</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Net Total Income Declined Modestly after Claiming</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Net Work-Related Income Relatively Flat after Claiming</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Net Work-Related Income Increased for Low Income, Remained Steady for Middle Income After Claiming</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Net Income Increased Substantially for Low Income Who Continued to Work</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Net Income Modestly Higher for Low Income Who No Longer Worked</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Average Tax Rates Declined the Most for Lower Income Workers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Net Work-Related Income Increased after Claiming for Many Individuals</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Replacement Rates Typically Higher for Lower Income Individuals</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Individuals Who Continued to Work Typically Had Higher Replacement Rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Predicted Replacement Rates Higher for Lower-Income Workers</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Predicted Replacement Rates Typically Higher for Individuals Who Claimed at Age 62</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Changes in Marital Status Affect Predicted Replacement Rates More Than Marital Status Itself</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Nearly Half of Individuals Were Working Three Years after Claiming Social Security</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Over 70 Percent Had Retirement Income Three Years after Claiming Social Security, Higher for Moderate Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Six in Ten Received Retirement Income in All Three Years After Claiming Social Security</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 23</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Nearly Nine in 10 Had Evidence of Non-Social Security Retirement Resources</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>No Easy Way to Distinguish DB Plan Distributions from DC Plan Distributions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 24</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Higher-Income Individuals More Likely to Have Had Investment and Business Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 25</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Social Security More Important than Retirement Income for Lower Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 26</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Individuals Who Continued to Work Were Higher Earning Prior to Claiming</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 27</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Importance of Social Security and Retirement Income Differs by 1999 Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 28</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Relative to Social Security, Retirement Income More Important for Individuals Who Stopped Working</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 29</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>Income Composition Fairly Stable in the Three Years After Claiming</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 30</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>Moderate Income Relied on Both Social Security Benefits and Retirement Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 31</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>Gains, Dividends, and Interest Important for Many Higher-Income Individuals</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>Types of Distributions Reported on Form 1099-R</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-35">
            <p>Definitions of Income and Tax Measures</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-36">
            <p>Comparison of Sample of Interest and Subsample Used for Analysis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.4</label>
         <caption id="ca-37">
            <p>Median Replacement Rate Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
