<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278358</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Heavy-Duty RCCI Operation Using Natural Gas and Diesel</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nieman</surname>
                  <given-names>Derek E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dempsey</surname>
                  <given-names>Adam B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>May 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278342</issue-id>
         <fpage>270</fpage>
         <lpage>285</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278358"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Many recent studies have shown that the Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) combustion strategy can achieve high efficiency with low emissions. However, it has also been revealed that RCCI combustion is difficult at high loads due to its premixed nature. To operate at moderate to high loads with gasoline/diesel dual fuel, high amounts of EGR or an ultra low compression ratio have shown to be required. Considering that both of these approaches inherently lower thermodynamic efficiency, in this study natural gas was utilized as a replacement for gasoline as the low-reactivity fuel. Due to the lower reactivity (i.e., higher octane number) of natural gas compared to gasoline, it was hypothesized to be a better fuel for RCCI combustion, in which a large reactivity gradient between the two fuels is beneficial in controlling the maximum pressure rise rate.</p>
            <p>The multi-dimensional CFD code, KIVA3V, was used in conjunction with the CHEMKIN chemistry tool and a Nondominated Sorting Genetic Algorithm (NSGA-II) to perform optimization for a wide range of engine operating conditions. Engine design parameters that were controlled by the genetic algorithm include the fraction of total fuel that is premixed (methane), the timing of the two diesel injections, the amount of diesel in each injection, the diesel fuel injection pressure, and the EGR percentage. The objective of the optimization was to simultaneously minimize soot, NOx, CO, and UHC emissions, as well as ISFC and ringing intensity. A broad load/speed range was investigated; six operating points from 4 to 23 bar IMEP and 800 to 1800 rev/min were optimized. These load/speed combinations represent typical heavy-duty engine conditions. Using the stock compression ratio of 16.1, it was determined that operation up to 13.5 bar IMEP could be achieved with no EGR, while still maintaining high efficiency and low emissions. The study also examined the sensitivity of RCCI combustion at high load to injection system parameters. The results emphasize that precise injection control is needed for combustion control.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, Y. Diesel Combustion Optimization and Emissions Reduction sing Adaptive Injection Strategies (AIS) with Improved Numerical odels, PhD Thesis, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamimoto, T. and Bae, M., “High Combustion Temperature for the eduction of Particulate in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 880423, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and Siebers, D., “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature ixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S. et al., “Mechanism of he Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” AE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najt, P. and Foster, D., “Compression-Ignited Homogeneous Charge ombustion,” SAE Technical Paper 830264, 1983, doi: 10.4271/830264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurushima, T., Kunishima, E., Asaumi, Y., Aoyagi, Y. et al., “The ffect of Knock on Heat Loss in Homogeneous Charge Compression gnition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0108, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., “Closed-Loop Control of an CCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1031, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-1031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J., Tunestål, P., Haraldsson, G., and Johansson, B., “A Turbo harged Dual Fuel HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1896, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1896.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J., Tunestål, P., Ulfvik, J., and Johansson, B., “The Effect of ooled EGR on Emissions and Performance of a Turbocharged HCCI ngine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0743, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0743.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noehre, C., Andersson, M., Johansson, B., and Hultqvist, A., “Characterization of Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical aper 2006-01-3412, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H., “Advantages of Fuels ith High Resistance to Auto-ignition in Late-injection, Lowtemperature, ompression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3385, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Johansson, B., and Tunestal, P., “Partially Premixed ombustion at High Load using Gasoline and Ethanol, a Comparison ith Diesel,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0944, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Tunestal, P., Johansson, B., and Cannella, W., “Effects of thanol and Different Type of Gasoline Fuels on Partially Premixed ombustion from Low to High Load,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0871, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0871.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manente, V., Zander, C., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P. et al., “An dvanced Internal Combustion Engine Concept for Low Emissions and igh Efficiency from Idle to Max Load Using Gasoline Partially remixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2198, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasegawa, R. and Yanagihara, H., “HCCI Combustion in DI Diesel ngine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0745, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0745.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. and Reitz, R., “Computational Optimization of a Heavy- uty Compression Ignition Engine Fueled with Conventional Gasoline,” AE Int. J. Engines 4(1):338-359, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Fuyuto, T., Nishikawa, K., Nakakita, K. et al., “Dual-Fuel CI Combustion Controlled by In-Cylinder Stratification of gnitability,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0028, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M. and Johansson, B., “Supercharged Homogeneous harge Compression Ignition (HCCI) with Exhaust Gas Recirculation nd Pilot Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1835, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-1835.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P., Schleyer, C., Duffy, K., Hardy, W. et al., “Effects of Fuel roperty Changes on Heavy-Duty HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical aper 2007-01-0191, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and odeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder uel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Kokjohn, S., Rein, K., Hanson, R. et al., “An Optical nvestigation of Ignition Processes in Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI ombustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):142-162, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0345.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “An Experimental nvestigation of Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion in a eavy-Duty Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):700-716, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S. L., and Reitz, R. D. Improving ngine Performance by Optimizing Fuel Reactivity with a Dual Fuel CCI Strategy, THIESEL Conference on Thermo and Fluid Dynamic rocesses in Diesel Engines, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. D., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Kokjohn, S. L. Engine ombustion Control via Fuel Reactivity Stratification, February, 2010, niversity of Wisconsin WARF Patent Application, P100054US.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L. and Reitz, R. D. Characterization of Dual-Fuel PCCI ombustion in a Light-Duty Engine, International Multidimensional ngine Modeling User's Group Meeting, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korakianitis, T., Namasivayam, A. M., Crookes, R. J. Natural-gas ueled spark-ignition (SI) and compression-ignition (CI) engine erformance and emissions, Progress in Energy and Combustion cience, 2011, Vol. 37, pp. 89-112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A., O'Rourke, P. J., and Butler, T. D. KIVA-II - A computer rogram for chemically reactive flows with sprays, 1989, Los Alamos ational Laboratory Report LA-11560-MS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A. KIVA-3V: A block-structured KIVA program for ngines with vertical or canted valves, 1997, Los Alamos National aboratory Report LA-13313-MS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A. KIVA-3V, Release 2, improvements to KIVA-3V, 1999, os Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-UR-99-915.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale, J. C. and Reitz, R. D. Modeling Spray Atomization with the elvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh-Taylor hybrid model, Atomization and prays, 1999, Vol. 9, pp. 623-650.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abani, N., Munnannur, A., and Reitz, R. D. Reduction of Numerical arameter Dependencies in Diesel Spray Models, Journal of ngineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 2008, Vol. 130, 032809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P. and Amsden, A., “A Spray/Wall Interaction Submodel for he KIVA-3 Wall Film Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0271, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y. and Reitz, R. D. The application of a multicomponent droplet aporization model to gasoline direct injection engines, International ournal of Engine Research, 2003, Vol. 4, pp. 193-218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z. and Reitz, R. D. Turbulence Modeling of Internal Combustion ngines Using RNG k-e Models, Combustion Science and Technology, 1995, Vol. 106, pp. 267-295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, R. J., Rupley, F. M., and Miller, J. A. CHEMKIN-II: A FORTRAN hemical kinetics package for the analysis of gas phase chemical inetics, 1989, Sandia Report SAND 89-8009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kong, S. C. and Reitz, R. D. Modeling Diesel Spray Flame Liftoff, ooting Tendency, and NOx Emissions Using Detailed Chemistry with henomenological Soot Model, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines nd Power, 2007, Vol. 129, pp. 245-251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turns, S. R. An Introduction to Combustion: Concepts and pplications, First Edition, McGraw-Hill, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shi, Y. and Reitz, R., “Assessment of Optimization Methodologies to tudy the Effects of Bowl Geometry, Spray Targeting and Swirl Ratio or a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Operated at High-Load,” SAE Int. J. ngines 1(1):537-557, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0949.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deb, K., Pratap, A., Agarwal, S., and Meyarivan, T. A Fast Elitist ultiobjective Genetic Algorithm: NSGA-II, IEEE Transactions on volutionary Computation, 2002, Vol. 6, No. 2, pp. 182-197.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. and Reitz, R., “Computational Optimization of Reactivity ontrolled Compression Ignition in a Heavy-Duty Engine with Ultra ow Compression Ratio,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2222-2239, 2011, oi:10.4271/2011-24-0015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” AE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J., Babajimopoulos, A., and Assanis, D., “Comparing nhanced Natural Thermal Stratification Against Retarded Combustion hasing for Smoothing of HCCI Heat-Release Rates,” SAE Technical aper 2004-01-2994, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine nock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions -using Conventional asoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):750-767, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragland, K. W. and Bryden, K. M. Combustion Engineering, Second dition, CRC Press, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
