<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277848</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling Soot Size Distribution Evolution and Pollutant Formation Inside Diesel Engine Using a 0D Multi-zone Gas Parcel Model with Detailed Chemistry and Soot Microphysics</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moniruzzaman</surname>
                  <given-names>Chowdhury G.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yu</surname>
                  <given-names>Fangqun</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>State University of New York at Albany</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1336</fpage>
         <lpage>1369</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277848"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Diesel engine emits soot which causes harm to human health, air quality and climate. It is important to understand the formation and time evolution of soot and its size distribution evolution inside engines to design strategies for emission reduction. We have developed a 0D multi-zone model for diesel fuel spray and coupled it with detailed surrogate diesel fuel chemistry and a sectional aerosol dynamics model for soot nucleation, surface growth and coagulation. Variable equivalence ratios in different zones are created by fixed fuel injection rates and variable air entrainment rates by a normal distribution function in different zones which ensures the existences of different pollutant forming zones having different equivalence ratios. Engine exit measured data of total soot mass and NOx for one operating condition are used to optimize the three model parameters. Model simulation of soot size distribution is consistent with typical measured data. Other than soot, the model also calculates the concentration of a wide range of combustion products (NOx, CO, SO₂, SO₃, NO, NO₂, N₂O, OH, HO₂ etc.) which may help to study engine exhaust chemistry of pollutant reduction. Sulfur oxidation efficiency ([SO₃]+[H₂SO₄])/([Total S]) is found to be 2% at end of the expansion stroke. The model simulation produces the typical trend that late injection increase soot but decrease NOx. The model may enable us to test the predicting capability of any existing or newly developed chemical kinetic mechanism of surrogate fuel oxidation and soot formation inside the engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope, C. A. and Dockery, D.W., “Health Effects of Fine Particulate Air Pollution: Lines that Connect,” J. Air Waste Manage. Assoc. 56: 709-742, 2006, doi:10.1080/10473289.2006.10464485.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gauderman, W.J., Vora, H., McConnell, R., Berhane, K. et al., “Effect of Exposure to Traffic on Lung Development from 10 to 18 Years of Age: a Cohort Study,” Lancet 369: 571-577, 2007, doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60037-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, A., Veronesi, B., Calderóon-Garcidueñnas, L., Gehr, P., Chen, L.C. et al., “Translocation and Potential Neurological Effects of Fine and Ultrafine Particles: A Critical Update,” Particle and Fibre Toxicol. 3: 13, 2006, doi:10.1186/1743-8977-3-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koren, H.S., Devlin, R.B., Graham, D.E., Mann, R. et al., “Ozone-induced Inflammation in the Lower Airways of Human Subjects,” Am. Rev. Respir. Dis. :139, 407-415, 1989, doi:10.1164/ajrccm/139.2.407.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosson, J., Barath, S., Pourazar, J., Behndig, A.F. et al., “Diesel Exhaust Exposure Enhances the Ozone-induced Airway Inflammation in Healthy Humans,” Eur Respir J 2008; 31: 1234- 1240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bell, M.L., McDermott, A., Zeger, S.L., Samet, J.M. et al., “Ozone and Short-term Mortality in 95 US Urban Communities, 1987- 2000,” J Am Med Assoc 2004; 292: 2372-2378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobson, M.Z., “Strong Radiative Heating due to the Mixing State of Black Carbon in Atmospheric Aerosols,” Nature 2001; 409: 695- 697.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hansen, J. and Nazarenko, L., “Soot Climate Forcing Via Snow and Ice Albedos,” Proc Natl Acad Sci 2004; 101: 423-428.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DieselNet, Online Information Service on Clean Diesel Engines and Diesel Emissions, Emission Standard of US EPA and Europe are Summarized at : &lt;http://www.dieselnet.com/standards/&gt;, Accessed, April, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EURO, Emission Regulation, Implementing and Amending Regulation (EC) N 715/2007 of the European Parliament and of the Council on Type-approval of Motor Vehicles with Respect to Emissions from Light Passenger and Commercial Vehicles (Euro 5 and Euro 6) and on Access to Vehicle Repair and Maintenance Information, 2008/692/EC, July 18, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, J., Stewart, M., Maupin, G., Herling, D. et al., “Single Wall Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) Filtration Efficiency Studies Using Laboratory Generated Particles,” Chem Engg Sci 2009; 64: 1625- 1634.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Balthasar, M. and Kraft, M., “A Stochastic Approach to Solve the Particle Size Distribution Function of Soot Particles in Laminar Premixed Flames,” Combust Flame 2003; 133: 289-298.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, J., Patterson, R.I.A., Kraft, M. and Wang, H., “Numerical Simulation and Sensitivity Analysis of Detailed Soot Particle Size Distribution in Laminar Premixed Ethylene Flames,” Combust Flame 2006; 145: 117-127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Netzell, K., Lehtiniemi, H. and Mauss, F., “Calculating the Soot Particle Size Distribution Function in Turbulent Diffusion Flames Using a Sectional Method,” Proc of the Combust Inst 2007; 31: 667-674, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2006.08.081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Anna, A., “Detailed Kinetic Modeling of Particulate Formation in Rich Premixed Flames of Ethylene,” Energ Fuels 2008; 22: 1610- 1619, doi:10.1021/ef700641u.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Q., Guo, H., Liu, F., Smallwood, G.J. and Thomson, M.J., “Implementation of an Advanced Fixed Sectional Aerosol Dynamics Model with Soot Aggregate Formation in a Laminar Methane/air Coflow Diffusion Flame,” Combust Theory Modeling 2008; 12: 621- 641, doi:10.1080/13647830801966153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lindstedt, R.P., Waldheim, B.B.O., “Modeling of Soot Particle Size Distributions in Premixed Stagnation Flow Flames,” Proc Combust Inst 2012, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2012.05.047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S.H., Rogak, S.N., Bushe, W.K., Wen, J.Z. et al., “An Aerosol Model to Predict Size and Structure of Soot Particles,” Combustion Theory and Modeling 2005; 9: 499-513, doi:10.1080/13647830500195005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wen, J.Z., Thomson, M.J., Lightstone, M.F., Park, S.H. et al., “An Improved Moving Sectional Aerosol Model of Soot Formation in a Plug Flow Reactor,” Combust Sci Technol 2006; 178: 921-951, doi:10.1080/00102200500270007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Celnik, M., Raj, A., West, R., Patterson, R. et al., “An Aromatic Site Description of Soot Particles,” Combust Flame 2008;155: 161-180, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2008.04.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mosbach, S., Celnik, M.S., Raj, A., Kraft, M. et al., “Towards a Detailed Soot Model for Internal Combustion Engines,” Combust Flame 2009; 156: 1156-1165, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2009.01.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moniruzzaman, C.G. and Yu, F., “A0D Aircraft Engine Emission Model with Detailed Chemistry and Soot Microphysics,” Combust Flame 2012; 159: 1670-1686, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2011.11.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Assanis, D. and Heywood, J., “Development and Use of a Computer Simulation of the Turbocompounded Diesel System for Engine Performance and Component Heat Transfer Studies,” SAE Technical Paper 860329, 1986, doi:10.4271/860329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Foster, D., “An Overview of Zero-Dimensional Thermodynamic Models for IC Engine Data Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 852070, 1985, doi:10.4271/852070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patterson, M., Kong, S., Hampson, G., and Reitz, R., “Modeling the Effects of Fuel Injection Characteristics on Diesel Engine Soot and NOx Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 940523, 1994, doi:10.4271/940523.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z., Uludogan, A., Hampson, G., and Reitz, R., “Mechanism of Soot and NOx Emission Reduction Using Multiple-injection in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 960633, 1996, doi:10.4271/960633.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golovitchev, V., Nordin, N., Jarnicki, R., and Chomiak, J., “3-D Diesel Spray Simulations Using a New Detailed Chemistry Turbulent Combustion Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01- 1891, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1891.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, F., Liu, Y., RempelEwert, B., Foster, D. et al., “Modeling the Effects of EGR and Injection Pressure on Soot Formation in a High-Speed Direct-Injection (HSDI) Diesel Engine Using a Multi- Step Phenomenological Soot Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2005- 01-0121, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Y., Tao, F., Foster, D., and Reitz, R., “Application of A Multiple- Step Phenomenological Soot Model to HSDI Diesel Multiple Injection Modeling,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0924, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corcione, F., Costa, M., Vaglieco, B., and Omote, H., “Assessment of a Detailed Kinetic Diesel Combustion Model by In-Cylinder Optical Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0057, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S.W. and Reitz, R.D., “Optimization of Fuel/Air mMixture Formation for Stoichiometric Diesel Combustion Using a 2-Spray- Angle Group-hole Nozzle,” Fuel 2009; 88: 843-852, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2008.10.028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y. and Reitz, R.D., “A Combustion Model for IC Engine Combustion Simulations with Multi-component Fuels,” Combust Flame 2011; 158: 69-90, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2010.07.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pang, K.M., Ng, H.K. and Gan, S., “Investigation of Fuel Injection Pattern on Soot Formation and Oxidation Processes in a Light-duty Diesel Engine Using Integrated CFD-reduced Chemistry,” Fuel 2012; 96: 404-418, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.01.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, D. and Assanis, D., “Multi-Zone DI Diesel Spray Combustion Model for Cycle Simulation Studies of Engine Performance and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1246, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C.D., Antonopoulos, K.A. and Rakopoulos, D.C., “Multi-zone Modeling of Diesel Engine Fuel Spray Development with Vegetable Oil, Bio-diesel or Diesel Fuels,” Energy Conversion and Management 2006; 47: 1550-1573, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2005.08.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C.D., Dimaratos, A.M., Giakoumis, E.G. and Rakopoulos, D.C., “Exhaust Emissions Estimation During Transient Turbocharged Diesel Engine Operation Using a Two-zone Combustion Model,” Int J Vehicle Design 2009; 49: 125-149, doi:10.1504/IJVD.2009.024244.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, Z., Wagner, R.M., Sluder, C.S., Daw, C.S. et al., “Using a Phenomenological Computer Model to Investigate Advanced Combustion Trajectories in a CIDI Engine,” Fuel 2011; 90: 1907- 1911, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2010.12.030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A.A., 1993: KIVA 3: A KIVA Program with Block Structured Mesh for Complex Geometries. Tech Rep LA-12503-MS, Los Alamos National Lab.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobson, M.Z., Turco, R.P., Jensen, E.J. and Toon, O.B., “Modeling Coagulation Among Particles of Different Composition and Size,” Atmos Environ 1994; 28: 1327-1338, doi:10.1016/1352- 2310(94)90280-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu, F., “From Molecular Clusters to Nanoparticles: Secondgeneration Ion-mediated Nucleation Model.” Chem. Phys. 2006; 6: 5193-5211, doi:10.5194/acp-6-5193-2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Kelly-Zion, P., “The Effects of Injection Timing and Diluent Addition on Late-Combustion Soot Burnout in a DI Diesel Engine Based on Simultaneous 2-D Imaging of OH and Soot,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0238, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Monyem, A., Gerpen, J.H. van, and Canakci, M., “The Effect of Timing and Oxidation on Emissions From Biodiesel-fueled Engines,” Transactions of the ASAE 2001; 44: 35-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nehmer, D. and Reitz, R., “Measurement of the Effect of Injection Rate and Split Injections on Diesel Engine Soot and NOx Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 940668, 1994, doi:10.4271/940668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittleson, D.B., Watts, W.F. and Johnson, J.P., “On-road and Laboratory Evaluation of Combustion Aerosols-Part1: Summary of Diesel Engine Results,” J. Aerosol Sci., 2006; 37: 913-930, doi:10.1016/j.jaerosci.2005.08.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seiser, H., Pitsch, H., Seshadri, K., Pitz, W.J. et al., “Extinction and Autoignition of n-Heptane in Counterflow Configuration,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 28, p. 2029-2037, 2000; Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, Livermore (LLNL), CA, UCRL-JC-137080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H. and Frenklach, M., “A Detailed Kinetic Modeling Study of Aromatics Formation in Laminar Premixed Acetylene and Ethylene Flames,” Combust Flame 1997; 110: 173-221, doi:10.1016/S0010- 2180(97)00068-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Appel, J., Bockhorn, H. and Frenklach, M., “Kinetic Modeling of Soot Formation with Detailed Chemistry and Physics: Laminar Premixed Flames of C2 Hydrocarbons,” Combust Flame 2000; 121: 122-136, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(99)00135-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frenklach, M. and Wang, H., “Detailed Mechanism and Modeling of Soot Particle Formation, in Soot Formation in Combustion: Mechanisms and Models (Edited by Bockhorn H.),” Springer- Verlag, New York 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kitamura, T., Ito, T. and Fujimoto, H., “Mechanism of Smokeless Diesel Combustion with Oxygenated Fuels Based on the Dependence of the Equivalence Ratio and Temperature on Soot Particle Formation,” Int J Engine Res 2002; 3: 223-248, doi:10.1243/146808702762230923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hughes, K.J., Tomlin, A.S., Hampartsoumian, E., Nimmo, W. et al., “An Investigation of Important Gas Phase Reactions of Nitrogen Species from the Simulation of Bulk Experimental Data in Combustion Systems,” Combust Flame 2001; 124: 573-589, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(00)00228-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leeds, University of Leeds Chemical Kinetic Database for NOx and Sox &lt;http://www.chem.leeds.ac.uk/Combustion/Combustion.html&gt;, Accessed in December, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marinov, N., Pitz, W., Hori, M., Matsunaga, N. et al., “An Experimental and Kinetic Calculation of the Promotion Effect of Hydrocarbons on the NO-NO2 Conversion in a Flow Reactor,” Proc Combust Inst 1998; 27: 389-396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LLNL. Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory Chemical Kinetic Database for NOx &lt;https://www-pls.llnl.gov/?url=science_and_technology-chemistry-combustion-nox&gt;, Accessed in December, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, R.J., Rupley, F.M., Meeks, E. and Miller, J.A., “CHEMKIN-III: A Fortran Chemical Kinetics Package for the Analysis of Gas Phase Chemical and Plasma Kinetics,” SANDIA Report SAND96-8216, Sandia National Laboratories, Livermore, CA94551-0969, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, P.N., Byrne, G.D. and Hindmarsh, A.C., “VODE: A Variable Coefficient ODE Solver,” SIAM J Sci Stat Comput 1989; 10: 1038- 1051, doi:10.1137/0910062.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turco, R.P., Hamill, P., Toon, O.B., Whitten, R.C. et al., “A Onedimensional Model Describing Aerosol Formation and Evolution in the Stratosphere: Part I. Physical Processes and Mathematical Analogs,” J Atmos Sci 1979; 36: 699-717, doi:10.1175/1520- 0469(1979)036&lt;0699:AODMDA&gt;2.0.CO;2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toon, O.B., Turco, R.P., Westphal, D., Malone, R. et al., “A Multidimensional Model for Aerosols: Description of Computational Analogs,” J Atmos Sci 1988; 45: 2123-2143, doi:10.1175/1520- 0469(1988)045&lt;2123:AMMFAD&gt;2.0.CO;2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu, F. and Turco, R.P., “From Molecular Clusters to Nanoparticles: Role of Ambient Ionization in Tropospheric Aerosol Formation,” J Geophys Res 2001; 106: 4797-4814, doi:10.1029/2000JD900539.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moniruzzaman, C.G., “Detailed Modeling of Soot Size Distribution Evolution and Pollutant Formation Inside Aircraft and Diesel Engines,” PhD Thesis, State University of New York at Albany, 2012, p 20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lepperhoff, G. and Petter, K.D., “The Influence of Diesel Fuel Composition on Gaseous and Particulate Emissions,” Int J Vehicle Design 2001;27: 10-19, doi:10.1504/IJVD.2001.001947.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bishop, G.A., Schuchmann, B.G. and Stedman, D.H., “Emission Changes Resulting from the San Pedro Bay, California Ports Truck Retirement Program,” Environ Sci Technol 2012; 46: 551-558, doi:10.1021/es202392g.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kock, B.F., Tribalet, B., Schulz, C. and Roth, P., “Two-color Timeresolved LII Applied to Soot Particle Sizing in the Cylinder of a Diesel Engine,” Combust Flame 2006; 147: 79-92, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2006.07.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boiarciuc, A., Foucher, F., Mounaïm-Rousselle, C. and Pajot, O., “Estimate Measurement of Soot Diameter and Volume Fraction Inside the Bowl of a Direct-injection-compression-ignition Engine: Effect of the Exhaust Gas Recirculation,” Combust Sci Technol 2007; 179: 1631-1648, doi:10.1080/00102200701244728.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US EPA, Environmental Protection Agency. Climate Leaders Greenhouse Gas Inventory Protocol Core Module Guidance. Direct Emissions from Mobile Combustion Sources, 2008, US EPA Report EPA430-K-08-004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engel, P.K., Thompson, R.E. and Silvestrini, R., “Corrosion and Fouling Potential in Diesel Exhausts II. Trans,” ASME Journal of Engineering for Power 101 (1979) 598-607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” New York: McGraw-Hill Book Co; 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyaso, H. and Arai, M., “Fuel Spray Penetration and Spray Angle of Diesel Engines,” Trans of JSAE 1980; 21: 5-11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>68.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., Arai, M., and Tabata, M., “Empirical Equations for the Sauter Mean Diameter of a Diesel Spray,” SAE Technical Paper 890464, 1989, doi:10.4271/890464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>69.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borman, G. and Johnson, J., “Unsteady Vaporization Histories and Trajectories of Fuel Drops Injected into Swirling Air,” SAE Technical Paper 620271, 1962, doi:10.4271/620271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>70.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gosman, A. and Johns, R., “Computer Analysis of Fuel-Air Mixing in Direct-Injection Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 800091, 1980, doi:10.4271/800091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <label>71.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranz, W.E. and Marshall, W.R., “Evaporation from I,” Chem Eng Prog 1953; 48(4): 173-180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <label>72.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Annand, W.J.D. “Heat Transfer in the Cylinder of Reciprocating International Combustion Engine,” Proc. I. Mech. E. 177, 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
