<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308470</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Two-Stage Variable Compression Ratio with Eccentric Piston Pin and Exploitation of Crank Train Forces</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wittek</surname>
                  <given-names>Karsten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV Motorentechnik GmbH, Aachen</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tiemann</surname>
                  <given-names>Christof</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV Motorentechnik GmbH, Aachen</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pischinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute for Internal Combustion Engines (VKA), RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1304</fpage>
         <lpage>1313</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308470"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>By variation of the compression ratio the fuel consumption of high boosted gasoline engines can be reduced, due to operating with higher compression ratios at low load compared to an engine with fixed compression ratio. The two-stage VCR-system enables a high share of fuel saving potential relative to full variable systems.</p>
            <p>Considering a low cost manufacturability and a beneficial integratability into common engine architectures the length-adjustable conrod using an eccentric piston pin in the small eye has proved as the best concept. The adjustment is performed by a combination of gas and mass forces.</p>
            <p>This article describes the design of such a two-stage VCR-system as well as the functional testing under motored and fired engine operating conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger, S.; Yapici, K.I.; Habermann, K.; Baumgarten, H.: Der Weg zum konsequenten Downsizing - Motor mit kontinuierlich variablem Verdichtungs¬verhältnis in einem Demonstrations¬fahrzeug, MTZ 64 05/2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bollig, C.; Habermann, K.; Schwaderlapp, M., Yapici, K. I.: Variable Verdichtung – Ein Weg zur effizienten Hochaufladung, MTZ 62 (2001) 12, S. 984 ff.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergsten, L; Drangel, H.: Der neue SAAB SVC Motor – Ein Zusammenspiel zur Verbrauchsreduzierung von variabler Verdichtung, Hochaufladung und Downsizing, 9. Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik, 4-6.10.2000, Aachen</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Houben, M.; Bick, W.; Thiel, R.; Stöck, H.-P.; Wittek, K.: Umsetzung innovativer Konzepte in die Serie, MTZ 68 10/2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Körfer, Th.; Lamping, M.; Kolbeck, A.: Genz, T. Pischinger, S.; Busch, H.; Adolph, D.: The Potential of Downsizing Diesel Engines - Considering Performance and Emissions Challenges, IMechE, Internal Combustion Engines 11. - 12.12.2007, London</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lamping, M.; Kolbeck, A.: Körfer, Th.; Adolph, D.; Busch, H.; Pischinger, S.: Modernes Dieselbrennverfahren zur Darstellung günstigster Motorrohemissionen bei verbessertem Verbrauchsverhalten, MTZ 1-2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, D.; Dohle, U.; Krüger, M.; Schumacher, H.; Hondros, Ch.: Kaltstart und Kaltlaufuntersuchungen an direkteinspritzenden Pkw- Dieselmotoren, 15. Aachener Kolloquium "Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik" 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rabhi, V.; Dionnet, F.; Beroff, J.: Die MCE-5 Technologie: eine neue technische Möglichkeit des variablen Verdichtungsverhältnis bei SI Motoren, 13. Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergsten, L.; Drangel, H.: Der neue Saab SVC Motor – Ein Zusammenspiel zur Verbrauchsreduzierung von variabler Verdichtung, Hochaufladung und Downsizing, 9. Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wittek, K.: Variables Verdichtungsverhältnis beim Verbrennungsmotor durch Ausnutzung der im Triebwerk wirksamen Kräfte, Dissertation RWTH Aachen, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kreuter, P.: Der aufgeladene Ottomotor mit variabler Verdichtung: Wirkung und Potentiale, 26. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwaderlapp, M.; Pischinger, S.; Yapici, K.I.; Habermann, K.; Bollig, C.: Variable Verdichtung - eine konstruktive Lösung für Downsizing-Konzepte, 10. Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yapici, K.I. Variables Verdichtungsverhältnis beim Verbrennungsmotor durch exzentrische Kurbelwellenverlagerung, Dissertation RWTH Aachen, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
