<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830674</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830681</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>DETERMINANTS OF SMALLHOLDERS' TRANSACTION COST OF PROCURING NON-BANK LOANS IN NIGERIA / LES DÉTERMINANTS DU COÛT DE TRANSACTION DES PRÊTS NON-BANCAIRES POUR LES PETITS EXPLOITANTS AGRICOLES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ade S.</given-names>
                  <surname>Olomola</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1999</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>95</fpage>
         <lpage>108</lpage>
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830681"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In spite of the involvement of non-bank institutions in credit delivery to farmers in Nigeria, access to this financial resource remains highly restricted. One of the major constraints is high transaction costs. This paper examines the structure and determinants of transaction costs of borrowing under farm credit schemes. Administrative expenses constitute the highet proportion of the borrowing transaction costs. And the costs are significantly affected by the size of loan, the borrowers' distance from loan office and loan disbursement lag. The costs are quite high when compared to the situation in rural credit markets in other developing countries. The remedial measures should include the establishment of loan offices within the vicinity of the farmers, minimization of delays in loan processing and disbursement, and employment of adequate and competent staff to enhance the effectiveness of credit operations. Malgré la présence d'institutions non bancaires dans le reseau de distribution du crédit aux exploitants agricoles au Nigeria, l'accès à cette ressource financière reste très limité. Cet article analyse la structure et les déterminants des coûts de transaction des prêts octroyé dans le cadre de deux schémas de crédit à l'agriculture. Les frais administratifs sont la composante majeure des coûts de transaction dans les prêts, mais les coûts sont également influencé de manière significative par la dimension des prêts, la distance de l'empunteur du bureau qui les octroie et le délai de déboursement. Les coûts sont aussi élevés par rapport aux marchés de crédit rural d'autres pays en voie de développement. Pour remédier à cette situation in faudrait, entre autres, établir des bureaux de crédit plus facilement accessibles aux exploitants agricoles, reduire les temps de traitement et de déboursement des prêts et embaucher des fonctionnaires compétents et en nombre suffisant pour améliorer l'efficacité des opérations de crédit.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e126a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e130" publication-type="other">
Adams, D.W. and G.D. Nehman (1979) "Borrowing Costs and the Demand for Rural Credit" The Journal of
Development Studies, 15 (12): 165-176.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e140a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e144" publication-type="other">
Ahmed, Zia U. (1982) "Transaction Costs in Rural Financial Markets in Bangladesh: A Study of a Rural Credit
Market", Ph. D. Dissertation, University of Virginia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e154a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e158" publication-type="other">
Cuevas, Carlos E. (1984) "Intermediation Costs and Scale Economies of Banking Under Financial Regula-
tions in Honduras", Ph. D. Dissertation, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e168a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e172" publication-type="other">
Cuevas, C.E. and D.H. Graham (1986) "Rationing Agricultural Credit in Developing Countries: The Role and
Determinants of Transaction Costs for Borrowers" Proceedings, Nineteenth International Conference of
Agricultural Economists, pp. 680-686.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e186a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e190" publication-type="other">
Gonzales-Vega, C. (1977) "Interest Rate Restrictions and Income Distribution", American Journal of Agricultu-
ral Economics, 59 (5): 973-976.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e200a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e204" publication-type="other">
Inter-American Development Bank, Agricultural Development Bank (BDA) (1983) "Evaluation of Global Agri-
cultural Credit Programmes: Panama", Operation Evaluation Office.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e218" publication-type="other">
Inter-American Development Bank, Banco Agrario del Peru (1983) "Evaluation of Global Agricultural Credit
Programmes: Peru", Operation Evaluation Office.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e228a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e232" publication-type="other">
Inter-American Development Bank, Banco Nacional de Fomento (1983) "Evaluacion de Programas Globales
de Credito Agropecuario: Ecuador", Operation Evaluation Office.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e242a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e246" publication-type="other">
Ladman, J.R. and D.W. Adams (1978) "The Rural Poor and the Recent Performance of Formal Rural Finan-
cial Markets in the Dominican Republic", Canadian Journal of Agricultural Economics, 26 (1).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e260" publication-type="other">
Olomola, A.S. (1990) "Loan Transaction Costs and Repayment Performance of Small-Scale Farmers in Ondo
State, Nigeria", Unpublished Ph. D. Thesis, University of Ibadan, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


