<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186378</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44433816</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Applications of X-Rays in the Automotive Industry</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>George L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Clark</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Robert H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Aborn</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Elmer W.</given-names>
                  <surname>Brugmann</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1927</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>85</fpage>
         <lpage>101</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44433816"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>A RESUME of X-ray science and experimental results regarding practical applications to the examination of automotive materials is presented by the authors, the main divisions of the subject being (a) X-rays; (b) radiography, or industrial diagnosis, being an application of the differential absorption of X-rays by matter; (c) the ultimate structures of materials; (d) metals and alloys, and (e) the constitution and structure of other automotive materials in relation to their practical behavior. The nature and the relationship of X-rays to light, the properties of X-rays which can be utilized practically, and production, including X-ray tubes, are discussed in division (a). The detection of imperfections in castings, the development of improved castingtechnique by X-rays, the substitution of castings for forgings and X-ray examination of rubber tires, valves and the like are treated in division (b). X-rays and crystals are analyzed in division (c) and the information obtainable from X-ray data regarding structural composition includes whether it is crystalline or amorphous; single crystal or aggregate; its crystal lattice-structure and dimensions; purity; chemical identity as to whether compound, mixture, adsorption complex, or solid solution. The data obtainable also apply to grain size, internal strain, uniformity of composition, chemical changes, and the differentiation of good and bad materials. In division (d), the ultimate crystalline structure of the pure metals and the alloys used in the automotive industry, such as brasses, bronzes, steels, alloy highspeed steels, aluminous alloys, and the like, is considered, and the effects of fabrication as determined by X-ray diffraction are discussed in relation to cast metals, to rolled and drawn metals such as hot-rolled and cold-rolled sheets and to heat-treatment and its effect upon preferred orientation of grains, strain and grain size. Some practical studies of commercial automotive metals are cited for cast steel and the X-ray determination of its proper annealing regarding the structure of welds and the comparison of various methods of welding from the viewpoint of X-ray structure, for forming steel such as that suitable for radiator construction and X-ray determination as to whether it is satisfactory or unsatisfactory, for drawing steelwire, and for case-hardened metals and their wearing qualities. Steel suitable for electrical purposes such as the construction of transformers and the relation of ultimate structures to magnetic hysteresis-loss are considered also, as well as the electrodeposited metals and the determination of desired electrodeposition conditions from X-ray structures. The materials discussed in division (e) include rubber; rubber fillers, with particular reference to carbon black; asbestos; the textile fibers such as cotton, flax, ramie, jute, sisal, hemp, rayon, silk, and wool; spark-plug porcelain; lubricants and X-ray indications of the mechanism of lubrication ; and paints, varnishes, waxes, shellacs, and similar substances. In the discussion of the paper, some of the important subjects are the possibilities of X-ray testing of bearings for the purpose of predicting their length of life; the preparation of specimens for X-ray testing; utilization of the fluoroscope for the examination of metals; and the length of time required for obtaining X-ray diagrams of various materials.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d85e351a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e358" publication-type="other">
American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers
Pamphlet No. 1576-C.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e368a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e375" publication-type="other">
Kungl. Svenska Vetenskapsa Handlinger No. 5, 1926;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e381" publication-type="other">
Zeitschrift f端r Anorganische Allgemeine Chemie, vol. 156, p. 27.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e388a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e395" publication-type="other">
Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, vol. 17, p. 1142 ;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e401" publication-type="other">
Tech Engineering News, April, 1926, p. 54 ;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e408a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e415" publication-type="other">
Annalen Physik, vol. 69, p. 59.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e423a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e430" publication-type="other">
Zeitschrift f端r Physik, vol. 24, p. 121.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e437a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e444" publication-type="other">
Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, vol. 17, p. 1142.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e451a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e458" publication-type="other">
Physical Review, vol. 26, p. 390.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e465a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e472" publication-type="other">
Zeitschrift f端r Elektrochemie, vol. 31, p. 655.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e479a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e486" publication-type="other">
Zeitschrift f端r Elektrochemie, vol. 32, p. 295.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e493a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e500" publication-type="other">
Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, vol. 18, p. 1131.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d85e508a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d85e515" publication-type="other">
American Dyestuff Reporter, December, 1926 ;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


