<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275512</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional Gasoline</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dec</surname>
                  <given-names>John E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>750</fpage>
         <lpage>767</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275512"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The potential of boosted HCCI for achieving high loads has been investigated for intake pressures (P<sub>in</sub>) from 100 kPa (naturally aspirated) to 325 kPa absolute. Experiments were conducted in a single-cylinder HCCI research engine (0.98 liters) equipped with a compression-ratio 14 piston at 1200 rpm. The intake charge was fully premixed well upstream of the intake, and the fuel was a research-grade (R+M)/2 = 87-octane gasoline with a composition typical of commercial gasolines.</p>
            <p>Beginning with P<sub>in</sub>= 100 kPa, the intake pressure was systematically increased in steps of 20 - 40 kPa, and for each P<sub>in</sub>, the fueling was incrementally increased up to the knock/stability limit, beyond which slight changes in combustion conditions can lead to strong knocking or misfire. A combination of reduced intake temperature and cooled EGR was used to compensate for the pressure-induced enhancement of autoignition and to provide sufficient combustion-phasing retard to control knock. The maximum attainable load increased progressively with boost from a gross indicated mean effective pressure (IMEP<sub>g</sub>) of about 5 bar for naturally aspirated conditions up to 16.34 bar for P<sub>in</sub>= 325 kPa. For this high-load point, combustion and indicated thermal efficiencies were 99% and 47%, respectively, and NOx emissions were &lt; 0.1 g/kg-fuel. Maximum pressure-rise rates were kept sufficiently low to prevent knock, and the COV of the IMEP<sub>g</sub>was &lt; 1.5%. Central to achieving these results was the ability to retard combustion phasing (CA50) as late as 19° after TDC with good stability under boosted conditions. Detailed examination of the heat release rates shows that this substantial CA50 retard was possible because intake boosting significantly enhances the early autoignition reactions, keeping the charge temperature rising toward the hot-ignition point despite the high rate of expansion at these late crank angles. Overall, the investigation showed that well-controlled boosted HCCI has a strong potential for achieving power levels close to those of turbo-charged diesel engines.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J-O., Tunestål, P., Johansson, B., Fiveland, S., Agama, J. R., and Assanis, D. N., “Compression Ratio Influence on Maximum Load of a Natural Gas-Fueled HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0111, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., Babajimopoulos, A., and Assanis, D., “Comparing Enhanced Natural Thermal Stratification against Retarded Combustion Phasing for Smoothing of HCCI Heat-Release Rates,” SAE Transactions, 113(3), pp. 1557-1575, Paper 2004-01-2994, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Influence of Fuel Autoignition Reactivity on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. of Engines 1(1):39-58, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Comparing Late-cycle Autoignition Stability for Single- and Two-Stage Ignition Fuels in HCCI Engines,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Vol. 31, pp. 2895-2902, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Amnéus, P. and Mauss, F., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 980787, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M. and Johansson, B., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) with Exhaust Gas Recirculation and Pilot Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1835, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J.-O., Tunestål, P., Haroldsson, G. and Johansson, B., “A Turbo-Charged Dual Fuel HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1896, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P. W., Schleyer, C. H., Duffy, K. P., Hardy W. L., and Liechty, M. P. “Effects of Fuel Property Changes on Heavy-Duty HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0191, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G. T., Risberg, P., and Ångström, H.-E., “Partially Pre-Mixed Auto-Ignition of Gasoline to Attain Low Smoke and Low NOx at High Load in a Compression Ignition Engine and Comparison with a Diesel Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper, 2007-01-0006, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Influence of EGR Quality and Unmixedness on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. of Engines, 2(1):492-510, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E., Sjöberg, M., and Hwang, W., “Isolating the Effects of EGR on HCCI Heat-Release Rates and NOx Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):58-70, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., and Hwang, W., “Thermodynamic and Chemical Effects of EGR and Its Constituents on HCCI Autoignition,” SAE Transactions 116(3), SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0207, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Sjöberg, M., “Isolating the Effects of Fuel Chemistry on Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine and the Potential of Fuel Stratification for Ignition Control,” SAE Transactions, 113(4), pp. 239-257, SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0557, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Transactions, 112(3), pp. 1119-1141, SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., and Cernansky, N. P., “The Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, based on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments,” SAE Transactions, 114(3), pp. 236-251, SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0113, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J. A., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “EGR and Intake Boost for Managing HCCI Low-Temperature Heat Release over Wide Ranges of Engine Speed,” SAE Transactions, 116(3), pp. 65-77, SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0051, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., and Hultqvist, A. “The Effect of Piston Topland Geometry on Emissions of Unburned Hydrocarbons from a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1893, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E., Davisson, M. L., Leif, R. N., Sjöberg, M., Hwang, W., “Detailed HCCI Exhaust Speciation and the Sources of Hydrocarbon and Oxygenated Hydrocarbon Emissions,” SAE Int. J. of Fuels and Lubricants, 1(1):50-67, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, W., Dec, J. E., and Sjöberg, M., “Spectroscopic and Chemical-Kinetic Analysis of the Phases of HCCI Autoignition and Combustion for Single- and Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” Combustion and Flame, 154(3), pp. 387-409, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Ethanol Autoignition Characteristics and HCCI Performance for Wide Ranges of Engine Speed, Load and Boost,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 84-106, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0338.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
