<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939378</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Responses to Local Taxation</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Household Mobility and Local Government Finance in U.S. Cities</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Wenjing</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cushing</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Anderson</surname>
                  <given-names>John E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>23</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939378"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In this paper, we examine how household mobility is affected by the choice of local government finance method (taxation vs. debt finance) for U.S. cities. We develop a discrete time dynamic optimization model that implies the optimal strategy for a resident household is to remain in the city during periods of debt finance and move out when future tax liabilities come due. The optimal strategy for households outside the city is to avoid moving into a city that is paying off past debt with high current taxes. To investigate the degree to which tax and debt policy affect household relocation decisions we estimate empirical models of in- and out-migration for a panel dataset of 150 Fiscally Standardized Cities between 2007 and 2012. Results indicate that although both increases in debt finance and taxes are associated with greater out-migration, the tax effects are much stronger. Further, higher current taxes have large negative effects on in-migration whereas debt finance has insignificant effects. The importance of these results is that the equivalence of taxation and debt finance suggested by the Ricardian Equivalence Theorem does not hold for U.S. cities. The observed difference is due to the greater salience of taxes relative to the implied future tax liabilities associated with debt financing. The lack of equivalence follows directly from optimizing behavior with full current information in the presence of household mobility.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Adji, Artidiatun, and James Alm, 2016. “Testing for Ricardian Equivalence in Indonesia.” Journal of Contemporary Economic and Business Issues. 3(1): 5-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Asefa, Sally A., Adams, Roy D., Starleaf, Dennis R., 1981. “Municipal Borrowing: Some Empirical Results.” Public Finance Review, 9(3): 271-280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Barro, Robert J., 1974. “Are Government Bonds Net Wealth?” Journal of Political Economy, 82(6): 1095-1117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bradley, Sebastien J. 2013. “Property Tax Salience and Payment Delinquency.” https://works.bepress.com/sebastien_bradley/3/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Cecchetti, Stephen G., M. S. Mohanty, and Fabrizio Zampolli, 2011. “The Real Effects of Debt.” Bank of International Settlements Working Papers. No. 352.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Checherita-Westphal, Cristina and Philipp Rother, 2012. “The Impact of High Government Debt on Economic Growth and Its Channels: An Empirical Investigation for the Euro Area.” European Economic Review, 56(7): 1392-1405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Chetty, Raj, Adam Looney and Kory Kroft, 2009. “Salience and Taxation: Theory and Evidence.” American Economic Review, 99(4): 1145-1177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Elmendorf, Douglas W. and N. Gregory Mankiw, 1999. “Government Debt.” In (J. B. Taylor &amp; M. Woodford (ed.)) Handbook of Macroeconomics 1, part 3: 1615-1669.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Fox, William F., Henry W. Herzog, Jr, and Alan M. Schlottman, 1989. “Metropolitan Fiscal Structure and Migration.” Journal of Regional Science, 29(4): 523-536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Grassmuech, Georg, 2011. “What Drives Intra-County Migration: The Impact of Local Fiscal Factors on Tiebout Sorting.” The Review of Regional Studies, 41(2, 3): 119-138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Hayo, Bernd, and Florian Neumeier, 2017. “The (In)validity of the Ricardian Equivalence Theorem-Findings from a Representative German Population Survey.” Journal of Macroeconomics. 51: 162-174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Langley, Adam H., 2016. “Methodology Used to Create Fiscally Standardized Cities Database.” Lincoln Institute of Land Policy Working Paper WP16AL1. Cambridge, MA: Lincoln Institute of Land Policy</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Reinhart, Carmen M. and Kenneth S. Rogoff. 2010. “Growth in a Time of Debt.” American Economic Review: Papers &amp; Proceedings, 100(2): 573-578.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Yinger, John, Howard S. Bloom, Axel Börsch-Supan and Helen F. Ladd. 1988. Property Taxes and House Values: The Theory and Estimation of Intrajurisdictional Property Tax Capitalization. Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Wassmer, Robert W. and Ronald C. Fisher. 2011. “State and Local Government Debt, 1992-2008.” State Tax Notes, 61(7): 427-436.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Wellisch, Dietmar, Richter, Wolfram F., 1995. “Internalizing Intergenerational Externalities by Regionalization.” Regional Science and Urban Economics, 25(6): 685-704.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Breusch-Pagan Test Results (In Logs)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>IV Regressions with Fixed-Effects (In Logs)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Breusch-Pagan Test Results (In Levels)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>IV Regressions with Fixed-Effects (In Levels)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Direct Test of the Ricardian Equivalence Theorem</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
