<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">52</volume>
         <issue-id>i40187875</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44468112</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Recent PROGRESS in SYNTHETIC RUBBERS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>P. M.</given-names>
                  <surname>TORRANCE</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1944</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>133</fpage>
         <lpage>136</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44468112"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>THE desire never again to risk the disaster of being cut off from our main source of rubber and the development of "tailor-made" synthetic elastic materials with special characteristics to take care of particular applications much better than natural rubber – these two reasons, Mr.Torrance feels, will assure that after the war synthetic materials will continue to be used in large quantities and will take their rightful place alongside of natural rubber in our economy. Even before the war, use of some of these special-purpose synthetics had been well established. The oil resistance of some synthetics has made them much more satisfactory than natural rubber for many applications where oil is encountered, such as in water pump seals, radiator hose, and fan belts. Continued development of synthetics has led to synthetic tires that are satisfactory when used at reasonable speeds and normal loads on passenger cars and light trucks. Use of rayon and even nylon cord in place of cotton results in greatly improved performance because of the reduction in running temperatures. GR-S inner tubes are reasonably satisfactory, except for the smaller sizes used on drop-center rims, where the high well stretch causes many premature failures. Good progress has been made in synthetic bogie rollers and rubber tank tracks, for the properties of synthetics appear to be very satisfactory in such solid-tire applications.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


