<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284962</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optical Investigations of Soot Formation Mechanisms and Possible Countermeasures on a Turbocharged Port Fuel Injection SI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schueck</surname>
                  <given-names>Claudius</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Bosch Engineering GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Koch</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>KIT Karlsruhe Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Samenfink</surname>
                  <given-names>Wolfgang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Robert Bosch GmbH, Gasoline Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schuenemann</surname>
                  <given-names>Erik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Robert Bosch GmbH, Gasoline Systems</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tafel</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Bosch Engineering GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Towae</surname>
                  <given-names>Oliver</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Bosch Engineering GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>December 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284959</issue-id>
         <fpage>2010</fpage>
         <lpage>2021</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284962"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Despite the known benefits of direct injection (DI) spark ignition (SI) engines, port fuel injection (PFI) remains a highly relevant injection concept, especially for cost-sensitive market segments. Since particulate number (PN) emissions limits can be expected also for PFI SI engines in future emission legislations, it is necessary to understand the soot formation mechanisms and possible countermeasures. Several experimental studies demonstrated an advantage for PFI SI engines in terms of PN emissions compared to DI. In this paper an extended focus on higher engine loads for future test cycles or real driving emissions testing (RDE) is applied. The combination of operating parameter studies and optical analysis by high-speed video endoscopy on a four-cylinder turbocharged SI engine allows for a profound understanding of relevant soot formation mechanisms. For selected operating points, engine operating parameters such as injection timing, inclination of a charge motion flap, and engine coolant temperature were varied. Furthermore, the impact of two different spray layouts on the mixture formation was evaluated. Parameter sets showing significant reduction of PN emissions were subsequently analyzed using high-speed video endoscopy. Optical access to both the intake port as well as the combustion chamber allows visualization of fuel transport mechanisms leading to diffusion flames and soot emissions respectively. In summary, this study shows that port fuel injection at high engine loads can lead to significant PN emissions. Three locations within the combustion chamber could be identified as sources for diffusion flames leading to particulate emissions. The governing parameters allowing substantial reduction of PN emissions at these locations were found to be the injection timing and the charge motion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. EPA, „Light-Duty Automotive Technology, Carbon Dioxide Emissions, and Fuel Economy Trends: 1975 Through 2015. Trends Report,” EPA-420-R-15-016, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch GmbH Robert, „Powertrain Scenarios,” Customer presentation, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kufferath, A., Wiese, W., Samenfink, W., Dageförde, H., et al., „Assessment of feasible system solutions for future particle emission requirements,” Fuel Systems for IC Engines Conference, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., Zheng, R., Shuai, S., Qin, Y. et al., "The Impact of Fuel Properties from Chinese Market on the Particulate and VOCs Emissions of a PFI and a DIG Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0838, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0838.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">European Commission, „Commission Regulation (EU) No. 136/2014,” 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">California Air Resources Board, „Attachment A-1 Final Regulation Order,” California Code of Regulations, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environmental Protection Agency, “Control of Air Pollution From Motor Vehicles: Tier 3 Motor Vehicle Emission and Fuel Standards; Final Rule,” Rules and Regulations 79(81), 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Central Environment Council (Japan), „Future Policy for Motor Vehicle Emission Reduction (Eighth Report),” 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hemminger, S., „Optimierung der Gemischbildung und Verbrennung von Hochleistungsottomotoren zur Einhaltung zukünftiger Emissionsgrenzwerte,” Ph.D. thesis, University of Stuttgart, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, J., Lin, W., Sterniak, J., Xu, M. et al., „Particulate Matter Emission Comparison of Spark Ignition Direct Injection (SIDI) and Port Fuel Injection (PFI) Operation of a Boosted Gasoline Engine,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 136(9):91513-91513, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S., Vaglieco, B., and Di Iorio, S., "Nanoparticles at Internal Combustion Engines Exhaust: Effect on Urban Area," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3006, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chan, T., Meloche, E., Kubsh, J., Rosenblatt, D. et al., "Evaluation of a Gasoline Particulate Filter to Reduce Particle Emissions from a Gasoline Direct Injection Vehicle," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(3):1277-1290, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1727.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S. and Vaglieco, B., „Optical investigations of fuel deposition burning in ported fuel injection (PFI) spark-ignition (SI) engine,” Energy 34(12):2108-2115, 2009, doi:10.1007/s12239-009-0063-8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Xue, J., Johnson, K., Durbin, T. et al., "Determination of Suspended Exhaust PM Mass for Light-Duty Vehicles," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1594, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1594.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S., Sementa, P., Tornatore, C., Carmignani, L. et al., "Fuel Injection Effect on In-cylinder Formation and Exhaust Emission of Particulate from a 4-Stroke Engine for 2-Wheel Vehicles," SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0354, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S., Sementa, P., Tornatore, C. and Vaglieco, B., „Effect of fuel injection strategies on the combustion process in a PFI boosted SI engine,” International Journal of Automotive Technology 10(5):545-553, 2009, doi:10.1007/s12239-009-0063-8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H. and Ladommatos, N., “Optical diagnostics for soot and temperature measurement in diesel engines,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 24(3):221-255, 1998</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stojkovic, B., Fansler, T., Drake, M. and Sick V., “High-speed imaging of OH* and soot temperature and concentration in a stratified-charge direct-injection gasoline engine,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute , 30(2):2657-2665, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2004.08.021</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertsch, M., Koch, T., Velji, A., and Kubach, H., "Thermodynamic and Optical Investigations on Particle Emissions in a DISI Engine at Boosted Operation," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(1):154-170, 2016, doi:10.4271/2015- 01-1888.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horiba, „MEXA-2000SPCS series,” data sheet http://www.horiba. com/fileadmin/uploads/Automotive/Documents/MEXA-2000SPCS_HRE2260C__spec.pdf, accessed Jul. 2016</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
