<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830199</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830202</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>EQUITY FINANCE IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES / LE FINANCEMENT PAR LE CAPITAL DE RISQUE DANS LES PAYS EN VOIE DE DÉVELOPPEMENT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Samuels</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <surname>Theobald</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>337</fpage>
         <lpage>349</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830202"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The paper examines various ways by which the availability of equity finance to firms in developing countries can be improved. The literature on the subject emphasises the difficulty many firms face in obtaining borrowed funds, the need for security and the financial gearing constraint, which means the rate of growth of the firm is limited. The choice, however, is not just between borrowing and straightforward equity. There are various types of risk sharing security that can be offered to investors which can give them some of the advantages of lending but with an equity 'sweetener". These include, not only convertible debentures, but also equity with dividends paid in goods rather than cash, or with the rate of cash dividend tied to movements in, say, commodity price. These forms of financial assets and others are discussed in the paper. To an investor, an equity security becomes more attractive if there is a capital market in which the security can be traded. The paper discusses the possibility of over the counter markets being established in developing countries. These can be in addition to, or instead of, a formal stock exchange. It is appreciated that there are many difficulties in the way of establishing a reasonably efficient market in equity shares in developing countries. Articles appearing at the moment, however, do point to the need for such sources of finance without looking at ways by which to make them available. Cet article analyse comment les entreprises dans les pays en voie de développement peuvent accroître leur disponibilité de capital de risque. La littérature sur le sujet met en evidence d'une part les difficultés que beaucoup d'entreprises rencontrent pour emprunter des fonds et d'autre part le besoin de sécurité et les contraintes de gestion financière des entreprises. A cause de ces facteurs le taux de croissance des entreprises est ainsi mis en danger. Toutefois le choix entre les emprunts et le recours au capital de risque n'est pas net. En effet on possède beaucoup d'instruments financiers qui permettent aux investisseurs de partager convenablement le risque leur donnant les avantages des prêts mais avec des caractéristiques proches aux actions. Ces instruments financiers comprennent non seulement des obligations convertissables mais aussi des actions dont les dividendes sont payés non en monnaie mais en produits ou bien dont les dividendes, payables en monnaie, sont liées par exemple à la variation des prix des produits. Ces differents instruments financiers sont analysés dans l'article. Pour un investisseur, une action est d'autant plus intéressante s'il existe un marché des capitaux dans lequel cet instrument financier peut etre négocié. L'article analyse la possibilité d'établir des marchés hors côte dans les pays en voie de développement. Ces marchés peuvent se développer parallèlement à la bourse ou bien la remplacer. On constate que beaucoup de difficultés se présentent lorsqu'on veut établir un marché actionnaire raisonnablement efficient dans les pays en voie de développement. La plus récente littérature sur l'argument met en evidence la nécessité d'une telle forme de financement aux entreprises mais sans analyser comment ce besoin peut être satisfait dans les conditions présentes des pays en voie de développement.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d22e119a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e123" publication-type="other">
Anderson, D., "Small Industry in Developing Countries: A Discussion of Issues", World Development, Vol 10,
No. 11, 1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e133a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e137" publication-type="other">
Harper, M., Small Business in the Third World, John Wiley, Chichester, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e144a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e148" publication-type="other">
Kitchen, R., "Venture Capital: is it unsuitable for developing countries?", paper presented at the International
Conference on Development Accounting and Finance, University of Birmingham, April 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e158a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e162" publication-type="other">
Nanjundan, S., "Small and Medium Enterprises: Some development issues", Industry and Development, No.
20, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e177" publication-type="other">
Samuels, J., "Inefficient capital markets and their implications" in Derkinderen, F. and Crum, R. (Eds), Risk,
Capital Costs, and Project Financing Decisions, Martjnus Nijhoff, 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e187a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e191" publication-type="other">
Schwartz, E., "The pricing of commodity linked bonds", Journal of Finance, May 1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e202" publication-type="other">
Sundararajan, V., "The Debt-Equity Ratio of firms and the effectiveness of interest rate policy: Analysis with
a dynamic model of saving, investment and growth in Korea", IMF Staff Paper, June 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e212a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e216" publication-type="other">
Timberg, T.A. and C.V. Aiyer, "Informal credit markets in India", Economic Development and Cultural Change,
Vol. 33, No. 1, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


