<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26296363</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>IN TOUCH</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>SPONSOR’S CORNER</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Crain</surname>
                  <given-names>Wm. Forrest</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Wm. Forrest Crain was appointed to the Senior Executive Service in September 2002. Currently, he is the Director of the Center for Army Analysis (CAA), G-8, Department of the Army. As Director, he leads an agency consisting of 147 military officers and civilian employees supporting Headquarters, Department of the Army, and Army Major Commands with analysis addressing Army leadership’s highest priority issues. CAA conducts studies across a wide range of planning and force development issues while focusing on and maintaining special expertise, in theater level operations and Army-wide processes, especially resource allocation. Dr. Crain received a BS degree from the US Military Academy, an MS in systems management from the University of Southern California, and a PhD in decision analysis from George Mason University. He is the recipient of numerous honors and awards, including the Bronze Star, Meritorious Service Medal (Silver Oak Leaf Cluster), and the MORS Clayton J. Thomas Award. He is on the Board of Directors of the Military Operations Research Society and on the Board of Advisors of the Department of Systems Engineering at the US Military Academy.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>March 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>50</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26296346</issue-id>
         <fpage>50</fpage>
         <lpage>53</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2016, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26296363"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
