<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277836</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Vehicular Emissions in Review</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Corning Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1207</fpage>
         <lpage>1227</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277836"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The review paper summarizes major developments in vehicular emissions regulations and technologies in 2013. First, the paper covers the key regulatory developments in the field, including proposed light-duty (LD) criteria pollutant tightening in the US; and in Europe, the continuing developments towards real-world driving emissions (RDE) standards. Significant shifts are occurring in China and India in addressing their severe air quality problems. The paper then gives a brief, high-level overview of key developments in fuels. Projections are that we are in the early stages of oil supply stability, which could stabilize fuel prices. LD and HD (heavy-duty) engine technology continues showing marked improvements in engine efficiency. Key developments are summarized for gasoline and diesel engines to meet both the emerging NOx and GHG regulations. HD engines are or will soon be demonstrating 50% brake thermal efficiency using common approaches. NOx control technologies are then summarized, including SCR (selective catalytic reduction) systems and SCR filter developments. Emphasis is on low-temperature deNOx and integration of components and control. Diesel PM (particulate matter) reduction technologies are evolving around the behavior of ash deposits and SCR integration. Filters for direct injection gasoline applications are developing very rapidly, and in some cases the back pressure, light-off characteristics, and emissions reductions are very similar to standard three way catalysts (TWCs). Oxidation catalysts mainly involve developments towards stubborn problems, like low-temperature performance with exhaust with high hydrocarbon and CO, and methane oxidation. Finally, the paper discusses some key developments in gasoline gaseous emission control, focusing on matching engine calibration with emissions system characteristics; and on lean burn gasoline emissions control.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):699-715, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Control of Air Pollution From Motor Vehicles: Tier 3 Motor Vehicle Emission and Fuel Standards”, Proposed Rules, Federal Register, Vol. 78, No. 98, May 21, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Low-Emission Vehicles (LEV) &amp; GHG 2012, CARB website, http://www.arb.ca.gov/regact/2012/leviiighg2012/leviiighg2012. htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steininger, K., “Completing European Emission Targets with RDE Test Procedures for Light Duty Vehicles”, IQPC International Conference on Real Driving Emissions 2-4 December 2013, Bonn/Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontaras, G., Franco, V., Dilara, P., Martini, G., Manfredi, U., “Development and Review of Euro 5 Passenger Car Emission Factors Based on Experimental Results Over Various Driving Cycles”, Science of the Total Environment 468-469 (2014) 1034- 1042.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deutsche Umwelthilfe (DUH) press release, October 29, 2013. http://www.duh.de/pressemitteilung.html?&amp;no_cache=1&amp;tx_ttnews%5btt_news%5d=3200&amp;cHash=58b125fbc6c5b932d5bbe 17221354dd2</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolke, R., “Die Grossen Herauseforderungen fuer Diesel-Pkw”, 11th FAD Conference “Challenge - Exhaust Aftertreatment for Diesel Engines”, Dresden, November 6-7, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EU PN-PEMS Evaluation Programme - First Report. EU JRC Scientific and Policy Report, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amanatidis, S., Ntziachristos, L., Samaras, Z., Janka, K. et al., “Applicability of the Pegasor Particle Sensor to Measure Particle Number, Mass and PM Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2013- 24-0167, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weiss, M., Bonnel P., Kühlwein J., Provenza, A., et al., “Will Euro 6 Reduce the NOx Emissions of New Diesel Cars? Insights from On-Road Tests with Portable Emissions Measurement Systems (PEMS)”, Atmospheric Environment 62 (2012) 657-665, doi. org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2012.08.056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Op de Beeck, J., “Influence of EURO 6 RDE on SCR System”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seiler, J., “The Development of AdBlue Infrastructure for Passenger Cars”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Presentation at the 13th Hyundai-Kia International Powertrain Conference, October 24-25, 2013, Seoul.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Private communications with Michael Walsh, vehicular emissions policy consultant.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Economic Times, India, January 11, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Troppmann, P., “Non-Road Mobile Machinery Review of Directive 97/68/EC: State of Play &amp; Next Steps”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perujo, A., “PEMS Experiences in the Non-Road Mobile Machinery Sector: Lessons Learnt”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IMO press briefing 18, May 21, 2013 “IMO Marine Environment Protection Committee 65th session pushes forward with energyefficiency implementation Marine Environment Protection Committee (MEPC), 65th session, 13 to 17 May 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hughes, E., “Control of NOx emissions from International Shipping - Regulatory Update,”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“World Energy Outlook 2013”, International Energy Agency, London, November 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BP Statistical Review of World Energy 2013, bp.com/statisticalreview.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Outlook for Energy: A View to 2040, 2013, exxonmobil.com/energyoutlook</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“World Energy Outlook 2012”, International Energy Agency, London, November 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghati, G., “The Outlook for Transport Fuels and GCI (Gasoline Compression Ignition) Engines”, SAE International High- Efficiency Engine Symposium, Apr. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wasinger, P., “Emission Solutions for Large Marine Engines”, 6th Integer Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; Diesel Exhaust Fluid Forum, Oct 2013, Atlanta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BNSF Press Release, “BNSF to Test Liquefied Natural Gas in Road Locomotives”, March 6, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kroeger, C., “Natural Gas (CNG/LNG),” Panel Presentation at SAE International 2013 Commercial Vehicle Engineering Congress, Oct. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horning, D., “Developments in Natural Gas Fueling Infrastructure in North America”, 6th Integer Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; Diesel Exhaust Fluid Forum, Oct 2013, Atlanta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US Energy Information Agency, www.eia.gov</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Exel, G., “Developments in Natural Gas Engine Technologies for Off-Road Applications”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, D. T., Torres, V. M., Thomas, J., Sullivan, D. W., et al., “Measurements of Methane Emissions at Natural Gas Production Sites in the United States”, www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1304880110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kofod, M. and Stephenson, T., “Well-to Wheel Greenhouse Gas Emissions of LNG Used as a Fuel for Long Haul Trucks in a European Scenario,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0110, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greszler, A., “CNG, LNG, DME: Natural Gas Pathways in the North American Heavy-Duty Truck Market,” Panel Presentation at SAE International 2014 Government and Industry Meeting, Jan. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">World Wide Fuel Charter, 5th Edition, September 2013, www. acea.be.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walsh, M. P., “PM2.5: Global Progress in Controlling the Motor Vehicle Contribution”, Frontiers in Environmental Science and Engineering, January 2014, DOI:10.1007/s11783-014-0634-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kampmann, S., “Bosch System Solutions for Gasoline Injection, Transmission and Electrification Bosch”, presentation at Hyundai Kia International Powertrain Conference, October 2013, Seoul.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kemmler, R., Enderle, C., Waltner, A., Vent, G., “The Lean- Combustion Gasoline Engine - A Concept with Global Application”, technical paper at 34th Vienna Motor Symposium, April 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., “Dedicated EGR™: A High Efficiency, Low Emissions Concept for SI Engines,” Panel Presentation at SAE International 2014 High-Efficiency Engine Symposium, Apr. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henry, C., “Dedicated EGR [D-EGR™]: A High Efficiency, Low Emissions Concept for SI Engines”, presentation at Emissions 2013 Conference, June 2013, Ann Arbor.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“PSA to Commercialize SwRI-Developed Dedicated-EGR Technology in High-Efficiency Gasoline Engines by 2018”, article in Green Car Congress, February 4, 2013, www. GreenCarCongress.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seiler, J., “The Development of AdBlue Infrastructure for Passenger Cars”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suresh, A., Langenderfer, D., Arnett, C., and Ruth, M., “Thermodynamic Systems for Tier 2 Bin 2 Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):167-183, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanton, D., “Light Duty Diesel Engine Development to Meet US EPA Tier 2 Bin 2 Emissions and Aggressive Fuel Efficiency Targets”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Freitag, A., presentation at University of Michigan Transportation Research Institute, “Focus on the Future” conference, February 2013, Ann Arbor</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Redon, F., Kalebjian, C., Kessler, J., Rakovec, N. et al., “Meeting Stringent 2025 Emissions and Fuel Efficiency Regulations with an Opposed-Piston, Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1187, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V., Gao, Z., Curran, S. J., Daw, C. S., et al., “Modeling Emissions Controls for RCCI Engines”, presented at Engine Research Center 2013 Symposium, June 2013, University of Wisconsin, Madison</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sellnau, M., Sinnamon, J., Hoyer, K., Kim, J. et al., “Part-Load Operation of Gasoline Direct-Injection Compression Ignition (GDCI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0272, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, J., Kalghatgi, G., Amer, A., Adomeit, P. et al., “Vehicle Demonstration of Naphtha Fuel Achieving Both High Efficiency and Drivability with EURO6 Engine-Out NOx Emission,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(1):101-119, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Theissl, H., Danninger, A., Sacher, T., Ofner, H. et al., “A Study on Operation Fluid Consumption for Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Application using both, EGR and SCR,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1500-1508, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2474.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berger, V., “Application of EASA Part 21 Requirement Regarding Change to Aircraft Type Design by Airbus,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2124, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanton, D., Charlton, S., and Vajapeyazula, P., “Diesel Engine Technologies Enabling Powertrain Optimization to Meet U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1757- 1770, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0094.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koeberlein, D., “Cummins SuperTruck Program Technology and System Level Demonstration of Highly Efficient and Clean, Diesel Powered Class 8 Trucks”, presentation at US Department of Energy Merit Review, May 2013, Washington.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sisken, K., “SuperTruck Program: Engine Project Review Recovery Act - Class 8 Truck Freight Efficiency Improvement Project”, presentation at US Department of Energy Merit Review, May 2013, Washington.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gibble, J., “Volvo SuperTruck Powertrain Technologies for Efficiency Improvement”, presentation at US Department of Energy Merit Review, May 2013, Washington.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ojeda, W. d., “SuperTruck - Development and Demonstration of a Fuel-Efficient Class 8 Tractor &amp; Trailer Engine Systems”, presentation at US Department of Energy Merit Review, May 2013, Washington.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roberts, C., E., “Strategies to Meet Proposed Lower NOx Heavy Duty Engine Standards”, 6th Integer Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; Diesel Exhaust Fluid Forum, Oct 2013, Atlanta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergmann, D., “Developing the Technology Innovation Process for Further Emissions Reduction”, 6th Integer Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; Diesel Exhaust Fluid Forum, Oct 2013, Atlanta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baufeld, T., Mohr, H., Philipp, H., “Future Perspectives and Technical Challenges for Large-Bore Dual Fueled Engines, 8th Dessauer Gasmotoren Konferenz, Dessau-Rosslau, Germany, March 21-22, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Faghani, E., Patychuk, B., McTaggart-Cowan, G., and Rogak, S., “Soot Emission Reduction from Post Injection Strategies in a High Pressure Direct-Injection Natural Gas Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0114, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Wissink, M., DelVescovo, D., and Reitz, R., “RCCI Engine Operation Towards 60% Thermal Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0279, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. P. B., Miles, P. C., Pickett, L. M., “Conceptual Models for Partially Premixed Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion,” Progress in Energy &amp; Combustion Science 39(2):246-283, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yasui, Y., Matsunaga, H., Hashimoto, E., Satoh, N., Hardam, H., Balland, J., Yamada, M., Takahashi, T., “A New Clean Diesel Concept for US LEV-III SULEV - First Report - A New Emission Strategy and Aftertreatment Management Control, presentation at the IAV MinNOx Conference, June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlé, M., “NH3 Sensor for Future HD, MD and LD Diesel Emission Regulations - SCR Control Based on NH3 Sensor”, presentation at 9th International Car Training Institute Conference - SCR Systems, July 2013, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Partridge, W., Pihl, J., Auvray, X., Olsson, L., Kamasamudram, K., Yezerets, A., et al., “Local Ammonia Storage in a Monolithic SCR Catalyst”, presentation at the 9th Catalysts for Automotive Pollution Control (CAPoC) Conference, September 2012, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reith, C., Dornhaus, F., Geisselmann, A., “Systemoptimierung und -Integration von Heavy Duty Abgasnachbehandlungssystemen”, presentation at FAD Diesel Emissions Symposium, November 2013, Dresden.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cox, J., “Fuel Economy and GHG Impacts on Light Duty Emissions Control,” Panel Presentation at SAE International 2013 Fuels, Lubes, and Emissions Symposium, Nov. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Geisselmann, A., “SCR Systems for HDD Applications - Open Potential”, presentation at 9th International Car Training Institute Conference - SCR Systems, July 2013, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>68.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Busch, P., Schaefer-Sindlinger, A., “High-Porosity, High-Cell Density Cordierite Substrates for SCR Applications,” Panel Presentation at SAE International 2013 Fuels, Lubes, and Emissions Symposium, Nov. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>69.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hovda, A., “High Efficiency DEF Mixing for Improved Fuel Economy and CO2 Reduction”, presentation at SAE Fuels, Lubes, and Emissions Symposium, November 2013, Long Beach.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>70.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmeisser, V., Weibel, M., Sebastian Hernando, L., Nova, I. et al., “Cold Start Effect Phenomena over Zeolite SCR Catalysts for Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 6(1):190- 199, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <label>71.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumar, A., Kamasamudram, K., and Yezerets, A., “Hydrocarbon Storage on Small-Pore Cu-Zeolite SCR Catalyst,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):680-687, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <label>72.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V., Pihl, J., Lewis, S., and Parks, J., “Hydrocarbon Fouling of SCR During PCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):947-957, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <label>73.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergmann, D., “Developing the Technology Innovation Process for Further Emissions Reduction”, 6th Integer Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; Diesel Exhaust Fluid Forum, Oct 2013, Atlanta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <label>74.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gabrielsson, P. “Technology Choices for the Future On-Road and Non-Road Emission Standards”, 6th Integer Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; Diesel Exhaust Fluid Forum, Oct 2013, Atlanta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <label>75.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, J., Greuel, J., Ratkos, B., and Schauer, E., “In-Situ Emissions Performance of EPA2010-Compliant On-Highway Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1490- 1499, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2430.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <label>76.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Mulla, S., Weigert, E., Camm, K. et al., “Cold Start Concept (CSC™): A Novel Catalyst for Cold Start Emission Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(2):372-381, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <label>77.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Körfer, T., Wittka, T., Jörg, C., “Advanced, Combined Aftertreatment Systems for Light-Duty Diesel Engines to Meet Emission Regulations”, presentation at Institution of Mechanical Engineers (IMechE) Internal Combustion Engines: Performance, Fuel Economy and Emissions Symposium, November 2013, London</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <label>78.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rose, D., George, S., Warkins, J., Golomb, N., Warren, C., Heibel, A. K., “A New Generation High Porosity DuraTrap® AT for Integration of DeNOx Functionalities”, presentation at 9th International Car Training Institute Conference - SCR Systems, July 2013, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <label>79.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newman, A., “System Requirements and Technologies for High Efficiency and Cost Optimised HDD Aftertreatment Systems”, presentation at 9th International Car Training Institute Conference - SCR Systems, July 2013, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <label>80.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mullem, K. V., “Emission Control Technology for Inland Vessels”, 6th Integer Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; Diesel Exhaust Fluid Forum, Oct 2013, Atlanta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <label>81.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laroo, C., Schenk, C., Sanchez, J., McDonald, J. et al., “Emissions of PCDD/Fs, PCBs, and PAHs from a Modern Diesel Engine Equipped with Selective Catalytic Reduction Filters,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):1311-1339, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1778.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <label>82.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neely, G., “Diesel Cold-start Emission Control Strategy for LEV III,” Panel Presentation at SAE International 2013 Fuels, Lubes, and Emissions Symposium, Nov. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <label>83.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matarresea, R., Castoldia, L., Artiolia, N., Finocchiob, E., Buscab, G., and Liettia, L., “On the Activity and Stability of Pt-K/Al2O3 LNT Catalysts for Diesel Soot and NOx Abatement”, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 144 (2014) 783-791, doi:.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2013.08.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <label>84.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I. A., Blanks, M. G., Merritt, P. M., “CRC Report: ACES Phase 2 of the Advanced Collaborative Emissions Study, November 2013, http://crcao.org/reports/recentstudies2013/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <label>85.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenbaum, D., Khalek, I., McDonald, J., Tennant, C., Shaikh, R., et al., “Advanced Collaborative Emissions Study (ACES)”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Merit Review, May 2013, Washington.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <label>86.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kassel, R., Couch, P., Conolly, M., Hammer-Barulich, A., “Ultrafine Particulate Matter and the Benefits of Reducing Particle Numbers in the United States”, report to the Manufacturers of Emission Controls Association (MECA) prepared by Gladstein, Neandross, and Associates, July 2013, www.MECA.org</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <label>87.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bardasz, E. A., Lubrizol, “Paths to Improved Engine Emission Performance via Evolving Lubricant Technologies”, presentation at Emissions 2013, June 2013, Ann Arbor.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref88">
            <label>88.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kotrba, A., Gardner, T., Bai, L., and Yetkin, A., “Passive Regeneration Response Characteristics of a DPF System,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0520, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref89">
            <label>89.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sappok, A., Govani, I., Kamp, C., Wang, Y. et al., “In-Situ Optical Analysis of Ash Formation and Transport in Diesel Particulate Filters During Active and Passive DPF Regeneration Processes,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(2):336-349, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01- 0519.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref90">
            <label>90.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thiruvengadam, A., Besch, M., Collins, J, Seungju, Y., et al., “Characterization of the Composition and Toxicity of Particulate Matter Emissions from Advanced Heavy-Duty Natural Gas Engines', presentation at 17th ETH Conference on Combustion Generated Nanoparticles”, June 2013, Zurich.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref91">
            <label>91.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tang, W., Youngren, D., SantaMaria, M., and Kumar, S., “On-Engine Investigation of SCR on Filters (SCRoF) for HDD Passive Applications,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):862-872, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref92">
            <label>92.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blakeman, B., “Catalyzed Exhaust Filters: Future Directions”, keynote presentation at US Department of Energy Cross-Cut Lean Exhaust Emissions Reduction Simulations (CLEERS) Workshop, April 2013, Dearborn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref93">
            <label>93.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vonarb, R., “Liebherr Strategy Towards Stage IV and Beyond”, Integer 9th Diesel Emissions Conference &amp; AdBlue Forum, June 2013, Duesseldorf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref94">
            <label>94.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, S., Heibel, A., Henrichsen, M., “Duratrap® AT Partial Filter for China IV Applications”, presentation at Advanced Diesel Emissions Control Conference, June 2013, Beijing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref95">
            <label>95.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, X., Tennison, P., and Ruona, W., “3D Numerical Study of Pressure Loss Characteristics and Filtration Efficiency through a Frontal Unplugged DPF,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):177-193, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref96">
            <label>96.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harth, K., Wassermann, K., Siemund, S., Siani, A., et al., “Catalyzed Gasoline Particulate Filters: Integrated Solutions for Stringent Emission Control”, Technical Paper at Vienna Motorsymposium, April 2013, Vienna.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref97">
            <label>97.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenwell, D., Optimisation of Three Way Filter (TWFTM) Coatings and Systems for Euro 6, IQPC Advanced Emission Control Concepts for Gasoline Engines, May 2013, Bonn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref98">
            <label>98.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitz, T., Siemund, S., Siani, A., Neubauer, T., and Wassermann, K., “Four-Way-Conversion Catalysts (FWCTM) in Gasoline Applications: Integrated Solutions for Stringent Emission Control”, presentation at 13th Hyundai-Kia International Powertrain Conference, October 2013, Seoul.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref99">
            <label>99.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rose, D., Boger, T., Ingram-Ogunwumi, R., Bischof, C., et al., “Advanced Filter Technologies to Reduce Particulate Emissions of GDI Engines Implications on Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment Systems and Functionalities”, 22nd Aachen Colloquium on Automobile and Engine Technology, October 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref100">
            <label>100.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran, S., Hanson, R., Wagner, R., and Reitz, R., “Efficiency and Emissions Mapping of RCCI in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0289, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01- 0289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref101">
            <label>101.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V., Curran, S., Parks, J., and Wagner, R., “Diesel Oxidation Catalyst Control of PM, CO, and HC from Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Combustion” presentation at US Department of Energy Cross-Cut Lean Exhaust Emissions Reduction Simulations (CLEERS) Workshop, April 2013, Dearborn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref102">
            <label>102.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toops, T. J., Parks, J. E., Bauer, J. C., “Low Temperature Emissions Control”, presentation at Department of Energy Annual Merit Review, May 2013, Washington.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref103">
            <label>103.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parks, J., “Emission Control Challenges for Advanced Combustion Approaches,” Panel Presentation at SAE International 2013 Fuels, Lubricants, and Emissions Symposium, Nov. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref104">
            <label>104.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guliaeff, A., Wanninger, K., Klose, F., Maletz, G. et al., “Development of a Sulfur Tolerant PGM Based Zeolite Catalyst for Methane Oxidation and Low Temperature Hydrocarbon Trapping,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0531, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref105">
            <label>105.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kinnunen, N., Kinnunen, T., and Kallinen, K., “Improved Sulfur Resistance of Noble Metal Catalyst for Lean-Burn Natural Gas Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0155, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref106">
            <label>106.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, J., Kim, E., Han, J., and Han, H., “Pt/Pd Bimetallic Catalyst with Improved Activity and Durability for Lean-Burn CNG Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(3):651-656, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2591.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref107">
            <label>107.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blakeman, P., “Emission Control Challenges Associated with Increasingly Lower Exhaust Temperatures from Advanced Combustion Engines”, panel presentation at US Department of Energy Cross-Cut Lean Exhaust Emissions Reduction Simulations (CLEERS) Workshop, April 2013, Dearborn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref108">
            <label>108.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ball, D., Negohosian, C., Ross, D., Moser, D. et al., “Comparison of Cold Start Calibrations, Vehicle Hardware and Catalyst Architecture of 4-Cylinder Turbocharged Vehicles,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(4):1922-1933, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2593.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref109">
            <label>109.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ball, D., Moser, D., Yang, Y., and Lewis, D., “N2O Emissions of Low Emission Vehicles,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(2):450-456, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref110">
            <label>110.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Philipp, S., Hoyer, R., Adam, F., Eckhoff, S. et al., “Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment for Lean Gasoline Direct Injection Engines - Potential for Future Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01- 1299, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1299.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
