<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830179</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830185</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>SOME EVIDENCE ON DEMAND FOR MONEY IN NIGERIA: A TEST OF MCKINNON MODEL OF DEMAND FOR MONEY IN DEVELOPING ECONOMIES / LA FONCTION DE DEMANDE DE MONNAIE AU NIGÉRIA: RÉSULTATS EMPIRIQUES CONCERNANT LE MODÈLE DE MCKINNON SUR LA DEMANDE DE MONNAIE DANS LES PAYS EN VOIE DE DÉVELOPPEMENT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Joshua O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Ajewole</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>183</fpage>
         <lpage>198</lpage>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830185"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper examines the relevance and workability of the McKinnon Model for money demand in Nigeria and the implications for monetary policy administration. The results reported show that there exists significant conduit effects between money assets and other physical assets in the Nigerian economy. Specifically, the paper shows that the real demand for money in Nigeria is considerably influenced by real income and return on physical assets. It avers that the broad definition of money performs much better than the narrow definition in the specification of money demand function (in the Nigerian context). The paper also finds that there is no significant difference in real money demand when expected and current (actual) income are used, and interest rate does not significantly influence money demand in Nigeria, even though it is correctly signed. Based on these findings, this paper concludes that the McKinnon Model is relevant and very much workable in the Nigerian economy. Cet article examine l'importance théorique et pratique du modèle de McKinnon dans l'explication de la demande de monnaie au Nigéria et les conséquences pour sa politique monétaire. Les résultats empiriques qui en découlent montrent qu'entre les actifs monétaires et les actifs réels il existe d'importants effets de liaison dans l'économie nigérienne. Plus particulièrement, l'article montre que la demande réelle de monnaie au Nigéria est influencée de façon considérable par le revenu réel et par le taux de rendement des actifs réels. On a pu démontrer encore que dans la spécification de la fonction de la demande de monnaie, il est préférable d'utiliser la notion élargie de monnaie plutôt que la notion plus étroite. Enfin, de l'analyse découle que 1) les résultats concernant la demande réelle de monnaie ne changent pas si on utilise le revenu attendu ou le revenu effectif et que 2) le taux d'intérêt n'influence pas de façon significative la demande de monnaie au Nigéria même si le taux d'intérêt et la demande de monnaie varient selon les prévisions. Se basant sur ces conclusions, l'article peut affirmer que le modèle de McKinnon est important et applicable dans le contexte de l'économie du Nigéria.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d36e117a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e124" publication-type="other">
William H. Branson, Macroeconomics and Policy - pp. 243 - 252.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e131a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e138" publication-type="other">
S. I. Ajayi, (1977), American Economist (Spring) - pp. 51 - 54.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e145a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e152" publication-type="other">
Ronald I. McKinnon, Money and Capital in Economic Development (The Brookings Institution) (1973),
pp. 42-50.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e162a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e169" publication-type="other">
Ibid., pp. 50-51.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e177a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e184" publication-type="other">
Thad W. Mirer, Economic Statistics and Econometrics - pp. 297-298.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e200a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e207" publication-type="other">
Ajayi S.I., (1977), «Some Empirical Evidence on the Demand for Money in Nigeria*, American Economist,
(Spring) pp 51 - 54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e217a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e224" publication-type="other">
Branson W.H., (1979), Macroeconomic Theory and Policy, 2nd Edition (Harper and Row Publishers)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e231a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e238" publication-type="other">
Kmenta, (January 1971), Elements of Econometrics, (Macmillan Publishing Company Inc.)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e245a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e252" publication-type="other">
McKinnon, R. I., (1973), Money and Capital in Economic Development (The Brookings Institution)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e260a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e267" publication-type="other">
Mirer, W. Thad, (1983), Economic Statistics and Econometrics (Macmillan Publishing Co., Inc.).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


