<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277915</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Comparison Between External and Internal Resonators Employment to Reduce the Gas-Dynamic Noise of a SI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siano</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniela</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bozza</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Naples - Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Teodosio</surname>
                  <given-names>Luigi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Naples Federico II</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Bellis</surname>
                  <given-names>Vincenzo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Naples Federico II</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>January 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277910</issue-id>
         <fpage>42</fpage>
         <lpage>52</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277915"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper reports 1D and 3D CFD analyses aiming to improve the gas-dynamic noise emission of a downsized turbocharged VVA engine through the re-design of the intake air-box device, consisting in the introduction of external or internal resonators.</p>
            <p>Nowadays, modern spark-ignition (SI) engines show more and more complex architectures that, while improving the brake specific fuel consumption (BSFC), may be responsible for the increased noise radiation at the engine intake mouth. In particular VVA systems allow for the actuation of advanced valve strategies that provide a reduction in the BSFC at part load operations thanks to the intake line de-throttling. In these conditions, due to a less effective attenuation of the pressure waves that travel along the intake system, VVA engines produce higher gas-dynamic noise levels. The worsening of the engine gas-dynamic performance can be compensated with a partial re-design of the air-box device, without significantly penalizing the engine power output. In order to find new design configurations of the air-box device capable of improving the noise levels, different numerical models can be successfully employed.</p>
            <p>In the present work, a detailed 1D engine model is firstly developed and validated against the experimental data at full load operations. 1D model is realized within GT-Power™ software and it utilizes proper user routines for the modeling of the turbulence and combustion process and for the handling of different intake valve strategies. The 1D engine model also includes a refined user model of the turbocharger able to better describe the acoustic behavior of the device.</p>
            <p>The engine model allows for the prediction of the main overall engine performances and the gas-dynamic noise with good accuracy. It also provides a first estimation of the gas-dynamic noise and gives reliable boundary conditions for the subsequent unsteady 3D CFD analyses, allowing to obtain a more accurate noise prediction.</p>
            <p>A proper Helmholtz resonator is designed and virtually installed along the inlet pipe of the air-box device. An additional geometrical configuration of the air-filter box, that includes an internal resonator, obtained through the insertion of inner walls, is considered, too. The effectiveness of the redesigned air-box configurations, are firstly tested in terms of Transmission Loss characteristics, and in terms of gasdynamic noise abatement, as well.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J., Lee, C., and Nitkiewicz, J., “The Application of a Lost Motion VVT System to a DOHC SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 950816, 1995, doi:10.4271/950816.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatano, K., Iida, K., Higashi, H., and Murata, S., “Development of a New Multi-Mode Variable Valve Timing Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 930878, 1993, doi:10.4271/930878.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wirth M., Schulte H., “Downsizing and Stratified Operation - an Attractive Combination Based on a Spray-guided Combustion System”, ICAT 2006 International Conference on Automotive Technologies Instanbul, November 17, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraser, N., Blaxill, H., Lumsden, G., and Bassett, M., “Challenges for Increased Efficiency through Gasoline Engine Downsizing,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):991-1008, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01- 1053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza, F., De Bellis, V., Marelli, S., and Capobianco, M., “1D Simulation and Experimental Analysis of a Turbocharger Compressor for Automotive Engines under Unsteady Flow Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1365-1384, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Bellis, V., Bozza, F., Siano, D., and Gimelli, A., “Fuel Consumption Optimization and Noise Reduction in a Spark- Ignition Turbocharged VVA Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):1262-1274, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1625.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GT-Power V.7.3, User's Manual, Gamma Tech. Inc., 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ansys V14, User's Manual, Ansys Inc. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza, F., Gimelli, A., Siano, D., Torella, E. et al., “A Quasi- Dimensional Three-Zone Model for Performance and Combustion Noise Evaluation of a Twin-Spark High-EGR Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0619, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0619.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Bellis, V., Severi, E., Fontanesi, S., Bozza, F., “Hierarchical 1D/3D approach for the development of a turbulent combustion model applied to a VVA turbochargerd engine. Part II: combustion model”, Energy Procedia 45, (2014), 1027-1036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Bellis, V., Severi, E., Fontanesi, S., Bozza, F., “Hierarchical 1D/3D approach for the development of a turbulent combustion model applied to a VVA turbochargerd engine. Part I: turbulence model”, Energy Procedia 45, (2014), 829-838.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano, D., Corcione, F., Bozza, F., Gimelli, A. et al., “Characterization of the Noise Emitted by a Single Cylinder Diesel Engine: Experimental Activities and 1D Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2483, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza, F., Gimelli, A., Piazzesi, R., Fortunato, F. et al., “The Prediction of the Performance and Gasdynamic Noise Emitted by a Medium-Size Spark-Ignition Engine by Means of 1D and 3D Analyses,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0380, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano D., Bozza F., Auriemma F., “Acoustic and fluiddynamic optimization of an automotive muffler”, Proc. of Inst. Mech. Eng., Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, published online December 10th 2012, doi:10.1177/0954407012465689.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano, D., Auriemma PhD, F., and Bozza, F., “Pros and Cons of Using Different Numerical Techniques for Transmission Loss Evaluation of a Small Engine Muffler,” SAE Technical Paper 2010- 32-0028, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano, D., Teodosio, L., De Bellis, V., and Bozza, F., “Analysis and Design of an Intake Filter Box for a Downsized VVA Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1693, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1693.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa, A. J., Broatch, A., Climent, H., &amp; Fernández, T.. “Timedomain modelling of turbo-compressors in direct injection diesel engines”, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 220(4), 445-457, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rämmal, H. Galindo, J., “The passive acoustic effect of turbocompressors”, 9th International Conference on Turbochargers and Turbocharging. (Toim.) Institution of Mechanical Engineers. London, UK, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Veloso, R., Elnemr, Y., Reich, F., and Allam, S., “Simulation of Sound Transmission through Automotive Turbochargers,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1560, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1560.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa, A., Arnau, F., Piqueras, P., Reyes-Belmonte, M. et al., “Acoustic One-Dimensional Compressor Model for Integration in a Gas-Dynamic Code,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0834, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Bellis V., Bozza F., Bevilacqua M., Bonamassa G., Schernus C., “Validation of a 1D Compressor Model for Performance Prediction”, SAE International Journal of Engines 6 (3), pp. 1786- 1800, 2013, DOI:10.4271/2013-24-0120, ISSN: 19463936.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza F., DeBellis V., “Steady modeling of a turbocharger turbine for automotive engines”, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 136 (1), art. no. 011701, 2014, doi:10.1115/1.4025263, ISSN: 07424795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rämmal, H., Åbom, M., Tiikoja, H., and Bodén, H., “Experimental Facility for the Complete Determination of Sound Transmission in Turbochargers,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1424, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
