<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277716</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Consequence Analysis in Predictive Health Monitoring of Automotive Diesel Engine Defects</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Abouel-Seoud</surname>
                  <given-names>Shawki</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Khalil</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohamed</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Metwalley</surname>
                  <given-names>Sameh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Allam</surname>
                  <given-names>Essam</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Assad</surname>
                  <given-names>Hany</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Helwan Univ</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>September 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277710</issue-id>
         <fpage>1521</fpage>
         <lpage>1531</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277716"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Reliability has always been an important aspect in the assessment of industrial products and/or equipments. Good product design is of course essential for products with high reliability. However, no matter how good the product design is, products deteriorate over time since they are operating under certain stress or load in the real environment, often involving randomness. Maintenance has, thus, been introduced as an efficient way to assure a satisfactory level of reliability during the useful life of a physical asset. The earliest maintenance technique is basically breakdown maintenance (also called unplanned maintenance, or run-to-failure maintenance), which takes place only at breakdowns. A later maintenance technique is time-based preventive maintenance (also called planned maintenance), which sets a periodic interval to perform preventive maintenance regardless of the health status of a physical asset. The vehicle component is judged to be safe depending on its reliability. Consequently, there is a general attention to establish approach by which the failure risk has to be known. To achieve this objective, the present work introduces an approach to establish the vehicle engine risk assessment using the excess air escaped inside the engine crankcase. The results indicate that the excess scalped air mass flow rate corresponding to the failure rate values computed based on the Weibull distribution with assured reliability can be considered to be guide for maintenance regime.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS:</label>
            <kwd>Diagnostic</kwd>
            <kwd>reliability</kwd>
            <kwd>hazard rate</kwd>
            <kwd>prognostic</kwd>
            <kwd>failure</kwd>
            <kwd>Weibull distribution</kwd>
            <kwd>deterioration</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jardine, K.S., Lin, D. B. and Banjevic, D. “A review on machinery diagnostics and prognostics implementing condition-based maintenance” Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 20, pp. 1483-1510, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davies, C. and Greenough, R.M. “The use of information systems in fault diagnosis” Proceedings of the 16th National Conference on Manufacturing Research, University of East London, UK, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, R. and Kwan, C. “Robust isolation of sensor failures” Asian Journal of Control 5, pp. 12-23, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, W.J. and McFadden, P.D. “Early detection of gear failure by vibration analysis II. Interpretation of the time frequency distribution using image processing techniques” Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 7, pp. 205-215, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell, J.E., Thompson, B.M. and Swiler, L.P. “Consequence analysis in predictive health monitoring systems” Proceedings of Probabilistic Safety Assessment and Management, Vols. I and II, Amsterdam, pp. 1353-1358, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Castanier, B., Berenguer, C. and Grall, A. “A sequential condition-based repair/replacement policy with non-periodic inspections for a system subject to continuous wear” Applied Stochastic Models in Business and Industry 19, pp. 327-347, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrar, C.R., Hemez, F., Park, G., Robertson, A.N., Sohn, H. and Williams, T.O. “A coupled approach to developing damage prognosis Solutions” Damage Assessment of Structures-The Fifth International Conference on Damage Assessment of Structures (DAMAS 2003), Southampton, UK, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yan, J., Koc, M. and Lee, J. “A prognostic algorithm for machine performance assessment and it's application” Production, Planning and Control 15, pp. 796-801, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Phelps, E., Willett, P. and Kirubarajan, T. “A statistical approach to prognostics, in: Component and Systems Diagnostics” Prognosis and Health Management, Vol. 4389, Bellingham, pp. 23-34, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vlok, P.-J., Wnek, M. and Zygmunt, M. “Utilizing statistical residual life estimates of bearings to quantify the influence of preventive maintenance actions, Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 18, pp. 833-847, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahmed, I., Khalil, M., Allam, E., and Abouel-Seoud, S., “Remaining lifetime Evaluation for Crankshaft Main Bearings,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1654, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1654.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saad, A., “Predicting Remaining Lifetime of Transmission Gears,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0903, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0903.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lugtigheid, D., Banjevic, D. A. K and Jardine, S. “Modeling repairable system reliability with explanatory variables and repair and maintenance actions” IMA Journal Management Mathematics 15, pp. 89-110, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, D., Wiseman, M., Banjevic, D. and Jardine, A. K. S. “An approach to signal processing and condition-based maintenance for gearboxes subject to tooth failure” Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 18, pp. 993-1007, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heng, A., Zhang, S., Tan, A.C.C. and Mathew, J. “Rotating machinery prognostics: State of the art, challenges and opportunities” Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 23, pp. 724-739, 2009.ref&gt;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
