<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i23018100</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23018116</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>State Spending on Higher Education: Testing the Balance Wheel over Time</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jennifer A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Delaney</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>William R.</given-names>
                  <surname>Doyle</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>343</fpage>
         <lpage>368</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2010 Board of Trustees of the University of Illinois Manufactured in the United States of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23018116"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This article considers the role of higher education in state budgets. It empirically models and tests the balance wheel hypothesis in a robust framework. The balance wheel model posits that in good economic times, higher education is an attractive area for states to fund and tends to be funded at a higher rate than other state budget categories. In bad economic times, the reverse is true. Higher education is often one of the first state budget categories to be cut, and it is cut more than other state budget categories due in part to its ability to raise outside revenue by charging tuition. This article expands upon previous work on the non-linear balance wheel model by including extensive controls for the economic, political, and higher education characteristics of each state. It finds evidence, robust to alternative specifications, of the balance wheel model over the time period from 1985—2004.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e208a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e212" publication-type="other">
Adams, W. 1977. Financing public higher education. The American Economic Review 67 (1): 86-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e219a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e223" publication-type="other">
Alesina, A. 1987. Macroeconomic policy in a two-party system as a repeated game. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 102: 651-678.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e233a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e237" publication-type="other">
Alesina, A. 1988. Macroeconomics and politics. In NBER Macroeconomics Annual 1988, ed. S.
Fischer, 13-62. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e247a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e251" publication-type="other">
Betts, J. R., and L. L. McFarland. 1995. Safe port in a storm: The impact of labor market conditions
on community college enrollments. The Journal of Human Resources 30 (4): 741-765.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e262a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e266" publication-type="other">
Boylan, R. T. 2010. States' responses to fiscal droughts and riches. Working paper, Rice University
Department of Economics, Social Science Research Network. Version July 16, 2010. http://
ssrn.com/abstract=1641360</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e279a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e283" publication-type="other">
Clotfelter, C. 1976. Public spending for higher education: An empirical test of two hypotheses.
Public Finance 31(2): 177-195.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e297" publication-type="other">
Drazen, A. 2001. The political business cycle after 25 years. In NBER Macroeconomics Annual
2000, ed. B. Bernanke and K. Rogoff, 75-138. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e307a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e311" publication-type="other">
Delaney, J. A., and W. R. Doyle. 2007. The role of higher education in state budgets. In State
postsecondary education research: New methods to inform policy and practice, ed. K. M. Shaw
and D. E. Heller, 55-76. Sterling, VA: Stylus Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e324a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e328" publication-type="other">
Greene, W. H. 2003. Econometric analysis. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e339" publication-type="other">
Hovey, H. A. 1999. State spending for higher education in the next decade: The battle to sustain
current support. San Jose, CA: National Center for Public Policy and Higher Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e354" publication-type="other">
Humphreys, B. R. 2000. Do business cycles affect state appropriations to higher education?
Southern Economic Journal 67 (2): 398-413.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e368" publication-type="other">
Kane, T. J., P. R. Orszag, and D. L. Gunter. 2003. State fiscal constraints and higher education
spending: The role of Medicaid and the business cycle. Washington, DC: Brookings Institution.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e382" publication-type="other">
Leslie, L. L., and G. Ramey. 1986. State appropriations and enrollments: Does enrollment growth
still pay? The Journal of Higher Education 57 (1): 1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e392a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e396" publication-type="other">
National Bureau of Economic Research (September 20, 2010). Business Cycle Dating Committee
announcement, http://www.nber.org/cycles/sept2010.pdf (accessed December 7, 2010).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e406a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e410" publication-type="other">
Nordhaus, W. 1975. The political business cycle. Review of Economic Studies 42:169-190.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e417a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e421" publication-type="other">
Okunade, A. A. 2001. What factors influence state appropriations for public higher education in
the United States? Journal of Education Finance 30 (2): 123-138.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e436" publication-type="other">
McLendon, M. K., and J. C. Hearn. 2007. Incorporating political indicators into comparative state
study of higher education policy. In State postsecondary education research: New methods
to inform policy and practice, ed. K. M. Shaw and D. E. Heller, 11-36. Sterling, VA: Stylus
Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e452a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e456" publication-type="other">
McLendon M. K., J. C. Hearn, and C. G. Mokher. 2009. Partisans, professionals, and power: The
role of political factors in state higher education funding. The Journal of Higher Education 80
(6): 686-713.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e469a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e473" publication-type="other">
Oates, W. E. 1972. Fiscal federalism. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e480a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e484" publication-type="other">
Peterson, R. G. 1976. Environmental and political determinants of state higher education
appropriations policies. The Journal of Higher Education 47 (5): 523-542.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e494a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e498" publication-type="other">
Rizzo, M. J. 2003. A (less than) zero sum game? State funding for public education: How public higher
education institutions have lost. Doctoral Dissertation, Cornell University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e508a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e512" publication-type="other">
Strathman, J. G. 1994. Migration, benefit spillovers and state support of higher education. Urban
Studies 31 (6): 913-920.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e523a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e527" publication-type="other">
Toutkoushian, R. K., and P. Hollis. 1998. Using panel data to examine legislative demand for higher
education. Education Economics 6 (2): 141-157.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e537a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e541" publication-type="other">
Willis, B. (August 1, 2009). U.S. recession worst since Great Depression, revised data show.
Bloomberg http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=newsarchive&amp;sid=aNivTjr852TI
(accessed December 7, 2010).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e558" publication-type="other">
Wooldridge, J. M. 2006. Introductory econometrics: A modern approach. Mason, OH: Thomson
Southwestern.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e568a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e572" publication-type="other">
Wooldridge, J. M. 2001. Econometric analysis of cross-section and panel data. Cambridge, MA:
MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


