<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275484</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comparison of Different Boosting Strategies for Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engines - A Modeling Study</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mamalis</surname>
                  <given-names>Sotirios</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nair</surname>
                  <given-names>Vishnu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andruskiewicz</surname>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Assanis</surname>
                  <given-names>Dennis</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Babajimopoulos</surname>
                  <given-names>Aristotelis</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wermuth</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicole</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>GM Research and Development</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Najt</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>GM Research and Development</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>296</fpage>
         <lpage>308</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275484"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Boosted Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) has been modeled and has demonstrated the potential to extend the engine's upper load limit. A commercially available engine simulation software (GT-Power®) coupled to the University of Michigan HCCI combustion and heat transfer correlations was used to model a 4-cylinder boosted HCCI engine with three different boosting configurations: turbocharging, supercharging and series turbocharging. The scope of this study is to identify the best boosting approach in order to extend the HCCI engine's operating range. The results of this study are consistent with the literature: Boosting helps increase the HCCI upper load limit, but matching of turbochargers is a problem. In addition, the low exhaust gas enthalpy resulting from HCCI combustion leads to high pressures in the exhaust manifold increasing pumping work. The series turbocharging strategy appears to provide the largest load range extension. Single turbocharging is the most efficient but is limited by increased mass flow rates at increased engine speeds. Supercharging helps avoid the backpressure problem but the mechanical work of the supercharger reduces useful work affecting overall brake efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onishi, S., Hong Jo, S. Shoda, K., Do Jo, P., and Kato, S., “Active Thermo-Atmosphere Combustion (ATAC) - A New Combustion Process for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 790501, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noguchi, M., Tanaka, Y., Tanaka, T., and Takeuchi, Y., “A Study on Gasoline Engine Combustion by Observation of Intermediate Reactive Products During Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 790840, 1979</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najt P. M. and Foster D. E., “Compression Ignited Homogeneous Charge Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 830264, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thring R. H., “Homogeneous-Charge Compression- Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 892068, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishibashi, Y. and Asai, M., “Improving the Exhaust Emissions of Two-Stroke Engines by Applying the Activated Radical Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 960742, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milovanovic N., Chen R. and Turner J., “Influence of the Variable Valve Timing Strategy on the Control of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, P.A., Song, H.H., Kaahaaina, N.B. and Edwards, C.F., “Residual-effected homogeneous charge compression ignition with delayed intake-valve closing at elevated compression ratio,” Int. J. Engine Res. 2005 Vol.6, No.4, p. 399-219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuo T.-W., 2006, “Valve and Fueling Strategy for Operating a Controlled Auto-Ignition Combustion Engine”, SAE 2006 HCCI Symposium, September 25-26, 2006, San Ramon, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Challa, V.S.S.P., Lavoie, G.A., and Assanis, D.N., “Model-Based Assessment of Two Variable Cam Timing Strategies for HCCI Engines: Recompression vs. Rebreathing,” Proceedings of the ASME Internal Combustion Engine Division 2009 Spring Technical Conference, ICES2009-76103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Lavoie, G.A. and Assanis, D.N., “Modeling HCCI Combustion with High Levels of Residual Gas Fraction - A Comparison of Two VVA Strategies,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3220, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., “EGR and Intake Boost for Managing HCCI Low-Temperature Heat Release over Wide Ranges of Engine Speed,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0051, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Silke, E., Pitz, W., Westbrook, C., Sjoberg, M., and Dec, J., “Understanding the Chemical Effects of Increased Boost Pressure under HCCI Conditions”, SAE Int J. of Fuels &amp; Lubes 1(1):12-25, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Amneus, P., and Mauss, F., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 980787, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J., Tunestal, P., Haraldsson, G., and Johansson, B., “A Turbo Charged Dual Fuel HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1896, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., “Boosting for High Load HCCI”, SAE Paper 2004-01-0940</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hyvonen, J., Haraldsson, G. and Johansson, B., “Supercharging HCCI to Extend the Operating Range in a Multi-Cylinder VCR-HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3214, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yap, D., Wyszynski, M., Megaritis, A., Xu, H., “Applying Boosting to Gasoline HCCI Operation with Residual Trapping,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2121, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yap, D., Wyszynski, M., Megaritis, A., Xu, H., “Effect of Inlet Valve Timing on Boosted Gasoline HCCI with Residual Gas Trapping,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2136, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A. and Blaxill, H., “Lean Boost and External Exhaust Gas Recirculation for High Load Controlled Auto- Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3744, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilhelmsson, C., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., “Operation Strategy of a Dual Fuel HCCI Engine with VGT,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1855, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, M., Liu, H., Zhang, B. and Zheng, Z., “The Influence of Boost Pressure and Fuel Chemistry on Combustion and Performance of a HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0051, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martins, M. and Zhao, H., “4-Stroke Multi-Cylinder Gasoline Engine with Controlled Auto-Ignition (CAI) Combustion: A Comparison Between Naturally Aspirated and Turbocharged Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-36-0305, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies, Inc., http://www.gtisoft.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A. Lavoie, G.A., Mo, Y., and Assanis D.N., “A CFD-Based Combustion Correlation for HCCI Engine System Level Modeling,” in preparation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J. A., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., 1988, Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill Inc., Singapore.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
