<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308463</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Influence of Diesel Injection Parameters on End-of-Injection Liquid Length Recession</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kook</surname>
                  <given-names>Sanghoon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Musculus</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark P.B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1194</fpage>
         <lpage>1210</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308463"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Diesel injection parameters effect on liquid-phase diesel spray penetration after the end-of-injection (EOI) is investigated in a constant-volume chamber over a range of ambient and injector conditions typical of a diesel engine. Our past work showed that the maximum liquid penetration length of a diesel spray may recede towards the injector after EOI at some conditions. Analysis employing a transient jet entrainment model showed that increased fuel-ambient mixing occurs during the fuel-injection-rate ramp-down as increased ambient-entrainment rates progress downstream (<italic>i.e.</italic>the entrainment wave), permitting complete fuel vaporization at distances closer to the injector than the quasi-steady liquid length.</p>
            <p>To clarify the liquid-length recession process, in this study we report Mie-scatter imaging results near EOI over a range of injection pressure, nozzle size, fuel type, and rate-of-injection shape. We then use a transient jet entrainment model for detailed analysis. Results show that an increased injection pressure correlates well with increasing liquid length recession due to an increased entrainment wave speed. Likewise, an increased nozzle size, with higher jet momentum and faster entrainment wave, enhances the liquid length recession. A low-density, high-volatility fuel does not decrease the strength of the entrainment wave; however, it decreases the steady liquid length causing the entrainment wave to reach the liquid spray tip earlier, which ultimately results in faster liquid length recession. A slow ramp down in injection rate causes a weaker entrainment wave so that the liquid length recession occurs even prior to injector close.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Iwabuchi, Y., Kawai, K., Shoji, T., and Takeda, Y. (1999). Trial of New Concept Diesel Combustion System – Premixed Compression-Ignition Combustion, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 108(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasegawa, R. and Yanagihara, H. (2003). HCCI combustion in DI diesel engine, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 112(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y., and Aiyoshizawa, E. (2001). Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low-Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards, SAE Transactions: Journal of Fuels and Lubricants, 110(4).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S. and Dean, A.M. (2001). Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel combustion by Reducing Temperature, SAE Transactions: Journal of Fuels and Lubricants, 110(4).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Bae, C., Miles, P.C., Choi, D., and Pickett, L.M. (2005). The Influence of Charge Dilution and Injection Timing on Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion and Emissions, SAE Transactions: Journal of Fuels and Lubricants, 114(4).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sowerby, P., Cummins’ Clean Diesel Technology Enhancements, presented at Motor Vehicle Emissions Control Workshop, Hong Kong, China, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Green Car Congress Monthly Archives September 2007, Scania Introducing New Euro 5 Engine Platform,http://www.greencarcongress.com/2007/09.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akagawa, H., Miyamoto, T., Harada, A., Sasaki, S., Shimazaki, N., Hashizume, T., and Tsujumura, K. (1999). Approaches to Solve Problems of the Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 108(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henein, N. (1976). Analysis of Pollutant Formation and Control and Fuel Economy in Diesel Engines, Progress of Energy and Combustion Science, 1, pp. 165-207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L.M., Idicheria, C. A. (2007). End-of-injection Over-Mixing and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions in Low- Temperature-Combustion Diesel Engines, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 116(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Pickett, L.M., Musculus, M.P.B., Kattke, K., and Gehmlich, R.K., Liquid-Phase Diesel Spray Penetration during End-of-Injection Transient, presented at the 7th COMODIA International Conference on Modeling and Diagnostics for Advanced Engine Systems, Hokkaido, Japan, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L. (1999). Scaling Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays Based on Mixing- Limited Vaporization, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 108(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G. (2005). Mixing Process in High Pressure Diesel Jets by Normalized Laser Induced Exciplex Fluorescence Part I: Free Jet, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 114(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets, SAE World Congress, 2009-01-1355, Detroit, USA, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L. (1998). Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 107(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network: Constant-Volume Diesel Combustion, http://www.ca.sandia.gov/ecn</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J.D. and Siebers, D.L. (1996). Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 105(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Hoogterp, L., “Fundamental Spray and Combustion Measurements of JP-8 at Diesel Conditions” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 1(1):108-118, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Badami, M., Mallamo, F., Millo, F., and Rossi, E.E. (2003). Experimental Investigation on the Effect of Multiple Injection Strategies on Emissions, Noise and Brake Specific Fuel Consumption of an Automotive Direct Injection Common-Rail Diesel Engine, International Journal of Engine Research, 4(4), pp. 299-314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, H., Su, W., and Pei, Y., Experimental and Numerical Study of Diesel HCCI Combustion by Multi-Pulse Injection, presented at SAE World Congress, 2008-01-0059, Detroit, USA, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Kook, S., and Williams, T., “Transient Liquid Penetration of Early-Injection Diesel Sprays” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):785-804, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roth, H., Giannadakis, E., Gavaises, M., Arcoumanis, C., Omae, K., Sakata, I., Nakamura, M., and Yanagihara, H. (2005). Effect of Multi- Injection Strategy on Cavitation Development in Diesel Injector Nozzle Holes, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 114(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ning, W., Reitz, R.D., Diwakar, R., and Lippert, A.M., A Numerical Investigation of Nozzle Geometry and Injection Condition Effects on Diesel Fuel Injector Flow Physics, presented at SAE World Congress, 2008-01-0936, Detroit, USA, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canaan, R. E., Dec, J.E., Green, R.M., and Daly, D.T. (1998). The Influence of Fuel Volatility on the Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in a Heavy-Duty D.I. Diesel Engine, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 107(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B. (2006). Multiple Simultaneous Optical diagnostic Imaging of Early-Injection Low- Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine, SAE Transactions: Journal of Engines, 115(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
