<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278230</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Smart Sensing and Decomposition of NOₓ and NH₃ Components from Production NOₓ Sensor Signals</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jones</surname>
                  <given-names>James C. Peyton</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Villanova University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Geveci</surname>
                  <given-names>Mert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1393</fpage>
         <lpage>1401</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278230"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Production<italic>NOₓ</italic>sensors have a strong cross-sensitivity to ammonia which limits their use for closed-loop SCR control and diagnostics since increases in sensor output can be caused by either gas component. Recently, Ammonia /<italic>NOₓ</italic>Ratio (ANR) perturbation methods have been proposed for determining the dominant component in the post-SCR exhaust as part of the overall SCR control strategy, but these methods or the issue of sensor cross-sensitivity have not been critically evaluated or studied in their own right. In this paper the dynamic sensor direct- and cross-sensitivities are estimated from experimental FTIR data (after compensating for the dynamics of the gas sampling system) and compared to nominal values provided by the manufacturer. The ANR perturbation method, and the use of different input excitations are then discussed within an analytical framework, and applied to experimental data from a large diesel engine. The method successfully discriminates between<italic>NOₓ</italic>and<italic>NH</italic>₃ in the post-SCR exhaust, and is extended to provide an estimate of the composition in situations where simultaneous<italic>NOₓ</italic>and<italic>NH</italic>₃ emissions occur. The results are validated against the previously processed and independent FTIR data.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willems, F., Cloudt, R., van den Eijnden, E., van Genderen, M. et al., “Is Closed-Loop SCR Control Required to Meet Future Emission Targets?,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1574, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1574.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sasaki, H., Scholl, D., Parsons, M., Inagaki, H. et al., “Development of an Al2O3/ZrO2-Composite High-Accuracy NOx Sensor,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0041, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peyton Jones, J.C., Jackson, R.A., “Potential and Pitfalls in the Use of Dual Exhaust Gas Oxygen Sensors for Threeway Catalyst Monitoring and Control”, Proc. Instn Mech. Engrs Part D: J. Automobile Engineering, Vol. 217, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schär, C. M., “Control of a selective catalytic reduction process,” ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schär, C.M., Onder, C. H., and Geering, H. P., “Control of an SCR Catalyst Converter System for a Mobile Heavy-Duty Application”, IEEE Transactions on Control System Technology, Vol. 14, No. 4, pp. 641-652, Jul. 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devarakonda, M., Parker, G., Johnson, J.H., Strots, V. et al., “Model-Based Estimation and Control System Development in a Urea-SCR Aftertreatment System,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):646-661, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1324.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, D.Y., Yao, S., Shost, M., Yoo, J.-H. et al., “Ammonia Sensor for Closed-Loop SCR Control,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars -Electron. Electr. Syst. 1(1):323-333, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chi, J.N., “Control Challenges for Optimal NOx Conversion Efficiency from SCR Aftertreatment Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0905, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0905.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hsieh, M.F., Wang, J., “An Extended Kalman Filter for NOx Sensor Ammonia Cross-Sensitivity Elimination in Selective Catalytic Reduction Applications”, 2010 American Control Conference, Baltimore MD, June 30-July 02, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T.V., “Diesel Emission Control in Review”, SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):68-81, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ljung, L., “System Identification: Theory for the User”, Prentice Hall, 2nd edition, 1999</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.dieselnet.com/standards/cycles/set.php</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
