<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308455</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Efficacy of EGR and Boost in Single-Injection Enabled Low Temperature Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Asad</surname>
                  <given-names>Usman</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Ming</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Windsor</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1085</fpage>
         <lpage>1097</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308455"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Exhaust gas recirculation, fuel injection strategy and boost pressure are among the key enablers to attain low NOx and soot emissions simultaneously on modern diesel engines. In this work, the individual influence of these parameters on the emissions are investigated independently for engine loads up to 8 bar IMEP. A single-shot fuel injection strategy has been deployed to push the diesel cycle into low temperature combustion with EGR. The results indicated that NOx was a stronger respondent to injection pressure levels than to boost when the EGR ratio is relatively low. However, when the EGR level was sufficiently high, the NOx was virtually grounded and the effect of boost or injection pressure becomes irrelevant. Further tests indicated that a higher injection pressure lowered soot emissions across the EGR sweeps while the effect of boost on the soot reduction appeared significant only at higher soot levels. Moreover, the peak soot values were observed to shift towards lower intake oxygen values. With high levels of EGR, the increased carbon monoxide emission largely followed the NOx-Soot trade-off (reduced oxygen concentration, 11∼14% of the working fluid), while the increased hydrocarbon emission was attributed to both the lowered flame temperature and the further reduced oxygen concentration (8∼12%).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asad, U., Zheng, M., Han, X. Reader, G.T. et al., “Fuel Injection Strategies to Improve Emissions and Efficiency of High Compression Ratio Diesel Engines” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):1220-1233, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Kook, C. Bae, P.C. Miles, D. Choi and L.M. Pickett, “The Influence of Charge Dilution and Injection Timing on Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion and Emissions”, SAE Paper 2005-01- 3837, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Akagawa, T. Miyamoto, A. Harada, S. Sasaki, N. Shimazaki, T. Hashizume and K. Tsujimura, "Approaches to Solve Problems of the Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion", SAE Paper 1999-01- 0183, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G. T. Reader and J. G. Hawley, (2004), “Diesel Engine Exhaust Gas Recirculation – A Review on Advanced and Novel Concepts”, Energy Conversion and Management, 45(6), pp. 883-900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Highway Diesel Progress Review-Report 2, Office of Transportation and Air Quality, EPA 420-R-04-004, March 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Alriksson, T. Rente and I. Denbratt, “Low Soot, Low NOx in a Heavy Duty Diesel Using High Levels of EGR”, SAE Paper 2005-01-3836, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Akihama, Y. Takatori, K. Inagaki, S. Sasaki and A.M. Dean, “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature”, SAE Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Kimura, O. Aoki, H. Ogawa, S. Muranaka and Y. Enomoto, “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines”, SAE Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Kimura, H. Ogawa, M. Matusi and Y. Enomoto, (2002), “An Experimental Analysis of Low Temperature and Premixed Combustion for Simultaneous Reduction of NOx and Particulate Emissions in Direct Injection Diesel Engines”, Int J Engine Research, 3(4), pp. 249-259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Kimura, O. Aoki, Y. Kitahara and E. Aiyoshizawa, “Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low-Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards”, SAE Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Ogawa, T. Li, N. Miyamoto, S. Kido and H. Shimizu, “Dependence of Ultra-High EGR and Low Temperature Diesel Combustion on Fuel Injection Conditions and Compression Ratio”, SAE Paper 2006-01-3386, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, M.C. Mulenga, G.T. Reader, Y. Tan, M. Wang and J. Tjong, “Neat Biodiesel Fuel Engine Tests and Preliminary Modelling”, SAE Paper 2007- 01-0616, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, Y. Tan, M.C. Mulenga and M. Wang, “Thermal Efficiency Analyses of Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Cycles”, SAE Transactions Paper 2007-01-4019, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Kumar, M. Zheng, U. Asad, G.T. Reader, “Heat Release Based Adaptive Control to Improve Low Temperature Diesel Engine Combustion”, SAE Paper 2007-01-0771, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D.N. Assanis, P.M. Najt, J.E. Dec, J.A. Eng, T.N. Asmus and F. Zhao, “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engines”, SAE Publication PT-94, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. A. Pierpont, D. T. Montgomery and R. D. Reitz, “Reducing Particulate and NOx Using Multiple Injections and EGR in a D.I. Diesel”, SAE Paper 950217, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C.A. Idicheria and L.M. Pickett, “Soot Formation in Diesel Combustion under High-EGR Conditions”, SAE Paper 2005-01-3834, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L.M. Pickett and D.L. Siebers, “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion”, SAE Paper 2004-01-1399, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Helmantel and I. Denbratt, “HCCI Operation of a Passenger Car Common-Rail Di Diesel Engine with Early Injection of Conventional Diesel Fuel”, SAE Paper 2004-01-0935, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G.T. Reader, R. Kumar, C. Mulenga, U. Asad, Y. Tan and M.Wang, “Adaptive Control to Improve Low Temperature Diesel Engine Combustion”, 12th Diesel Engine-Efficiency and Emission Reduction Conference (DEER), 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.O. Olsson, P. Tunestal and B. Johansson, “Boosting for High Load HCCI”, SAE Paper 2004-01- 0940, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Kodama, I. Nishizawa, T. Sugihara, N. Sato, T. Iijima and T. Yoshida, “Full-load HCCI Operation with Variable Valve Actuation System in a Heavy- Duty Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2007-01-0215, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Ogawa, N. Miyamoto, H. Shimizu, S. Kido; “Characteristics of Diesel Combustion in Low Oxygen Mixtures with Ultra-High EGR”, SAE Paper 2006-01-1147, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U. Asad and M. Zheng, “EGR Oxidation and Catalytic Fuel Reforming for Diesel Engines”, ASME Paper ICES2008-1684, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X. Han, U. Asad, R. Kumar, M.C. Mulenga, S. Banerjee, M. Wang, G.T. Reader and M. Zheng, “Empirical Studies of the Diesel Low Temperature Combustion on a Modern Diesel Engine”, Combustion Institute/Canadian Section, 2007 Spring Technical Meeting, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L.G. Dodge, S. Simescu, G.D. Neely, M.J. Maymar, D.W. Dickey and C.L. Savonen, “Effect of Small Holes and High Injection Pressures on Diesel Engine Combustion”, SAE Paper 2002-01-0494, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Stone, “Introduction to Internal Combustion Engines”, 3rd Edition, Macmillan, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Heywood, “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, 1st Edition, McGraw-Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Dronniou, M. Lejeune and I. Balloul, “Combination of High EGR Rates and Multiple Injection Strategies to Reduce Pollutant Emissions”, SAE Paper 2005-01-3726, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G.T. Reader, U. Asad, Y. Tan and M. Wang, “Adaptive Control to Improve Low Temperature Diesel Engine Combustion”, Paper No. DE1-2, Proceedings of the 7th COMODIA International Conference on Modeling and Diagnostics for Advanced Engine Systems, Japan, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, M., Kumar, R., Tan, Y., and Reader, G.T., “Heat Release Pattern Diagnostics to Improve Diesel Low Temperature Combustion” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):1242-1258, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Ladomatos, S. Abdelhalim and H. Zhao, (2000), “The Effects of Exhaust Gas Recirculation on Diesel Combustion and Emissions”, Int J Engine Research, 1(1), pp. 107-126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Alriksson and I. Denbratt, “Low Temperature Combustion in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Using High Levels of EGR”, SAE Paper, 2006-01-0075, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Helmantel, “Reduction of NOx Emissions from a Light Duty DI Diesel Engine in Medium Load Conditions with High EGR Rates”, SAE Paper 2008- 01-0643, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Ached, U.D.T. Sat and H. Sugar, “Combined Effects of EGR and Supercharging on Diesel Combustion and Emissions”, SAE Paper 930601, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Satoh, L. Zhang, H. Hatanaka, T. Takatsuki and K. Yokota, (1997), “Relationship between NOx and PM emissions from DI diesel engine with EGR”, JSAE Review, 18(4), pp. 369-375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Ladomatos, S. Abdelhalim and H. Zhao, (1998), “Control of Oxides of Nitrogen from Diesel Engines using Diluents while minimizing the Impact on Particulate Pollutants”, Applied Thermal Engineering, 18, pp. 963-980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. F. Colban, P. C. Miles and S. Oh, “Effect of Intake Pressure on Performance and Emissions in an Automotive Diesel Engine Operating in Low- Temperature Combustion Regimes”, SAE Paper 2007-01-4063, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Alriksson, S. Gjirja and I. Denbratt, “The Effect of Charge Air and Fuel Injection Parameters on Combustion with High Levels of EGR in a HDDI Single Cylinder Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2007-01- 0914, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Noehre, M. Andersson, B. Johansson and A. Hultqvist, “Characterization of Partially Premixed Combustion”, SAE Paper 2006-01-3412, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EcoPoint Inc., “Unit Injector &amp; Unit Pump Systems”, www.DieselNet.com, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U. Asad, M. Zheng, (2008), “Fast Heat Release Characterization of a Diesel Engine”, International Journal of Thermal Sciences, 47(12), pp. 1688- 1700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G.T Reader, U. Asad, Y. Tan, K. Xie and M. Wang, “An Enabling Study of Diesel Low- Temperature Combustion via Adaptive Control”, 14th Diesel Engine-Efficiency and Emission Reduction Conference (DEER), 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
