<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275525</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Investigation of a Control Method for SI-HCCI-SI Transition in a Multi-Cylinder Gasoline Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wu</surname>
                  <given-names>Hao</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Collings</surname>
                  <given-names>Nick</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Regitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Simon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Etheridge</surname>
                  <given-names>Jonathan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kraft</surname>
                  <given-names>Markus</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ. of Cambridge</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>928</fpage>
         <lpage>937</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275525"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In HCCI engines, the Air/Fuel Ratio (AFR) and Residual Gas Fraction (RGF) are difficult to control during the SI-HCCI-SI transition, and this may result in incomplete combustion and/or high pressure raise rates. As a result, there may be undesirably high engine load fluctuations. The objectives of this work are to further understand this process and develop control methods to minimize these load fluctuations.</p>
            <p>This paper presents data on instantaneous AFR and RGF measurements, both taken by novel experimental techniques. The data provides an insight into the cyclic AFR and RGF fluctuations during the switch. These results suggest that the relatively slow change in the intake Manifold Air Pressure (MAP) and actuation time of the Variable Valve Timing (VVT) are the main causes of undesired AFR and RGF fluctuations, and hence an unacceptable Net IMEP (NIMEP) fluctuation. We also found large cylinder-to-cylinder AFR variations during the transition. Therefore, besides throttle opening control and VVT shifting, cyclic and individual cylinder fuel injection control is necessary to achieve a smooth transition. The control method was developed and implemented in a test engine, and the result was a considerably reduced NIMEP fluctuation during the mode switch. The instantaneous AFR and RGF measurements could furthermore be adopted to develop more sophisticated control methods for SI-HCCI-SI transitions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onishi, S., Jo, S.H., Shoda, K., Jo, P.D. et al., “Active Thermo-Atmosphere Combustion (ATAC) - A New Combustion Process for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 790501, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noguchi, M., Tanaka, Y., Tanaka, T., and Takeuchi, Y., “A Study on Gasoline Engine Combustion by Observation of Intermediate Reactive Products during Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 790840, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najt, P.M. and Foster, D.E., “Compression-Ignited Homogeneous Charge Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 830264, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thring, R.H., “Homogeneous-Charge Compression- Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 892068, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J.E., “Influence of EGR Quality and Unmixedness on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):492-510, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Wermuth, N., and Najt, P., “Development of Robust Gasoline HCCI Idle Operation Using Multiple Injection and Multiple Ignition (MIMI) Strategy,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0499, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wermuth, N., Yun, H., and Najt, P., “Enhancing Light Load HCCI Combustion in a Direct Injection Gasoline Engine by Fuel Reforming During Recompression,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):823-836, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, C., Zhao, H., and Megaritis, T., “Investigation of CAI Combustion with Positive Valve Overlap and Enlargement of CAI Operating Range,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1104, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L., Ström, H., Lundgren, S., Backlund, O. et al., “Demonstrating a SI-HCCI-SI Mode Change on a Volvo 5-Cylinder Electronic Valve Control Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0753, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santoso, H., Matthews, J., and Cheng, W.K., “Managing SI/HCCI Dual-Mode Engine Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0162, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milovanovic, N., Blundell, D., Gedge, S., and Turner, J., “SI-HCCI-SI Mode Transition at Different Engine Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0156, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y., Xie, H., Zhou, N., Chen, T., and Zhao, H., “Study of SI-HCCI-SI Transition on a Port Fuel Injection Engine Equipped with 4VVAS”, SAE Paper 2007-01-0199, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsuda, T., Wada, H., Kono, T., Nakamura, T. et al., “A Study of a Gasoline-fueled HCCI Engine ∼ Mode Changes from SI Combustion to HCCI Combustion∼,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0050, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kakuya, H., Yamaoka, S., Kumano, K., and Sato, S., “Investigation of a SI-HCCI Combustion Switching Control Method in a Multi-Cylinder Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0792, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tian, G., Wang, Z., Ge, Q., Wang, J. et al., “Mode Switch of SI-HCCI Combustion on a GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0195, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A. and Blaxill, H., “The Effects of Two-Stage Cam Profile Switching and External EGR on SI-CAI Combustion Transitions,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0187, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karagiorgis, S., Collings, N., Glover, K., Coghlan, N. et al., “Residual Gas Fraction Measurement and Estimation on a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine Utilizing the Negative Valve Overlap Strategy,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3276, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw-Hill International Editions, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Regitz, S. and Collings N., 2008, “Fast response Air-To- Fuel Ratio measurements using a novel device based on a wide band lambda sensor”, Meas. Sci. And Technol., 19, 075201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Regitz, S., “An ultra fast Air-To-Fuel measurement device for cyclic combustion analysis”, Ph.D., 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Etheridge, J., Mosbach, S., Kraft, M., Wu, H. et al., “A Detailed Chemistry Multi-cycle Simulation of a Gasoline Fueled HCCI Engine Operated with NVO,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):13-27, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
