<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910343</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures for Quick Reaction Analysis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Nestler</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hall</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrew O.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <bio>
               <p>Lieutenant Colonel Scott T. Nestler, PhD is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Mathematical Sciences, and Director, Center for Data Analysis and Statistics, US Military Academy at West Point. Lieutenant Colonel Andrew O. Hall is a PhD candidate in Operations Management and Management Science at the R.H. Smith School of Business, University of Maryland. They are both Operations Research Analysts with experience in the Army G-1, Plans and Resources Division and as Assistant Professors in the Department of Mathematical Sciences of the US Military Academy at West Point. LTC Nestler’s operational experience was with PATRIOT air defense missile units in Texas, Saudi Arabia, and South Korea. LTC Hall served in both light and mechanized infantry units in the US and South Korea, with operational deployments to Saudi Arabia and most recently to Iraq, as the Effects Analyst for Multi-National Corps-Iraq.</p>
            </bio>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>June 2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>42</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910337</issue-id>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>8</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2009, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910343"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Q Course mentioned did expose students to the types of analysis (e.g. personnel, training, force development, joint, etc.) that could be encountered in headquarters and operational staffs; however, it did not appear to provide a general framework for analysts in these organizations.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Mythical Man-Month: Essays on Software Engineering, Frederick P. Brooks, Jr.; Addison-Wesley 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Decision-Making in Systems Engineering and Management. Parnell, Driscoll, and Henderson, Editors; Wiley, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Eyes Have It: ATask by Data Type Taxonomy for Information Visualization. Shneiderman, Ben; Proceedings of the IEEE Symposium on Visual Languages, pp 336-343, 1996. Available at http://citeseer.ist.psu.edu/409647.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Human-Computer Interaction Laboratory (HCIL), University of Maryland, http://www.cs.umd.edu/hcil/research/visual ization.shtml.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Web Timeline Analysis System (WebTAS), available through the Air Force Research Laboratory; more information is available at www.webtas.com.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
