<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278145</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Impact of Fuel Properties on Diesel Low Temperature Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Ojeda</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Navistar</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bulicz</surname>
                  <given-names>Tytus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Navistar</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Xiaoye</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Windsor</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Ming</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Windsor</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cornforth</surname>
                  <given-names>Frederick</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ConocoPhillips Co.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>188</fpage>
         <lpage>201</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278145"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Extensive empirical work indicates that exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) is effective to lower the flame temperature and thus the oxides of nitrogen (NOx) production in-cylinder in diesel engines. Soot emissions are reduced in-cylinder by improved fuel/air mixing. As engine load increases, higher levels of intake boost and fuel injection pressure are required to suppress soot production. The high EGR and improved fuel/air mixing is then critical to enable low temperature combustion (LTC) processes.</p>
            <p>The paper explores the properties of the Fuels for Advanced Combustion Engines (FACE) Diesel, which are statistically designed to examine fuel effects, on a 0.75L single cylinder engine across the full range of load, spanning up to 15 bar IMEP.</p>
            <p>The lower cetane number (CN) of the diesel fuel improved the mixing process by prolonging the ignition delay and the mixing duration leading to substantial reduction of soot at low to medium loads, improving the trade-off between NOx and soot. Low load performance, such as cycle-to-cycle variability, was worsened by less effective post flames and the less reactive nature of the mixture.</p>
            <p>The higher volatility of the lower T90 fuels promoted the evaporation of the injected fuel spray, thereby accelerating the fuel/air mixing process and improving the homogeneity of cylinder charge. The T90 effect on ignition delay is minor, yet the improved vaporization and mixing translated in a noticeable soot reduction.</p>
            <p>The higher aromatic contents in the diesel fuels prolonged the ignition delay. Howerver, the soot emissions were not necessarily reduced according to the extended ignition delay. The soot trend competed with the aromatics, which are precursors of soot.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asad, U., Zheng, M., Han, X., Reader, G.T. and Wang, M., “Fuel Injection Strategies to Improve Emissions and Efficiency of High Compression Ratio Diesel Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):1220-1233, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-2472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alriksson, M., Rente, T. and Denbratt, I., “Low Soot, Low NOx in a Heavy Duty Diesel Using High Levels of EGR”, SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3836, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kodama, Y., Nishizawa, I., Sugihara, T., Sato, N., Iijima, T. and Yoshida, T., “Full-Load HCCI Operation with Variable Valve Actuation System in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0215, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Miyamoto, N., Shimizu, H. and Kido, S., “Characteristics of Diesel Combustion in Low Oxygen Mixtures with Ultra-High EGR,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1147, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S. and Enomoto, Y., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asad, U. and Zheng, M., “Efficacy of EGR and Boost in Single-Injection Enabled Low Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1085-1097, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, X., Asad, U., Kumar, R., Mulenga, M.C., Banerjee, S., Wang, M., Reader, G.T. and Zheng, M., “Empirical Studies of the Diesel Low Temperature Combustion on a Modern Diesel Engine”, Combustion Institute/Canadian Section, 2007 Spring Technical Meeting, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamanouchi, M., Morihisa, H., Yamada, S., Iida, J. Sasaki, T. and Sue, H., “Effects of Fuel Properties on Exhaust Emissions for Diesel Engines with and without Oxidation Catalyst and High Pressure Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 970758, 1997, doi:10.4271/970758.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reynolds, E. G., “The Effect of Fuel Processes on Heavy Duty Automotive Diesel Engine Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 952350, 1995, doi:10.4271/952350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akasaka, Y. and Sakurai, Y., “Effects of Oxygenated Fuel and Cetane Improver on Exhaust Emission from Heavy- Duty DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 942023, 1994, 942023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCarthy, C. I., Slodowske, W. J., Sienicki, E. J. and Jass, R. E., “Diesel Fuel Property Effects on Exhaust Emissions from a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine that Meets 1994 Emissions Requirements,” SAE Technical Paper 922267, 1992, doi:10.4271/922267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cunningham, L. J., Henry, T. J. and Kulinowski, A. M., “The Effects of Diesel Ignition Improvers in Low-Sulfur Fuels on Heavy-Duty Diesel Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 902173, 1990, doi:10.4271/902173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bielaczyc, P., Kozak, M. and Merkisz, J., “Effects of Fuel Properties on Exhaust Emissions from the Latest Light Duty DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1882, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1882.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Risberg, P., Kalghatgi, G., Ångstrom, H.E. and Wåhlin, F., “Auto-Ignition Quality of Diesel-Like Fuels in HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2127, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-2127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Kalghatgi, G., Tait, N., Johansson, B. and Harrison, A., “Fuel Octane Effects in the Partially Premixed Combustion Regime in Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2648, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., Kalghatgi, G. and Harrison, A. “Some Effects of Fuel Autoignition Quality and Volatility in Premixed Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):440-460, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bobba, M., Musculus, M. and Neel, W., “Effect of Post Injections on In-Cylinder and Exhaust Soot for Low- Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):496-516, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0612.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Bae, C., Miles, P.C., Choi, D. and Pickett, L.M., “The Influence of Charge Dilution and Injection Timing on Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3837, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asad, U. and Zheng, M., “Fast Heat Release Characterization of a Diesel Engine”, International Journal of Thermal Sciences, 47, 2008, pp. 1688-1700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CRC Report No. FACE-1 Chemical and Physical Properties of the Fuels for Advanced Combustion Engines (FACE) Research Diesel Fuels, July 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Ojeda, W. Zoldak, P., Espinosa, R. and Kumar, R., “Development of a Fuel Injection Strategy for Partially Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1473-1488, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
