<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910289</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Cooperative Navigation and Adaptive Guidance</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Allen</surname>
                  <given-names>Randal T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mr. Randall Allen is currently employed with Lone Star Aerospace, Inc. in Plano, TX where he serves as a senior systems engineer working on 6DOF simulation of weapon systems, including navigation, guidance, and control systems. His previous experience includes flight operations for west-coast Titan-IV missions and orbit control for the Iridium satellite constellation. He also serves as an Adjunct Professor at the University of Central Florida in Orlando, FL.</p> 
                  <p>Mr. Allen’s academic history includes a B.S. in Engineering Physics and an M.S. in Applied Mathematics from the University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign) and an Engineer’s Degree in Aeronautical/Astronautical Engineering from Stanford University. He is currently a Ph.D. candidate studying under the direction of Dr. Chengying Xu at the University of Central Florida and expects to be conferred in the spring of 2009.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Chengying</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Chengying Xu is currently an Assistant Professor in University of Central Florida. She earned her Ph.D. degree in 2006 in Mechanical Engineering from Purdue University, IN, USA and her M.S. degree in 2001 in Mechanical Manufacturing &amp; Automation from Beijing University of Aeronautics &amp; Astronautics, Beijing, China. Her research interests include intelligent systems, control, manufacturing, system dynamics, online monitoring and diagnostics, robotics, mechatronics and automation. Dr. Xu has coauthored Intelligent Systems: Modeling, Optimization and Control (CRC Press, 2008). She has authored and co-authored 30 publications in archived journals and refereed conference proceedings, and received the Best Paper in Session award in the 3rd International Conference on Cybernetics and Information Technologies Systems and Applications (CITSA). She has served as an organizing committee member and session co-chair for a number of national and international conferences, and has reviewed papers for ASME and IEEE Transactions journals. She is an active member for multiple professional societies, such as American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME), the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Society of Manufacturing Engineers (SME), and Society for Experimental Mechanics (SEM). She has been an Associate Editor of International Journal of Nanomanufacturing since 2008.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2008</year>
            <string-date>December 2008</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910279</issue-id>
         <fpage>12</fpage>
         <lpage>17</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2008, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910289"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label> 
            <p>Anovel cooperative navigation method is proposed for multiple unmanned air vehicles (UAVs) based on online target position measurements, which are used to estimate the target’s velocity for non-maneuvering targets; or the target’s velocity and acceleration for maneuvering targets. Since the maneuvering mode of the target is unknown, the estimator incorporates adaptive logic to determine the maneuvering status of the target during flight in real-time. Furthermore, the estimator’s tracking capability is physically constrained due to the target’s kinematic limitations, and therefore can be potentially improved by designing a higher performance estimator. An H-infinity filter is implemented to increase the robustness of the estimation accuracy to compensate for surrounding noises and disturbances. The performance of the adaptive robust estimator is compared to a regular adaptive Kalman filter and the results illustrate more precise estimation of the target’s motion. The main objective of this work is to develop an adaptive robust estimator/tracker which is directly applicable to UAV weaponization.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
