<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277972</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Injection Pressure Effects on the Flame Development in a Light-Duty Optical Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Le</surname>
                  <given-names>Minh Khoi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kook</surname>
                  <given-names>Sanghoon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>The University of New South Wales</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>609</fpage>
         <lpage>624</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277972"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The impact of fuel injection pressure on the development of diesel flames has been studied in a light-duty optical engine. Planer laser-induced fluorescence imaging of fuel (fuel-PLIF) and hydroxyl radicals (OH-PLIF) as well as line-of-sight integrated chemiluminescence imaging of cool-flame and OH* were performed for three different common-rail pressures including 70, 100, and 130 MPa. The injection timing and injected fuel mass were held constant resulting in earlier end of injection for higher injection pressure. The in-cylinder pressure was also measured to understand bulk-gas combustion conditions through the analysis of apparent heat release rate. From the cool-flame images, it is found that the low-temperature reaction starts to occur in the wall-interacting jet head region where the fuel-air mixing could be enhanced due to a turbulent ring-vortex formed during jet-wall interactions. Also, the cool-flame images together with the apparent heat release rate suggest that the low-temperature reaction becomes stronger with increasing injection pressure. The influence of in-cylinder swirl flow on the OH* chemiluminescence signals was observed such that the high-temperature reaction on the down-swirl side of the jet is earlier than that on the up-swirl side of the jet regardless of the injection pressure. Moreover, the second-stage ignition on the down-swirl side of the jet is found to be stronger than the up-swirl side of the jet. This is consistent with higher fuel penetration and more intense fuel fluorescence signals observed on the down-swirl side of the jet, suggesting that relatively richer mixtures caused stronger high-temperature reactions. As the injection pressure increases, however, the spread and magnitude of the up-swirl OH* chemiluminescence signals become comparable to the down-swirl signals due to the increased injection momentum overcoming the swirl flow. On account of the unavoidable laser beam attenuation, the OH-PLIF signals on the up-swirl side could not be observed clearly. The down-swirl OH-PLIF signals, however, display interesting behaviour of the wall-interacting jet head such that the OH-PLIF region expands drastically in the turbulent ring-vortex region where the cool-flame signals were detected at earlier timings. The expansion of wall-jet head OH signals shows an increasing trend with increasing injection pressure, which is explained by a stronger ring-vortex due to the increased injection momentum.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schommers, J., Duvinage, F., Stotz, M., Peters, A. et al., “Potential of Common Rail Injection System for Passenger Car DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0944, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaillard, P. and Hedna, M., “Performance Development of the First European Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Equipped with Full Electronic High Injection Pressure Common Rail System,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1821, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Birch, S., “Delphi claims world-first for direct-acting diesel injection,” SAE International Automotive Engineering Magazine, http://articles.sae. org/4200/, accessed Aug. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. and Siebers, D., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi:10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuti, O.A., Zhu, J., Nishida, K., Wang, X. et al., “Characterization of spray and combustion processes of biodiesel fuel injected by diesel engine common rail system,” Fuel 104:838-846, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.05.014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shundoh, S., Kakegawa, T., Tsujimura, K., and Kobayashi, S., “The Effect of Injection Parameters and Swirl on Diesel Combustion with High Pressure Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 910489, 1991, doi:10.4271/910489.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rajalingam, B. and Farrell, P., “The Effect of Injection Pressure on Air Entrainment into Transient Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 1999- 01-0523, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0523.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Mixing Process in High Pressure Diesel Jets by Normalized Laser Induced Exciplex Fluorescence Part I: Free Jet,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2100, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rusly, A., Le, M., and Kook, S., “Effect of Injection Pressure on Transient Behaviour of Wall-Interacting Jet Flame Base in an Automotive-Size Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(3):615-626, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Liquid and vapor spray structure in high- pressure common rail diesel injection,” Atomization and Sprays 11(5):533-556, 2001, doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.v11.i5.40</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gumus, M., Sayin, C., Canakci, M., “The impact of fuel injection pressure on the exhaust emissions of a direct injection diesel engine fueled with biodiesel-diesel fuel blends,” Fuel 95:486-494, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2011.11.020.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Labecki, L., Ganippa, L.C., “Effects of injection parameters and EGR on combustion and emission characteristics of rapeseed oil and its blends in diesel engines,” Fuel 98:15-28, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.03.029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agarwal, A.K., Dhar, A., Srivastava, D.K., Maurya, R.K. et al., “Effect of fuel injection pressure on diesel particulate size and number distribution in a CRDI single cylinder research engine,” Fuel 107:84-89, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.01.077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Mixing Process in High Pressure Diesel Jets by Normalized Laser Induced Exciplex Fluorescence Part II: Wall Impinging Versus Free Jet,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2097, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2097.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cossali, G., Coghe, A., and Brunello, G., “Effect of Spray-Wall Interaction on Air Entrainment in a Transient Diesel Spray,” SAE Technical Paper 930920, 1993, doi:10.4271/930920.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and López, J., “Jet-Wall Interaction Effects on Diesel Combustion and Soot Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0921, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0921.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andreassi, L., Ubertini, S., Allocca, L., “Experimental and numerical analysis of high pressure diesel spray-wall interaction,” International Journal of Multiphase Flow 33(7):742-765, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.ijmultiphaseflow.2007.01.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rusly, A.M., Le, M.K., Kook, S., Hawkes, E.R., “The shortening of lift-off length associated with jet-wall and jet-jet interaction in a small-bore optical diesel engine,” Fuel 125:1-14, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2014.02.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, W., Nishida, K., Gao, J., Miura, D., “An experimental study on flat-wall-impinging spray of microhole nozzles under ultra-high injection pressures,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 222:1731-1741, 2008, doi:10.1243/09544070JAUTO858.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Le, M.K., Kook, S., Hawkes, E.R., “The planar imaging of laser induced fluorescence of fuel and hydroxyl for a wall-interacting jet in a singlecylinder, automotive-size, optically accessible diesel engine,” Fuel 140:143-155, 2015 doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2014.09.089.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Genzale, C., Reitz, R., and Musculus, M., “Effects of Piston Bowl Geometry on Mixture Development and Late-Injection Low- Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):913-937, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, X., Huang, Z., Zhang, W., Kuti, O.A. et al., “Effects of ultra-high injection pressure and micro-hole nozzle on flame structure and soot formation of impinging diesel spray,” Applied Energy 88(5):1620-1628, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2010.11.035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polonowski, C., Mueller, C., Gehrke, C., Bazyn, T. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-Cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):51-77, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chartier, C., Aronsson, U., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R. et al., “Influence of jet-jet interactions on the lift-off length in an optical heavy-duty DI diesel engine,: Fuel 112:311-318, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.05.021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Menkiel, B., Donkerbroek, A., Uitz, R., Cracknell, R. et al., “Combustion and soot processes of diesel and rapeseed methyl ester in an optical diesel engine,” Fuel 118:406-415, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.10.074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., Miles, P.C., Pickett, L.M., “Conceptual models for partially premixed low- temperature diesel combustion,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 39(2-3):246-283, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2012.09.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Coy, E., “OH Radical Imaging in a DI Diesel Engine and the Structure of the Early Diffusion Flame,” SAE Technical Paper 960831, 1996, doi:10.4271/960831.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., “Multiple Simultaneous Optical Diagnostic Imaging of Early-Injection Low- Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0079, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006- 01-0079.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal combustion engine fundamentals, First Edition,” (New York, McGraw-Hill, 1988), p509-510, ISBN:9780070286382.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Espey, C., “Ignition and Early Soot Formation in a DI Diesel Engine Using Multiple 2-D Imaging Diagnostics,” SAE Technical Paper 950456, 1995, doi:10.4271/950456.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., McQuay, M.Q., Lacas, F., Rolon, J.C. et al., “Systematic measurements of OH chemiluminescence for fuel-lean, high-pressure, premixed, laminar flames,” Fuel 80(1):67-74, 2001, doi:10.1016/S0016- 2361(00)00069-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Kook, S., and Williams, T., “Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool- Flame, Ignition, High-Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High-Speed Imaging,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):439-459, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mancaruso, E., Vaglieco, B.M., “Spectroscopic measurements of premixed combustion in diesel engine” Fuel 90(2):511-520, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2010.09.052.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Espey, C., “Chemiluminescence Imaging of Autoignition in a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 982685, 1998, doi:10.4271/982685.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D., “Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, J., Jing, W., Fang, T., “High speed imaging of OH* chemiluminescence and natural luminosity of low temperature diesel spray combustion,” Fuel 99:226-234, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.04.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dronniou, N., Kashdan, J., Lecointe, B., Sauve, K. et al., “Optical Investigation of Dual-fuel CNG/Diesel Combustion Strategies to Reduce CO2 Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):873-887, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1313.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nishida, K., Zhang, W., and Manabe, T., “Effects of Micro-Hole and Ultra-High Injection Pressure on Mixture Properties of D.I. Diesel Spray,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1890, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007- 01-1890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuti, O., Zhang, W., Nishida, K., Wang, X. et al., “Effect of Injection Pressure on Ignition, Flame Development and Soot Formation Processes of Biodiesel Fuel Spray,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):1057-1070, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kashdan, J., Anselmi, P., and Walter, B., “Advanced Injection Strategies for Controlling Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion and Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1835-1856, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dawson, W.R., Windsor, M.W., “Fluorescence yields of aromatic compounds,” The Journal of Physical Chemistry 72(9):3251-3260, 1968, doi:10.1021/j100855a027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., Musculus, M.P.B., Reitz, R.D., “Mixing and flame structures inferred from OH-PLIF for conventional and low-temperature diesel engine combustion,” Combustion and Flame 156(10):1898-1908, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2009.07.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Engine Combustion Network, “Lift-Off Length,” http://www.sandia. gov/ecn/cvdata/expDiag/liftoff.php, accessed Oct. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, P.C., Wang, W.C., Roberts, W.L., Fang T., “Spray and atomization of diesel fuel and its alternatives from a single-hole injector using a common rail fuel injection system,” Fuel 103:850-861, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.08.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuti, O., Zhang, W., Nishida, K., Wang, X. et al., “Effect of Injection Pressure on Ignition, Flame Development and Soot Formation Processes of Biodiesel Fuel Spray,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):1057-1070, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, S. and Bae, C., “The Influence of Fuel Injection Pressure and Intake Pressure on Conventional and Low Temperature Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1721, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1721.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Padala, S., Woo, C., Kook, S., Hawkes, E.R., “Ethanol utilisation in a diesel engine using dual-fuelling technology,” Fuel 109:597-607, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.03.049.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L., Hanson, R.M., Splitter, D.A., Reitz, R.D., “Fuel reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI): a pathway to controlled high-efficiency clean combustion,” International Journal of Engine Research 12(3):209-226, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411401548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Antonius, R., “Interpreting quantitative data with SPSS, First Edition” (California, Sage Publications Ltd., 2004), 165-467, ISBN:9780761973980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, S., Hewson, J.C., Chen, J.H., “Nonpremixed n-heptane autoignition in unsteady counterflow,” Combustion and Flame 145(4):730-739, 2006, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2006.01.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
