<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>אגוד הבנקים בישראל</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">ג'</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</issue>
         <issue-id>i24010132</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24011973</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comments and Rejoinder / תשובה להשגותיה של הגב' דורנשטיין</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>י.</given-names>
                  <surname>בר-יוסף</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Y.</given-names>
                  <surname>Bar-Yosef</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1963</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>59</fpage>
         <lpage>66</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24011973"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Mr. Bar-Yosef highlights the dilemma of the Finance Ministry in reconciling the need to increase the country's foreign currency reserves, with the desire to avoid an undue increase in the money supply arising from the conversion of foreign exchange into local currency. He points out that one of the ways of counterbalancing the increased flow of income is to increase the supply of goods and services. Hence the Government should allow importers to utilize suppliers' credits, which are by far cheaper than credits obtained locally. He points out that in practice, measures requiring the purchase of foreign currency or depositing local currency when documentary credits are opened, have unfortunately proved ineffective. The importer may reduce stocks, which would lead to a decrease in the supply of goods and possibly to an inflationary price rise. Alternatively, the importer may obtain credit from banks, which will in all probability under present conditions be supplied via the bill-market. The problem facing the Monetary Authorities is whether this market can supply all the credit thus required by importers. Moreover, will borrowing by importers from this market drive out other borrowers? The writer contends that an increase in demand for credit by importers will lead to higher interest rates and tempt holders of time deposits and other inactive funds to invest their money in the bill-market, either via the banking system, or through other agents. This would increase the velocity of circulation of bank deposits, (in fact it has increased the velocity of deposits), and thereby defeat the whole object of the Monetary Authorities, which is to compel importers to borrow locally, instead of using foreign suppliers credits and thereby squeezing credit. Mr. Bar-Yosef demonstrates by the use of schematic balance sheets that if the banking system were to extend to importers the credit which was formerly supplied to them by suppliers abroad, it would be tantamount to raising the "liquidity ratio" by the Central Bank. In itself this may be desirable, but when carried to extremes, forces borrowers to seek credit from non-bank sources, thus again defeating its own purposes. He refers the reader to the bill-market, which has developed because of the very high "liquidity ratio" which banks are required to maintain. He emphasizes, that the low interest rate on credit granted by suppliers abroad, helps maintain the stability of the price level, and its replacement by higher priced local credit will not be at the expense of the importer, but of the economy as a whole. Theoretically, a rise in the rate of interest should curb demand for credit, which as Mrs. Dornstein states, is after all, one of the aims of present monetary policy. However, as interest is a deductible expense for income tax purposes, about 50% of the cost of the additional interest payable by borrowers will as a matter of fact, be borne by the Treasury. Furthermore, the public sector, which borrows on a large scale in the money market, is not sensitive to higher interest rates. In Israel, past experience has shown that relatively high interest rates have not curbed credit demand. In his view theoreticians must, from time to time, test their theories empirically, in order to improve monetary control and to adapt financial tools to a rapidly changing economy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>[הערות שוליים]</title>
        <ref id="d64e156a1310">
            <label>"</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e163" publication-type="other">
) כל זה מתוך הנחה שמערכת הבנקאות מקיימת נזילות עודפת והיא יכולה, איפוא, להרהיב
את האשראי.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e173a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e180" publication-type="other">
לא בכדי נקבל בחוק בלגי חדש, שהבנק המרכזי רשאי לקבול, שהבנקים יחזיקו אצלו יתרה מיני-
מלית בשיעור מקסימלי של 20 אחתים על חשבונות עובר ושב ד6 אחוזים על פקדונות לזמנים
קצובים. הגבלה דומה לל שילורי נזילות מקסימליים נמצא בארצות-הברית ובארצות אחדות, כלום לא
ידול לשלטונות באותן ארצות, שמבחינה תאורטית ניתן לקבול שילוד נדלות של 100 אחוז לל
פקדוגות? מדול, אם בן, כבלו את ידיהם של הבנקים המרכזיים ז</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e199a1310">
            <label>"•</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e206" publication-type="other">
ליין דו"ח ולדת המשנה לל לסקי התיווך בשטרות והנספח לדו''ח זה.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e213a1310">
            <label>"</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e220" publication-type="other">
) אנחנו, משלמי המסים, נושאים בתוספת זו, בין אם מממנים את השיכונים מתוך
מסי האוכלוסיה ובין אם מסתייעים בהלוואות, שהמדינה מקבלת בחוץ-לארץ.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


