<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014678</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effects of Group Dynamics on Language Learning and Use in an MMOG</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vosburg</surname>
                  <given-names>Donald</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>The Pennsylvania State University.</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Donald Vosburg is a lecturer of German at The Pennsylvania State University. His research interests include Germanic linguistics and Second Language Acquisition. His primary interest is with second language acquisition and technology, focusing on the reduction of anxiety both in the face-to-face and online classroom, teaching with technology, distance language learning course and material design, online instructor training and evaluation, and a special interest in the use of games as a tool for language learning. In particular, he has a deep interest in the use of massively multiplayer online games as a language learning tool.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014673</issue-id>
         <fpage>58</fpage>
         <lpage>74</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014678"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>The use of video games as a learning tool, in particular massively multiplayer online games (MMOGs), continues to grow, as does the research in this field of study; research to date has revealed benefits to the language learner as well as hindrances and research gaps (Godwin-Jones, 2014). This study examines participant perspectives on group dynamics, and how comradery and a foreign language guide affect participants’ in-game production of L2 German while playing World of Warcraft (WoW) as an extramural activity. This study focuses on an eight-week long MMOG gaming project, in which two groups of participants played WoW with a native German speaker in order to investigate the effects inter-group dynamics have on a participant’s real-time target language production and willingness to communicate. Participants reported during interviews and written journal entries that a lack of shared interests and motivation (learning and gaming) negatively affected the groups’ target language participation. The findings additionally suggest that a trained foreign language instructor paired with a motivated learner may result in increased participation; however, these increases may be temporary if a group’s relationship does not extend beyond the shared goal of foreign language improvement.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>community</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>extramural</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>gaming</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>SLA</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>MMOG</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blizzard Entertainment. (n.d.). World of Warcraft. Retrieved from https://worldofwarcraft.com/en-us/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cornillie, F., Thorne, S. L., &amp; Desmet, P. (2012). Editorial: Digital games for language learning: From hype to insight? ReCALL, 24(3), 243–256. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344012000134</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">deHaan, J. (Ed.). (2013). Video games and second language acquisition: Six genre case studies. Champaign, IL: The Learner, Common Ground Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">deHaan, J., Reed, W. M., &amp; Kuwada, K. (2010). The effect of interactivity with a music video game on second language vocabulary recall. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 14(2), 74–94. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/vol14num2/dehaanreedkuwada.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engeström, Y. (1999). Activity theory and individualand social transformation. In Y. Engeström, R. Miettinen &amp; R.-L. Punamäki (Eds.), Perspectives on activity theory (pp. 19–38). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511812774.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gee, J. P. (2007). Good games + good learning. New York, NY: Peter Lang Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Godwin-Jones, R. (2014). Games in language learning: Opportunities and challenges. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 18(2), 9–19. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/issues/june2014/emerging.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, C-Y. (2009). A case study using synchronous computer-mediated communication system for spoken English teaching and learning based on sociocultural theory and communicative language teaching approach curriculum (Unpublished doctoral dissertation). Ohio University, Athens, OH.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leontiev, A. N. (1978). Activity, consciousness, and personality. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Makuch, E. (2015). Blizzard will no longer report World of Warcraft subscriber numbers. Retrieved from http://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-will-no-longer-reportworld-of-warcraft-s/1100-6431943/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitchell, A., &amp; Savill-Smith, C. (2004). The use of computer and video games for learning: A review of the literature. London: LSDA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nardi, B., Ly, S., &amp; Harris, J. (2007). Learning conversations in World of Warcraft. In The Proceedings of the 2007 Hawaii International Conference on Systems Science (p. 79). New York, NY: IEEE Press. https://doi.org/10.1109/HICSS.2007.321</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2010). Massively multiplayer online role-playing games as arenas for language learning. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 23(5), 429–439. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2010.520673</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2011). Digital gaming and second language development: Japanese learners interactions in a MMORPG. Digital Culture &amp; Education, 3(1), 56–73. Retrieved from http://www.digitalcultureandeducation.com/cms/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/dce1048_peterson_2011.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2012a). Language learner interaction in a massively multiplayer online roleplaying game. In H. Reinders (Ed.), Digital games in language learning and teaching. (pp. 70–92). Basingstoke: Palgrave Macmillan. https://doi.org/10.1057/9781137005267_5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2012b). Learner interaction in a massively multiplayer online role playing game (MMORPG): A sociocultural discourse analysis. ReCALL, 24(3), 361–380. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344012000195</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2013). Computer games and language learning. New York, NY. Palgrave Macmillan. https://doi.org/10.1057/9781137005175</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Purushotma, R., Thorne, S. L., &amp; Wheatley, J. (2009). Language learning and video games: 10 key principles for designing video games for foreign language learning. Retrieved from: https://lingualgames.wordpress.com/article/10-key-principles-for-designing-video-27mkxqba7b13d-2/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rama, P. S., Black, R. W., Van Es, E., &amp; Warschauer, M. (2012). Affordances for second language learning in World of Warcraft. ReCALL, 24(3), 322–338. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344012000171</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rankin, Y., Gold, R., &amp; Gooch, B. (2006). 3D Role-playing games as language learning tools. In E. Gröller &amp; L. Szirmay-Kalos (Eds.), Proceedings of EuroGraphics 2006, 25(3). New York, NY: ACM.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reinders, H., &amp; Wattana, S. (2011). Learn English or die: The effects of digital games on interaction and willingness to communicate in a foreign language. Digital Culture &amp; Education, 3(1), 3–29. Retrieved from http://www.digitalcultureandeducation.com/cms/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/dce1049_reinders_2011.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reinders, H., &amp; Wattana, S. (2015). Affect and willingness to communicate in digital gamebased learning. ReCall, 27(1), 38–57. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344014000226</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siwek, S. (2014). Video games in the 21st century. The 2014 report. Retrieved from http://www.theesa.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/VideoGames21stCentury_2014.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suh, S., Kim, S. W., &amp; Kim, N. J. (2010). Effectiveness of MMORPG-based instruction in elementary English education in Korea. Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 26(5), 370–378. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2729.2010.00353.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sykes, J., &amp; Holden, C. (2011). Communities: Exploring digital games and social networking. In L. Ducate and N. Arnold (Eds.), Present and future promises of CALL: From theory and research to new directions in language teaching, CALICO monograph 2011, (pp. 311–336). San Marco, TX: CALICO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sykes, J., Reinhardt, J., &amp; Thorne, S. (2010). Multiuser digital games as sites for research and practice. In F. Hult (Ed.), Directions and prospects for educational linguistics (pp. 117–136). New York, NY: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-90-481-9136-9_8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sylvén, L. K., &amp; Sundqvist, P. (2012). Similarities between playing World of Warcraft and CLIL. Apples—Journal of Applied Language Studies, 6(2), 113–130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">THEESA (The Entertainment Software Association). (2015). Industry facts. Retrieved from http://www.theesa.com/facts/index.asp</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L. (2008). Mediating technologies and second language learning. In D. Leu, J. Coiro, C. Lankshear, &amp; M. Knobel (Eds.), Handbook of research on new literacies (pp. 417–449). Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., &amp; Black, R. (2007). Language and literacy development in computer-mediated contexts and communities. Annual Review of Applied Linguistics, 27, 133–160. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0267190508070074</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., Black, R., &amp; Sykes, J. (2009). Second language use, socialization, and learning in internet interest communities and online gaming. The Modern Language Journal, 93 (Focus issue), 802–821. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2009.00974.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vosburg, D. (2015). Language learning in an MMORPG (massively multiplayer online roleplaying game): A case study of L2 learners of German. (Unpublished doctoral dissertation). Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wattana, S. (2013). Talking while Playing: The Effects of Computer Games on Interaction and Willingness to Communicate in English (Unpublished doctoral dissertation). University of Canterbury, Canterbury.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, Y., &amp; Lai, C. (2009). MMORPGs and foreign language education. In R. Ferdig, Handbook of research on effective electronic gaming in education (pp. 402–422). Hershey, PA: Information Science Reference. https://doi.org/10.4018/978-1-59904-808-6.ch024</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, D., Bischoff, M., &amp; Gilliland, B. (2015). Vocabulary learning in massively multiplayer online games: Context and action before words. Education Technology, Research and Development, 63(5), 771–790. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11423-015-9387-4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
