<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277567</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Mileage Influence on Conversion Efficiency of Catalytic Converter from In-Use Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tartakovsky</surname>
                  <given-names>Leonid</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Baibikov</surname>
                  <given-names>Vladimir</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Veinblat</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Popescu</surname>
                  <given-names>Doron</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zvirin</surname>
                  <given-names>Yoram</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gutman</surname>
                  <given-names>Marcel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Technion Israel Inst. of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1617</fpage>
         <lpage>1623</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277567"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Although many works are published about the achieved advancements in the manufacturing of the catalytic converters (CC) system for vehicle engines and their testing under laboratory conditions, there is a lack in the published research about the mileages influence on their conversion efficiency (CE). Dependence of dual-brick CCs' CE in real-world driving conditions on vehicle mileage is studied for the first time. The CC tested are dismantled from the vehicles with mileage from 0 (new one) up to 150000 km. The studied CC are evaluated at the engine test bench containing a dynamometer coupled with a spark ignition engine suitable for this type of CC system. Measurements of CC efficiency are performed at four different engine operation regimes: two loaded regimes and two non-load regimes - low and high speed idling. It is found that the oxidation of CO and HC at all four tested regimes took place almost totally in the first CC. Under higher engine loads the conversion of NOx also took place mainly in the first CC. The overall efficiency of conversion reaches values above 99% for most of the tested systems. No significant degradation of CE is found in the studied vehicle mileage range. CE of the CC system that has accumulated the highest mileage, of almost 150000 km, reaches values of 97-99% for CO, 86-99% for HC and 64-99% for NOx at the loaded testing regimes. The smaller values are obtained for the low load regime when the CC temperature is decreased. Considering that the European legislation imposes a durability of 160000 km for the CCs, the results obtained in this work show that for the mileage of 150000 km CC keep a very high CE rate. The CC system that included an aftermarket non-genuine CC is the only one, where significant catalyst deactivation is observed. Registered values of the backpressure do not show any of the tested CC systems as being clogged.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller-Haas, K., Rice, M., Dean, R., Olsen, R. et al., “Development of Advanced Metallic Substrate Design for Close Coupled Converter Application,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1262, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inaguma, T., Konya, S., Sakamoto, H., Yamauchi, T. et al., “New Type of Metal Substrates for Catalytic Converters Durability for Elevated Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1264, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watson, M. and González, J., “Engineered Mat Technology for High Temperature Close Coupled Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1077, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagel, T. and Diringer, J., “Minimum Test Requirements for High Cell- Density, Ultra-Thin Wall Catalyst Supports; Part I,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0495, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0495.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold, L., Collins, N., Cooper, J., Eyre, D. et al., “Development and Application of New Low Rhodium Three-Way Catalyst Technology,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0046, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bonnefoy, F., De Meyer, J., and Steenackers, P., “High Flexibility in Converter Design by Using Modular Block Metallic Substrates,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0497, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0497.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brisley, R., Collins, N., French, C., Morris, D. et al., “Development of Advanced Platinum-Rhodium Catalyst for Future Emissions Requirements,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3627, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-3627.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williamson, W., Denison, G., Starin, G., and Robota, H., “Palladium- Rhodium Catalyst Strategies for LEV Emission Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 972844, 1997, doi: 10.4271/972844.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williamson, W., Dou, D., and Robota, H., “Dual-Catalyst Underfloor LEV/ULEV Strategies for Effective Precious Metal Management,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0776, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0776.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, S., Bae, C., Lee, Y., and Han, T., “Effects of Engine Operating Conditions on Catalytic Converter Temperature in an SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1677, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1677.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Q., Zhao, B., Li, B., Zhou, R., “Application or rare earth modified Zr-based Ceria-Zirconia solid solution in three way catalyst for automotive emission control.” Environ. Sci. Technol. 2010, 44, 3870-3875, doi: 10.1021/es903957e.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rohart, E., Verdier, S., Takemori, H., Suda, E. et al., “High OSC CeO2/ZrO2 Mixed Oxides Used as Preferred Metal Carriers for Advanced Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1057, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lloyd, S. M., Lave, L.B., Matthews, H. S., “Life cycle benefits of using nanotechnology to stabilize platinum-group metal particles in automotive catalysts.” Environ. Sci. Technol. 2005, 39, 1384-1392, doi: 10.1021/es049325w.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">More, K., Kenik, E., Coffey, D., Geer, T. et al., “Thermally-Induced Microstructural Changes in a Three-Way Automotive Catalyst,” SAE Technical Paper 972905, 1997, doi: 10.4271/972905.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bomback, J. L., Wheeler, M. A., Tabock, J., Janowsky, J. D., “Distribution of contaminants in used automotive emission catalysts.” Environ. Sci. Technol. 1975, Vol 9, No. 2, 139-143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fishel, N. A., Lee, R. K., Wilhelm, F. C., “Poisoning of vehicle control catlysts by sulfur compounds.” Environ. Sci. Technol. 1974, Vol 8, No 3. 260-267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arapatsakos, C.I. and Sparis, P.D., “Catalyst regeneration via chemical treatment and emission tests at idle speeds.” Proc. Instn. Mech. Engrs. 1999, Vol. 213, Part D, 359-364, doi: 10.1177/095440709921300405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ball, D., Mohammed, A., and Schmidt, W., “Application of Accelerated Rapid Aging Test (RAT) Schedules with Poisons: The Effects of Oil Derived Poisons, Thermal Degradation and Catalyst Volume on FTP Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 972846, 1997, doi: 10.4271/972846.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beck, D., Sommers, J., DiMaggio, C., Monroe, D. et al., “Impact of Oil- Derived Catalyst Poisons on FTP Performance of LEV Catalyst Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 972842, 1997, doi: 10.4271/972842.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
