<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284818</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CFD Modelling of a Two Stroke Engine to Predict and Reduce Short Circuit Losses</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Garg</surname>
                  <given-names>Manish</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>TVS Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kumar</surname>
                  <given-names>Davinder</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>TVS Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Syed</surname>
                  <given-names>Madani</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>TVS Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nageswara</surname>
                  <given-names>Siva</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CD-adapco</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>355</fpage>
         <lpage>364</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284818"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>One of the major reason for lower efficiency and higher unburned hydrocarbon and carbon monoxide emission for two stroke engine is short circuit losses during the scavenging process. An attempt has been made in this study to understand and improve this phenomenon. A three dimensional transient CFD model is developed for a loop scavenged, Schnullar type, 70 cc two stroke engine. Three major processes, namely, blow down (expansion); scavenging and compression have been modelled. The model is validated with PIV measurement done in motoring mode. Model is also validated with experimental data for trapping efficiency with Watson method and for in-cylinder pressure during expansion, blow down and intake events. A good correlation is observed between experimental and simulation results. CFD model is used to quantify various parameters, such as, delivery ratio, trapping efficiency, scavenging efficiency, and amount of fresh mass short circuit at different load and speed points. Around 20 to 25% short circuit losses are observed at all the load cases analyzed. The mechanism for this short circuit loss is understood with the help of a passive scalars based visualization method. Two major root causes identified are, port design and exhaust pressure wave dynamics. Three different designs of ports are analyzed. With the best design, the short circuit loss is reduced by 12%. Same design has been tested on a chassis dynamo-meter, that resulted into a reduction of 10% in HC (hydro-carbon) emission in a mass emission test on a drive cycle and 10% to 25% improvement in WOT (wide open throttle) wheel force in mid and higher speed operating points.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Two-Stroke Cycle Engine, Its Development, Operation, and Design, by Heywood, J. B., and Sher, E. SAE International and Taylor &amp; Francis Group, ISBN: 1-56032-831-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coplin, N., “Simplification of Air Assisted Direct Injection via Performance Benchmarking,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3310, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oswald, R., Ebner, A., and Kirchberger, R., “High Efficient 125- 250 cm3 LPDI Two-Stroke Engines, a Cheap and Robust Alternative to Four-Stroke Solutions?,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-32-0019, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krimplstätter, S., Winkler, F., Oswald, R., and Kirchberger, R., “Air Cooled 50cm3 Scooter Euro 4 Application of the Two-Stroke LPDI Technology,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-32-0008, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-32-0008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garg, M. and Ravikrishna, R. V., “CFD Modeling of In-Cylinder Fuel- Air Mixing in a CNG-Fuelled SI Engine with Port Gas Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-32-0003, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garg, M. and Ravikrishna, R.V. (2014), ‘Effect of port gas injection on in-cylinder stratification in a CNG fuelled SI engine’, Progress in Computational Fluid Dynamics, Vol. 14, No. 4, pp.244-258.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murakami, Y., Kurosaka, H., and Kamiya, H., “Practical Application of Combustion Simulation using CFD for Small Engine of Two-Wheeled Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-32-0006, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004- 32-0006.CD-adapco Group (2006) Methodology STAR-CD version 4.00, pp.4.7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CD-adapco Group (2006) Methodology STAR-CD version 4.00, pp.4.7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">An Introduction to Combustion: Concepts and Applications by Turns Stephen, McGraw-Hill Science/Engineering/Math; 3 edition (January 24, 2011). ISBN-13: 978-0073380193</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asproulis, P. N. (1994) ‘High resolution numerical predictions of hypersonic flows on unstructured meshes’, Imperial College, Dept. of Aeronautics, Ph.D Dissertation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hashimoto, E., Tottori, T., and Terata, S., “Scavenging Performance Measurements of High Speed Two-Stroke Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 850182, 1985, doi:10.4271/850182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krishna, A., Mallikarjuna, J., Davinder, K., and Ramachandra Babu, Y., “In-Cylinder Flow Analysis in a Two-Stroke Engine - A Comparison of Different Turbulence Models Using CFD,” SAE Technical Paper 2013- 01-1085, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1085.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
