<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">finamana</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100419</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Financial Management</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Management Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00463892</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">1755053X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">3666058</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Corporate Performance and Adherence to Shareholder Wealth-Maximizing Principles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dan</given-names>
                  <surname>Cooper</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Glenn</given-names>
                  <surname>Petry</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i284591</issue-id>
         <fpage>71</fpage>
         <lpage>78</lpage>
         <page-range>71-78</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1994 Financial Management Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/3666058"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Positive finance focuses upon the observed actions of firms while normative finance prescribes firm actions in an ideal world. To analyze some of the correlations between normative and positive finance, we compile self-reported financial policies of a sample of Business Week 1,000 firms for comparison with five years of financial performance data. Indices of a firm's relative use of shareholder wealth maximizing (SWM) and sophisticated techniques are then constructed. We test three hypotheses. The first, that there is a positive relationship between firm size and index values, is based on the notion that large firms generally have larger corporate finance staffs and more access to computing power. The second, that index values are negatively related to firm risk. The third, that index values are positively related to industry-adjusted ex post corporate performance. In each case, the null hypothesis is that no such relationship exists. A portfolio analysis is undertaken to reveal whether these indices delineate the sample firms from a market perspective. A set of comparison portfolios ranked by total assets and market value of equity are also formed from the entire sample. These comparison portfolios control for size effect alone. If the index values are simply a proxy for firm size, the size-based comparison portfolios should yield similar return results as the index-ranked portfolios. The analysis produces significant results for the size and risk proxies (market value of equity, total assets, and Value Line's beta). As hypothesized, the size proxies are positively related to the index variables. The index values also exhibit the hypothesized negative relationship to the published risk proxy (the higher index values are associated with lower-risk firms). Perhaps not surprisingly, the sophistication index produced the highest significance levels for the size proxies. The industry-adjusted efficiency data for the indices reveal consistently significant but negative relationships. The efficiency measures indicate that low-index firms made better use of sales, assets, and working capital--this is an unanticipated result. The portfolio analysis also shows a negative link between portfolio performance and index values. The low-index firms outperformed both the market and the high-index portfolios over the five-year period. High-index firms generally performed below the market benchmark. The results are stable across portfolio sizes. The ex post portfolio risk measures (ex post beta and standard deviation) run counter to the Value Line beta and safety measures. The high-index portfolios were riskier according to ex post results. The size-based comparison portfolios generate no consistent risk-adjusted pattern. The positive relationship between the size proxies and the index values is consistent with the hypothesis that firm size is associated with the use of SWM policies and sophisticated evaluation techniques. As firms grow, the number of potentially profitable investment opportunities increases, and staffing levels and computing power must also grow in order to evaluate them. Evidence in a previous study by Hirshleifer suggests that a financial manager might adopt more advanced or sophisticated techniques, whatever the firm's investment opportunity set or capital structure concerns, as a means of maximizing reputation. He identifies three areas of bias that influence a manager's financial decision-making: visibility bias, resolution preference, and mimicry and avoidance. Hirshleifer's model of external (interfirm) reputation bias can be extended to apply to internal (intrafirm) circumstances. In Hirshleifer's terminology, a financial manager might undertake excess analysis because of visibility bias. An additional motivation is to mimic other apparently successful financial managers in order to insure some explanatory recourse in the event of poor performance. Less established or smaller firms are less likely to have excess analytical capacity. These firms are less hierarchical and may offer fewer career advancement opportunities. Managers in smaller firms are constrained by resource limitations such as time, staffing, and computer access. One cannot conclude that using SWM techniques causes lower returns. The use of SWM techniques should produce either no relationship or a positive relationship. Careful examination of various subsamples suggest that the index values may be proxies for corporate life-cycle effects. The evolution of corporate financial decision-making closely follows maturation of a firm. The index values portray this process. Comments from respondents support this point of view. Low index-value firm managers indicated that they are less interested in employing absolute optimal standards and more interested in firm competitiveness and survival. Managers in higher index-value (larger) firms are generally more preoccupied with methodologies, expressing interest in evidence supporting empirically proven superior techniques. These comments are consistent with the life-cycle perspective. We believe that the evidence supports the theory of a corporate progression or evolution.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d71e132a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e139" publication-type="journal">
S. F. Haka, L. Gordon, and G. Pinches, "Sophisticated Capital
Budgeting Selection Techniques and Firm Performance," The
Accounting Review (October 1985), pp. 651-669.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/247460</object-id>
               <fpage>651</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e158a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e165" publication-type="journal">
K. L.Hastie, "One Businessman's View of Capital Budgeting,"
Financial Management (Winter 1974), pp. 36-44.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/3664928</object-id>
               <fpage>36</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e181a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e188" publication-type="journal">
K. Hickman, and G. Petry, "A Comparison of Stock Price
Prediction Using Court Accepted Formulas and Dividend
Discount and P/E Models," Financial Management (Summer
1990), pp. 76-87.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/3665636</object-id>
               <fpage>76</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e211a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e218" publication-type="journal">
D. Hirshleifer, "Managerial Reputation and Corporate Investment
Decisions," Financial Management (Summer 1993), pp. 145-160.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/3665866</object-id>
               <fpage>145</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e235a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e242" publication-type="book">
Industly Norms and Key Business Ratios, New York, NY, Dunn
&amp; Bradstreet Credit Services, 1990.<source>Industly Norms and Key Business Ratios</source>
               <year>1990</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e258a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e265" publication-type="journal">
S. H. Kim, "An Empirical Study on the Relationship Between
Capital Budgeting Practices and Earnings Performance,"
Engineering Economist (Spring 1982), pp. 185-196.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kim</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>Spring</issue>
               <fpage>185</fpage>
               <source>Engineering Economist</source>
               <year>1982</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e300a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e309" publication-type="journal">
T. P. Klammer, "The Association of Capital Budgeting
Techniques with Firm Performance," The Accounting Review
(April 1978), pp. 353-364.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/244924</object-id>
               <fpage>353</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e328a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e335" publication-type="journal">
D. Miller and P. H. Friesen, "A Longitudinal Study of the
Corporate Life Cycle," Management Science (October 1984), p.
161.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2631384</object-id>
               <fpage>161</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e354a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e361" publication-type="book">
M. E. Porter, Competitive Strategy, New York, N.Y., Free Press,
1981.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Porter</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <source>Competitive Strategy</source>
               <year>1981</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e386a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e393" publication-type="journal">
R. E. Quinn and K. Cameron, "Organizational Life Cycles and
Shifting Criteria of Effectiveness: Some Preliminary Evidence,"
Management Science (January 1983), p. 35.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2631164</object-id>
               <fpage>35</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e413a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e420" publication-type="journal">
G. G. Ramirez, D. A. Waldman, and D. J. Lasser, "Research
Needs in Corporate Finance: Perspectives from Financial
Managers," Financial Management (Summer 1991), pp. 17-29.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/3665726</object-id>
               <fpage>17</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e439a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e446" publication-type="book">
W. F. Sharpe and G. J. Alexander, Investments, Englewood Cliffs,
N.J., Prentice Hall, 1990, pp. 739-753.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Sharpe</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <fpage>739</fpage>
               <source>Investments</source>
               <year>1990</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d71e475a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d71e482" publication-type="journal">
G. L. Sundem, "Evaluating Capital Budgeting Models in
Simulated Environments," Journal of Finance (September 1975),
pp. 977-992.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/2326717</object-id>
               <fpage>977</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
