<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26605591</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>School Spending in England 2010–15</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sibieta</surname>
                  <given-names>Luke</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26605589</issue-id>
         <fpage>283</fpage>
         <lpage>302</lpage>

         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26605591"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>School spending in England has been relatively protected over the past five years, with day-to-day school spending per pupil rising by about 0.6 per cent in real terms. This contrasts with cuts to other areas of education spending and across other areas of government spending more generally. This real-terms increase has been delivered by an increase in funding going to the most disadvantaged pupils via the pupil premium. (Other types of funding were frozen in cash terms per pupil.) One of the consequences of this reform is that funding is increasingly concentrated on schools catering for the highest proportions of pupils from disadvantaged backgrounds. This is in contrast to school systems in some other countries (for example, the US), where resources tend to be more highly correlated with local property values. Looking forward, rising pupil numbers, together with reforms that will increase the cost of employing staff, will contribute to increasing school costs over the coming years, with school spending needing to increase by at least 20 per cent in cash terms just to keep funding per pupil constant in real terms after accounting for expected cost increases for schools.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Allen, R., Belfield, C., Greaves, E., Sharp, C. and Walker, M. (2014), The Costs and Benefits of Different Initial Teacher Training Routes, Report no. R100, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7435).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Card, D. and Payne, A. A. (2002), ‘School finance reform, the distribution of school spending, and the distribution of student test scores’, Journal of Public Economics, vol. 83, pp. 49–82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Chowdry, H., Muriel, A. and Sibieta, L. (2008), Level Playing Field? The Implications of School Funding, Reading: CfBT Education Trust (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/4252).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Chowdry, H. and Sibieta, L. (2011), ‘School funding reform: an empirical analysis of options for a national funding formula’, Institute for Fiscal Studies, Briefing Note no. BN123 http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/5754).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Crawford, C. and Britton, J. (2015), Estimating the Cost to Government of Providing Undergraduate and Postgraduate Education, Report no. R105, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7674).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">De Haan, M. (2014), ‘The effect of additional funds for low-ability pupils: a nonparametric bounds analysis’, Economic Journal, doi: 10.1111/ecoj.12221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Department for Education (2014), ‘Fairer schools funding in 2015-16’, Consultation Document (https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/fairer-schools-funding-2015-to-2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Department for Education and Skills (2003), ‘Statistics of education: education and training expenditure since 1993-94’, National Statistics Bulletin no. 04/03.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Fernandez, R. and Rogerson, R. (2003), ‘Equity and resources: an analysis of education finance systems’, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 111, pp. 858–97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Hanushek, E. (2003), ‘The failure of input-based schooling policies’, Economic Journal, vol. 113, pp. F64–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">House of Commons Education Committee (2015), Academies and Free Schools, Fourth Report of Session 2014–15, HC258 (http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201415/cmselect/cmeduc/258/258.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Hoxby, C. M. (2001), ‘All school finance equalizations are not created equal’, Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 116, pp. 1189–231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Leuven, E., Lindahl, M., Oosterbeek, H. and Webbink, D. (2007), ‘The effect of extra funding for disadvantaged pupils on achievement’, Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 89, pp. 721–36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Machin, S., McNally, S. and Meghir, C. (2010), ‘Resources and standards in urban schools’, Journal of Human Capital, vol. 4, pp. 365–93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Sibieta, L. (2015a), ‘The distribution of school funding and inputs in England: 1993–2013’, Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. W15/10 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7645).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Sibieta, L. (2015b), ‘Schools spending’, Institute for Fiscal Studies, Briefing Note no. BN168 http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/7669).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Silva, F. and Sonstelie, J. (1995), ‘Did Serrano cause a decline in school spending?’, National Tax Journal, vol. 48, pp. 199–215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Verstegen, D. A. and Jordan, T. S. (2009), ‘A fifty-state survey of school finance policies and programs: an overview’, Journal of Education Finance, vol. 34, pp. 213–30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">West, A. (2009), ‘Redistribution and financing schools in England under Labour: are resources going where needs are greatest?’, Education Management, Administration and Leadership, vol. 37, pp. 158–79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">West, A., West, R., Pennell, H. and Travers, T. (2001), ‘Financing school-based education in England: poverty, examination results and expenditure’, Environment and Planning C: Government and Policy, vol. 19, pp. 461–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Change in Department for Education DEL budget, 2010–11 to 2014–15</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Increases in various components of public spending, 1998 to 2009</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Changes in funding per pupil by quintile of school deprivation level between 2010–11 and 2014–15 (2015–16 prices)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Changes in local authority funding per pupil by level of deprivation, 2015–16</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Changes in local authority funding per pupil by region, 2015–16</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Actual and forecast pupil numbers at state-funded schools</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
