<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285053</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study on Engine Hood with Negative Poisson's Ratio Architected Composites Based on Pedestrian Protection</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Zhao</surname>
                  <given-names>Ying</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jilin University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ma</surname>
                  <given-names>Fangwu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jilin University Automotive Engrg College</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Longfan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jilin University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yueqiang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>China FAW Group Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Liang</surname>
                  <given-names>Hongyu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Jilin University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>391</fpage>
         <lpage>404</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285053"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The conventional hood with single material and stiffener structural form conceals some limitations on pedestrian protection and lightweight, not satisfying the requirements of structural strength, pedestrian protection and lightweight contradictory with each other at the same time. In this paper, a novel type hood is proposed to develop sandwich structure using architected cellular material with negative Poisson's ratio (NPR) configuration based on the decoupling thought of structural strength and energy absorption. Core-layer aluminum alloy material with NPR is used to meet the requirement of impact energy absorption, inner and outer skin using carbon fiber is selected to achieve high structural stiffness needed. This paper starts from the relations between geometric parameters of core-layer architected cellular material and mechanical properties, on this basis, the optimal geometric parameters can be expected using the multiobjective optimization method. Eventually, the optimal novel hood can be obtained using three layer thicknesses as optimization variables, minimum HIC value and minimum mass as objectives. It should be noted that global stiffness of the novel hood is not less than that of conventional hood, and entire thickness of the novel hood is not larger than conventional hood and impact intrusion of novel hood is less than safe distance between hood and engine. Based on limitations above, optimal layer thicknesses of architected cellular structure can be achieved. Then, the novel hood is compared with the conventional hood. The results show that the average HIC value of corresponding collision points in the novel hood decreases by 45%. In addition, bending stiffness of the novel hood achieved increases by 33%, and torsional stiffness increases by 67%. While the weight is reduced, 18.95% exactly. Thus, the novel hood proposed in this paper demonstrates outstanding performance in terms of pedestrian protection, structural stiffness enhancement and weight reduction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label> 
            <kwd>Architected Composites</kwd> 
            <kwd>Negative Poisson's Ratio</kwd> 
            <kwd>Pedestrian Protection</kwd> 
            <kwd>HIC</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ying-Hua Y U, Zhi-Chao L I, Liu J F. Research present situation and prospect for application on porous foam aluminum[J]. Journal of Liaoning Technical University, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xinchun Zhang. Dynamic Performance of Cellular Metal Materials and Their Microstructural Design[D]. Beijing Jiaotong University. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma Z, Bian H, Sun C, Hulbert GM, Bishnoi K, Rostam-Abadi F. Functionallygraded NPR material for a blast-protective deflector; 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scarpa F, Yates JR, Ciffo LG, Patsias S. Dynamic crushing of auxetic open-cell polyurethane foam. J Mech Eng Sci 2002;216(12):1153-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller W, Ren Z, Smith C W, et al. A negative Poisson's ratio carbon fiber composite using a negative Poisson's ratio yarn reinforcement [J]. Composites Science and Technology, 2012, 72(7): 761-766.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pasternak E, Dyskin A V. Materials and structures with macroscopic negative Poisson's ratio [J]. International Journal of Engineering Science, 2012,52: 103-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertoldi K, Reis P M, Willshaw S, et al. Negative Poisson's ratio behavior induced by an elastic instability[J]. Advanced Materials, 2010,22(3): 361-366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pasternak E, Dyskin A V. Materials and structures with macroscopic negative Poisson's ratio[J]. International Journal of Engineering Science, 2012, 52:103-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grima J N, Caruana-Gauci R, Attard D, et al. Three-dimensional cellular structures with negative Poisson's ratio and negative compressibility properties [J]. Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences. 2012,468(2146); 3121-3138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olympio K R, Gandhi F. Zero Poisson's ratio cellular honeycombs for flex skins undergoing one-dimensional morphing [J]. Journal of Intelligent Material Systems and Structures,2010,21(17):1737-1753.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gibson L J, Ashby M F, Schajer G S, et al. The mechanics of twodimensional cellular materials [J]. Proceedings of the Royal Society of London Series A:Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences, 1982,382(1782): 25-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babaee S, Shim J, Weaver J C, et al. 3D Soft metamaterials with negative Poisson's ratio [J]. Advanced Materials, 2013, el al. Composite chiral structures for morphing airfoils: Num 25(36); 5044-5049.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Veltin B A, Gandhi F. Effect of cell geometry on energy absorption of honeycombs under in plane compression [J]. AIAA Journal, 2010,48(2): 466-478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tekog C, Gibson L J, Pardoen T, et al. Size effects in foams: Experiments and modeling [J]. Progress in Materials Science, 2011, 56(2): 109-138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fozdar D Y, Soman P, Lee J W, et al. Three-Dimensional Polymer Constructs Exhibiting a Tunable Negative Poisson's Ratio [J]. Advanced Functional Materials, 2011, 21(14): 2712-2720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meng L Q, Wu Y, Chen S Z, et al. Quasi-static failure analysis of honeycomb sandwich beam with composite facesheets [J]. Advanced Materials Research, 2011, 160: 855-859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller W, Smith C W, Evans K E. Honeycomb cores with enhanced buckling strength [J].Composite Structures, 2011,93(3): 1072-1077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cricri G, Perrella M, Call C. Honeycomb failure processes under in-plane loading [J]. Composites Part B: Engineering, 2013,45(1):1079- 1090.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang X, Ding H, An L, et al. Numerical Investigation on Dynamic Crushing Behavior of Auxetic Honeycombs with Various Cell-Wall Angles [J]. Advances in Mechanical Engineering, 2015, 7(2):679678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hou Y, Tai Y H, Lira C, et al. The bending and failure of sandwich structures with auxetic gradient cellular cores [J]. Composites Part A: Applied Science and Manufacturing, 2013, 49:119-131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strek T, Jopek H, Maruszewski B T, et al. Computational analysis of sandwich-structured composites with an auxetic phase [J]. Physica Status Solidi (B), 2014, 251(2): 354-366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olympio K R, Gandhi F. Flexible skins for morphing aircraft using cellular honeycomb cores [J]. Journal of Intelligent Material Systems and Structures, 2010, 21(17):1719-1735.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen Q, Pugno N M. In-plane elastic buckling of hierarchical honeycomb materials [J]. European Journal of Mechanics-A/Solids, 2012, 34:120-129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
