<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">90006033</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Numerical Study on the Improvement of the Performance of a Banki Wind Turbine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wenlong</surname>
                  <given-names>Tian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Baowei</surname>
                  <given-names>Song</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhaoyong</surname>
                  <given-names>Mao</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>School of Marine Science and Technology, Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi’an, China, 710072</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">38</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e90006025</issue-id>
         <fpage>109</fpage>
         <lpage>116</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90006033"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Banki wind turbine is a kind of vertical axis wind turbine (VAWT) with high solidity, and has been proved to have a relatively high starting torque and maximum power coefficient under low wind conditions. This study introduces an arcshaped windshield to further improve the performance of Banki wind turbines. The windshield is placed in front of the turbine to deflect wind and reduce the negative torque on the blades in the upwind direction. Computational investigations are carried out to study the influence of the angle of the arc-shaped windshield on the performance of the turbine using the commercial computational fluid dynamics (CFD) code Fluent 13.0. The results demonstrated that the maximum power coefficient of the Banki wind turbine was increased by 66.9% with the optimal windshield angle of 60°. The maximum power coefficient was found to be 0.2784 at a tip speed ratio of 0.5 in the presence of the windshield.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>vertical axis wind turbine</kwd>
            <x>,</x>
            <kwd>VAWT</kwd>
            <x>,</x>
            <kwd>Banki</kwd>
            <x>,</x>
            <kwd>CFD</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herbert G M J, Iniyan S, Sreevalsan E, et al. A review of wind energy technologies. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 2007, 11:1117-1145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pope K, Naterer G and Dincer I et al. Power correlation for vertical axis wind turbines with varying geometries. International Journal of Energy Research, 2011, 35:423-435.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mishnaevsky L, Freere P and Sinha R et al. Small wind turbines with timber blades for developing countries: materials choice, development, installation and experiences. Renewable Energy. 2011, 36:2128-2138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Armstrong S, Fiedler A and Tullis S. Flow separation on a high Reynolds number, high solidity vertical axis wind turbine with straight and canted blades and canted blades with fences. Renewable Energy. 2012, 41:13-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang B, Lawn C. Fluid dynamic performance of a vertical axis turbine for tidal currents. Renewable Energy, 2011, 36:3355-3366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Declaire P, Engblom S and Agren O et al. Analytical solutions for a single blade in vertical axis turbine motion in two-dimensions. European Journal of Mechanics B/Fluids, 2009, 28:506-520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ye L, Calisal M. Three-dimensional effects and arm effects on modeling a vertical axis tidal current turbine. Renewable Energy, 2010, 35:2325-2334.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lain S, Osorio C. Simulation and evaluation of a straight-bladed Darrieus-type cross flow marine turbine. Journal of Scientific &amp; Industrial Research, 2010, 69:906-912.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Howell R, Qin N, and Edwards J et al. Wind tunnel and numerical study of a small vertical axis wind turbine. Renewable Energy, 2010, 35:412-422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schonbore A, Chantzidakis M. Development of a hydraulic control mechanism for cyclic pitch marine current turbines. Renewable Energy, 2007, 32:662-679.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ponta F, Dutt G. An improved vertical axis water current turbine incorporating a channeling device. Renewable Energy, 2000, 20:223 -241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gupta R, Biswas A. Computational fluid dynamics analysis of a twisted three-bladed H-Darrieus rotor. Renewable and Sustainable Energy, 2010, 2:1–15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McTavish S, Feszty D and Sankar T. Steady and rotating computational fluid dynamics simulations of a novel vertical axis wind turbine for small-scale power generation. Renewable Energy, 2012, 41:171-179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saha U, Thotla S and Maity D. Optimum design configuration of Savonius rotor through wind tunnel experiments. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics, 2008, 96:1359-1375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Irabu K, Roy J. Study of direct force measurement and characteristics on blades of Savonius rotor at static state. Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science, 2011, 35:653-659.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akwa J, Junior G and Petry A. Discussion on the verification of the overlap ratio influence on performance coefficients of a Savonius wind rotor using computational fluid dynamics. Renewable Energy, 2012, 38:141-149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golecha K, Eldho T and Prabhu S. Influence of the deflector plate on the performance of modified Savonius water turbine. Applied Energy, 2011, 88: 3207-3217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Altan B, Atilgan M. An experimental and numerical study on the improvement of the performance of Savonius wind rotor. Energy Conversion and Management, 2008, 49:3425-3432.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dragomirescu A. Performance assessment of a small wind turbine with crossflow runner by numerical simulations. Renewable Energy, 2011, 36:957-965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fluent 13.0 user’s guide. ANSYS Inc., 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
