<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>אגוד הבנקים בישראל</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">ג'</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i24010139</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24010926</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Report on the Issue of and the Trade in Securities / דין וחשבון הועדה להנפקת נירות ערך ולמסחר בהם</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>1963</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>78</fpage>
         <lpage>88</lpage>
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24010926"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>BACKGROUND, PROBLEMS AND PRINCIPLES In recent years, there has been a considerable expansion in the amount of securities that have been issued. The old Tel-Aviv blearing Hause for Securities established in 1936, has developed into the present Stock Exchange. Up to a few years ago, the volume of business transacted in the Stock Exchange was small. The following figures indicate recent developments. For example, in 1956, total securities issued amounted to IL 44.0 millions, of which IL 1.3 millions represented shares, whilst in 1961, securities issued totalled IL 233.0 millions comprising IL 50.0 millions in shares. In 1962 total securities issued reached a figure of IL 214.0 millions of which IL 34.0 millions were in shares and the rest in Government and private debentures. This noteworthy growth is also reflected in the total nominal value of securities registered in the Stock Excange, which increased from IL 148.0 millions (including IL 18.0 millions in share) in 1958 to IL 898.0 millions in 1962 (including IL 196.0 millions in shares). The volume of transactions dealt with in the Stock Excange tells a similar story. This went up from IL 72.0 millions in 1960, to IL 122.0 millions in 1962. The figures for the first quarter of 1963, show a further increase. This quick expansion in the securities market has made it necessary for the Government to arrange for an investigation to be conducted into the legal and administrative aspects of this market. The necessity did not arise because of some special deficiencies or difficulties that have been encountered, but in view of the importance attached to this market from the public point of view. A Committee was accordingly appointed by the Government for this purpose. The main objectives of the Committee were to suggest ways for strengthening of confidence of the local public as well as of foreign investors in the Israel securities market. To attain these objectives, the Committee deemed it necessary to impose on all concerned, civil and penal liabilities, and to establish Government supervision over the issuing and the placing of securities on the market and to regulate the trade in them. The majority of the Committee was of the opinion that the said supervision should not comprise an examination into the quality of the security, its speculative character etc. EXISTING LEGAL REQUIREMENTS As regards the existing legal position, the Companies Ordinance requires, that a prospectus be issued, if the public is invited to subscribe to shares or debentures. The provisions of the above Ordinance require every company, whether it has issued shares or not, to submit an annual return to the Registrar of Companies. The issue of shares, is subject to licensing by the Finance Minister, under the Defence (Finance) Regulations, 1941, and the issuing of debentures is subject to approval under the Companies Ordinance. Trading in securities is not regulated by law. From the administrative point of view, the duties of the Registar of Companies are to ensure that a prospectus is issued and that certain requisite documents be sunmitted to him. These may be examined by the public. In addition, the Finance Minister, appointed a few years ago, two Committees to examine applications for the issuing of securities. These Committees, in carrying out their duties, are assisted by officers, especially appointed for this purpose by the Ministry of Finance, which, together with the Bank of Israel, (The Central Bank) are both represented on the management of the Stock Exchange. The management of the Stock Exchange is free to decide whether any security should be added to the Stock Exchange list, or, whether it should be refused. The Committee on the Issue and Trading in Securities is of the opinion that the following legal and administrative changes should be made: 1. The obligation to issue a prospectus should apply to various other securities besides shares and debentures. 2. The prospectus should be more detailed. 3. Companies that have issued securities to the public, should be required to submit regular returns on their activities. 4. The Stock Exchange should have a legal status and its own regulations should be based on certain principles to be determined. 5. A special Authority should be established and charged with supervising and enforcing the legislation to be enacted subsequently regarding the issuing of prospectuses, the submission of regular returns, the drafting of the Stock Exchange repulations, and should ensure compliance therewith. 6. This Authority should be independent and separate from the licensing Agencies, the latters' functions being the encouragement of investments, savings schemes, the Companies Ordinance, the Defence (Finance) Regulations, etc.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>[הערות שוליים]</title>
        <ref id="d22e120a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e124" publication-type="other">
בשנים 1961 ר1962 אין הפרדה בין מלוות בערבות הממשלה לבין אגדות חוב אחרית.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


