<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285082</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of a RANS-Based Knock Model to Infer the Knock Probability in a Research Spark-Ignition Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>D'Adamo</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Modena</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Breda</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastiano</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Modena</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Iaccarino</surname>
                  <given-names>Salvatore</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Modena</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Berni</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Modena</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fontanesi</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefano</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Modena</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Zardin</surname>
                  <given-names>Barbara</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Modena</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Borghi</surname>
                  <given-names>Massimo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Modena</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Irimescu</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Merola</surname>
                  <given-names>Simona</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori CNR</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>722</fpage>
         <lpage>739</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285082"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Engine knock is one of the most limiting factors for modern Spark-Ignition (SI) engines to achieve high efficiency targets. The stochastic nature of knock in SI units hinders the predictive capability of RANS knock models, which are based on ensemble averaged quantities.</p>
            <p>To this aim, a knock model grounded in statistics was recently developed in the RANS formalism. The model is able to infer a presumed log-normal distribution of knocking cycles from a single RANS simulation by means of transport equations for variances and turbulence-derived probability density functions (PDFs) for physical quantities. As a main advantage, the model is able to estimate the earliest knock severity experienced when moving the operating condition into the knocking regime.</p>
            <p>In this paper, improvements are introduced in the model, which is then applied to simulate the knock signature of a single-cylinder 400cm³ direct-injection SI unit with optical access; the engine is operated with two spark timings, under knock-safe and knocking conditions respectively. The statistical prediction of knock resulting from the presented knock model is compared to the experimental evidence for both investigated conditions.</p>
            <p>The agreement between the predicted and the measured knock distributions validates the proposed knock model. Finally, limitations and some unprecedented possibilities given by the model are critically discussed, with particular emphasis on the meaning of RANS knock prediction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahnz, C., and Spicher, U., “Irregular combustion in supercharged spark ignition engines: Pre-ignition and other phenomena,” International Journal of Engine Research 2010(11), 485-498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhen, X., Wang, Y., Xu, S., Zhu, Y., Tao, C., Xu, T., Song, M., The engine knock analysis - An overview, Applied Energy 2012;92:628-36, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2011.11.079.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert, A., Richard, S., Colin, O., Martinez, L., De Francqueville, D., “LES prediction and analysis of knocking combustion in a spark ignition engine,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Volume 35, Issue 3, 2015, Pages 2941-2948</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Misdariis, A., Vermorel, O., Poinsot, T., “LES of knocking in engines using dual heat transfer and two-step reduced schemes,” Combustion and Flame, Volume 162, Issue 11, November 2015, Pages 4304-4312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontanesi S., d'Adamo A., Rutland C.J., Large-Eddy simulation analysis of spark configuration effect on cycle-to-cycle variability of combustion and knock, International Journal of Engine Research, April 2015; Vol. 16, 3: pp. 403-418., first published on January 9, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontanesi, S., Paltrinieri, S., D'Adamo, A., Cantore, G. et al., "Knock Tendency Prediction in a High Performance Engine Using LES and Tabulated Chemistry," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):98-118, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1082.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">d’Adamo, A., Breda, S., Cantore, G., “Large-Eddy Simulation of Cycle- Resolved Knock in a Turbocharged SI Engine,” Energy Procedia 82 (2015) 45-50, doi:10.1016/j.egypro.2015.11.881.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontanesi S., Paltrinieri S., d'Adamo A. and Duranti S., Investigation of Boundary Condition and Field Distribution Effects on the Cycle-to- Cycle Variability of a Turbocharged GDI Engine Using LES, Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology - Rev. IFP Energies nouvelles, Vol. 69 (2014), No. 1, pp. 107-128 DOI:10.2516/ogst/2013142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">d'Adamo, A., Breda, S., Fontanesi, S., and Cantore, G., "LES Modelling of Spark-Ignition Cycle-to-Cycle Variability on a Highly Downsized DISI Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(5):2029-2041, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2403.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Breda, S., D'Adamo, A., Fontanesi, S., Giovannoni, N. et al., "CFD Analysis of Combustion and Knock in an Optically Accessible GDI Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(1):641-656, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forte, C., Bianchi, G.M., Corti, E., Fantoni, S., Costa, M., “CFD Methodology for the evaluation of knock of a PFI Twin Spark engine,” Energy Procedia 45 ( 2014 ) 859 - 868.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Linse, D., Kleemann, A., Hasse, C., “Probability density function approach coupled with detailed chemical kinetics for the prediction of knock in turbocharged direct injection spark ignition engines,” Combustion and Flame 161 (2014) 997-1014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D'Adamo, A., Breda, S., Fontanesi, S., and Cantore, G., "A RANSBased CFD Model to Predict the Statistical Occurrence of Knock in Spark-Ignition Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(1):618-630, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0581.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spelina, J.M., Peyton Jones, J. C., Frey, J., “Characterization of knock intensity distributions: Part 1: statistical independence and scalar measures, “Published online before print August 15, 2013, doi: 10.1177/0954407013496233, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering February 2014 vol. 228 no. 2 117-128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spelina, J.M., Peyton Jones, J. C., Frey, J., “Characterization of knock intensity distributions Part 2: parametric models,” Published online before print August 23, 2013, doi: 10.1177/0954407013496234, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering August 23, 2013 0954407013496234.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leppard, W., "Individual-Cylinder Knock Occurence and Intensity in Multicylinder Engines," SAE Technical Paper 820074, 1982, doi:10.4271/820074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferraro, CV, Millo, F., Fenoglio, C., et al. “A critical analysis of knock detection methods based on cylinder pressure analysis,” 1st international conference on control and diagnostics in automotive applications, Genova, Italy, 3-4 October 1996, pp. 293-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F. and Ferraro, C., "Knock in S.I. Engines: A Comparison between Different Techniques for Detection and Control," SAE Technical Paper 982477, 1998, doi:10.4271/982477.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Corti, E. and Moro, D., "Knock Indexes Thresholds Setting Methodology," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1508, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livengood, J.C., Wu, P.C., Proc. Combust. Inst. 5 (1955) 347-356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, R. O., Computational models for turbulent reacting flows, Cambridge University Press, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Subramanian, G., Vervisch, L., and Ravet, F., "New Developments in Turbulent Combustion Modeling for Engine Design: ECFM-CLEH Combustion Submodel," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0154, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klimstra, J., "The Knock Severity Index - A Proposal for a Knock Classification Method," SAE Technical Paper 841335, 1984, doi:10.4271/841335.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S., Irimescu, A., Marchitto, L., Tornatore, C. et al., "Flame Contour Analysis through UV-Visible Imaging during Regular and Abnormal Combustion in a DISI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015- 01-0754, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0754.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Irimescu, A., Tornatore, C., Merola, S., and Valentino, G., "Combustion Process Investigation in a DISI Engine Fuelled with n-butanol Through Digital Imaging and Chemiluminescence," SAE Technical Paper 2015- 01-1887, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bowditch, F., "A New Tool for Combustion Research A Quartz Piston Engine," SAE Technical Paper 610002, 1961, doi:10.4271/610002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., "Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J, Yang, Y, “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock, and with Ultra-Low NOX Emissions using a Conventional Fuel,” 15th Directions in Engine-Efficiency &amp; Emissions Research Conference, August 3 - 6, 2009, Dearborn, MI</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S.S., Tornatore, C., Irimescu, A., "Cycle-resolved visualization of pre-ignition and abnormal combustion phenomena in a GDI engine," Energ Convers Manage 127:380-391, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2016.09.035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colin O., Benkenida A. (2004) The 3-Zone Extended Coherent Flame Model (ECFM3Z) for computing premixed/diffusion combustion, Oil Gas Sci. Technol. - Rev. IFP 59, 6, 593-609.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boudier, P., Henriot, S., Poinsot, T., Baritaud, T., “A Model for Turbulent Flame Ignition and Propagation in Spark Ignition Engines,” Twenty- Fourth Symposium (International) on Combustion/The Combustion Institute, 1992/pp. 503-510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">von Kuensberg Sarre, C., Kong, S., and Reitz, R., "Modeling the Effects of Injector Nozzle Geometry on Diesel Sprays," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0912, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0912.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. and Diwakar, R., "Effect of Drop Breakup on Fuel Sprays," SAE Technical Paper 860469, 1986, doi:10.4271/860469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senda, J. and Fujimoto, H. 1999. 'Multidimensional modeling of impinging sprays on the wall of diesel engines', Appl Mech Review, 52, pp. 119-138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senda, J., Kanda, T., Al-Roub, M., Farrell, P. et al., "Modeling Spray Impingement Considering Fuel Film Formation on the Wall," SAE Technical Paper 970047, 1997, doi:10.4271/970047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrae, J. C. G., and Head, R. A., “HCCI Experiments with gasoline surrogate fuels modeled by a semidetailed chemical kinetic model,” Combustion and Flame 156 (2009) 842-851.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
