<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association (NTA)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26418788</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CAPITAL GAINS TAXATION AND CORPORATE INVESTMENT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Weisbach</surname>
                  <given-names>David A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>The University of Chicago Law School and The Computation Institute and Argonne National Laboratories, Chicago, IL, USA</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>September, 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>70</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26418782</issue-id>
         <fpage>621</fpage>
         <lpage>642</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26418788"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This study examines the interaction of dividend taxes and capital gains taxes from the sale of stock. Capital gains taxes produce lock-in, increasing the required rate of return for a sale and reinvestment. Using a model of the new view of the corporate tax, this study shows that the lock-in effect when stock is sold determines the optimal dividend payment, increasing the required rate of return for corporate investment. As a result, capital gains taxes on sales of stock increase dividend payments and reduce investment. The new view result, that dividend taxes do not affect investment, however, survives in this setting. The study also considers differences between dividends and repurchases and sales between heterogeneous investors, both which alter the tax incentives for sales and distributions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label> 
            <kwd>dividend taxation</kwd> 
            <kwd>capital gains</kwd> 
            <kwd>new view</kwd> 
            <kwd>lock-in</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, Franklin, and Roni Michaely, 2003. “Payout Policy.” In Constantinides, George M., Milton Harris, and René M. Stulz (eds.), Handbook of the Economics of Finance, Volume 1A, 337–429. Elsevier, New Holland, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., 1979. “Wealth Maximization and the Cost of Capital.” Quarterly Journal of Economics 93 (3), 433–446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., 2002. “Taxation and Corporate Financial Policy.” In Auerbach, Alan J., and Martin Feldstein (eds.), Handbook of Public Economics, Volume 3, 1251–1292. Elsevier, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and Kevin A. Hassett, 2003. “On the Marginal Source of Investment Funds.” Journal of Public Economics 87 (1), 205–232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernheim, B. Douglas, and Adam Wantz, 1995. “A Tax-Based Test of the Dividend Signaling Hypothesis” American Economic Review 85 (3), 532–551.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bradford, David F., 1981. “The Incidence and Allocation Effects of a Tax on Corporate Distributions.” Journal of Public Economics 15 (1), 1–22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brennan, Michael, 1970. “Taxes, Market Valuation, and Corporate Financial Policy.” National Tax Journal 23 (4), 417–427.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chetty, Raj, and Emmanuel Saez, 2010. “Dividend and Corporate Taxation in an Agency Model of the Firm.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 2 (3), 1–31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collins, Julie H., and Deen Kemsley, 2000. “Capital Gains and Dividend Taxes in Firm Valuation: Evidence of Triple Taxation.” Accounting Review 75 (4), 405–427.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, Mihir A., and Li Jin, 2011. “Institutional Tax Clienteles and Payout Policy.” Journal of Financial Economics 100 (1), 68–84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dhaliwal, Dan, Merle Erickson, Mary Margaret Frank, and Monica Banyi, 2003. “Are Shareholder Dividend Taxes on Corporate Retained Earnings Impounded in Equity Prices? Additional Evidence and Analysis.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 35 (2), 179–200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dhaliwal, Dan, and Oliver Zhen Li, 2006. “Investor Tax Heterogeneity and Ex-Dividend Day Trading Volume.” Journal of Finance 61 (1), 463–490.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elton, Edwin J., and Martin J. Gruber, 1970. “Marginal Stockholder Tax Rates and the Clientele Effect.” Review of Economics and Statistics 52 (1), 68–74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, John, 2013. “Do Taxes Affect Corporate Decisions? A Review.” In Constantinides, George M., Milton Harris, and Rene M. Stulz (eds.), Handbook of the Economics of Finance, Volume 2A, 123–210. Elsevier, North-Holland, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guenther, David A., and Richard Sansing, 2006. “Fundamentals of Shareholder Tax Capitalization.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 42 (3), 371–383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanlon, Michelle, and Shane Heitzman, 2010. “A Review of Tax Research.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 50 (2–3), 127–178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanlon, Michelle, James N. Myers, and Terry Shevlin, 2003. “Dividend Taxes and Firm Valuation: A Re-examination.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 35 (2), 119–153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawano, Laura, 2014. “The Dividend Clientele Hypothesis: Evidence from the 2003 Tax Act.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 6 (1), 114–136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">King, Mervyn A., 1974. “Taxation and the Cost of Capital.” Review of Economic Studies, 21–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">King, Mervyn A., 1977. Public Policy and the Corporation. Chapman &amp; Hall, London, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kingson, Charles I., 1976. “The Deep Structure of Taxation: Dividend Distributions.” Yale Law Journal 85 (7), 861–913.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lang, Michael B., 1986. “Dividends Essentially Equivalent to Redemption: The Taxation of Bootstrap Stock Acquisitions.” Tax Law Review 41, 309–382.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levmore, Saul, 1988. “Recharacterizations and the Nature of Theory in Corporate Tax Law.” University of Pennsylvania Law Review 136, 1019–1066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, Merton H., and Franco Modigliani, 1961. “Dividend Policy, Growth, and the Valuation of Shares.” Journal of Business 34 (4), 411–433.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba, James, 2004. “Taxation and Corporate Payout Policy.” American Economic Review 94 (2), 171–175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poterba, James M., and Lawrence H. Summers, 1985. “The Economic Effects of Dividend Taxation.” In Altman, Edward, and Marti Subrahmanyam (eds.), Recent Advances in Corporate Finance, 227–284. Richard D. Irwin Publishers, Homewood, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rantapuska, Elias, 2008. Ex-dividend Day Trading: Who, How, and Why?: Evidence from the Finnish Market.” Journal of Financial Economics 88, 355–374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Yi, Kathleen A. Farrell, and Todd A. Brown, 2008. “Ex-Dividend Day Price and Volume: The Case of 2003 Dividend Tax Cut.” National Tax Journal 61 (1), 105–127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zodrow, George R., 1991. “On the ‘Traditional’ and ‘New’ Views of Dividend Taxation.” National Tax Journal 44 (4), 497–509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
