<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464752</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464758</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Does Family Control Matter? International Evidence from the 2008–2009 Financial Crisis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Karl V.</given-names>
                  <surname>Lins</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Paolo</given-names>
                  <surname>Volpin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hannes F.</given-names>
                  <surname>Wagner</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2583</fpage>
         <lpage>2619</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464758"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We study whether and how family control affects valuation and corporate decisions during the 2008–2009 financial crisis using a sample of more than 8,500 firms from 35 countries. We find that family-controlled firms underperform significantly, they cut investment more relative to other firms, and these investment cuts are associated with greater underperformance. Further, we find that within family groups liquidity shocks are passed on through investment cuts across the group. Our evidence is consistent with families taking actions to increase the likelihood that the firms under their control and their control benefits survive the crisis, at the expense of outside shareholders.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d22e257a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e264" publication-type="other">
See Morck, Wolfenzon, and Yeung (2005) for a comprehensive survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e271a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e278" publication-type="other">
Although data do not allow us to observe direct instances of tunneling or other diversion of firm resources to the
family, this link between underperformance and high expected agency costs suggests that outside investors may
expect controlling families to take such actions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e291a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e298" publication-type="other">
Law and finance research shows that the agency conflicts that shape the relation between firm value and ownership
are likely to depend on countries' institutional structures (La Porta et al. 1998) and are more likely to be a first-
order effect in samples of non-U.S. firms (La Porta, Lopez-de-Silanes, and Shleifer 1999; Claessens, Djankov,
and Lang 2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e314a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e321" publication-type="other">
In robustness tests in Section 2.2, we alternatively consider both shorter and longer fixed-length event windows
as well as country-specific event windows.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e332a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e339" publication-type="other">
According to Bureau van Dijk, the shareholding links contained in their database have been built up over several
years, relying on a large number of public and semipublic sources, and at the time of our study it contained 6.69
million such links. Bureau van Dijk maintains the link database dynamically, updating it with new information
when it becomes available. Therefore, the database represents snapshots of the international web of shareholder
structures at relatively precise points in time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e358a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e365" publication-type="other">
Blockholder definition thresholds vary in the literature, and our more restrictive approach classifies relatively
more firms as widely held. Some prior studies focusing on family control use slightly lower thresholds (e.g., 20%
in Faccio and Lang 2002) or no threshold but restrict family definitions to founding families (e.g., Anderson and
Reeb 2003; Villalonga and Amit 2006). In robustness tests, which we describe later, we lower the threshold for
family control and find our results to be unaffected.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e384a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e391" publication-type="other">
An alternative clustering method is to cluster by country-industry, which assumes no correlation between firms in
different industries in the same country. Because of the comprehensive nature of the financial crisis, we believe
that such correlations are likely to exist and, if true, country-industry clustering will produce standard errors that
are too low, even if this effect is mitigated by our inclusion of country fixed effects. When we re-estimate our
regressions and cluster standard errors by country-industry, rather than by country, standard errors of our point
estimates typically decline. To be conservative, we report all of our results with country clustering.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e414a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e421" publication-type="other">
We also estimate our models using the log of a firm's total assets as a size control and all of our results hold (not
tabulated for the sake of brevity). We prefer the market value of equity as a size control because our dependent
variable is directly tied to it. Additionally, because family-controlled firms are smaller, they might have higher
operating leverage, which could affect crisis period performance. As such, we estimate models that include either
the change in operating income divided by the change in sales or the change in EBIT divided by the change in
sales, each averaged over the period 2000-2006, as additional controls. Operating leverage is never significant
in the regressions, however, and also is not significantly correlated with family control.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e447a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e454" publication-type="other">
Lemmon and Lins (2003) study eight East Asian emerging market countries and find that high managerial control
is associated with lower stock returns during the region's 1997 financial crisis. Our results during the unexpected
"event" of the financial crisis are consistent with a number of other papers whose analyses indicate that families'
interests are not always aligned with those of minority shareholders (see, e.g., La Porta, Lopez-de-Silanes, and
Shleifer 1999; Claessens et al. 2002; Faccio and Lang 2002; Volpin 2002; Lins 2003; Durnev and Kim 2005;
Bennedsen et al. 2007; Bertrand et al. 2008; Almeida et al. 2011; Ellul, Pagano, and Panunzi 2010; Masulis,
Pham, and Zein 2011; Franks et al. 2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e480a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e487" publication-type="other">
We thank Jan Sokolowski for suggesting us this test.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e495a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e502" publication-type="other">
Claessens, Djankov, and Klapper (2003) find that during the 1997 East Asian crisis, 644 of their 1,472 sample
firms became financially distressed and 83 of these had filed for bankruptcy by the end of 1998, a much higher
rate of distress and bankruptcy than in normal times. We obtain all bankruptcies and restructurings from SDC
for our sample countries for the period 2004-2012. After excluding censored, that is, ongoing, events, this yields
2,729 observations. We find that restructuring and bankruptcy events increase from an average of 0.54 events
per month per 1,000 listed firms in the period before the crisis (from 2004 to 2007) to an average of 0.94 events
per month per 1,000 listed firms after the crisis (from 2009 to 2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e528a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e535" publication-type="other">
We note here that our Panel A, Table 6, group statistics also indicate that controlling families are indeed relatively
less diversified in terms of the firm(s) they control compared with nonfamily blockholders. From Table 2, there
are 969 family firms and 2,121 nonfamily firms (11% and 25% of the 8,584 total sample firms, respectively).
Thus, Panel A shows that 75% of the occurrences of family control are for a single firm ((969-240)/969), whereas
only 60% of the occurrences of nonfamily control are for a single firm ((2,121-844)72,121).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e554a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e561" publication-type="other">
Another possible explanation for the underperformance of family-controlled firms is survivorship bias. We require
market return availability throughout the crisis period and exclude firms that do not survive. If family firms are
more likely to survive, our finding that family firms underperform may be due to their poor, but not catastrophic,
performance being captured in our sample, whereas other firms' catastrophic performance is not captured because
they do not survive. To analyze whether nonsurvival is related to blockholder type, we identify all firms that
do not survive as listed firms from August 2008 to December 2009 (74 firms) and estimate the determinants
of nonsurvival for this sample, using both Cox hazard rate and logit regression models. In both the hazard rate
and logit models (not tabulated for the sake of brevity), we find that nonsurvivors have higher leverage, lower
momentum, lower liquidity, and are not part of an MSCI index. The type of controlling blockholder, however,
does not affect survival. Because family firms are not more likely to survive than other firms, survival bias is
unlikely to account for our results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e599a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e606" publication-type="other">
Because non-family and widely held firms increase investment relative to family firms in the crisis, our finding
that family firms do not reduce labor costs more indicates they may be less productive in terms of their labor
to capital ratios. We also note that if we cluster standard errors in the less conservative manner at the country-
industry level, the negative coefficient of (Family control) x (Crisis period) in Column 1 becomes significant at
the 5% level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e625a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e632" publication-type="other">
15 In addition to potential access-to-finance benefits assessed in Wruck (1989), Hertzel and Smith (1993), Winton
(1993), and Weinstein and Yafeh (1998), blockholders have been argued to help in product markets (Khanna and
Palepu 1997,2000) and to provide monitoring (e.g.,ShleiferandVishny 1986;Burkart,Gromb, andPanunzi 1997;
Maug 1998). In unreported regressions, we distinguish between firms with a single nonfamily blockholder and
firms with multiple blockholders. Bennedsen and Wolfenzon (2000) show how having several large blockholders
forces them to form coalitions to exercise control, which can result in more efficient actions, and Laeven and
Le vine (2008) find that firms with multiple large blockholders have different valuations than other firms. We find
that both single and multiple nonfamily blockholders are associated with higher crisis period returns, and there
is no significant difference between their coefficients. We note here that we are not aware of any crisis-specific
empirical nonfamily blockholder research.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e667a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e674" publication-type="other">
We arbitrarily set the length of the downturn to the sample median for Greece as its market did not experience
any positive return between September 2008 and December 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e685a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e692" publication-type="other">
Because of data availability, our valuation factor is the Fama-French HML factor portfolio instead of the,
according to the authors more suitable, cash flow to price factor portfolio. Also, we use a twelve-month momentum
factor instead of their six-month factor.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e705a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e712" publication-type="other">
For some countries, mixed prior evidence exists. For example, in the case of South Korea, Baek, Kang, and Park
(2004) find that family control was costly during the 1997 Asian financial crisis, whereas Almeida and Kim (2012)
find that being part of a chaebol business group, which significantly overlaps with family control, was on net
beneficial. Also, the recent crisis was truly global, and was arguably more pronounced economically in countries
typically viewed as having better governance, and less pronounced in countries with weaker governance. This
would make it difficult to detect incremental underperformance of family firms in weaker governance countries,
should such underperformance exist.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d22e747a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e751" publication-type="other">
Almeida, H., and C. S. Kim. 2012. Internal capital markets in business groups: Evidence from the Asian financial
crisis. Working Paper, Yonsei University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e761a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e765" publication-type="other">
Almeida, H., S. Y. Park, M. G Subrahmanyam, and D. Wolfenzon. 2011. The structure and formation of business
groups: Evidence from Korean chaebols. Journal of Financial Economics 99:447-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e775a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e779" publication-type="other">
Anderson, R., and D. Reeb. 2003. Founding-family ownership and firm performance. Journal of Finance
58:1301-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e789a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e793" publication-type="other">
Bach, L., and N. Serrano-Velarde. 2009. The power of dynastic commitment. Working Paper, Stockholm School
of Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e804a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e808" publication-type="other">
Baek, J.-S., J.-K. Kang, and K. S. Park. 2004. Corporate governance and firm value: Evidence from the Korean
financial crisis. Journal of Financial Economics 71:265-313.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e818a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e822" publication-type="other">
Beber, A., and M. Pagano. 2013. Short selling bans around the world: Evidence from the 2007-09 crisis. Journal
of Finance 68:343-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e832a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e836" publication-type="other">
Bennedsen, M., K. Nielsen, F. Pérez-Gonzâlez, and D. Wolfenzon. 2007. Inside the family firm: The role of
families in succession decisions and performance. Quarterly Journal of Economics 122:647-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e846a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e850" publication-type="other">
Bennedsen, M., and D. Wolfenzon. 2000. The balance of power in closely held corporations. Journal of Financial
Economics 58:113-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e860a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e864" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., S. Johnson, K. Samphantharak, and A. Schoar. 2008. Mixing family with business: A study of Thai
business groups and the families behind them. Journal of Financial Economics 88:466-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e874a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e878" publication-type="other">
Burkart, M., D. Gromb, and F. Panunzi. 1997. Large shareholders, monitoring, and the value of the firm. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 112:693-728.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e889a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e893" publication-type="other">
Campello, M., E. Giambona, J. Graham, and C. Harvey. 2012. Access to liquidity and corporate investment in
Europe during the financial crisis. Review of Finance 16:323-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e903a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e907" publication-type="other">
Campello, M., J. Graham, and C. Harvey, 2010. The real effects of financial constraints: Evidence from a financial
crisis. Journal of Financial Economics 97:470-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e917a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e921" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e928a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e932" publication-type="other">
Claessens, S., S. Djankov, J. Fan, and L. Lang. 2002. Disentangling the incentive and entrenchment effects of
large shareholdings. Journal of Finance 57:2741-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e942a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e946" publication-type="other">
Claessens, S., S. Djankov, and L. Klapper. 2003. Resolution of corporate distress in East Asia. Journal of
Empirical Finance 10:199-216.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e960" publication-type="other">
Claessens, S., S. Djankov, and L. Lang. 2000. The separation of ownership and control in East Asian corporations.
Journal of Financial Economics 58:81-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e975" publication-type="other">
Dehejia, R. H., and S. Wahba. 2002. Propensity score-matching methods for nonexperimental causal studies.
Review of Economics and Statistics 84:151-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e985a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e989" publication-type="other">
Demsetz, H., and K. Lehn. 1985. The structure of corporate ownership: Causes and consequences. Journal of
Political Economy 93:1155-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e999a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1003" publication-type="other">
Desai, M., C. F. Foley, and K. Forbes. 2008. Financial constraints and growth: Multinational and local firm
responses to currency crises. Review of Financial Studies 21:2857-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1013a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1017" publication-type="other">
Duchin, R., O. Ozbas, and B. Sensoy. 2010. Costly external finance, corporate investment, and the subprime
mortgage credit crisis. Journal of Financial Economics 97:418-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1027a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1031" publication-type="other">
Djankov, S., R. La Porta, F. Lopez-de-Silanes, and A. Shleifer. 2008. The law and economics of self-dealing.
Journal of Financial Economics 88:430-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1041a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1045" publication-type="other">
Doidge, C., G A. Karolyi, K. V. Lins, D. P. Miller, and R. M. Stulz. 2009. Private benefits of control, ownership,
and the cross-listing decision. Journal of Finance 64:425-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1056a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1060" publication-type="other">
Durnev, A., and E. H. Kim. 2005. To steal or not to steal: Firm attributes, legal environment and valuation.
Journal of Finance 60:1461-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1070a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1074" publication-type="other">
Ellul, A., M. Pagano, and F. Panunzi. 2010. Inheritance law and investment in family firms. American Economic
Review 100:2414-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1084a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1088" publication-type="other">
Faccio, M., and L. Lang. 2002. The ultimate ownership of Western European corporations. Journal of Financial
Economics 65:365-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1098a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1102" publication-type="other">
Faccio, M., M.-T. Marchica, and R. Mura. 2011. Large shareholder diversification and corporate risk taking.
Review of Financial Studies 24:3601-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1112a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1116" publication-type="other">
Franks, J., C. Mayer, R Volpin, and H. F. Wagner. 2012. The life cycle of family ownership: International evidence.
Review of Financial Studies 25:1687-712.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1126a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1130" publication-type="other">
Hau, H., and S. Lai. 2011. The role of equity funds in the financial crisis propagation. Working Paper, Swiss
Finance Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1141a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1145" publication-type="other">
Hertzel, M., and R. L. Smith. 1993. Market discounts and shareholder gains for placing equity privately. Journal
of Finance 48:459-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1155a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1159" publication-type="other">
Himmelberg, C. P., R. G Hubbard, and D. Palia. 1999. Understanding the determinants of managerial ownership
and the link between ownership and performance. Journal of Financial Economics 53:353-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1169a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1173" publication-type="other">
Hou, K., G A. Karolyi, and B.-C. Kho. 2011. What factors drive global stock returns? Review of Financial Studies
24:2527-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1183a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1187" publication-type="other">
Ivashina, V., and D. Scharfstein. 2010. Bank lending during the financial crisis of 2008. Journal of Financial
Economics 97:319-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1197a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1201" publication-type="other">
Kalcheva, I., and K. V. Lins. 2007. International evidence on cash holdings and expected managerial agency
problems. Review of Financial Studies 20:1087-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1215" publication-type="other">
Khanna, T., and K. G Palepu. 1997. Why focused strategies may be wrong for emerging markets. Harvard
Business Review 75:41-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1230" publication-type="other">
. 2000. Is group affiliation profitable in emerging markets? An analysis of diversified Indian business
groups. Journal of Finance 55:867-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1244" publication-type="other">
Kuppuswamy, V., and B. Villalonga. 2010. Does diversification create value in the presence of external financing
constraints? Evidence from the 2007-2009 financial crisis. Working Paper, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1254a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1258" publication-type="other">
Laeven, L., and R. Levine. 2008. Complex ownership structures and corporate valuations. Review of Financial
Studies 21:579-604.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1272" publication-type="other">
La Porta, R., F. Lopez-de-Silanes, and A. Shleifer. 1999. Corporate ownership around the world. Journal of
Finance 54:471-517.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1282a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1286" publication-type="other">
. 2006. What works in securities laws? Journal of Finance 61:1-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1297" publication-type="other">
La Porta, R., F. Lopez-de-Silanes, A. Shleifer, and R. W. Vishny. 1998. Law and finance. Journal of Political
Economy 106: 111 3—55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1312" publication-type="other">
. 2002. Investor protection and corporate valuation. Journal of Finance 57:1147-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1319a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1323" publication-type="other">
Lemmon, M. L., and K. V. Lins. 2003. Ownership structure, corporate governance, and firm value: Evidence
from the East Asian financial crisis. Journal of Finance 58:1445-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1333a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1337" publication-type="other">
Leuz, C., K. V. Lins, and F. Warnock. 2009. Do foreigners invest less in poorly governed firms. Review of
Financial Studies 22:3245-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1347a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1351" publication-type="other">
Lins, K. V. 2003. Equity ownership and firm value in emerging markets. Journal of Financial and Quantitative
Analysis 38:159-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1361a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1365" publication-type="other">
Masulis, R. W., P. K. Pham, and J. Zein. 2011. Family business groups around the world: Financing advantages,
control motivations, and organizational choices. Review of Financial Studies 24:3556-600.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1375a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1379" publication-type="other">
Maug, E. 1998. Large shareholders as monitors: Is there a trade-off between liquidity and control? Journal of
Finance 53:65-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1390a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1394" publication-type="other">
Morck, R., D. Wolfenzon, and B. Yeung. 2005. Economic entrenchment and growth. Journal of Economic
Literature 43:655-711.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1404a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1408" publication-type="other">
Mueller, H., and T. Philippon. 2011. Family firms and labor relations. American Economic Journal:
Macroeconomics 3:218-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1418a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1422" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M. A. 2009. Estimating standard errors in finance panel data sets: Comparing approaches. Review of
Financial Studies 22:435-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1436" publication-type="other">
Preacher, K. J., and A. F. Hayes. 2004. SPSS and SAS procedures for estimating indirect effects in simple
mediation models. Behavior Research Methods, Instruments, &amp; Computers 36:717-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1446a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1450" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A., and R. W. Vishny. 1986. Large shareholders and corporate control. Journal of Political Economy
94:461-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1460a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1464" publication-type="other">
Sobel, M. E. 1982. Asymptotic confidence intervals for indirect effects in structural equation models. In
Sociological methodology. Ed. S. Leinhart. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1475a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1479" publication-type="other">
Spamann, H. 2010. The 'Antidirector Rights Index' revisited. Review of Financial Studies 23:467-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1486a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1490" publication-type="other">
Sraer, D., and D. Thesmar. 2007. Performance and behavior of family firms: Evidence from the French stock
market. Journal of the European Economic Association 5:709-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1500a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1504" publication-type="other">
Villalonga, B., and R. Amit. 2006. How do family ownership, control and management affect firm value? Journal
of Financial Economics 80:385-417.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1514a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1518" publication-type="other">
Volpin, P. 2002. Governance with poor investor protection: Evidence from top executive turnover in Italy. Journal
of Financial Economics 64:61-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1532" publication-type="other">
Weinstein, D. E., and Y. Yafeh. 1998. On the costs of a bank-centered financial system: Evidence from the
changing main bank relations in Japan. Journal of Finance 53:635-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1542a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1546" publication-type="other">
Winton, A. 1993. Limitation of liability and the ownership structure of the firm. Journal of Finance 48:487-512.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1558" publication-type="other">
Wruck, K. H. 1989. Equity ownership concentration and firm value: Evidence from private equity financings.
Journal of Financial Economics 23:3-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1568a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1572" publication-type="other">
Zhou, X. 2001. Understanding the determinants of managerial ownership and the link between ownership and
performance: Comment. Journal of Financial Economics 62:559-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1582a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1586" publication-type="other">
Zingales, L. 1994. The value of the voting right: A study of the Milan stock exchange experience. Review of
Financial Studies 7:125-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


