<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278212</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Extension of Operating Range of a Multi-Cylinder Gasoline HCCI Engine using the Blowdown Supercharging System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kuboyama</surname>
                  <given-names>Tatsuya</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moriyoshi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hatamura</surname>
                  <given-names>Koichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Hatamura Engine Research Office Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Takanashi</surname>
                  <given-names>Junichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Urata</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yamada</surname>
                  <given-names>Toshio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CD-adapco JAPAN Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1150</fpage>
         <lpage>1168</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278212"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The objective of this study is to develop a practical technique to achieve HCCI operation with wide operation range. To attain this objective, the authors previously proposed the blowdown supercharge (BDSC) system and demonstrated the potential of the BDSC system to extend the high load HCCI operational limit. In this study, experimental works were conducted with focusing on improvement of combustion stability at low load operation and the reduction in cylinder to cylinder variation in ignition timing of multi-cylinder HCCI operation using the BDSC system. The experiments were conducted using a slightly modified production four-cylinder gasoline engine with compression ratio of about 12 at constant engine speed of 1500 rpm. The test fuel used was commercial gasoline which has RON of 91.</p>
            <p>To improve combustion stability at low load operation, the valve actuation strategy for the BDSC system was newly proposed and experimentally examined. With the newly proposed valve actuation strategy, only intake valve lift was varied and EGR and exhaust valve lifts were fixed with variation in target load. Compared to the previously proposed valve actuation strategy for the BDSC system, relatively late EGR valve opening timing with early intake valve closing timing is applied at low load condition in the proposed strategy.</p>
            <p>This provides high in-cylinder temperature and relatively rich fuel concentration at low load operation while providing a large amount of diluted mixture at high load operation. Additionally, effect of coolant water temperature on combustion stability was experimentally investigated. Coolant water temperature was varied from 85°C to 105°C. Experimental result showed that for low load HCCI operation, the valve timing with early intake valve closing and relatively late EGR valve opening was effective to increase combustion stability due to increases in in-cylinder temperature and fuel concentration. With early intake valve closing and relatively late EGR valve opening, a stable HCCI operation at net IMEP of 200 kPa was achieved. However, brake thermal efficiency was slightly deteriorated due to increase in pumping work utilized to increase in in-cylinder temperature. The increase in coolant water temperature also improved combustion stability and extends the low load operational limit due to increase in in-cylinder temperature. With a cooling water temperature of 105°C, the low load HCCI with net IMEP of 134 kPa was attained.</p>
            <p>In addition, to reduce the cylinder to cylinder variation in ignition timing which restricts HCCI operating range with multi-cylinder operation, the secondary air injection system in which air is injected into an exhaust port of each cylinder to control recharged EGR gas temperature using gas fuel injector was proposed and examined to control ignition timing of each cylinder independently. As a result, the cylinder to cylinder variation in ignition timing was successfully reduced and the high load HCCI operational limit with four-cylinder operation was extended up to net IMEP of 570 kPa. Compared to conventional SI operation, brake thermal efficiency was improved by about 15% using the newly proposed strategy with more than 99% reduction in NOₓ emission.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willand, J., Nieberding, R., Vent, G., and Enderle, C., “The Knocking Syndrome- Its Cure and Its Potential,” SAE Technical Paper 982483, 1998, doi:10.4271/982483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuerhapter, A., Piock, W.F., and Fraidl, G.K., “CSI - Controlled Auto Ignition - the Best Solution for the Fuel Consumption - Versus Emission Trade-Off?,”. SAE Technical Paper 2003-10-0754, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0754.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urata, Y., Awasaka, M., Takanashi, J., Kakinuma, T., Hakozaki, T. and Umemoto, A., “A Study of Gasoline- Fuelled HCCI Engine Equipped with an Electromagnetic Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1898, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1898.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiraya, K., Hasegawa, K., Urushihara, T., Iiyama, A. and Itoh, T. “A Study on Gasoline Fueled Compression Ignition Engine ~ A Trial of Operation Region Expansion ~,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0416, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002- 01-0416.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hyvönen, J., Haraldsson, G. and Johansson, B., “Supercharging HCCI to Extend the Operating Range in a Multi-Cylinder VCR-HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3214, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3214.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cristensen, M. and Johansson, B., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) with Exhaust Gas Recirculation and Pilot Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1835, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000- 01-1835.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E. and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):750- 767, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mamalis, S., Nair, V., Andruskiewicz, P., Assanis, D., Babajimopoulos, A., Wermuth, N. and Najt, P., “Comparison of Different Boosting Strategies for Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engines - A Modeling Study,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):296-308, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0571.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takanashi, J., Awasaka, M., Kakinuma, T., Takazawa, M. and Urata, Y. A STUDY OF GASOLINE HCCI ENGINE EQUIPPED WITH AN ELECTROMAGNETIC VVT MECHANISM - INCREASING THE HIGHER LOAD OPERATIONAL RANGE WITH THE INTERCYLINDER EGR BOOST SYSTEM -. F2006P360, FISITA2006, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J.E., Babajimopoulos, A. and Assanis, D., “Comparing Enhanced Natural Thermal Stratification Against Retarded Combustion Phasing for Smoothing of HCCI Heat-Release Rates,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01- 2994, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J.E., “Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure- Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, Based on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0113, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Effects of Engine Speed, Fueling Rate, and Combustion Phasing on the Thermal Stratification Required to Limit HCCI Knocking Intensity,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2125, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005- 01-2125.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., Hwang, W. and Sjöberg, M. An Investigation of Thermal Stratification in HCCI Engine Using Chemiluminescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1518, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1518.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Assanis, D.N. and Fiveland, S., “An Approach for Modeling the Effects of Gas Exchange processes on HCCI Combustion and its Application in Evaluating Variable Valve Timing Control Strategies,” SAE Technical Paper No. 2002-01-2829, 2002. doi:10.4271/2002- 01-2829.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Lavoie, G.A. and Assanis, D., “Modeling HCCI Combustion With High Levels of Residual Gas Fraction - A Comparison of Two VVA Strategies,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3220, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krasselt, J., Foster, D., Ghandhi, J., Herold, R., Reuss, D. and Naji, P., “Investigation into the Effects of Thermal and Compositional Stratification on HCCI Combustion - Part I: Metal Engine Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1105, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herold, R.E., Krasselt, J.M., Foster, D.E., Ghandhi, J.B., Reuss, D.L. and Najt, P.M., “Investigation into the Effects of Thermal and Compositional Stratification on HCCI Combustion - Part II: Optical Engine Results,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1034-1053, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009- 01-1106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Yamaguchi, K., Yoshizawa, K. and Itoh, T., “A Study of a Gasoline-fueled Compression Ignition Engine ~ Expansion of HCCI Operation Rnage Using SI Combustion as a Trigger of Compression Ignition ~,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0180, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., “A Computational Study of the Effect of Low Fuel Loading and EGR on Heat Release Rates and Combustion Limits in HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1309, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aroonsrisopon, T., Werner, P., Waldman, J. O., Foster, D. E., Morikawa, T. and Iida, M., “Expanding the HCCI Operation With the Charge Stratification, SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1756, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-1756.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mariott, C.D. and Reitz, R. D., “Experimental Investigation of Direct Injection-Gasoline for Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion Phasing Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0418, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0418.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mariott, C. D., Kong, S. and Reitz, R. D., “Investigation of Hydrocarbon Emission from a Direct Injection-Gasoline Premixed Charge Compression Ignited Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0419, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0419.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Edling, L., Eliassen, T., Magnusson, L. and Ångström, H., “GDI HCCI: Effects of Injection Timing and Air Swirl on Fuel Stratification, Combustion and Emissions Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0106, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003- 01-0752, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, J., Culp, T. and Kenny, T., “Development of a Gasoline Engine System Using HCCI Technology - The Concept and the Test Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2002- 01-2832, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2832.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flowers, D., Aceves, S.M., Martinez-Frias, J., Smith, J.R., Au, M., Girard, J. and Dibble, R., “Operation of a Four-Cylinder 1.9L Propane Fueled Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine: Basic Operating Characteristics and Cylinder-to-Cylinder Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1895, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1895.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Kang, J., Chang, M. and Najt, P., “Improvement on Cylinder-to-Cylinder Variation Using a Cylinder Balancing Control Strategy in Gasoline HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0848, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0848.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatamura, K., “A Study on HCCI (Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition) Gasoline Engine Supercharged by Exhaust Blow Down Pressure,” SAE Technical Paper 2007- 01-1873, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuboyama, T., Moriyoshi, Y., Hatamura, K., Suzuki, M, Takanashi, J., Yamada, T. and Gotoh, S., Effect of Fuel and Thermal Stratifications on the Operational Range of an HCCI Gasoline Engine Using the Blow-Down Super Charge System, SAE International Journal of Engines, Vol. 3, pp. 666 - 680, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morita, A., Hatamura, K., Yamada, T. and Uesugi, N., “A Study on HCCI (Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition) Gasoline Engine Supercharged by Exhaust Blow Down Pressure (Third Report)”, Review of Automotive Engineering, No. 29, pp. 61 - 64, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J.A., Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milovanovic, N., Blundell, D., Pearson, R., Turner, J. and Chen, R., “Enlarging the Operational Range of a Gasoline HCCI Engine By Controlling the Coolant Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0157, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
