<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">14</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198602</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44720511</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>AIRPLANE AND SEAPLANE ENGINEERING</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>H C</given-names>
                  <surname>Richardson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1919</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>333</fpage>
         <lpage>372</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright, 1920, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44720511"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>After stating the general problem confronting the Navy relative to the use of aircraft in the war, the author outlines airplane design in a general way, discussing the principal factors involved and applying them to a definite example to illustrate the methods of computation used. The effects of different arrangements and disposition of wings and other elements on performance and stability are indicated, covering the effects of monoplane, biplane, triplane, gap ratio, aspect ratio, stagger, dihedral, etc. Airplane performance is treated as depending upon the horsepower required and the horsepower available. Horsepower required is shown to depend upon, "planes" horsepower and "head-resistance" horsepower. Horsepower available is shown to depend upon the mutual influence of the engine and the propeller characteristics, the importance of suitable revolutions for the speed of advance being pointed out. The advantage of gearing down is demonstrated to be desirable for planes of moderate speed. Seaplane float design is discussed at length as to both form and structure, and the important influence of this element in seaplane design is shown by data from model-basin tests. The horsepower required and available when the seaplane is running on the surface is specified. The influence and effects of steps, ventilation, V-bottoms, etc., are taken up. The value of model-basin tests is shown, and the fallacy of requiring the beam to be directly proportioned to the load is made evident. The merits of the central-float type of construction are explained; also the advantage of the longitudinal method of bottom framing. Naval seaplanes used during the war are illustrated and described, including the NC-1, the predecessor of the NC-4, which was the first airplane to cross the Atlantic.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


