<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000367</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40006910</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CAT2: An Experimental Eurotra Alternative</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Randall</given-names>
                  <surname>Sharp</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>1991</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>215</fpage>
         <lpage>228</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1991 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40006910"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>In developing a theory of MT, it is desirable to have a methodology just powerful enough to achieve the intended results without introducing unnecessary complexity. A formalism designed to embody the methodology, and its implementation in some computer language, should also reflect this characteristic. This notion of appropriate complexity underlies the philosophy behind the Cat2 MT system, a powerful yet simple instantiation of the Eurotra MT methodology. This report describes the Cat2 formalism, and compares it to the Eurotra Engineering Framework, as well as to other formalisms for linguistic analysis. It is stressed that with a minimal set of formal devices the Cat2 formalism achieves a level of adequacy equivalent to if not superior to the official Eurotra system.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>complexity</kwd>
            <kwd>English</kwd>
            <kwd>French</kwd>
            <kwd>German</kwd>
            <kwd>formalism</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d1873951e132a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e136" publication-type="other">
Abramson, H. 1984. Definite Clause Translation Grammars. In Proceedings of the 1984
International Symposium on Logic Programming, Silver Springs, Md., 233-240.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e146a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e150" publication-type="other">
Allegranza, V. and A. Bech. 1991. A Treatment of Unbounded Dependencies in Eurotra
with an Experimental Coindexation Tool. Machine Translation 6:171-182 [this isue].</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e160a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e164" publication-type="other">
Arnold, D., L. Jaspaert, R. Johnson, S. Krauwer, M. Rosner, L. des Tombe, G.B. Varile
and S. Warwick. 1985. A MU1 View of the &lt;C,A&gt;,T Framework in Eurotra. In
Proceedings of the Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine
Translation of Natural Languages, Hamilton, N.Y., 1-14.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e180a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e184" publication-type="other">
Arnold, D., S. Krauwer, M. Rosner, L. des Tombe and G.B. Varile. 1986. The &lt;C,A&gt;,T
Framework in Eurotra: A Theoretically Committed Notation for MT. In Proceedings
of COLING-86, Bonn, 297-303.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e198a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e202" publication-type="other">
Arnold, D. and L.des Tombe. 1987. Basic Theory and Methodology in Eurotra. In
S.Nirenburg (ed.), Machine Translation: Theoretical and Methodological Issues,
Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 114-135.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e215a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e219" publication-type="other">
Carbonell, J. and M. Tomita. 1987. Knowledge-based Machine Translation: The CMU
Approach. In S. Nirenburg (ed.), Machine Translation: Theoretical and Method-
ological Issues, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 68-89.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e232a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e236" publication-type="other">
Evans, R. and G. Gazdar. 1989. Inference in DATR. Proceedings of the Fourth Conference
of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Manchester,
66-71.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e249a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e253" publication-type="other">
Gazdar, G., E. Klein, G. Pullum and I. Sag. 1985. Generalized Phrase Structure
Grammar. Oxford: Basil Blackwell.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e263a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e267" publication-type="other">
Halliday, M.A.K. 1985. An Introduction to Functional Grammar. London: Edward
Arnold.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e277a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e281" publication-type="other">
Hirsh, S. 1987. P-PATR: A Compiler for Unification-based Grammars. In Proceedings
of the Second International Workshop on Natural Language Understanding and Logic
Programming, Vancouver, 63-74.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e295a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e299" publication-type="other">
Karttunen, L. 1986. D-PATR: A Development Environment for Unification-Based Gram-
mars. CSLI Report No. CSLI-86-61, SRI, Stanford, Calif.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e309a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e313" publication-type="other">
Kasper, R. 1987a. A Unification Method for Disjunctive Feature Descriptions. In Proceed-
ings of ACL-25, Stanford, 235-242.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e323a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e327" publication-type="other">
Kasper, R. 1987b. Conditional Descriptions in Functional Unification Grammar. ISI
Report IS/RR-87-191, University of Southern California, Marina del Rey, Calif.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e337a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e341" publication-type="other">
Kay, M. 1984. Functional Unification Grammar: A Formalism for Machine Translation.
In Proceedings of Coling-84, Stanford, 75-78.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e351a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e355" publication-type="other">
Matsumoto, Y., H. Tanaka, H. Hirakawa, H. Miyoshi and H. Yasukawa. 1983. BUP: A
Bottom-Up Parser Embedded in Prolog. New Generation Computing 1:145-158.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e365a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e369" publication-type="other">
Pereira, F. and S. Shieber. 1987. Prolog and Natural Language Analysis. CSLI Lecture
Notes 10, Stanford, Calif.: CSLI.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e380a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e384" publication-type="other">
Pereira, F. and D. Warren. 1980. Definite Clause Grammars for Language Analysis-A
Survey of the Formalism and a Comparison with Augmented Transition Networks.
Artificial Intelligence 13:231-278.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e397a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e401" publication-type="other">
Pollard, C. and I.Sag. 1987. Information-Based Syntax and Semantics, Vol. 1. CSLI
Lecture Notes 13, Stanford, Calif.: CSLI.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e411a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e415" publication-type="other">
Sharp, R. 1988. CAT2-Implementing a Formalism for Multi-Lingual MT. In Proceedings
of the Second International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in
Machine Translation of Natural Language, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pa.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e428a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e432" publication-type="other">
Sharp, R. 1990. Modelling GB in the CAT2 Machine Translation System. Paper delivered
at the Workshop on GB Parsing, June 15-16, University of Geneva.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e442a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e446" publication-type="other">
Shieber, S. 1984. The Design of a Computer Language for Linguistic Information. In
Proceedings of COLING-84, Stanford, 362-366.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e456a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e460" publication-type="other">
Shieber, S. 1986. An Introduction to Unification-Based Approaches to Grammar.
CSLI Lecture Notes 4, Stanford, Calif.: CSLI.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e471a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e475" publication-type="other">
Steiner, E., U. Eckert, B. Roth and J.Winter-Thielen. 1988. The Development of the
Eurotra-D System of Semantic Relations. In E. Steiner, P. Schmidt and C. Zelinsky-
Wibbelt (eds.), From Syntax to Semantics: Insights from Machine Translation,
London: Frances Pinter, 40-104.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e491a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e495" publication-type="other">
Zelinsky-Wibbelt, C. 1988. From Cognitive Grammar to the Generation of Semantic
Interpretation in Machine Translation. In: E. Steiner, P. Schmidt and C. Zelinsky-
Wibbelt (eds.), From Syntax to Semantics: Insights from Machine Translation,
London: Frances Pinter, 105-132.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1873951e511a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1873951e515" publication-type="other">
Zelinsky-Wibbelt, C. 1991. Handling Transfer of Determination in a Eurotra Environment.
Machine Translation 6:183-192 [this issue].</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
