<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014677</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Encouraging Free Play</article-title>
            <subtitle>Extramural Digital Game-Based Language Learning as a Complex Adaptive System</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Scholz</surname>
                  <given-names>Kyle</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Waterloo, ON, Canada.</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Kyle Scholz works at the Centre for Teaching Excellence at the University of Waterloo, Canada. He received his doctorate in German applied linguistics at the University of Waterloo, focusing on digital game-based language learning. His research focuses specifically on the means by which language learners can develop second language proficiency in extramural environments using games and other educational technologies. More broadly, his research interests include computer-assisted language learning and complex adaptive systems.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014673</issue-id>
         <fpage>39</fpage>
         <lpage>57</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014677"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>Massively multiplayer online role-playing games like World of Warcraft are ideally suited to encourage and facilitate second language development (SLD) in the extramural setting, but to what extent do the language learners’ actual trajectories of gameplay contribute to SLD? With the current propensity to focus research in digital game-based language learning on vernacular games, or commercially available games that are designed with entertainment in mind, it is vital to focus on the extramural setting in which these games are designed to be played, while still being subject to rigorous and empirical analysis. This article examines the extramural gameplay and language-learning trajectories of four university German-language learners as they play World of Warcraft with native German speakers. Positioning learners’ experiences within a complex adaptive systems framework (Larsen-Freeman &amp; Cameron, 2008; de Bot &amp; Larsen-Freeman, 2011), the change that each learner undergoes while playing the game over the course of four months is explored in detail. Understanding the game environment as an affinity space (Gee, 2005) helps to substantiate how a game, independent of instructor guidance or classroom intervention, can still promote SLD amongst language learners of varying experiences and proficiencies. The results of this study suggest that numerous factors influence the success of a language learner’s extramural gameplay experience, but that these factors must be analyzed in conjunction with the emergent internal and external resources of the complex adaptive system as language learners play and interact with other players in a context removed from the traditional classroom.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>digital game-based language learning</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>complex adaptive systems</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>affinity space</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beckner, C., Blythe, R., Bybee, J., Christiansen, M. H., Croft, W., Ellis, N. C., Holland, J., Ke, J., Larsen-Freeman, D., &amp; Schoenemann, T. (2009). Language is a complex adaptive system: Position paper. Language Learning, 59 Supplement 1, 1–26. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2009.00533.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bytheway, J. (2014). In-game culture affects learners’ use of vocabulary learning strategies in massively multiplayer online role-playing games. International Journal of Computer-Assisted Language Learning and Teaching, 4(4), 1–13. https://doi.org/10.4018/ijcallt.2014100101</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cobb, T. (2002). Web Vocabprofile, an adaptation of Heatley, Nation &amp; Coxhead’s (2002) Range. Retrieved 21 July 2015 from http://www.lextutor.ca/vp/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cornillie, F., Jacques, I., De Wannemacker, S., Paulussen, H., &amp; Desmet, P. (2011). Vocabulary treatment in adventure and role-playing games: A playground for adaptation and adaptivity. In S. De Wannemacker, G. Clarebout, &amp; P. De Causmaecker (Eds.), Interdisciplinary approaches to adaptive learning: A look at the neighbours (pp. 131–146). Berlin: Springer-Verlag. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-20074-8_11</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Bot, K., &amp; Larsen-Freeman, D. (2011). Researching second language development from a dynamic systems theory perspective. In M. H. Verspoor, K. de Bot, &amp; W. Lowie (Eds.), A dynamic approach to second language development: Methods and techniques (pp. 5–24). Amsterdam: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.29.01deb</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Delwiche, A. (2006). Massively multiplayer online games (MMOs) in the new media classroom. Educational Technology &amp; Society, 9(3), 160–172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellis, N. C., &amp; Larsen-Freeman, D. (2009). Constructing a second language: Analyses and computational simulations of the emergence of linguistic constructions from usage. In N. C. Ellis &amp; D. Larsen-Freeman (Eds.), Language as a Complex Adaptive System (pp. 90–125). Chichester: Wiley-Blackwell. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2009.00537.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gee, J. P. (2005). Semiotic social spaces and affinity spaces: From the age of mythology to today’s schools. In D. Barton &amp; K. Tusting (Eds.), Beyond communities of practice: Language, power, and social context (pp. 214–232). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511610554.012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heatley, A., Nation, P., &amp; Coxhead, A. (2002). RANGE and FREQUENCY programs. Retrieved from http://www.victoria.ac.nz/lals/staff/paul-nation.aspx</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsen-Freeman, D. (2002). Language acquisition and language use form a chaos/complexity theory perspective. In C. Kramsch (Ed.), Language acquisition and language socialization: Ecological p[erspectives (pp. 33–46). London: Continuum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsen-Freeman, D., &amp; Cameron, L. (2008). Complex systems and applied linguistics. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lave, J., &amp; Wenger, E. (1991). Situated learning: Legitimate peripheral participation. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511815355</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liou, H.-C. (2012). The roles of Second Life in a college computer-assisted language learning (CALL) course in Taiwan, ROC. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 25(4), 365–382. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2011.597766</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, M., &amp; Hegelheimer, V. (2006). The SIMs meet ESL: Incorporating authentic computer simulation games into the language classroom. Interactive Technology and Smart Education, 3(4), 311–328. https://doi.org/10.1108/17415650680000070</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2010a). Learner participation patterns and strategy use in Second Life: An exploratory case study. ReCALL, 22(3), 273–292. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344010000169</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, M. (2010b). Massively multiplayer online role-playing games as arenas for second language learning. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 23(5), 429–439. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2010.520673</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piirainen–Marsh, A., &amp; Tainio, L. (2009). Collaborative game-play as a site for participation and situated learning of a second language. Scandinavian Journal of Educational Research, 53(2), 167–183. https://doi.org/10.1080/00313830902757584</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polat, B., &amp; Kim, Y. (2014). Dynamics of complexity and accuracy: A longitudinal case study of advanced untutored development. Applied Linguistics, 35(2), 184–207. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/amt013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Quasthoff, U., &amp; Wolff, C. (1999). Korpuslinguistik und große einsprachige Wörterbücher. Linguistik Online, 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rama, P. S., Black, R. W., Van Es, E., &amp; Warschauer, M. (2012). Affordances for second language learning in World of Warcraft. ReCALL, 24(3), 322–338. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344012000171</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rankin, Y., McNeal, M., Shute, M. W., &amp; Gooch, B. (2008). User centered game design: Evaluating massive multiplayer online role playing games for second language acquisition. In Sandbox ’08: Proceedings of the 2008 ACM SIGGRAPH Symposium on Video Games (pp. 43–49). New York, NY: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/1401843.1401851</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scholz, K. W., &amp; Schulze, M. (in press). Digital-gaming trajectories and second-language development. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 21(1).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sockett, G. (2011). From the cultural hegemony of English to online informal learning: Cluster frequency as an indicator of relevance in authentic documents. Asp, 60, 5–20. https://doi.org/10.4000/asp.2469</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sockett, G. (2013). Understanding the online informal learning of English as a complex dynamic system: An emic approach. ReCALL, 25(1), 48–62. https://doi.org/10.1017/S095834401200033X</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sockett, G., &amp; Toffoli, D. (2012). Beyond learner autonomy: A dynamic systems view of the informal learning of English in virtual online communities. ReCALL, 24(2), 138–151. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2012.02.042</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steinkuehler, C. (2007). Massively multiplayer online gaming as a constellation of literary practices. In B. E. Shelton &amp; D. A. Wiley (Eds.), The design and use of simulation computer games in education (pp. 187–212). Rotterdam: Sense Publishers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundqvist, P. (2009). Extramural English matters: Out-of-school English and its impact on Swedish ninth graders’ oral proficiency and vocabulary (Doctoral dissertation). Karlstad University, Karlstad.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundqvist, P., &amp; Sylvén, L. K. (2012). World of VocCraft: Computer games and Swedish learners’ L2 English vocabulary. In H. Reinders (Ed.), Digital games in language learning and teaching (pp. 189–208). Basingstoke: Palgrave Macmillan. https://doi.org/10.1057/9781137005267_10</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundqvist, P., &amp; Sylvén, L. K. (2014). Language-related computer use: Focus on young L2 English learners in Sweden. ReCALL, 26(1), 3–20. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344013000232</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sykes, J., &amp; Reinhardt, J. (2013). Language at play: Digital games in second and foreign language teaching and learning. New York, NY: Pearson.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sylvén, L. K., &amp; Sundqvist, P. (2012). Similarities between playing World of Warcraft and CLIL. APPLES: Journal of Applied Language Studies, 6(2), 113–130. Retrieved from http://apples.jyu.fi/article/abstract/199</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L. (2008). Transcultural communication in open internet environments and massively multiplayer online games. In S. Sieloff Magnan (Ed.), Mediating discourse online (pp. 305–327). Amsterdam: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/aals.3.17tho</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., Fischer, I., &amp; Lu, X. (2012). The semiotic ecology and linguistic complexity of an online game world. ReCALL, 24(3), 279–301. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344012000158</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toffoli, D., &amp; Sockett, G. (2010). How non-specialist students of English practice informal learning using web 2.0 tools. Asp, 58, 125–144. https://doi.org/10.4000/asp.1851</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Das Wortschatz-Lexikon. (2001). Retrieved from http://wortschatz.uni-leipzig.de/Papers/top1000de.txt</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, D. (2012). Caring in the dynamics of design and languaging: Exploring second language learning in 3D virtual spaces. Language Sciences, 34(5), 543–558. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.langsci.2012.03.010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, D., Newgarden, K., &amp; Young, M. F. (2012). Multimodal analysis of language learning in World of Warcraft play: Languaging as values-realizing. ReCALL, 24(3), 339–360. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344012000183</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, D., Young, M. F., Wagner, M. M., &amp; Brewer, R. A. (2009). Negotiation for action: English language learning in game-based virtual worlds. The Modern Language Journal, 93(4), 489–511. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2009.00927.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
