<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">40</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24459470</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24459473</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Which School Districts Qualified for Federal School Facility Funding under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009? Evidence from Ohio</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>W. Kyle</given-names>
                  <surname>Ingle</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alex J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Bowers</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Thomas E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Davis</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>17</fpage>
         <lpage>37</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 Board of Directors of the Journal of Education Finance, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24459473"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA) allocated $11 billion per year for 2009 and 2010 for qualified school construction bonds (QSCBs) for America's schools. From a historical perspective, this program is a broad transformation of the federal role in school facility funding. This study examined factors associated with federal allocations to school districts in Ohio, asking the following questions: What demographic and finance characteristics of Ohio school districts are associated with an increased likelihood of qualifying for a QSCB? Did school districts with greater need qualify? We found that Ohio districts that had previously deferred participation in the state's capital funding program (typically unable to raise the local share) were strongly associated with an increased likelihood of QSCB qualification (p &lt; .001), thus providing an opportunity for these districts to overcome local voter reticence of additional taxes and address school construction and renovation needs with the availability of lower-interest-rate borrowing over a shorter period of time. Higher poverty rates were associated with an increased likelihood of receiving QSCB awards, but marginally so (p &lt; .10). Our findings suggest that QSCB qualification may have helped to address the equity concerns raised in the prior literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d43e183a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e187" publication-type="other">
Alexander, Kern, and M. David Alexander. 2009. American public school law, 7th ed. Belmont, CA:
Wadsworth Cengage Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e197a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e201" publication-type="other">
Arsen, David, and Thomas Davis. 2006. Taj Mahals or decaying shacks: Patterns in local school
capital stock and unmet capital need. Peabody Journal of Education 81(4): 1-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e215" publication-type="other">
Baird, Katherine E. 2008. Federal direct expenditures and school funding disparities, 1990-2000.
Journal of Education Finance 33(3): 297-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e229" publication-type="other">
Beckham, James, and Jeffrey Maiden. 2003. The effects of technology inclusion on school bond
election success in Oklahoma. Journal of Education Finance 28(4): 557-574.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e244" publication-type="other">
Berry, Christopher R„ and William G. Howell. 2007. Accountability and local elections: Rethinking
retrospective voting. The Journal of Politics 69(3): 844-858.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e254a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e258" publication-type="other">
Biddle, Bruce. J., and David C. Berliner. 2002. Unequal school funding in the United States.
Educational Leadership 59(8): 48-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e272" publication-type="other">
Bowers, Alex J., and Jooyoung Lee. 2013. Carried or defeated? Examining the factors associated
with passing district bond elections in Texas, 1997-2009. Educational Administration Quarterly
49(5): 732-767.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e285a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e289" publication-type="other">
Bowers, Alex J., Scott A. Metzger, and Matthew Militello. 2010a. Knowing the odds: Parameters
that predict passing or failing school district bonds. Educational Policy 24(2): 398-420.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e303" publication-type="other">
Bowers, Alex J., Scott A. Metzger, and Matthew Militello. 2010b. Knowing what matters: An
expanded study of school bond elections in Michigan, 1998-2006. Journal of Education Finance
35(4): 374-396.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e316a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e320" publication-type="other">
Brunner, Eric J., and Kim Rueben. 2001. Financing new school construction and modernization:
Evidence from California. National Tax Journal 54(3): 527-539.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e331a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e335" publication-type="other">
The Center for Green Schools. 2013. State of our schools report. Washington, DC: The Center for
Green Schools.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e345a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e349" publication-type="other">
Clotfelter, Charles T., Helen L. Ladd, and Jacob Vigdor. 2005. Who teaches whom? Race and the
distribution of novice teachers. Economics of Education Review 24(4): 377-392.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e359a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e363" publication-type="other">
Cohen, Jacob, Patricia Cohen, Stephen G. West, and Leona S. Aiken. 2003. Applied multiple
regression/correlation analysis for the behavioral sciences, 3rd ed. New York, NY: Taylor and
Francis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e376a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e380" publication-type="other">
Cohen, Jennifer, and Jason Delisle. 2011. Information needed on ARRA school construction
funds before Congress acts on Obamas proposal for more. Ed Money Watch. http://edmoney.
newamerica.net/blogposts/2011 /information_needed_on_arra_school_construction_funds_
before_congress_acts_on_obamas_p</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e400" publication-type="other">
Crampton, Faith E. 2003. Unmet school infrastructure funding need as a critical educational
capacity issue. In F. E. Crampton and D. C. Thompson (Eds.), Saving America's school
infrastructure (pp. 3-26). Greenwich, CT: Information Age Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e417" publication-type="other">
Duncombe, William D., and Wen Wang. 2009. School facilities funding and capital outlay
distribution in the states. Journal of Education Finance 34: 324-350.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e428a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e432" publication-type="other">
Edlefson, Carla, and Robert Barrow. 2001. The impact of litigation on school facilities funding in
Ohio. Journal of Education Finance 27: 701-712.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e442a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e446" publication-type="other">
Ehrenberg, Ronald, Randy Ehrenberg, Christopher Smith, and Liang Zhang. 2004. Why do school
district budget referenda fail? Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis 26(2): 111-125.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e456a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e460" publication-type="other">
Filardo, Mary, Stephanie Cheng, Marni Allen, Michelle Bar, and Jessi Ulsoy. 2010. State capital
spending on PK-12 school facilities. 21st Century School Fund. www.21csf.org/csf%2Dhome/
publications.asp</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e473a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e477" publication-type="other">
Filardo, Mary, and Sean O'Donnell. 2010. Federal spending on PK-12 school facilities. 21st
Century School Fund. www.21csf.org/csf-home/Documents/FederalStateSpendingNov2010/
FederalSpendingPK12PublicSchoolFacilitiesNovember2010.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e490a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e494" publication-type="other">
Fisher, Ronald C. 2006. State and local public finance, 3rd ed. Mason, OH: Thomson Southwestern.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e501a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e505" publication-type="other">
Gradstein, Mark, and Michael Kaganovich. 2004. Aging population and education finance. Journal
of Public Economics 88(12): 2469-2485.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e516a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e520" publication-type="other">
Hunter, Molly A. 2000. Trying to bridge the gaps: Ohio's search for an education finance remedy.
Journal of Education Finance 26(1): 63-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e530a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e534" publication-type="other">
Ingle, W. Kyle, Paul A. Johnson, Matt Givens, and Jerry Rampelt. 2013. Campaign expenditures
in school levy campaigns and their relationship to voter approval: Evidence from Ohio, 2007-
2010. Leadership and Policy in Schools 12(1): 1-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e551" publication-type="other">
Ingle, W. Kyle, Paul A. Johnson, and Ruth A. Petroff. 2012. "Hired guns" and "legitimate voices":
The politics and participants of levy campaigns in five Ohio school districts. Educational
Administration Quarterly 48(5): 814-858.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e564a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e568" publication-type="other">
Jones, Rodger. 2011. Please, Mr. President, don't build us new schools. Dallas Morning News.
http://dallasmorningviewsblog.dallasnews.coni/archives/2011/08/please-mr-presi.html</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e582" publication-type="other">
Klein, Alyson. 2011. Lawmaker eyes school construction to spur economy. Education Week, http://
blogs.edweek.org/edweek/campaign-k-12/201 l/09/rumors_are_swirling_that_presi.html</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e592a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e596" publication-type="other">
Kutner, Michael, Christopher Nachtsheim, and John Neter. 2004. Applied linear regression models,
4th ed. Boston, MA: McGraw-Hill/Irwin.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e611" publication-type="other">
Ladd, Helen. 1975. Local education expenditures, fiscal capacity, and the composition of the
property tax base. National Tax Journal 28(2): 145-158.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e625" publication-type="other">
Ladd, Helen F., and Sheila E. Murray. 2001. Intergenerational conflict reconsidered: County
demographic structure and the demand for public education. Economics of Education Review
20(4): 343-357.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e638a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e642" publication-type="other">
Long, John S. 1997. Regression models for categorical and limited dependent variables. Thousand
Oaks, CA: SAGE Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e652a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e656" publication-type="other">
Maxwell, Richard, and Scott Sweetland. 2008. Ohio school finance: A practitioners guide, 4th ed.
Newark, NJ: Lexis Nexis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e666a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e670" publication-type="other">
McCarthy, Martha, Neida H. Cambron-McCabe, and Suzanne E. Eckes. 2014. Public school law:
Teachers' and students' rights, 7th ed. Boston, MA: Pearson.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e680a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e684" publication-type="other">
McDonnell, Lorraine M. 2005. No Child Left Behind and the federal role in education: Evolution
or revolution? Peabody Journal of Education 80(2): 19-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e695a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e699" publication-type="other">
McKinley, Sandra, and William Phillis. 2008. Collaboration in search of a school funding remedy
post DeRolph. Journal of Education Finance 33(3): 311-330.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e709a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e713" publication-type="other">
Menard, Scott. 2002. Applied logistic regression analysis. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e720a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e724" publication-type="other">
Murphy, Joseph. 1983. A statistical analysis of Ohio's financially troubled school districts.
Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis 5:107-117.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e734a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e738" publication-type="other">
Myers, Raymond H. 1990. Classical and modern regression with applications. Boston, MA: PWS-
Kent.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e748a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e752" publication-type="other">
O'Brien, Kevin, Claudette, Robey, Larry C. Ledebur, Billie, K. Geyer, K. Toth, and Michael
McGoun. 2005. Team process review of the Accelerated Urban Initiative: Toledo Public Schools.
Urban Publications. Paper 331. http://engagedscholarship.csuohio.edu/urban_facpub/331</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e765a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e769" publication-type="other">
OSFC. 2012. Ohio School Facilities Commission. www.osfc.ohio.gov/Home.aspx</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e777a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e781" publication-type="other">
Piele, Phillip K., and John Hall. 1973. Budgets, bonds, and ballots: Voting behaviors in school
financial elections. Lexington, MA: Lexington Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e791a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e795" publication-type="other">
Plummer, Elizabeth. 2006. The effects of state funding on property tax rates and school
construction. Economics of Education Review 25(5): 532-542.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e805a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e809" publication-type="other">
Poterba, James. 1997. Demographic structure and the political economy of public education.
Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 16:48-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e819a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e823" publication-type="other">
Porter. Tod S. 2010. Trends in the fiscal capacity of Ohio's public schools. Journal of Education
Finance 35(3): 217-244.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e833a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e837" publication-type="other">
Rebell, Michael A. 2012. Safeguarding the right to a sound basic education in times of fiscal
constraint. Albany Law Review 75(4): 1855-1976.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e847a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e851" publication-type="other">
Rice, Jennifer. 2004. Equity and efficiency in school finance reform: Competing or complementary
goods? Peabody Journal of Education 72(2): 134-151.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e862a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e866" publication-type="other">
Shober, Arnold F. 2011. Attracting capital: Magnets, charters, and school referendum success.
Journal of School Choice 5(2): 205-223.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e876a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e880" publication-type="other">
Sielke, Catherine C. 1998. Michigan school facilities, equity issues, and voter response to bond
issues following finance reform. Journal of Education Finance 23(3): 309-322.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e890a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e894" publication-type="other">
Sielke, Catherine C. 2001. Financing school infrastructure: What are the options? School Business
Affairs 67(12): 12-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e904a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e908" publication-type="other">
Silverman, Robert M. 2011. How unwavering is support for the local property tax? Voting on
school district budgets in New York, 2003-2010. Journal of Education Finance 36(3): 294-311.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e918a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e922" publication-type="other">
Singer, Judith D., and John B. Willett. 2003. Applied longitudinal data analysis: Modeling change
and event occurrence. New York, NY: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e932a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e936" publication-type="other">
Stevens, James P. 2002. Applied multivariate statistics for the social sciences, 4th ed. Mahwah, NJ:
Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e947a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e951" publication-type="other">
Superfine, Benjamin. 2008. The courts and standards based reform. New York, NY: Oxford Uni-
versity Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e961a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e965" publication-type="other">
Superfine, Benjamin, Jessica Gottlieb, and Mark Smylie. 2012. The expanding federal role in
teacher workforce policy. Educational Policy 26(1): 58-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e975a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e979" publication-type="other">
Temin, Peter. 2010. The great recession and the great depression. Cambridge, MA: National Bureau
of Economic Research (NBER). www.nber.org/papers/wl5645.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e989a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e993" publication-type="other">
21st Century School Fund. 2010. Interim analysis of school facility funding in the American
Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009. www.21csf.org/csf-home/Documents/
InterimAnalysisoSchooFacilityFundingARRA.pdf</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1006a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1010" publication-type="other">
U.S. Government Accounting Office. 1995. School facilities: States'financial and technical support
varies. Washington DC: GAO.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1020a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1024" publication-type="other">
Vander Ark, Tom. 2013, February 8. It's time to separate facilities from operations, http://
blogs.edweek.org/edweek/on_innovation/2013/02/its_time_to_separate_facilities_from_
operations.html</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1038a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1042" publication-type="other">
Venters, Monoka, Meghan V. Hauptli, and Lora Cohen-Vogel. 2012. Federal solutions to school
fiscal crises: Lessons from Nixon's failed national sales tax for education. Educational Policy
26(1): 35-57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1055a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1059" publication-type="other">
Wood, R. Craig. 2007. Educational finance law, 3rd ed. Dayton, OH: Education Law Association.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1066a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1070" publication-type="other">
Wood, R. Craig, Thompson, David C., and Faith E. Crampton. 2012. Money and schools. New
York, NY: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1080a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1084" publication-type="other">
Zimmer, Ron, and John T. Jones. 2005. Unintended consequences of centralized public school
funding in Michigan education. Southern Economic Journal 71(3): 534-544.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1094a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1098" publication-type="other">
Zimmer, Ron W., Richard Buddin, John T. Jones, and Na Liu. 2011. What types of school capital
projects are voters willing to support? Public Budgeting and Finance 31(1): 37-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


