<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308434</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Characteristics of Evaporating Diesel Spray</article-title>
            <subtitle>A Comparison of Laser Measurements and Empirical/Theoretical Predictions</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gao</surname>
                  <given-names>Jian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nishida</surname>
                  <given-names>Keiya</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Hiroshima</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moon</surname>
                  <given-names>Seoksu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Hiroshima</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Matsumoto</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuhei</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Hiroshima</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>805</fpage>
         <lpage>818</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308434"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The objective of the paper is to characterize the diesel spray under the ambient conditions relevant for direct injection (D.I.) diesel engines. The particular emphasis is on the comparisons between laser measurements and predictions by empirical correlations and theoretical analyses. The ultraviolet-visible laser absorption-scattering (LAS) imaging technique is employed to quantitively determine the spray/mixture properties of the diesel spray injected by a hole-type injector, in terms of spray tip penetration and spatial concentration distributions of liquid and vapor phase. The structure of evaporating spray is obtained and analyzed. Based on the penetration correlations in the literature, a non-dimensional analysis of the spray tip penetration data is carried out. The results indicate that a self-similar state of the evaporating fuel spray is achieved. The measured mean fuel concentration distribution along the spray axis is in good agreement with the predicted one by the quasi-steady momentum theory for the spray with constant mass flow rate.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. Diesel engine combustion and its modeling. Proceedings of COMODIA 1985, JSME Symposium, Tokyo Japan, 1985, pp. 53-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borman, G. L. and Ragland, K. W. Combustion Engineering, 1998 (McGraw Hill, New York), 289- 336.Ishikawa, S., Ohmori, Y., Suzuki, T., Takamura, A. and Kamimoto, T. Measurement of Pilot Injection Quantity by Advanced Injection Rate Meter, JSAE Spring Convention Proceedings, No.40-99, 9933664, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujimoto, H., Hyun, G., Nogami, M., Hirakawa, K., Asai, T. and Senda, J. Characteristics of Free and Impinging Gas Jets by Means of Image Processing, SAE Paper 970045, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G. A study of mixture formation in Direct injection Diesel like Conditions Using Quantitative Fuel Concentration Visualizations in a Gaseous Fuel Jet, SAE Paper 2002-01-1632, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Browne, K. R., Partridge, I. M. and Greeves, G. Fuel property effects on fuel/air mixing in an experimental diesel engine. SAE Paper 860223, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yatsufusa, T., Nishida, K., Yoshizaki, T. and Hiroyasu, H. Behaviors of D.I. diesel sprays with split in a model combustion chamber (1st report, effect of injection interval). JSME transactions (B), 2000, 66(643), 919-925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yatsufusa, T., Nishida, K., Yoshizaki, T. and Hiroyasu, H. Behaviors of D.I. diesel sprays with split in a model combustion chamber (2nd report, effect of injection mass ratio). JSME transactions (B), 2000, 66(644), 1229-1236.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nishida, K., Murakami, N. and Hiroyasu, H. Holographic measurement of evaporating diesel sprays at high pressure and temperature. JSME transactions (B), 1986, 30(259), 107-115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Song, Y. C., Shi, F. M., Gao, X. Y., Yan, F. C. and Chen, J. H. The Laser Interfero-Holographic and Tomographic Analysis of Concentration and Temperature Distribution of a Three Dimensional Transient Diesel Spray, SAE Paper 941756, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heinze, T. and Schmidt, T. Fuel-air ratios in a spray, determined between injection and autoignition by pulsed spontaneous Raman spectroscopy. SAE Paper 892102, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rabenstein, F., Egermann, J. and Leipertz, A. Quantitative analysis of vapor phase structures in transient liquid fuel sprays. Proc. COMODIA ‘98, Kyoto Japan, July 1998, pp. 435- 440.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P. C. Raman line imaging for spatially and temporally resolved mole fraction measurements in internal combustion engines. Appli. Opti., 1999, 38(9), 1714-1732.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Espey, C., Dec, J. E., Litzinger, T. A. and Samtavicca, D. A. Planar laser Rayleigh scattering for quantitative vapor-fuel imaging in a diesel jet. Combust. and Flame, 1997, 109(1-2), 65-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C. A. and Pickett, L. M. Quantitative mixing measurements in a vaporizing diesel spray by Rayleigh imaging. SAE Paper 2007-01-0647, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. P., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L. M. and Idicheria, C. A. End-of-injection over-mixing and unburned hydrocarbon emissions in lowtemperature- combustion diesel engines. SAE Paper 2007-01-0907, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Melton, L. A. Spectrally separated fluorescence emissions for diesel fuel droplets and vapor. Appli. Opti., 1983, 21(14), 2224-2226.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senda, J., Fukami, Y., Tanabe, Y. and Fujimoto, H. Visualization of evaporative diesel spray impinging upon wall surface by Exciplex fluorescence method. SAE Paper 920578, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Felton, P. G., Bracco, F. V. and Bardsley, M. E. On the quantitative application of Exciplex fluorescence to engine sprays. SAE Paper 930870, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujimoto, H., Kusano, S. and Senda, J. Distribution of vapor concentration in a diesel spray impinging on a flat wall by means of exciplex fluorescence method - in case of high injection pressure. SAE Paper 972916, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., Verhoeven, D. and Baritaud, T. A. High-pressure diesel spray and combustion visualization in a transparent model diesel engine. SAE Paper 1999-01-3648, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chraplyvy, A. R. Nonintrusive measurements of vapor concentrations inside sprays. Appli. Opti., 1981, 20(15), 2620-2624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drallmeier, J. A. and Peters, R. E. Experimental investigation of fuel spray vapor phase characterization. Atomization and Sprays, 1991, 1(1), 63-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Billings, T. P. and Drallmeier, J. A. A detailed assessment of the infrared extinction technique for hydrocarbon vapor measurements in a controlled two-phase flow. Atomization and Sprays, 1994, 4(1), 99-121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suzuki, S., Nishida, K. and Hiroyasu, H. Simultaneous concentration measurement of vapor and liquid in an evaporating diesel spray. SAE Paper 930863, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y. Y., Yoshizaki, Y. and Nishida, K. Imaging of droplets and vapor distributions in a diesel fuel spray by means of a laser absorption-scattering technique. Appli. Opti., 2000, 39(33), 6221-6229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y. Y., Nishida, K. and Yoshizaki, Y. Quantitative measurement of droplets and vapor concentration distributions in diesel sprays by processing UV and visible images. SAE Paper 2001- 01-1294, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hammond, D. C. Jr. Deconvolution technique for line-of-sight optical scattering measurements in axisymmetric sprays. Appli. Opti., 1981, 20(3), 493- 498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamimoto, T., Yokata H. and Kobayashi, H. A new technique for the measurement of Sauter mean diameter of droplets in unsteady dense sprays. SAE Paper 890316, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y. Y. A study on mixture formation in diesel sprays with split-injection strategies. Dissertation of Hiroshima University, 2001, chap.2, 24-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Senda, J., Kanda, T. and Fujimoto, H. Quantitative analysis of fuel vapor concentration in diesel spray by Exciplex fluorescence method. SAE Paper 970796, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y. Y., Ito, T., Nishida, K. and Yoshizaki, T. Quantitative measurement of liquid and vapor phase concentration in a fuel spray by processing UV and visible laser images. JSAE transactions, 2001, 32(3), 37-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takamura, A., Ohata, T., Fukushima, S. and Kamimoto, T. A Study on Precise Measurement of Diesel Fuel Injection Rate, SAE Paper 920630, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishikawa, S., Omori, Y., Fukushima, S., Suzuki, T., Takamura, A. and Kamimoto, T. Measurement of Rate of Multiple-Injection in Cdi Diesel Engines, SAE Paper 2000-01-1257, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Climent, H., Salvador, F. J., Favennec, A. G. Diesel Injection System Modelling. Methodology and Application for a First-generation Common Rail System, Proc. Instn. Mech. Engrs. Vol.218, Part D: Automobile Engineering, pp.81-91, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D. L. Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays, SAE Paper 980809, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nishida, K., Zhang, W. and Manabe, T. Effects of Micro-Hole and Ultra-High Injection Pressure on Mixture Properties of D.I. Diesel Spray, SAE Paper 2007-01-1890, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. D. and Siebers, D. L. Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays, SAE Paper 960034, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dent, J. C. Basis for the comparison of various experimental methods for studying spray penetration. SAE Paper 710571, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakuri, Y., Fujii, M., Amitani, T. and Tsuneya, R.: Studies on the penetration of fuel spray of diesel engine. Trans. JSME, Series II, Vol. 25, No.156, p. 820-826, 1959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J. M., Payri, R., Salvador, F. J. and Gil, A. Development and Validation of a Theoretical Model for Diesel Spray Penetration, Fuel, vol.85, pp.910- 917, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuo, T. W. and Bracco, F. V. On the Scaling of Transient, Laminar, Turbulent and Spray Jets, SAE Paper 820038, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Pastor, J. V. and Pastor, J. M. and Julia, J. E. Diesel Spray Analysis by Means of Planar Laserinduced Exciplex Fluorescence, International Journal of Engine Research, vol.7, pp.77-89, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hill, P.G. and Ouellette, P. Transient Turbulent Gaseous Fuel Jets for Diesel Engines, Journal of Fluids Engineering, vol.121, pp.93-101, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B. R. and Ghandhi, J. B. Transient High- Pressure Hydrogen Jet Measurements, SAE Paper 2006-01-0652, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamimoto, T., Ahn, S. K., Chang, Y. J. and Kobayashi, H. Measurement of droplet diameter and fuel concentration in a non-evaporating diesel spray by means of an image analysis of shadow photographs, SAE Paper 840276, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
