<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">112</volume>
         <issue-id>i40199581</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44741374</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Improved In-Cylinder Local CAD-Resolved Equivalence Ratio Measurement Probe for SI Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Guibert</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Z.</given-names>
                  <surname>Boutar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Le Moyne</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2003</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1549</fpage>
         <lpage>1560</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2004 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44741374"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>A new tool able to deliver the local in-cylinder equivalence air fuel ratio with high temporal CA resolution is presented for SI engines. Although nonintrusive laser techniques have considerable advantages, they are inappropriate for series engines application and other measurement techniques do not have a fast enough time response. The probe presented fullfills the demand for fast local air-fuel ratio measurement with a simpler device than fast FID. Mounted at the spark plug location, it allows a completely normal running of the engine as it is integrated in a spark plug. The probe is based on hot wire anemometry technique involving catalytic oxidation of hydrocarbons on the wire. A parametric study giving the major characteristics of the measurement sensitivity, confidence, response time and some applications of the probe to in-cylinder engine measurements are presented which confirm the ability of the technique to characterize, quantitatively, the homogeneity or in-homogeneity of airfuel mixture, especially during the compression stroke with CA resolution.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d897722e373a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e380" publication-type="other">
Adler, D. A hot wire technique for continuous measurement in
unsteady concentration fields of binary gaseous mixtures. Journal of
Physics E: Scientific Instruments, Vol 5, 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e393a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e400" publication-type="other">
Arcoumanis, C., Green, H., Whitelaw, JH. The application of
laser Rayleigh scattering to reciprocating model engine. SAE Paper
840376, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e413a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e420" publication-type="other">
Birch, AD., Brown, DR., Dodson, MG., Swaffield, F. Aspects of
design and application of hot film aspirating probes used for the
measurement of gas concentration. J. Phys. E, Sci. Instr. 19, 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e433a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e440" publication-type="other">
Blackshear, PL., Lingerson, L. Rapid response heat flux probe
for high temperature gases. ARS Journal, Vol 32, N째l, pp 1709-
1715, 1962.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e454a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e461" publication-type="other">
Brown GL., Rebollo MR. A small, fast response probe to
measure composition of binary gas mixture. AIAA J. Vol 10, N째 5,
pp 649-652, 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e474a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e481" publication-type="other">
Castagne M., Cheve E., Dumas J.P., Henriot S. Advanced tools
for analysis of gasoline direct injection engines. SAE paper 2000-01-
1903,2000</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e494a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e501" publication-type="other">
Chang, MF., Nolan, MP., Rillings, JH., Quader, AA The axially
stratified charge engine: control, calibration, and vehicle
implementation. SAE Paper 851674, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e514a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e521" publication-type="other">
Cho, P., Law, CK. Catalytic ignition of fuel/oxygen/nitrogen
mixtures over platinum. Comb, and Flame 66, pp 159-170, 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e531a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e538" publication-type="other">
Collis, DC., Williams, MJ. Two dimensional convection from
heated wires at low Reynolds numbers. J. Fluid Mech. Vol 6, pp 357-
383, 1959.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e551a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e558" publication-type="other">
Depussay E., Mounaim-Rousselle C., Burnel S, Ricordeau V.,
Deschamps ?.-Comparative Measurements of Local Iso-Octane
Concentrations By Planar Laser Induced Fluorescence and Catalytic
Hot Wires Probe in Si Engine. SAE 982474, 1998</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e575a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e582" publication-type="other">
Mounaim-Rousselle C. -Deschamps B.-Depussay E., Ricordeau
V. -Combined Catalytic Hot Wires Probe and Fuel-Air-Ratio-Laser-
Induced-Exciplex Fluorescence Fuel/air Ratio Measurements At the
Spark Location Prior to Ignition in a Stratified Gdi Engine, SAE
1999-01-3536, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e601a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e608" publication-type="other">
Edwards, WM., Worley, FL., Luss, D Temperature fuctuations
(flickering) of catalytic wires and gauzes -II: Experimental study of
butane oxidation on platinum wires. Chemical Engineering Science,
Vol 28 pp. 1479-1491, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e624a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e631" publication-type="other">
Fansler, T., Drake, M., French, D -Fuel distributions in a firing-
direct-injection spark-ignition engine using laser-induced
fluorescence imaging. SAE Paper 9501 10, 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e644a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e651" publication-type="other">
Griffin, TA., Pfefferle, LD. Gas phase and catalytic ignition of
Methane and Ethane in air over platinum. AICHE J., Vol 36, N째 6,
pp 861-870, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e664a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e671" publication-type="other">
Guibert, P., Dicocco, E. Development of a local continuous
sampling probe for the equivalence fuel-air ratio measurement.
Application to spark ignition engine. Experiments in Fluids 32 494-
505, 2002.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e687a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e694" publication-type="other">
Hiam, L., Wise, H., Chaikin, S. Catalytic oxidation of
hydrocarbons on platinum. Journal of Catalysis 9, 10, 272-276, 1968.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e705a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e712" publication-type="other">
Li, CF., Murat, M., Jullien, J., Zhu, J. A fast response catalytic
hot wire sonic nozzle probe to measure fuel concentration in a fuel
air mixture. Meas. Seien. Technol. 5 pp 151-156, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e725a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e732" publication-type="other">
Lo Russo, JA., Lavoie, GA., Kaiser, EW. An electrohydraulic
gas sampling valve with application to HC emissions studies. SAE
Paper 800045, 1980.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e745a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e752" publication-type="other">
Morris, CJ., Dent, JC. The simultaneous measurement of gas
concentration and velocity in binary flows using hot wire
anemometry. Inst, of Mech. Eng. Paper C61/76, 1976.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e765a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e772" publication-type="other">
Murase, I., Moriyama, A., Nakai, M. A portable fast response
air-fuel ratio meter using an extended range oxygen sensor. SAE
Paper 880559, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e785a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e792" publication-type="other">
Watry, D., Sawyer, R., Green, R., Cousyn B The application of
an air to fuel ratio sensor to the investigation of a two stroke engine.
SAE Paper 910720, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d897722e805a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d897722e812" publication-type="other">
Way, J., Libby, PA. Hot-wire probes for measuring velocity and
concentration in helium-air mixtures. AIAA J. Vol 8, N째5, pp 976-
978, 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


