<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272343</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of the Performance of a Boosted HCCI Gasoline Engine with Blowdown Supercharge System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gotoh</surname>
                  <given-names>Shunsuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kuboyama</surname>
                  <given-names>Tatsuya</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moriyoshi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hatamura</surname>
                  <given-names>Koichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Hatamura Engine Research Office</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yamada</surname>
                  <given-names>Toshio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IDAJ Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Takanashi</surname>
                  <given-names>Junichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Urata</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>2171</fpage>
         <lpage>2179</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright @2013 SAE Japan and Copyright @ 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272343"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>HCCI combustion can realize low NOx and particulate emissions and high thermal efficiency. Therefore, HCCI combustion has a possibility of many kinds of applications, such as an automotive powertrain, general-purpose engine, motorcycle engine and electric generator. However, the operational range using HCCI combustion in terms of speed and load is restricted because the onset of ignition and the heat release rate cannot be controlled directly. For the extension of the operational range using either an external supercharger or a turbocharger is promising. The objective of this research is to investigate the effect of the intake pressure on the HCCI high load limit and HCCI combustion characteristics with blowdown supercharging (BDSC) system. The intake pressure (Pin) and temperature (Tin) were varied as experimental parameters. The intake pressure was swept from 100 kPa (naturally aspirated) to 200 kPa using an external mechanical supercharger. The experimental results showed that the maximum load successfully increased with increasing the intake pressure. The highest load in this study was 935kPa in IMEPg at the condition of 200 kPa in Pin and 32 °C in Tin. The maximum load of boosted BDSC-HCCI engine can be achieved comparable to the full load of naturally aspirated SI engine. In addition, for conditions with above 200 kPa in Tin, A/F and G/F could be almost the same. The comparison of heat release rate between with and without BDSC showed that the peak value of heat release rate decreased and the combustion duration was prolonged with BDSC by thermal stratification. Not only the pressure rise rate but also the peak cylinder pressure could be reduced by BDSC system. Moreover, the intake temperature was decreased while maintaining the conditions of G/F and intake pressure to investigate the intake temperature on heat release. The results showed that the dP/dθ max is reduced with Tin less than 50 °C.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hyvönen Jari, Haraldsson Göran, and Johansson Bengt, “Supercharging HCCI to extend the operating range in a Multi Cylinder VCR-HCCI engine,” SAE technical paper 2003-01-3214, 2003,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):750-767, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl Marco, Pitz William, Sarathy Mani, Yang Yi, and Dec John, “Detailed Kinetic Modeling of Conventional Gasoline at Highly Boosted Conditions and the Associated Intermediate Temperature Heat Release,” 2012-01-1109, 2012,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urata Yasuhiro, Awasaka Moriyoshi, Takanashi Junichi, Kakinuma Takashi, Hakozaki Takazou, and Umemoto Atsushi, “A Study of Gasoline Fuelled HCCI Engine Equipped with an Electromagnetic Valve-train,” SAE technical paper 2004-01-1898, 2004,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer Andre, Nier Tobias, and Karrelmeyer Roland, “A Thermodynamic Study on Boosted HCCI: Experimental Results, SAE technical paper 2011-01-0905, 2011,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson Thomas, Johansson Bengt, Tunestål Per, and Aulin Hans, “HCCI Operating Range in a Turbocharged Multi Cylinder Engine with VVT and Spray-Guided DI,” SAE technical paper 2009-01-0494, 2009,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatamura Koichi, “A Study on HCCI (Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition) Gasoline Engine Supercharged by Exhaust Blow own pressure,” SAE Technical paper 2007-01-1873, 2007,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuboyama Tatsuya, Moriyoshi Yasuo, Hatamura Koichi, Yamada Toshio, and Takanashi Junichi, “An Experimental Study of a Gasoline HCCI Engine Using the Blow-Down Super Charge System,” SAE technical paper 2009-01-0496, 2009,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng J. A, “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE technical paper 2002-01-2859, 2002,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood John B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw-Hill, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
