<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910590</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Inconsistencies in Joint and Allied Methods for Course of Action Comparison</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Holzgrefe</surname>
                  <given-names>James P. L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ James P. L. Holzgrefe serves as a Functional Area 49 Operations Research and Systems Analysis officer in the United States Army. He is currently pursuing a PhD in engineering management at Old Dominion University full-time under the Army’s Advanced Civil Schooling program. His previous assignments include tactical combat deployments to Iraq with the 17th Air Cavalry Regiment and analytical leadership positions at the Center for Army Analysis and in Army PA&amp;E.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hester</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Patrick T. Hester is an associate professor of engineering management and systems engineering at Old Dominion University. He received a PhD in risk and reliability engineering from Vanderbilt University. His research interests include systemic thinking, multicriteria decision analysis, and enterprise performance measurement and management, and he is a member of the IIE, Performance Management Association, Society for Judgment and Decision Making, and International Society on Multiple Criteria Decision Making.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>March 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>47</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910577</issue-id>
         <fpage>35</fpage>
         <lpage>42</lpage>
         <page-range>35-37, 42</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2013, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910590"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, J., and Slate, N. K. 2003. The case for a joint military decision making process, Military Review, Vol 83, No 5, 11–19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, C. L., and Yoon, K. P. 1981. Multiattribute decision making, methods and applications, Vol 186. New York: Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stevens, S. S. (1946). On the theory of scales of measurement, Science, Vol 103, 667–680.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
