<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308476</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling the Cold Start of the Ford 3.5L V6 EcoBoost Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Zheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yi</surname>
                  <given-names>Jianwen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wooldridge</surname>
                  <given-names>Steven</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reiche</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Curtis</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Papaioannou</surname>
                  <given-names>George</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1367</fpage>
         <lpage>1387</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308476"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Optimization of the engine cold start is critical for gasoline direct injection (GDI) engines to meet increasingly stringent emission regulations, since the emissions during the first 20 seconds of the cold start constitute more than 80% of the hydrocarbon (HC) emissions for the entire EPA FTP75 drive cycle. However, Direct Injection Spark Ignition (DISI) engine cold start optimization is very challenging due to the rapidly changing engine speed, cold thermal environment and low cranking fuel pressure. One approach to reduce HC emissions for DISI engines is to adopt retarded spark so that engines generate high heat fluxes for faster catalyst light-off during the cold idle. This approach typically degrades the engine combustion stability and presents additional challenges to the engine cold start.</p>
            <p>This paper describes a CFD modeling based approach to address these challenges for the Ford 3.5L V6 EcoBoost engine cold start. A Ford in-house developed CFD code MESIM (Multi-dimensional Engine Simulation) was applied to study the effect of injection parameters and piston designs on the fuel preparation process under various engine speed and engine temperature conditions during the engine crank, run up and cold idle operations. It was found through the modeling studies that the formation of a robust fuel-air mixture distribution around the spark plug was the key to improving combustion stability and reducing the emissions. The factors that could directly affect the fuel-air mixture distribution are the injection timing, fuel pressure, and piston bowl design. Modeling results provided the physical insight of the fuel preparation mechanism of various injection strategies, and helped to optimize the split-injection strategy to improve the fuel-air mixture distribution around the spark plug. The engine test data confirmed that the optimized split injection strategies reduce HC emission by about 30% with lower fuel consumption and substantially improved combustion stability during engine cold-start.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ranini and G. Monnier, Turbocharging a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine, SAE 2001-01-0736</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Lecointe and G. Monnier, Downsizing a Gasoline EngineUsing Turbocharging with Direct Injection, SAE 2003-01-0542</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Borrmann, F. Brinkmann, K. Walder, B. Pingen, J. Wojahn, P. Behrends, Gasoline Direct Injection and Turbo Charging – A New Opportunity for Downsizing, Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technologies, Aachen, Germany, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O. Lang, J. Geiger, K. Habermann and M. Wittler, Boosting and Direct Injection – Synergies for Future Gasoline Engines, SAE 2005-01-1144</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Kleeberg, D. Tomazic, O. Lang, K. Habermann, Future Potential and Development Methods for High Output Turbocharged Direct Injection Gasoline Engines, SAE 2006-01-0046</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yi, J., Wooldridge, S., Coulson, G., Hilditch, J. et al., “Development and Optimization of the Ford 3.5L V6 EcoBoost System” SAE Int. J. Engines :1388- 1407, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Landenfeld, M. Kuesell and J. Gerhardt, Gasoline Direct Injection – an Attractive Concept for Emission Reduction”, 11th Aachener Motorkolloquium, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Kufferath, W. Samenfink and J. Gerhadrt,High pressure-Stratefied Start, the Better Start Strategy for Gasoline Direct Injection”, 12th Aachener Motorkolloquium, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Landenfeld, A. Kufferath and J. Gerhardt, Gasoline Direct Injection – SULEV Emission Concept, SAE 2004-01-004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Han, J. Yi, N. Trigui, Stratified Mixture Formation and Piston Wetting in a DISI Engine, SAE 2002-01- 2655</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Yi, Z. Han, N. Trigui, Fuel-Air Mixing Homogeneity and Performance Improvements of a Stratified- Charge DISI Combustion System, SAE 2002-01- 2656</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Han, C. Weaver, S. Wooldridge, T. Alger, J. Hilditch, J. Mcgee, B. Westrate, Z. Xu, J. Yi, X. Chen, N. Trigui, and G. Davis, Development of a New Light Stratified-Charge Combustion System for a Family of Engines with Upfront CFD Coupling with Thermal and Optical Engine Experiments, SAE- 2004-01-0545</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Yi, Z. Han, Z. Xu and L. Stanley, Combustion Improvement of a Light Stratified-Charge Direct Injection Engine, SAE-2004-01-0546</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. A. Amsden, "KIVA-3V: A Block-Structured KIVA Program for Engines with Vertical or Canted Valves", Los Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-13313- MS, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. A. Amsden, "KIVA-3V, Release 2: Improvements to KIVA-3V", Los Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-13608-MS, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Yi and Z. Han, A Methodology of Rapid Mesh Generation and Dynamic Mesh Management with Moving Valves for Engine CFD, SRR-2001-0268, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Han, Z. Xu and N. Trigui, Spray/Wall Interaction Models for Multidimensional Engine Simulation, International Journal of Engine Research, 1, 127- 146, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Han, Z. Xu, S. Wooldridge, J. Yi and G. Lavoie, Modeling of DISI Engine Sprays with Comparison to Experimental In-Cylinder Spray Images, 2001, SAE 2001-01-3667</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Han, Z. Xu, Wall Film Dynamics Modeling for Impinging Sprays in Engines, SAE 2004-01-0099</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Yi and S. Wooldridge, Modeling of Multi-hole Gasoline Injector Spray, Ford Research-SRR-2006- 0076.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. M., Lippert, R. D. Reitz, Modeling of Multicomponent fuels Using Continuous Distributions with Application to Droplet Evaporation and Sprays, SAE Paper 972282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Zeng, and C. F. Lee, A Multicomponent Droplet Preferential Vaporization Model for Spray Computations, Atomization and Spray, 12:1, pp. 163- 186, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Wang, C. F. Lee, Y. Zeng, Modeling of Fuel Air Mixing in a Stratified Gasoline Direct Injection Engine Using Multicomponent Representation, SAE 2003-01-0067.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Michael, G. Lavoie, C. Smith, E. Curtis, Macrospic Model of the D86 Fuel Volatility Procedure, SAE Paper 982724</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. B. Reiche, S. T. Wooldridge, P. C. Moilanen, G. C. Davis, Experimental Optimization of the Cold Start for the EcoBoost Engine, SAE 2009-01-1491</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
