<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939362</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Optimal Tax 1</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do justice perceptions support the concept of equal sacrifice? Evidence from Germany</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Metzing</surname>
                  <given-names>Maria</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>32</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939362"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The ability-to-pay approach assesses taxes paid as a sacrifice by the taxpayers. This raises the question of how to define and how to measure it: in absolute, relative, or marginal terms? U.S. respondents prefer a tax schedule that is either a pure (absolute) Equal Sacrifice or a mixture of Equal Sacrifice and Utilitarianism [Weinzierl, 2014]. To determine whether Germans prefer absolute, relative, or marginal Equal Sacrifice principle for their income taxation, I use a question item from the German Socio-Economic Panel (SOEP) to obtain information on the level of taxes individuals consider as fair. I estimate tax and transfer schedules with regard to three Equal Sacrifice definitions and analyze which one of the three best fits the data. The absolute and the relative Equal Sacrifice principle are the dominant candidates in terms of statistical fit.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Kenneth Joseph Arrow. Essays in the theory of risk-bearing. Markham Pub. Co Chicago, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Anthony B Atkinson. On the measurement of inequality. Journal of Economic Theory, 2(3):244 – 263, 1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Marcus Berliant and Miguel Gouveia. Equal sacrifice and incentive compatible income taxation. Journal of Public Economics, 51(2):219–240, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Raj Chetty. A new method of estimating risk aversion. American Economic Review, 96(5):1821–1834, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Pierre Chiappori and Monica Paiella. Relative Risk Aversion Is Constant: Evidence From Panel Data. Journal of the European Economic Association, 9(6):1021–1052, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Thomas Dohmen, Armin Falk, David Huffman, Uwe Sunde, Jürgen Schupp, and Gert G. Wagner. Individual risk attitudes: Measurement, determinants, and behavioral consequences. Journal of the European Economic Association, 9(3):522–550, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Udo Ebert and Patrick Moyes. Consistent income tax structures when households are heterogeneous. Journal of Economic Theory, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Francis Y. Edgeworth. The pure theory of taxation. The Economic Journal, 7:46–70, 1897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Irwin Friend and Marshall E Blume. The demand for risky assets. American Economic Review, 65(5):900–922, 1975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Jan Goebel, Markus Grabka, Stefan Liebig, Martin Kroh, David Richter, Carsten Schröder, and Jürgen Schupp. The German Socio-Economic Panel (SOEP). Jahrbücher für Nationalökonomie und Statistik, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas and Jonathan Parker. Consumption Over the Life Cycle. Econometrica, 70(1):47–89, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Peter Haan and Katharina Wrohlich. Optimal Taxation: The Design of Child-Related Cash and In-Kind Benefits. German Economic Review, 11: 278–301, 08 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Guilermina Jasso and Murray Jr. Webster. Double standards in just earnings for male and female workers. Social Psychology Quarterly, 60:66–78, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Guillermina Jasso. On the Justice of Earnings: A New Specification of the Justice Evaluation Function. American Journal of Sociology, 83:1398–1419, 1978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Robin Jessen, Maria Metzing, and Davud Rostam-Afschar. Optimal Taxation Under Different Concepts of Justness. Discussion Papers Free University Berlin, 26, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Greg Kaplan. Inequality and the life cycle. Quantitative Economics, 3(3): 471–525, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Stefan Liebig, Peter Valet, and Jürgen Schupp. Perceived income justice depends on the economy. Weekly Report - Deutsches Institut für Wirtschaftsforschung (DIW), 6:187–192, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Stefan Liebig, Carsten Sauer, and Jürgen Schupp. The justice of earnings in dual-earner households. Research in Social Stratification and Mobility, 30 (2):219 – 232, 2012. ISSN 0276-5624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">James Stuart Mill. Principle of Political Economy. Longmans Green &amp; Co., London, 1848.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">James A. Mirrlees. An Exploration in the Theory of Optimum Income Taxation. Review of Economic Studies, 38(2):175–208, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">R. A. Musgrave and P. B. Musgrave. Public finance in theory and practice. McGraw-Hill, New York, 1973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Richard A. Musgrave. The Theory of Public Finance. McGraw-Hill, 1959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Richard A. Musgrave. Fairness in taxation. In Robert D. Ebel Joseph J. Cordes and Jane G. Gravelle, editors, The Encyclopedia of Taxation and Tax Policy. Urban Institute Press, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Thomas Piketty and Emmanuel Saez. Optimal Labor Income Taxation. In M. Feldstein A. Auerbach, R. Chetty and E. Saez, editors, Handbook of Public Economics, chapter 9. Elsevier-North Holland, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">John W. Pratt. Risk Aversion in the Small and in the Large. Econometrica, 32(1/2):122–136, 1964.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Wolfram F. Richter. From Ability to Pay to Concepts of Equal Sacrifice. Journal of Public Economics, 20:211–229, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Emmanuel Saez and Stefanie Stantcheva. Generalized social marginal welfare weights for optimal tax theory. American Economic Review, 106(1):24–45, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Henry Sidgwick. Principle of Political Economiy. Macmillan, London, 1883.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Adam Smith. An Inquiry into the Nature and Causes of the Wealth of Nations. 1776.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Justin van de Ven, Nicolas Herault, and Francisco Azpitarte. Identifying tay implicit equivalence scales. Journal of Economic Inequality, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Matthew Weinzierl. The promise of positive optimal taxation: normative diversity and a role for equal sacrifice. Journal of Public Economics, 118 (C):128–142, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Peyton Young. Distributive justice in taxation. Journal of Economic Theory, 44:321–335, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Peyton Young. Progressive taxation and sacrifice. American Economic Review, 80:253–266, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Questionnaire</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Summary statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Additional summary statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>ATR of the fair perceived income for different household types</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Social Security and Tax (SST) Formulas</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Equal Sacrifice and ATRs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Equal Sacrifice Tax Schedule vs. Fair Tax Schedule</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>OLS regression for the three Equal Sacrifice SST and Fair SST Schedule (in logs and without a constant)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Equal Sacrifice Tax Schedule vs. Fair Tax Schedule for different household types</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Equal Sacrifice and Government Consumption</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Regression for estimating the risk aversion parameter ε by the method of Young [1990]</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table B.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Additional summary statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Scatter plot of ATR-fair ATR over income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Scatter plot of MTR-fair MTR over income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table B.2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Cramer’s V</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Equal Sacrifice Tax Schedule vs. Fair Tax Schedule</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure B.4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Equal Sacrifice Tax Schedule vs. Fair Tax Schedule for different household types</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
