<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562373</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Conditioning Turbocharger Compressor Map Data for Use in Engine Performance Simulation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>McMullen</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pino</surname>
                  <given-names>Yirot</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>John Deere Power Systems</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562366</issue-id>
         <fpage>491</fpage>
         <lpage>508</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562373"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Turbocharger compressor maps are used in engine performance modeling and simulation to predict engine air system operating conditions. Errors in compressor map data can result in inaccurate engine performance prediction. A method is described for conditioning compressor map data for use in engine performance simulation, by detecting and replacing suspect data points, and interpolating and extrapolating the map data. The method first characterizes enthalpy rise through the compressor, after removing data points likely influenced by heat transfer from turbine to compressor, using energy transfer coefficient vs. impeller outlet flow coefficient. This is done concurrently with estimating impeller outlet conditions using simplified geometry assumptions and a modified definition for compressor stage reaction. A single value for this modified stage reaction is determined to collapse all of the compressor map data onto one curve for energy transfer coefficient vs. impeller outlet flow coefficient. Next, the method characterizes pressure recovery corresponding to enthalpy rise, using simplified models for flow friction and incidence losses. To verify capability, the method is applied to compressor map data historically resulting in accurate engine performance prediction. The modeled compressor map predicts speed within ±2% and specific enthalpy rise within ±3% of measured data for more than 90% of the evaluated engine data points. To demonstrate usefulness, compressor maps with suspected issues are conditioned using this method. The conditioned maps reduce speed prediction error to measured engine data by up to 5 percentage points. However, predictions using the conditioned map for the extrapolated region to low compressor speed may not be sufficiently accurate for all compressor data. Future work will focus on improving method assumptions for this operating region.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>Compressor map</kwd> 
            <kwd>Turbocharger modeling</kwd> 
            <kwd>Engine performance simulation</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Turbocharger Gas Stand Test Code,” SAE Standard J1826, Rev. Mar. 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watson, N. and Janota, M., Turbocharging the Internal Combustion Engine (London: MacMillan Press, 1982).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guzella, L. and Onder, C., Introduction to Modeling and Control of Internal Combustion Engine Systems Third Edition (Berlin Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag, 2010), doi:10.1007/978- 3-642-10775-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals (New York: McGraw-Hill, 1988).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guillou, E., “Uncertainty and Measurement Sensitivity of Turbocharger Compressor Gas Stands,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0925, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiva Kumar, S., van Leeuwen, B., and Costall, A., “Quantification and Sensitivity Analysis of Uncertainties in Turbocharger Compressor Gas Stand Measurements Using Monte Carlo Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01- 1651, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1651.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Japiske, D. and Baines, N., Introduction to Turbomachinery (White River Junction, VT: Concepts ETI, 1997).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, R. and McDonald, A., Introduction to Fluid Mechanics Forth Edition (New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1992).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Casey, M. and Schlegel, M., “Estimation of the Performance of Turbocharger Compressors at Extremely Low Pressure Ratios,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part A: Journal of Power and Energy 224:239-250, 2010, doi:10.1243/09576509JPE810.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moraal, P. and Kolmanovsky, I., “Turbocharger Modeling for Automotive Control Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0908, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0908.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, G., Talon, V., Higelin, P., Charlet, A. et al., “Implementing Turbomachinery Physics into Data Map- Based Turbocharger Models,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):211- 229, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El Hadef, J., Colin, G., Chamaillard, Y., and Talon, V., “Physical-Based Algorithms for Interpolation and Extrapolation of Turbocharger Data Maps,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):363-378, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canova, M., Naddeo, M., Liu, Y., Zhou, J. et al., “A Scalable Modeling Approach for the Simulation and Design Optimization of Automotive Turbochargers,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(4):1616-1628, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1288.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sirakov, B. and Casey, M., “Evaluation of Heat Transfer Effects on Turbocharger Performance,” ASME Journal of Turbomachinery 135, 2013, doi:10.1115/1.4006608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luddecke, B., Filsinger, D., and Bargende, M., “On Wide Mapping of a Mixed Flow Turbine with Regard to Compressor Heat Flows during Turbocharger Testing,” IMechE 10th International Conference on Turbochargers and Turbocharging, 2012, 185-202, doi:10.1533/9780857096135.4a.185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
