<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437350</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Child Support, Income Support and Lone Mothers</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>PAUL</given-names>
                  <surname>BINGLEY</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>ELIZABETH</given-names>
                  <surname>SYMONS</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>IAN</given-names>
                  <surname>WALKER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437343</issue-id>
         <fpage>81</fpage>
         <lpage>98</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1994</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437350"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d50e205a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e212" publication-type="other">
See Haskey (1993) for estimates of the number of lone parents from a number of sample surveys including
the Family Expenditure Surveys used here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e222a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e229" publication-type="other">
A comprehensive description of the labour market behaviour of UK lone mothers drawn from the large
Labour Force Surveys of 1981,1984,1987 and 1990 can be found in Bartholomew et al. (1992). The evidence
there support the trends that we observe in the much smaller FES data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e242a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e249" publication-type="other">
See Brown (1989) for an overview of the welfare system relating to UK lone mothers and an interesting
comparison across a number of countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e259a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e266" publication-type="other">
See Jenkins (1992), Ermisch and Wright (1990), and Walker (1990) for estimates of models of participation
in the UK. Ermisch and Wright (1992) estimate equations for participation and for full-time participation for
all women. Blundell et al. (1992) estimate an hours equation for a subsample of UK lone parent taxpayers.
Bingley et al. (1993) estimate a random utility discrete choice model of labour supply for UK lone mothers
which is a more complex model than the one used here. See Hausman (1980) and Moffitt (1986a) for US
models of participation and hours of work. Fraker and Moffitt (1988), in particular, estimate a model of part-
time and full-time labour force participation, Food Stamp and AFDC participation. There has been no
equivalent UK work that addresses both labour supply and the take-up of means-tested benefits (see Blundell
et al., 1988 for a study of the take-up of UK housing benefit).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e299a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e306" publication-type="other">
Although, for married mothers, the proportion of mothers with pre-school children who work rose by a factor
of 3. There was also a major growth in all forms of child care facilities over the period, although husbands
remain the principal carer in households with working married mothers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e319a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e326" publication-type="other">
However, see Blundell et al. ( 1992) for an approach which estimates a labour supply model over a subsample
of lone mothers which is selected to face the standard tax rate only.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e336a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e343" publication-type="other">
An alternative method is to instrument the (net marginal) wage. However, because there are no obvious
exclusion restrictions IV methods usually have to make arbitrary assumptions and Mroz (1987) has shown that
labour supply estimates are quite sensitive to alternative assumptions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e356a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e363" publication-type="other">
Individuals are categorized as PT if they work less than 32 hours and FT if they work 32 hours or more.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e370a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e377" publication-type="other">
See Jenkins (1990) for a theoretical justification of this idea.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e384a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e391" publication-type="other">
Further methodological details are given in Bingley et al. (1993).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e399a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e406" publication-type="other">
See Dilnot and Walker (1990) for details of the 1988 reforms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e413a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e420" publication-type="other">
Age, time and regional dummies are included for a number of reasons: the differences in the composition
of the type of lone mother over time and cohorts and across regions, differences in the fixed costs of work, etc.
There has been a noticeable increase in the provision of child care facilities over this period, a marked
deterioration in unemployment over the first half of this period, and quite marked changes in the composition
of lone parents, all of which may be expected to play a role but may be only imperfectly captured by the
included variables. Similarly job market and child care opportunities may differ systematically across regions,
but the local level of unemployment may not adequately capture the former. Finally, age dummies are included
for both cohort and life-cycle reasons and to capture the time series changes that have occurred in the
composition of lone mothers: for example, there has been a quite marked reduction in the proportion of
widowed and a marked increase in the proportion of never married lone mothers over the period considered
here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e458a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e465" publication-type="other">
Some of the social policy aspects of the legislation not considered here are discussed in Bradshaw and Millar
(1991).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e475a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e482" publication-type="other">
Minor changes to the formula and arrangements for phasing in large changes in CS payments have just been
introduced and these are not included here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e492a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e499" publication-type="other">
However, there is no guarantee that the new formula-driven levels of CS would exceed the actual present
levels, especially since the former depend on the earnings of the mother while under the present arrangements
the existing CS levels are essentially independent of earnings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e512a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e519" publication-type="other">
In order to assess the labour market impact we need to be able to compute the level of CS under the reform
as well as know the existing level. This poses a considerable problem since the proposed CS formula is driven
partly by the earnings of the both the caring parent and the absent parent. In the absence of specific information
about the earnings of absent parents in FES data we have estimated an earnings equation for a sample of
married men with children and a spouse present in the household where the explanatory variables are the
characteristics of the wife. This equation is used to predict the incomes of absent parents - the presumption
being that separation is exogenous so that the equation produces unbiased predictions of the earnings of absent
parents. These predictions allow us to compute the maintenance bill if we make a further assumption about
the housing costs, and new domestic circumstances of the absent parent. The main drawback of this procedure
is that it assumes that absent fathers have the same earnings as employed married men. It seems likely that men
who are "unsuccessful" in marriage are likely to be less successful than average in the labour market - although
it is possible to think of arguments that go in the other direction. Moreover, they may be more likely to be
unemployed than married men with spouse present. We ignore both these sources of error which would lead
us to predict lower government expenditure than would otherwise be the case.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e568a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e575" publication-type="other">
Moreover, we interpret the CS dummies in the model as indicating that this source of income is uncertain,
and in our reform simulation we assume that the reform has the effect of eliminating this uncertainty.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d50e585a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e592" publication-type="other">
The participation rate is predicted to rise by approximately 4 percentage points.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d50e608a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e612" publication-type="other">
Bartholomew, R., Hibbett, A. and Sidaway, J. (1992) "Lone parents and the labour market:
evidence from the labour force survey", Employment Gazette, November, pp. 559-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e622a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e626" publication-type="other">
Bingley, P., Symons, E. and Walker, I. (1992) "The labour supply of UK lone mothers: the effects
of maintenance and the welfare system", IFS Working Paper 92/19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e636a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e640" publication-type="other">
—, Lanot,G., —and— (1993)"ChildsupportreformandthelaboursupplyofUKlonemothers",
Journal of Human Resources.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e650a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e654" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R.W., Fry, V. and Walker, I. (1988)" Modelling the take-up of means tested benefits
in the UK: the case of housing benefits", Economic Journal, no. 98, pp. 58-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e665a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e669" publication-type="other">
—, Meghir,C. andDuncan, A. (1992) "Taxation in empirical labour supply models: lone mothers
in the UK", Economic Journal, no. 102, pp. 265-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e679a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e683" publication-type="other">
Bradshaw, J. and Millar, J. (1991) Lone Parents in the UK, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e690a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e694" publication-type="other">
Brown, J.C. (1989) "Why don't they go to work: mothers on benefit?", Social Security Advisory
Committee Research Paper 2, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e704a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e708" publication-type="other">
Department of Social Security (1990) Children Come First, London: DSS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e715a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e719" publication-type="other">
Dilnot, A. and Walker, I. (1990) The Economics of Social Security, Oxford: Oxford University
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e729a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e733" publication-type="other">
Ermisch, J. and Wright, R. (1992) "Welfare benefits and lone parents' employment", Journal of
Human Resources, no. 26, pp. 424-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e744a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e748" publication-type="other">
— and — (1993) "Wage offers and full-time and part-time employment by British women",
Journal of Human Resources, no. 28, pp. 111-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e758a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e762" publication-type="other">
Fraker, T. and Moffitt, R. (1988) "The effect of food stamps on labour supply", Journal of Public
Economics, no. 35, pp. 25-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e772a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e776" publication-type="other">
Haskey, J. (1993) "Estimated numbers and demographic characteristics of one-parent families in
Great Britain", Population Trends, no. 71, pp. 26-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e786a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e790" publication-type="other">
Hausman, J. (1980) "The effect of wages, taxes, and fixed costs of work on women's labour force
participation", Journal of Public Economics, no. 14, pp. 161-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e800a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e804" publication-type="other">
Jenkins, S.P. (1990) in Dilnot and Walker (eds.).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e811a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e815" publication-type="other">
Jenkins, S.P. (1992) "Lone mothers' employment and full-time work probabilities", Economic
Journal, no. 102, pp. 310-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e826a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e830" publication-type="other">
MaCurdy, T. (1992) "Work disincentive effects of taxes: a re-examination of the evidence",
American Economic Review (Papers and Proceedings), no. 82, pp. 243-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e840a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e844" publication-type="other">
—, Green, D. and Paarsch, H. (1990) "Assessing empirical approaches for analysing taxes and
labour supply", Journal of Human Resources, no. 25, pp. 415-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e854a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e858" publication-type="other">
Moffitt, R. (1986a)"Work incentives in the AFDC system: an analysis of the 1981 reforms",
American Economic Review (Papers and Proceedings), no. 76, pp. 219-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e868a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e872" publication-type="other">
— (1986b) "The econometrics of piecewise linear budget constraints: a survey and exposition of
the maximum likelihood method", Journal of Economics and Business Statistics, no. 4, pp.
317-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e885a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e889" publication-type="other">
Mroz, T.A. (1987) "The sensitivity of an empirical model of married women's hours of work to
economic and statistical assumptions", Econometrica, vol. 55, pp. 765-800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e899a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e903" publication-type="other">
Walker, I. ( 1990) "The effect of income support measures on the labour market behaviour of lone
mothers", Fiscal Studies, vol.11, pp. 55-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
