<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277633</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Steady-State Combustion Development of a Downsized Multi-Cylinder Engine with Range Extended HCCI/SACI Capability</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Polovina</surname>
                  <given-names>Dusan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AVL Powertrain Engineering Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>McKenna</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AVL Powertrain Engineering Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wheeler</surname>
                  <given-names>Jennifer</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AVL Powertrain Engineering Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sterniak</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeff</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Robert Bosch LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miersch-Wiemers</surname>
                  <given-names>Oliver</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Robert Bosch LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mond</surname>
                  <given-names>Alan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Robert Bosch LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yilmaz</surname>
                  <given-names>Hakan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Robert Bosch LLC</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>504</fpage>
         <lpage>519</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277633"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper focuses on the combustion development portion of the Advanced Combustion Controls Enabling Systems and Solutions (ACCESS) project, a joint research project partially funded by a Department of Energy grant. The main goal of the project is to improve fuel economy in a gasoline fueled light-duty vehicle by 30% while maintaining similar performance and meeting SULEV emission standards for the Federal Test Procedure (FTP) cycle.</p>
            <p>In this study, several combustion modes Spark Ignited (SI), Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI), Spark- Assisted Compression Ignition (SACI)) were compared under various conditions (naturally aspirated, boosted, lean, and stoichiometric) to compare the methods of controlled auto-ignition on a downsized, boosted multi-cylinder engine with an advanced valvetrain system capable of operating under wide negative valve overlap (NVO) conditions. The engine was operated under steady state conditions at a constant engine speed of 1500rpm and various loads (2.0 - 6.0 bar BMEP) to investigate the impact of extending the HCCI/SACI operating range and compare the results to traditional SI combustion modes. The HCCI operating mode was tested under lean conditions both naturally aspirated and with mechanically supercharged operation to increase the load range. SACI combustion was examined at both lean and stoichiometric operating conditions, with the use of external cooled Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) for mitigation of combustion noise at high loads.</p>
            <p>It was found that the effective load range of naturally aspirated lean HCCI is limited but provides good combustion stability with significant improvements in BSFC compared to the optimized SI combustion mode. Extending the lean HCCI range via forced induction improves the lean capability at higher loads but exacerbates loss mechanisms that reduce overall brake thermal efficiency. Extending the operating range through stoichiometric SACI combustion modes resulted in BSFC improvements at the mid and high load points tested.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A. and Blaxill, H., “The Effects of Combined Internal and External Exhaust Gas Recirculation on Gasoline Controlled Auto- Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0133, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0133.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najt, P. and Foster, D., “Compression-Ignited Homogeneous Charge Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 830264, 1983, doi: 10.4271/830264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thring, R., “Homogeneous-Charge Compression-Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 892068, 1989, doi: 10.4271/892068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurushima, T., Harada, A., Iwashiro, Y., Enomoto, Y. et al., “Thermodynamic Characteristics of Premixed Compression Ignition Combustions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1891, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-1891.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurushima, T., Kunishima, E., Asaumi, Y., Aoyagi, Y. et al., “The Effect of Knock on Heat Loss in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0108, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saxena, S., Chen, J., and Dibble, R., “Maximizing Power Output in an Automotive Scale Multi-Cylinder Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0907, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L., Ogink, R., and Denbratt, I., “Direct Gasoline Injection in the Negative Valve Overlap of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1854, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, Y., King, E., Pfahl, U., Krile, R. et al., “Fuel Chemistry Impacts on Gasoline HCCI Combustion with Negative Valve Overlap and Direct Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4105, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-4105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A., and Itoh, T., “Expansion of HCCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, Negative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0749, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Wermuth, N., and Najt, P., “High Load HCCI Operation Using Different Valving Strategies in a Naturally-Aspirated Gasoline HCCI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1190-1201, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yap, D., Wyszynski, M., Megaritis, A., and Xu, H., “Applying Boosting to Gasoline HCCI Operation with Residual Gas Trapping,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2121, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall, A., Szybist, J., Edwards, K., Foster, M. et al., “HCCI Load Expansion Opportunities Using a Fully Variable HVA Research Engine to Guide Development of a Production Intent Cam-Based VVA Engine: The Low Load Limit,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1149-1162, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, T., Johansson, B., Tunestål, P., and Aulin, H., “HCCI Operating Range in a Turbo-charged Multi Cylinder Engine with VVT and Spray-Guided DI,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0494, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0494.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Wermuth, N., and Najt, P., “Development of Robust Gasoline HCCI Idle Operation Using Multiple Injection and Multiple Ignition (MIMI) Strategy,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0499, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0499.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hyvönen, J., Haraldsson, G., and Johansson, B., “Supercharging HCCI to Extend the Operating Range in a Multi-Cylinder VCR-HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3214, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-3214.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
