<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i30219551</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">30219553</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1007/s10590-008-9040-7</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Automatic Extraction of Translations from Web-Based Bilingual Materials</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Qibo</given-names>
                  <surname>Zhu</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Diana</given-names>
                  <surname>Inkpen</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ash</given-names>
                  <surname>Asudeh</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>139</fpage>
         <lpage>163</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 Springer Science Business Media B.V.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/30219553"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper describes the framework of the StatCan Daily Translation Extraction System (SDTES), a computer system that maps and compares web-based translation texts of Statistics Canada (StatCan) news releases in the StatCan publication The Daily. The goal is to extract translations for translation memory systems, for translation terminology building, for cross-language information retrieval and for corpus-based machine translation systems. Three years of officially published statistical news release texts at http://www.statcan.ca were collected to compose the StatCan Daily data bank. The English and French texts in this collection were roughly aligned using the Gale-Church statistical algorithm. After this, boundary markers of text segments and paragraphs were adjusted and the Gale-Church algorithm was run a second time for a more fine-grained text segment alignment. To detect misaligned areas of texts and to prevent mismatched translation pairs from being selected, key textual and structural properties of the mapped texts were automatically identified and used as anchoring features for comparison and misalignment detection. The proposed method has been tested with web-based bilingual materials from five other Canadian government websites. Results show that the SDTES model is very efficient in extracting translations from published government texts, and very accurate in identifying mismatched translations. With parameters tuned, the text-mapping part can be used to align corpus data collected from official government websites; and the text- comparing component can be applied in prepublication translation quality control and in evaluating the results of statistical machine translation systems.</p>
          </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Automatic translation extraction</kwd>
            <kwd>Bitext mapping</kwd>
            <kwd>Machine translation</kwd>
            <kwd>Parallel alignment</kwd>
            <kwd>Translation memory system</kwd>
          </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
        
         <fn-group>
            <title>[Footnotes]</title>
            <fn id="d3752131e289a1310">
               <label>1</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e296" publication-type="other">
http://www.d.umn.edu/∼tpederse/parallel.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      
        
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d3752131e312a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e316" publication-type="other">
Brown PF, Lai JC, Mercer RL (1991) Aligning sentences in parallel corpora. In: 29th annual meeting of
the association for computational linguistics, Berkeley, CA, pp 89-94</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e326a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e330" publication-type="other">
Callison-Burch C, Bannard C, Schroeder J (2005) A compact data structure for searchable translation
memories. In: 10th European association for machine translation conference: building applications of
machine translation, conference proceedings, pp 59-65</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e343a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e347" publication-type="other">
Chen S (1996) Building probabilistic models for natural language. PhD thesis. Harvard University,
Cambridge, MA</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e357a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e361" publication-type="other">
Chen A, Gey F (2001) Translation term weighting and combining translation resources in cross-language
retrieval. The tenth text retrieval conference (TREC 2001), Gaithersburg, MD, pp 529-533</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e372a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e376" publication-type="other">
Chen J, Nie JY (2000) Parallel web text mining for cross-language IR. In: Proceedings of RIAO 2000:
content-based multimedia information access, vol 1, Paris, France, pp 62-78</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e386a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e390" publication-type="other">
Chesñevar C, Sabaté M, Maguitman A (2006) An argument-based decision support system for assessing
natural language usage on the basis of the web corpus. Int J Intelligent Syst 21(1 1):1151-1180</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e400a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e404" publication-type="other">
Danielsson P, Miihlenbock K (2000) The misconception of high-frequency words in Scandinavian transla-
tion. In: Envisioning machine translation in the information future, 4th conference of the Association
for Machine Translation in the Americas, AMTA 2000, Cuernavaca, Mexico, pp 158-168</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e417a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e421" publication-type="other">
Deng Y, Kumar S, Byrne W (2006) Segmentation and alignment of parallel text for statistical machine
translation. J Nat Lang Eng 12(4):235-260</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e431a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e435" publication-type="other">
Fung P, Church KW (1994) K-vec: a new approach for aligning parallel texts. In: Proceedings of the 15th
international conference on computational linguistics, Kyoto, Japan, pp 1096-1102</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e445a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e449" publication-type="other">
Gale WA, Church KW (1991) A program for aligning sentences in bilingual corpora. In: 29th Annual
meeting of the association for computational linguistics, Berkeley, CA, pp 177-184</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e460a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e464" publication-type="other">
Gey FC, Chen A, Buckland MK, Larson RR (2002) Translingual vocabulary mappings for multilingual
information access. In: 25th Annual international ACM SIGIR conference on research and develop-
ment in information retrieval (SIGIR 2002), Tampere, Finland, pp 455-456</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e477a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e481" publication-type="other">
Hutchins J (2005) Towards a definition of example-based machine translation. In: MT summit X. Workshop:
second workshop on example-based machine translation. Phuket, Thailand, pp 63-70</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e491a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e495" publication-type="other">
Inkpen D, Frunza O, Kondrak G (2005) Automatic identification of cognates and false friends in French and
English. In: Proceedings of international conference on recent advances in natural language processing
(RANLP'05), Borovets, Bulgaria, pp 251-257</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e508a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e512" publication-type="other">
Jutras J-M (12000) An automatic reviser: the transCheck system. In: 6th applied natural language process-
ing conference and 1st meeting of the North American chapter of the association for computational
linguistics, proceedings of the conferences, Seattle, WA, pp 127-134</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e525a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e529" publication-type="other">
Kay M, Röscheisen M (1993) Text-translation alignment. Comput Linguist 19(1): 121-142</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e536a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e540" publication-type="other">
Kondrak G, Dorr B (2004) Identification of confusable drug names: a new approach and evaluation meth-
odology. In: Coling, 20th international conference on computational linguistics, proceedings, Geneva,
Switzerland, vol II, pp 952-958</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e554a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e558" publication-type="other">
Li KW, Yang C (2006) Conceptual analysis of parallel corpus collected from the Web. J Am Soc Inf Sci
Technol 57(5):632-644. doi: 10. 1002/asi.20326</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e568a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e572" publication-type="other">
McArthur T (ed) (1992) The Oxford companion to the English language. Oxford University Press, Oxford</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e579a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e583" publication-type="other">
Melamed ID (1999) Bitext maps and alignment via pattern recognition. Comput Linguist 25(1):107-130</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e590a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e594" publication-type="other">
Moore RC (2002) Fast and accurate sentence alignment of bilingual corpora. In: Machine translation: from
research to real users, 5th conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas,
AMTA 2002, Tiburon, CA, proceedings, LNAI 2499. Springer, Berlin, pp 135-144</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e607a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e611" publication-type="other">
Neumann S, Hansen-Schirra S (2005) The CroCo project. Cross-linguistic corpora for the investigation
of explicitation in translations. In: Proceedings from the corpus linguistics conference series, Corpus
Linguistics 2005, Birmingham, UK, vol 1, no. 1. Available online: http://www.corpus.bham.ac.uk/
PCLC/cl- 134-pap.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e627a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e631" publication-type="other">
Pedersen T, Varma N (2002) K-vec++: approach for finding word correspondences. Available online:
http://www.d.umn.edu/∼tpederse/parallel.html</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e642a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e646" publication-type="other">
Resnik P (1999) Mining the web for bilingual text. In: 37th annual meeting of the association for compu-
tational linguistics, College Park, MD, pp 527-534</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e656a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e660" publication-type="other">
Resnik P, Smith N (2003) The web as a parallel corpus. Comput Linguist 29(3):349-380.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e667a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e671" publication-type="other">
Ribeiro A, Dias G, Lopes G, Mexia J (2001) Cognates alignment. In: MT summit VIII, machine translation
in the information age, proceedings, Santiago de Compostela, Spain, pp 287-292</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e681a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e685" publication-type="other">
Sánchez-Villamil E, Santos-Antón S, Ortiz-Rojas S, Forcada NIL (2006) Evaluation of alignment meth-
ods for HTML parallel text. Advances in natural language processing, proceedings of FinTAL 2006,
5th international conference on natural language processing, Turku, Finland, LNCS 4139. Springer,
Berlin, pp 280-290</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e701a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e705" publication-type="other">
Sigurbjörnsson B, Kamps J, de Rijke, M (2005) EuroGOV: engineering a multilingual web corpus.
In: Accessing multilingual information repositories: 6th workshop of the cross-language evaluation
forum, CLEF 2005. LNCS 4022. Springer, Berlin, pp 825-836</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e718a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e722" publication-type="other">
Simard M, Foster G, Isabelle P (1992) Using cognates to align sentences in bilingual corpora. In: Fourth
international conference on theoretical and methodological issues in machine translation, empiricist
vs. rationalist methods in MT (TMI 92), proceedings of the conference, Montreal, Canada, pp 67-81</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e736a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e740" publication-type="other">
Simões AM, Almeida JJ (2006) Combinatory examples extraction for machine translation. In: 11th
annual conference of the European association for machine translation, proceedings, Oslo, Norway,
pp 27-32</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e753a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e757" publication-type="other">
Tufig D, Barbu AM, Ion R (2004) Extracting multilingual lexicons from parallel corpora. Comput Hum
38(2):163-189.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e767a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e771" publication-type="other">
Véronis J (2000a) Alignement de corpus multilingues. In: Pierrel J-M (ed) Ingénierie des langues, Traité
IC2-Série Informatique et SI. Èditions Hermes Science, Paris</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e781a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e785" publication-type="other">
Véronis J (2000b) From the Rosetta stone to the information society: a survey of parallel text processing. In:
Véronis J (ed) Parallel text processing: alignment and use of translation corpora. Kluwer Academic
Publishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands, pp 1-24</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e798a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e802" publication-type="other">
Wang JH, Teng JW, Lu WH, Chien LF (2006) Exploiting the Web as the multilingual corpus for unknown
query translation. J Am Soc Inf Sci Technol 57(5):660-670</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3752131e812a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3752131e816" publication-type="other">
Wu D (1994) Aligning a parallel English-Chinese corpus statistically with lexical criteria. In: 32nd annual
meeting of the association for computational linguistics, proceedings of the conference, Las Cruces,
NM, pp 80-87</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      </back>
</article>
