<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278025</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Combining the Classical and Lumped Diesel Particulate Filter Models</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Depcik</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Kansas</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1261</fpage>
         <lpage>1270</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278025"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The growing presence of Spark Ignition Direct Injection (SIDI) engines along with the prevalence of direct injected Compression Ignition (CI) engines results in the requirement of Particulate Matter (PM) exhaust abatement. This occurs through the implementation of Gasoline Particulate Filters (GPFs) and Diesel Particulate Filters (DPFs). Modeling of GPFs and DPFs are analogous because of the similar flow patterns and wall flow PM capture methodology. Conventional modeling techniques include a two-channel (inlet/outlet) formulation that is applicable up to three-dimensions. However, the numerical stiffness that results from the need to couple the solution of these channels in compressible flow can result in relatively long run times. Previously, the author presented a lumped DPF model using dynamically incompressible flow intended for an Engine Control Unit (ECU) in order to generate a model that runs faster than real time using a high-level programming language. Building on the favorable outcomes of temperature evolution from this prior effort, this work enhances the model to predict compressible flow gas dynamics in order to match the evolution of pressure drop. Another enhancement is the inclusion of deep bed filtration within the wall, and the transition to the cake layer. Results show comparable temperature profiles with the dynamically incompressible model with a pressure drop that follows appropriately by linking through the ideal gas model. However, solving chemical species as an independent equation separate from compressible flow still deviates significantly from the classical two-channel approach.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diaz-Sanchez, D., “The Role of Diesel Exhaust Particles and their Associated Polyaromatic Hydrocarbons in the Induction of Allergic Airway Disease,” Allergy, 52 (38 Suppl):52-6; discussion 57-8, 1997, doi:10.1111/j.1398-9995.1997.tb04871.x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depcik, C., Langness, C., and Mattson, J., “Development of a Simplified Diesel Particulate Filter Model Intended for an Engine Control Unit,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1559, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1559.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koltsakis, G., Haralampous, O., Depcik, C., and Ragone, J. C., “Catalyzed Diesel Particulate Filter Modeling,” Reviews in Chemical Engineering, 29 (1): 1-61, 2013, doi:10.1515/revce-2012-0008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bissett, E. J., “Mathematical Model of the Thermal Regeneration of a Wall-flow Monolith Diesel Particulate Filter,” Chemical Engineering Science, 39 (7-8):1232-1244, 1984, doi:10.1016/0009-2509(84)85084-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depcik, C., and Assanis, D., “Graphical User Interfaces in an Engineering Educational Environment,” Computer Applications in Engineering Education, 13 (1):48-59, 2005, doi:10.1002/cae.20029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A. and Johnson, J., “Wall-Flow Diesel Particulate Filters-Their Pressure Drop and Collection Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 890405, 1989, doi:10.4271/890405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A., Kostoglou, M., Skaperdas, E., Papaioannou, E. et al., “Fundamental Studies of Diesel Particulate Filters: Transient Loading, Regeneration and Aging,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1016, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A., Skaperdas, E., and Masoudi, M., “Microstructural Properties of Soot Deposits in Diesel Particulate Traps,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1015, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A., Kostoglou, M., Vlachos, N., and Kladopoulou, E., “Progress in Diesel Particulate Filter Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0946, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fukushima, S., Ohno, K., Vlachos, N., and Konstandopoulos, A., “New Approach for Pore Structure and Filtration Efficiency Characterization,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1918, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A., Kladopoulou, E., and Skaperdas, E., “Transient Pressure Drop of Diesel Particulate Filters,” J. Aerosol Sci., 31 (Suppl. 1):S208-S209, 2000, doi:10.1016/S0021-8502(00)90215-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depcik, C., and Assanis, D., “Simulating Area Conservation and the Gas-Wall Interface for One- Dimensional Based Diesel Particulate Filter Models,” ASME Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 130 (6):062807, 2008, doi:10.1115/1.2939002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depcik, C., “Simulating the Concentration Equations and the Gas-Wall Interface for One-Dimensional Based Diesel Particulate Filter Models,” ASME Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 132 (3):032803, 2010, doi:10.1115/1.3155792.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haralampous, O., Koltsakis, G., and Samaras, Z., “Partial Regenerations in Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1881, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1881.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sprouse, C.III, Mangus, M., and Depcik, C., “Diesel Particulate FIlter Model with Detailed Permeability Analysis,” ASME 2011 International Mechanical Engineering Congress &amp; Exposition, Denver, CO, 2011, doi:10.1115/IMECE2011-63687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gantawar, A., Opris, C., and Johnson, J., “A Study of the Regeneration Characteristics of Silicon Carbide and Cordierite Diesel Particulate Filters Using a Copper Fuel Additive,” SAE Technical Paper 970187, 1997, doi:10.4271/970187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, D., Warren, C., Gadkaree, K., and Johannesen, L., “Silicon Carbide for Diesel Particulate Filter Applications:Material Development and Thermal Design,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0324, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0324.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
