<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169097</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Consequences of Deep Cycling 24 Volt Battery Strings</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Catherino</surname>
                  <given-names>Henry A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oakland University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Feres</surname>
                  <given-names>Fred</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Exide Technologies</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>July 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169081</issue-id>
         <fpage>378</fpage>
         <lpage>387</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169097"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Deep charge and discharge cycling of 24 Volt battery strings composed of two 12 Volt VRLA batteries wired in series affects reliability and life expectancy. This is a matter of interest in vehicle power source applications. These cycles include those specific operational cases requiring the delivery of the full storage capacity during discharge. The concern here is related to applications where batteries serve as a primary power source and the energy content is an issue. It is a common practice for deep cycling a 24 volt battery string to simply add the specified limit voltages during charge and discharge for the individual 12 Volt batteries. In reality, the 12 Volt batteries have an inherent capacity variability and are not identical in their performance characteristics. The actual voltages of the individual 12 Volt batteries are not identical. The experimental measurements reveal that one of the two individual batteries in the series configuration is driven to voltages exceeding the acceptable operational limits for a single 12 Volt battery. This condition results in a loss of battery capacity during cycling and results in early string failure because of cell reversals. This condition appears whenever the battery polarization is determined by a single cell rather than being shared by a number of cells that are presumed to be matched.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Symons P.C., “PITFALLS IN USING LONG STRINGS OF SERIES CONNECTED LEAD-ACID BATTERY CELLS,” The Battcon 2004 Proceedings, Battcon 2004 Conference, Ft. Lauderdale, FL</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MIL-PRF-32143B, PERFORMANCE SPECIFICATION, BATTERIES, STORAGE: AUTOMOTIVE, VALVE REGULATED LEAD ACID (VRLA), SUPERSEDING MIL-PRF-32143A w/Amendment 1 25 March 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Standard, “Storage Batteries,” SAE Standard J537, Rev. Sept. 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catherino H.A., Feres F.F., Trinidad F., Sulfation in lead acid batteries, J. Power Sources 129 (1) (2004) 113-120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catherino H.A., “Estimation of the heat generation rates in electrochemical cells,” J. Power Sources 239 (2013) 505-512.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Som P. and Szymborski J., “Operational impacts on VRLA life,” Proc. Thirteenth Annual Battery Conference on Applications and Advances, 1998, pp. 285-290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hung S. T., Hopkins D. C., and Mosling C. R., “Extension of battery life via charge equalization control,” IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, vol. 40, pp. 96-104, Feb. 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krein P. T. and Balog R. S., “Life extension through charge equalization of lead-acid batteries,” Proc. International Telecommunications Energy Conference, 2002, pp. 516-523.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuhn B. T., Pitel G. E., and Krein P. T., “Electrical properties and equalization of lithium-ion cells in automotive applications,” Proc. IEEE Conference on Vehicle Power and Propulsion, 2005, pp. 55-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuhn B. T., Spee R., and Krein P. T., “Lifetime effects of voltage and voltage imbalance on VRLA batteries in cable TV network power,” Proc. International Telecommunications Energy Conference, 2005, pp. 233-238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">West S. and Krein P. T., “Equalization of valve-regulated leadacid batteries: issues and life test results,” Proc. International Telecommunications Energy Conference, 2000, pp. 439-446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hopkins D. C., Mosling C. R., and Hung S. T., “Dynamic equalization during charging of serial energy storage elements,” IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications, vol. 29, pp. 363-368, Mar.-Apr. 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boden David P, Arias Jeff, Fleming Frank A, “The effect of organic expander materials on the performance, life, surface area and crystal structure of negative electrodes in valve regulated cells,” Journal of Power Sources, Volume 95, Issues 1-2, 15 March 2001, Pages 277-292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
