<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278128</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of Fuel Economy Potential of an Active Grille Shutter by the Means of Model Based Development Including Vehicle Heat Management</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bouilly</surname>
                  <given-names>Julien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Europe</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lafossas</surname>
                  <given-names>Francois</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Europe NV/SA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mohammadi</surname>
                  <given-names>Ali</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Europe NV/SA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Van Wissen</surname>
                  <given-names>Roger</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Europe NV/SA</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>November 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278095</issue-id>
         <fpage>2394</fpage>
         <lpage>2401</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278128"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In the automotive field, reducing harmful pollutant, CO2 emissions and fuel consumption of vehicles while increasing customer comfort is a continuous challenge that requires more and more sophisticated technology implementations. However, it is often difficult to anticipate the advantages and drawbacks of a technology without having its prototype parts and/or knowing the optimal control strategy. In order to meet these challenges, the authors have developed a vehicle thermal model in AMESim platform to evaluate the benefits of an Active Grille Shutter (AGS) on fuel economy when applied. The vehicle model was based on a C-Segment vehicle powered by a 1.4L Diesel engine. The complete oil and coolant circuits were modeled as well as a friction model based on engine coolant and oil temperature. The entire model was validated on the European homologation cycle (NEDC) at −7°C and +25°C ambient temperature and achieved an accurate estimation of the fuel consumption, coolant and oil temperatures. Then, an AGS model was developed and integrated into the vehicle thermal model in order to assess the control of the coolant temperature (radiator cooling efficiency) and the vehicle road load (drag coefficient). Several control strategies were investigated on an in-house country-highway driving cycle to clarify the best compromise among fuel consumption reduction, engine coolant temperature control stability and AGS durability. The model demonstrated a potential fuel economy of 1.7% and 2.0% at +25°C ambient temperature on NEDC and in-house country-highway driving cycles respectively. In addition, the model showed further fuel economy up to 2.4% on NEDC at −7°C ambient temperature thanks to the combined effects of reduced frictions and road load. Finally, simulation and experimental results were compared and the fuel economy predicted by the model achieved a deviation lower than 0.3%.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Traussnig, A., Petutschnig, H., Ennemoser, A., Stolz, M. et al., “Vehicle Thermal Management Simulation Method Integrated in the Development Process from Scratch to Prototype,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-0668, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shutty, J., Wenzel, W., Becker, M., Bohan, S. et al., “Advanced Thermal Management of a Light Duty Diesel Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper a2013-01-0546, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahmoud, K., Loibner, E., Wiesler, B., Samhaber, C. et al., “Simulation-Based Vehicle Thermal Management System - Concept and Methodology,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0276, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahmoud, K., Loibner, E., and Krammer, J., “Integrated 1-D Tools for Modeling Vehicle Thermal Management System,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3406, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-3406.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shigarkanthi, V., Damodaran, V., Soundararaju, D., and Kanniah, K., “Application of Design of Experiments and Physics Based Approach in the Development of Aero Shutter Control Algorithm,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0155, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">El-Sharkawy, A., Kamrad, J., Lounsberry, T., Baker, G. et al., “Evaluation of Impact of Active Grille Shutter on Vehicle Thermal Management,” SAE Int. J. Mater. Manuf. 4(1):1244-1254, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Charnesky, S., Fadler, G., and Lockwood, T., “Variable and Fixed Airflow for Vehicle Cooling,” SAE Int. J. Mater. Manuf. 4(1):1286-1296, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1340.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mustafa, R., Schulze, M., Eilts, P., Küçükay, F. et al., “Improved Energy Management Using Engine Compartment Encapsulation and Grille Shutter Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):803-812, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pfeifer, C., “Evolution of Active Grille Shutters,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-0633, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0633.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
