<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285046</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Cyclic Material Behavior of High-Strength Steels Used in the Fatigue Assessment of Welded Crane Structures with a Special Focus on Transient Material Effects</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Möller</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tomasella</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wagener</surname>
                  <given-names>Rainer</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Melz</surname>
                  <given-names>Tobias</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Fraunhofer LBF</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>331</fpage>
         <lpage>339</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285046"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The cyclic material behavior is investigated, by strain-controlled testing, of 8 mm thick sheet metal specimens and butt joints, manufactured by manual gas metal arc welding (GMAW). The materials used in this investigation are the high-strength structural steels S960QL, S960M and S1100QL. Trilinear strain-life curves and cyclic stress-strain curves have been derived for the base material and the as-welded state of each steel grade. Due to the cyclic softening in combination with a high load level at the initial load cycle, the cyclic stress-strain curve cannot be applied directly for a fatigue assessment of welded structures. Therefore, the transient effects have been analyzed in order to describe the time-variant material behavior in a more detailed manner. This should be the basis for the enhancement of the fatigue life estimation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kirschbaum, M., Hamme, U., “Einsatz von hochfesten Feinkornbaustählen im Kranbau“, Stahl und Eisen 135(5):69-74, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hobbacher A., “Recommendations for Fatigue Design of Welded Joints and Components”, Springer International Publishing , 2016, doi:10.1007/978-3-319-23757-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DIN EN 1993-1-9:2010-12 - Eurocode 3: Design of steel structures - Part 1-9: Fatigue, German version EN 1993-1-9:2005 + AC:2009, DIN Deutsches Institut für Normung e. V., 2010, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Möller, B., Baumgartner, J., Wagener, R., Kaufmann, H. et al., “Low cycle fatigue life assessment of welded high-strength structural steels based on nominal and local design concepts”, International Journal of Fatigue, in preparation</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Möller, B., Wagener, R., Kaufmann, H., Melz, T., “Fatigue life and cyclic material behaviour of butt-welded high-strength steel in the LCF regime”. Mat Test 57(2):141-148, 2015, doi:10.31.39/120.110691.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomasella, A., “Description of transient material behaviour under constant and variable amplitude loading for cold formed steels by linear flow splitting”, Dissertation, Fraunhofer Institute for Structural Durability and System Reliability LBF, Report no. FB-247, Fraunhofer Verlag, 2014, Stuttgart, ISBN 978-3-8396-1049-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Basquin, O.H., “The exponential law of endurance tests”, ASTM Proceedings 10:625-630, 1910.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coffin L.A., “A study of the effects of cyclic thermal stresses on a ductile metal”, Trans. ASME, No. 76:931-950, 1964.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manson, S.S., “Fatigue: A complex subject - Some simple approximations”, Experimental Mechanics 5, No. 7:193-226, 1965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morrow, J.D., “Cyclic Plastic strain Energy and Fatigue of Metals”, Internal Friction, Damping and Cyclic Plasticity, Special Technical Publication No. 378, ASTM:45-87, 1965</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramberg W., Osgood, W.R., “Description of Stress-Strain Curves by Three Parameters”, NACA Technical Note No. 902, 1943.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagener, R., “Zyklisches Werkstoffverhalten bei konstanter und variable Beanspruchungsamplitude“, Dissertation, TU Clausthal, Papierfliegerverlag, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagener, R., Esderts, A., ”Cyclic Material Behaviour of Aluminium Wrought Alloys”, Proc. of the 6th International Conference on Low Cycle Fatigue (LCF6), DVM, Berlin, 2008, pp. 205-210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SEP 1240: Testing and Documentation Guideline for the Experimental Determination of Mechanical Properties of Steel Sheets for CAECalculations, 1st Edition, Stahlinstitut VDEh, Düsseldorf, Germany, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bäumel, A., Seeger, T., Boller, C., “Materials Data for Cyclic Loading - Supplement 1”, Elsevier, 1990, Amsterdam</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korkmaz, S., “Extension of the Uniform Material Law for High Strength Steels”, Master’s Thesis, Bauhaus University, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
