<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275404</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kokjohn</surname>
                  <given-names>Sage L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hanson</surname>
                  <given-names>Reed M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Splitter</surname>
                  <given-names>Derek A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin – Madison</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>24</fpage>
         <lpage>39</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275404"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study investigates the potential of controlling premixed charge compression ignition (PCCI and HCCI) combustion strategies by varying fuel reactivity. In-cylinder fuel blending using port fuel injection of gasoline and early cycle direct injection of diesel fuel was used for combustion phasing control at both high and low engine loads and was also effective to control the rate of pressure rise. The first part of the study used the KIVA-CHEMKIN code and a reduced primary reference fuel (PRF) mechanism to suggest optimized fuel blends and EGR combinations for HCCI operation at two engine loads (6 and 11 bar net IMEP). It was found that the minimum fuel consumption could not be achieved using either neat diesel fuel or neat gasoline alone, and that the optimal fuel reactivity required decreased with increasing load. For example, at 11 bar net IMEP, the optimum fuel blend and EGR rate for HCCI operation was found to be PRF 80 and 50%, respectively. Engine experiments using a dual-fuel PCCI strategy with port fuel injection of gasoline and early cycle multiple injections of diesel fuel with a conventional diesel injector (i.e., wide angle and large nozzle hole) were performed. The experimental results confirmed that an extension of the PCCI operating regime is possible when optimized fuel blends are used. At the 11 bar operating point, NOx and soot were ∼0.01 g/kW-hr and ∼0.008 g/kW-hr, respectively. That is, US 2010 heavy duty emissions regulations are easily met without after-treatment while achieving 50% thermal efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. R. Turns, “An Introduction to Combustion: Concepts and Applications”, WCB/McGraw-Hill, Boston, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bression, G., Soleri, D., Savy, S., Dehoux, S. et al., "A Study of Methods to Lower HC and CO Emissions in Diesel HCCI," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):37-49, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. L. Hardy and R. D. Reitz, "A Study of the Effects of High EGR, High Equivalence Ratio, and Mixing Time on Emissions Levels in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine for PCCI Combustion", SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0026, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Opat, Ra, Y. , Gonzalez D., M.A. , Krieger, R. ,Reitz, R.D., Foster, D.E., Siewert, R. , Durrett, R., "Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine", SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Yokota, Y. Kudo, H. Nakajima, T. Kakegawa and T. Suzuki, "A New Concept for Low Emission Diesel Combustion", SAE Technical Paper 970891, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Sun, "Diesel Combustion Optimization and Emissions Reduction Using Adaptive Injection Strategies (AIS) with Improved Numerical Models", PhD Thesis, University of Wisconsin--Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Kamimoto and M. Bae, "High Combustion Temperature for the Reduction of Particulate in Diesel Engines", SAE Technical Paper 880423, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. M. Pickett and D. L. Siebers, "Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion", SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1399, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Akihama, Y. Takatori, K. Inagaki, S. Sasaki and A. M. Dean, "Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature", SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Liu, M. Yao, B. Zhang and Z. Zheng, "Effects of Inlet Pressure and Octane Numbers on Combustion and Emissions of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engine", Energy &amp; Fuels, vol.22, no.4, pp. 2207-2215, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Christensen, A. Hultqvist and B. Johansson, "Demonstrating the Multi-fuel Capability of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine with Variable Compression Ratio", SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3679, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Inagaki, T. Fuyuto, K. Nishikawa, K. Nakakita and I. Sakata, "Dual-Fuel PCI Combustion Controlled by In-Cylinder Stratification of Ignitability", SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0028, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. W. Bessonette, C. H. Schleyer, K. P. Duffy, W. L. Hardy and M. P. Liechty, "Effects of Fuel Property Changes on Heavy-Duty HCCI Combustion", SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0191, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. M. Nevin, Y. Sun, G. M. A. and R. D. Reitz, "PCCI Investigation Using Variable Intake Valve Closing in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine, SAE Paper 2007-01-0903", 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Sun and R.D. Reitz "Adaptive Injection Strategies (AIS) for Ultra-Low Emissions Diesel Engines", SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0058, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. A. Amsden, "Kiva-3v, Release 2, Improvements to KIVA-3v", in LA-UR-99-915, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Abani, S. L. Kokjohn, S. W. Park, M. Bergin, A. Munnannur, W. Ning, S. Y. and R. D. Reitz, "An Improved Spray Model for Reducing Numerical Parameters Dependencies in Diesel Engine CFD Simulations", SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0970, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Abani, A. Munnannur and R. D. Reitz, "Reduction of numerical parameter dependencies in diesel spray models", Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, vol.130, no.3, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Han and R. D. Reitz, "Turbulence Modeling of Internal Combustion Engines Using RNG k-e Models", Combustion Science and Technology, vol.106, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Ra and R. D. Reitz, "A Reduced Chemical Kinetic Model for IC Engine Combustion Simulations with Primary Reference Fuels", Combustion and Flame, Vol. 155, pp. 713–738, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Ra, J. E. Yun and R. D. Reitz, "Numerical parametric study of diesel engine operation with gasoline", Combustion Science and Technology, vol.181, pp. 1-29, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S.-C. Kong, Y. Sun and R. D. Reitz, "Modeling Diesel Spray Flame Lift-off, Sooting Tendency and NOx Emissions Using Detailed Chemistry with a Phenomenological Soot model", ASME Journal of Gas Turbines and Power, vol.129, pp. 245-251, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Hiroyasu and T. Kadota, "Models for Combustion and Formation of Nitric Oxide and Soot in DI Diesel Engines", SAE Technical Paper 760129, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Frenklach, T. Bowman, G. Smith and B. Gardiner, 2000, http://www.me.berkeley.edu/grimech/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Shi, R. P. Hessel, and R. D. Reitz, "An Adaptive Multi-Grid Chemistry (AMC) Model for Efficient Simulation of HCCI and DI Engine Combustion", Combustion Theory and Modeling, vol. 13(1), pp. 83-104, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Shi, S. L. Kokjohn, Ge, Hai-wen, and R. D. Reitz, "Efficient Multidimensional Simulation of HCCI and DI Engine Combustion with Detailed Chemistry", SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0701, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Abraham, "What is Adequate Resolution in the Numerical Computation of Transient Jets", SAE Technical Paper 970051, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Abraham, "Entrainment Characteristics of Transient jets", Numerical Heat Transfer, vol. 30, Part A, pp. 347-364, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. C. Beale and R. D. Reitz, "Modeling Spray Atomization with the Kelvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh- Taylor Hybrid Model", Atomization and Sprays, vol.9, pp. 623-650, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Munnannur, "Droplet Collision Modeling in Multi- Dimensional Engine Spray Computations", PhD thesis in Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. J. O'Rourke and A. A. Amsden, "A Particle Numerical Model for Wall Dynamics in Port-Injected Engines", SAE Technical Paper 961961, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. J. O'Rourke and A. A. Amsden, "A Spray/Wall Interaction Submodel for the KIVA-3 Wall Film Model", SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0271, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. T. Kalghatgi, "Auto-ignition Quality of Practical Fuels and Implications for Fuel Requirements of Future SI and HCCI Engines", SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0239, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. L. Kokjohn and R. D. Reitz, "A Modeling Study of Charge Preparation in an HCCI Engine Using a Variable Pressure Pulse (VPP) Injection System and Optimized PRF Blends", 11th International Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L., Swor, T.A., Andrie, M.J., and Reitz, R.D., "Experiments and Modeling of Adaptive Injection Strategies (AIS) in Low Emissions Diesel Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 16-32, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Ando, Y. Sakai and K. Kuwahara, "Universal Rule of Hydrocarbon Oxidation", SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0948, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Sjoberg, J. E. Dec and N. P. Cernansky, "Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, Based on Multi-zone Modeling and Experiments", SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0113, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., "Influence of Fuel Autoignition Reactivity on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):39-58, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
