<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663759</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/380826</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB770110</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Doctoral Dissertations Accepted, 2002‐2003</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>01</month>
            <year>2004</year>
            <string-date>January 2004</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>77</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2004.77.issue-1</issue-id>
         <fpage>209</fpage>
         <lpage>232</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/380826"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Accounting</title>
         <p>Susan Albring. Univ. Arizona. “The Effect of the Cost of Foreign Internal Funds on Firm's Choice of Debt versus Internal Funding.”</p>
         <p>Bokhyeon Baik. California, Berkeley. “Essays on Analysts' Forecasts.”</p>
         <p>Pascal Bizarro. Alabama. “Effect of Different Database Structure Representation, Query Languages, and User Characteristics on Information Retrieval.”</p>
         <p>Julia M. Brennan. Univ. Kentucky. “Revisiting the Choice between Incentive Stock Options and Non Qualified Options: A Study of Tax and Non‐Tax Costs.”</p>
         <p>Daniel Bryan. Univ. Oregon. “The Effects of Persistence, Growth, and Conservative Accounting on the Association of Accounting Information with Market Value.”</p>
         <p>Marcus Butler. Chicago. “Valuation Conflicts in Corporate Bankruptcy.”</p>
         <p>Shuping Chen. USC. “Managerial Guidance of Market's Expectations: Incentives and Effects.”</p>
         <p>Jacqueline S. Hammersley. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Pattern Identification and Industry‐Specialist Auditors.”</p>
         <p>Kirsten Harrington. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Clamping Down on Upcoding: Government Efforts to Curb Medicare Billing Fraud and Abuse.”</p>
         <p>Adel Ibrahim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “A Re‐examination of the Market’s Reaction to Quarterly Dividend Change Announcements.”</p>
         <p>David Jenkins. Maryland. “Profitability, Firm Survival and the Value Relevance of Negative Earnings.”</p>
         <p>Guohua Jiang. California, Berkeley. “An Essay on `Accrual Anomaly.'”</p>
         <p>Tony Kang. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Trading Volume as a Proxy for Other Information in the Returns‐Earnings Regression.”</p>
         <p>Jia‐Wen Liang. Univ. Oregon. “Relative Performance Evaluation and Product Market Competition.”</p>
         <p>Lihong Liang. Pennsylvania State. “Post‐earnings Announcement Drift and Market Participants' Information Processing Biases.”</p>
         <p>Christopher Luchs. Kent State. “The Impact of US GAAP Reconciliations of American Depository Receipts on Security Analysts' Forecast Errors.”</p>
         <p>Garth Novack. Univ. Arizona. “Treasury Bill Yield Reactions to the 1997 Capital Gain Tax Rate Reduction.”</p>
         <p>Lay Khim Ong. USC. “Does Adding Nonfinancial Value Drivers to a Summary Financial Measure Improve the Learning and Performance of Managers?”</p>
         <p>Zhao Ouyang. Maryland. “An Equilibrium Model for Stock Message Boards on the Internet.”</p>
         <p>Yonpae Park. Nebraska—Lincoln. “The Effect of Accounting Conservatism on Firm Valuation.”</p>
         <p>Robin Pennington. South Carolina. “The Effects of Information Overload on Information Processing and Judgment in an Information Systems Audit Task.”</p>
         <p>Jon Douglas Perkins. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Informal Consultation in Public Accounting: A Strategic View and an Experimental Investigation.”</p>
         <p>Monvika Phadoongsitthi. Maryland. “The Role of Managerial Accounting in Emerging Economies: An Empirical Study of Thailand.”</p>
         <p>Edward J. Riedl. Pennsylvania State. “An Examination of Long‐Lived Asset Impairments.”</p>
         <p>Yusuf Sahingur. SUNY at Buffalo. “Why and How Firms Issue Convertible Debt: An Empirical Analysis of the Convertible Financing Decision.”</p>
         <p>John Shon. Chicago. “The Relation between Earnings Surprises and Discretionary Disclosure Behavior in Periods with Short‐Term Price Declines.”</p>
         <p>Ferdinand Siagian. Univ. Oregon. “Earnings Manipulation and the Association between CEO Bonus and Accounting Earnings.”</p>
         <p>Susan Sorensen. Minnesota. “Transfer Pricing Risks for a U.S. Based Multinational Subject to the OECD Guidelines and IRC Section 482.”</p>
         <p>Wannee Metiyapan Taechoyotin. Univ. Colorado. “Conformity and Frequency of Financial Analysts' Earnings Forecasts and Momentum in Returns on Equity Securities.”</p>
         <p>Carmelita Troy. Maryland. “`The Devil Made Me Do It': Managerial and Strategic Factors Leading to Accounting Fraud.”</p>
         <p>Joon Sun Yang. Temple. “Audit Committees and Quarterly Earnings Management.”</p>
         <p>Ping Eric Yeung. Univ. Oregon. “Belief‐Revisions after Earnings Announcements: Evidence from Security Analysts' Forecast Revision.”</p>
         <p>Yoonseok Zang. California, Berkeley. “Discretionary Behavior with Respect to the Adoption of SFAS 142 and the Behavior of Security Prices.”</p>
         <p>Yuan Zhang. USC. “Revenue Recognition Timing and Attributes of Reported Revenue: The Case of Software Industry's Adoption of SOP 91‐1.”</p>
         <p>Lin (Sandy) Zheng. Alabama. “Did the 1998 Chinese Accounting System Improve Earnings Quality?”</p>
         <p>Liu Zheng. USC. “Six‐Month‐One‐Day Employee Stock Options Repricing: An Examination of Accounting Considerations and Incentive Implications.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Banking and Public Finance</title>
         <p>Yalcin Akcay. Pennsylvania State. “Three Essays on Resource Allocation Problems: Inventory Management in Assemble‐to‐Order Systems and Online Assignment of Flexible Resources.”</p>
         <p>Ali Toossi Ardakani. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays in Political Economy and Public Policy.”</p>
         <p>Audra Leigh Boone. Pennsylvania State. “Essays on the Causes and Effects of Corporate Restructuring.”</p>
         <p>Andrew Christopher Helms. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “The Economics of Housing Renovation: Three Empirical Studies.”</p>
         <p>Guozhong Ma. Alabama. “An Examination of the Bank Lending Channel from a Regional Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Sameh Sakr. Southern Illinois at Carbondale. “Competition for Board Seats in Banks' Mergers.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Behavioral Science</title>
         <p>Obasi Akan. Case Western Reserve. “Concrescent Conversations Interpreting the Meaning of Speech Acts in the Start‐Up Period of New Work Groups.”</p>
         <p>Aleta Alli. Mississippi State. “The Effects of Academic Origin and Academic Affiliation on Research Productivity: An Empirical Investigation of Information Systems Faculty.”</p>
         <p>Remus Ilies. Univ. Florida. “A Dynamic Multilevel Model of Task Motivation Linking Personality, Affective Reactions to Feedback and Self‐Regulation.”</p>
         <p>Samantha Murray. Mississippi State. “A Quantitative Examination to Determine if Knowledge Sharing Activities, Given the Appropriate Media Richness, Lead to Knowledge Transfer and if Implementation Factors Influence the Use of These Knowledge Sharing Activities.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Business Economics and Economics</title>
         <p>Xiang Ao. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Essays on Economic Growth in China.”</p>
         <p>Kevin D. Barber. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “The Pricing Strategy of a Bayesian Learning Monopolistic Insurer.”</p>
         <p>Garrick Blalock. California, Berkeley. “Technology Adoption from Foreign Direct Investment and Exporting: Evidence from Indonesian Manufacturing.”</p>
         <p>Michael Haydon Brown. Univ. Kentucky. “Geographic and Group Variation in Supplemental Security Income.”</p>
         <p>David Daewhan Cho. Chicago. “Uncertainty in Second Moments: Implications for Portfolio Allocation.”</p>
         <p>Bradley Alan Clouse. Univ. Kentucky. “The Economics of Dental Care Utilization.”</p>
         <p>Ilan Cooper. Chicago. “Asset Pricing Implications of Non‐convex Adjustment Costs of Investment.”</p>
         <p>Georgio Coricelli. Univ. Arizona. “Experiments on Interactive Economic Behavior.”</p>
         <p>Chifeng Dai. Univ. Florida. “Essays in Incentive and Information Economics.”</p>
         <p>Mary Davis. Univ. Florida. “The Politics of the Environment: An Analysis of State Regulations and Special Interest.”</p>
         <p>Ozgur Demirtas. Boston College. “Essays on Analyst Earnings Estimates and Stock Returns.”</p>
         <p>James Feigenbaum. Iowa. “Exploring the Causes of Savings.”</p>
         <p>Deborah Fletcher. Univ. Florida. “Intergenerational Conflict and Publicly Provided Goods.”</p>
         <p>Feng Gao. Iowa. “Essays on Fertility Choice, Child Labor and the Gender Wage Gap.”</p>
         <p>Sudeep Ghosh. Iowa. “Optimal Learning and Other Essays in Game Theory.”</p>
         <p>Federico Alejandro Guala. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Three Essays on Private and Public Finance in Argentina.”</p>
         <p>Guillermo Israilevich. Chicago. “Assessing Product Line Decisions with Supermarket Scanner Data.”</p>
         <p>Karel Janda. Iowa. “Essays on Credit Contracts.”</p>
         <p>Christopher K. Johnson. Alabama. “Essays in Urban and Regional Economics.”</p>
         <p>Ryan Johnson. Univ. Arizona. “The Economic Progress of American Black Workers in a Period of Crisis and Change, 1916–1950.”</p>
         <p>Dong Kwan Kang. Univ. Kentucky. “Ownership Concentration, Vertical Integration and Its Determinants in the Korean Corporation: How Does Chaebol's Organization Affect Ownership Concentration and Vertical Integration.”</p>
         <p>Hyunsook Kim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Transmission Capacity Effects on Market Inefficiencies in the California Electrical Market.”</p>
         <p>Caprice Knapp. Univ. Florida. “Essays on the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act and Disabled Children.”</p>
         <p>Liang‐Feng Lin. Temple. “Deregulation and Efficiency in the Taiwan Life Insurance Industry.”</p>
         <p>Robert Lowe. California, Berkeley. “Invention, Innovation and Entrepreneurship: The Commercialization of University Research by Inventor‐Founded Firms.”</p>
         <p>Marcello Mello. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays in Economic Growth and Asset Pricing.”</p>
         <p>Patrick Moreton. California, Berkeley. “Pricing, Increasing Returns and Competition in Cellular Telephone Service.”</p>
         <p>Jeremy Nalewaik. Chicago. “The Response of Consumption and Leisure to Expected Future Income.”</p>
         <p>Stefanos A. Nastis. Wyoming. “Some Economics of Natural and Human Capital Integration.”</p>
         <p>Kara Elizabeth Norlin. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Political Corruption: Theory and Evidence from the Brazilian Experience.”</p>
         <p>Gregory M. Parkhurst. Wyoming. “Economic Incentives for Endangered Species Protection.”</p>
         <p>Paulo Augusto Pettenuzzo de Britto. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Essays on Financial Contracting and Debt.”</p>
         <p>Roxana Toma Postloche. Univ. Kentucky. “The Corporate Merger Phenomenon: Determinants and Changes in Merger Policies Evidence for Acquiring Firms, 1986–1998.”</p>
         <p>Francisco Renna. Univ. Arizona. “The Economics of Dual Job Holding.”</p>
         <p>Supriya Sarnikar. Univ. Arizona. “Empirical Essays on Network Effects in Markets.”</p>
         <p>Kurt Schnier. Univ. Arizona. “Economic Analysis of Spatially Heterogeneous Resources: The Case of the Fishery.”</p>
         <p>Souren Soumbatiants. South Carolina. “Forecasting the Probabilities of Winning the U.S. Presidential Elections.”</p>
         <p>James Swarthout. Univ. Arizona. “Three Essays on Strategic Behavior.”</p>
         <p>Troy Tassier. Iowa. “Path to Equality: Economic Implications of Referral Hiring and Social Networks.”</p>
         <p>Kirsten Wandschneider. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Central Bank Independence and Policy Performance: Central‐East Europe, 1919–1939.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Business Finance and Investments</title>
         <p>Anne Anderson. Univ. Arizona. “Unlocking the Keys to Hidden Value.”</p>
         <p>Vladimir Alexandrov Atanasov. Pennsylvania State. “Equity Investments with Private Benefits of Control.”</p>
         <p>Charles Blaylock. Mississippi State. “The Marginal Reaction to American Depositary Receipt (ADR) Issuance in Emerging Markets.”</p>
         <p>Bruce A. Campbell. Kent State. “Commercial Bank Debt and Optimal Capital Structure in a Theory of Incomplete Contracts.”</p>
         <p>Charles Chang. California, Berkeley. “Essays on International Information Structures and Barriers.”</p>
         <p>Yung‐Ho Chang. Houston. “The Dynamic Response of Financial Analysts Earnings Forecast Revisions to Stock Price Behavior and Analysts' Opinions.”</p>
         <p>Yenn‐Ru Chen. Houston. “Executive Stock Options and Managerial Risk Taking.”</p>
         <p>Wen‐I Chuang. Houston. “Empirical Tests of the Overconfidence Hypothesis.”</p>
         <p>Ozgur Demirtas. Boston College. “Essays on Analyst Earnings Estimates and Stock Returns.”</p>
         <p>Ning Ding. Univ. Colorado. “Three Essays on Mutual Funds.”</p>
         <p>Susan M. Edwards. Kent State. “Downsizing Strategy, Stakeholder‐Agency Theory and the Value of the Firm.”</p>
         <p>Geoff Friesen. Iowa. “New Methods for Measuring Cognitive Biases and Heterogeneous Skill in Financial Analysts and Mutual Fund Managers.”</p>
         <p>Yanling Ge. Univ. Mississippi. “Two Essays on Long‐Term Care Insurance.”</p>
         <p>David Michael Gross. Univ. Colorado. “Price Discovery in Opening Procedures: A Comparison of NYSE and NASDAQ Delayed Openings.”</p>
         <p>Levant Guntay. Maryland. “Pricing Defaultable Callable Coupon Bonds.”</p>
         <p>Qiang Guo. Maryland. “Essays on Commodity Commitment Pricing and Hedging.”</p>
         <p>Dirk Hackbarth. California, Berkeley. “Corporate Financial Decision‐Making and Managerial Traits.”</p>
         <p>Todd Hazelkorn. Chicago. “Outside Equity and Growth.”</p>
         <p>Christoph Hinkelmann. Rochester. “Monetary Policy and Asset Returns.”</p>
         <p>Jennifer Lynn Juergens. Pennsylvania State. “Essays on Investment Analysts.”</p>
         <p>Samir Kamat. Alabama. “Two Essays in Finance.”</p>
         <p>Dong‐Kyoon Kim. South Carolina. “Two Essays on Managerial Incentives and Corporate Decisions.”</p>
         <p>Aaron Lebovitz. Chicago. “Disagreement and Return Dynamics.”</p>
         <p>Chuo‐Hsuan Lee. Kent State. “Stock Repurchases, Dilution Error in Earnings‐per‐Share and Firm Valuation.”</p>
         <p>Gang Li. California, Berkeley. “Three Essays on Information and Asset Prices.”</p>
         <p>Yuanzhi Luo. Rochester. “Information from Capital Markets to Firms during Corporate Takeovers.”</p>
         <p>Christopher Malloy. Chicago. “The Geography of Equity Analysis.”</p>
         <p>Matthew Delaney Malone. Boston Univ. “Essays in Portfolio Management.”</p>
         <p>Tim Michael. South Carolina. “Convertible Bond Calls Revisited: An Examination of the Wealth Transfer Motive for Call Policy.”</p>
         <p>Suchismita Mishra. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Skewness Preference and Measurement of Abnormal Returns: A Comparative Evaluation and Current Area versus Proposed Event Structure Paradigm.”</p>
         <p>Robert Novy‐Marx. California, Berkeley. “An Equlibrium Model of Investment under Uncertainty.”</p>
         <p>Galina Ovtcharova. Chicago. “Institutional Ownership and Long‐Term Stock Returns.”</p>
         <p>Javier Rodriguez. Houston. “Essays in Behavioral Finance.”</p>
         <p>Kenneth Roskelly. Univ. Arizona. “Three Essays in Empirical Finance.”</p>
         <p>Seung Kyoon Shin. SUNY at Buffalo. “Denormalization Effects on Performance of Relational Database for Data Warehouse.”</p>
         <p>Marc Shivers. California, Berkeley. “Convertible Bond Valuation and Pricing: Theory and Evidence.”</p>
         <p>Ane Miren Tamayo. Rochester. “Stock Return Predictability and Conditional Asset Pricing Models.”</p>
         <p>David Tien. California, Berkeley. “Essays on International Financial Markets.”</p>
         <p>Eric Chingyi Tsai. Pennsylvania State. “Essays on Corporate International Investments.”</p>
         <p>Shih‐Chuan Tsai. Boston Univ. “Dynamic Models of Investment Distortions.”</p>
         <p>Biao Xie. Southern Illinois at Carbondale. “The Effects of Co‐managers on IPOs.”</p>
         <p>Jr‐Ming Yang. Cincinnati. “A Market Stabilization Mechanism Circuit Breaker: Theory and Evidence.”</p>
         <p>Twan‐Shan Yang. Univ. Arizona. “Rescission and Repricing of Executive Stock Options.”</p>
         <p>Xiaofan (Steven) Zheng. SUNY at Buffalo. “Initial Public Offerings of Equity, Share Retention, and Lockup.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Information Systems</title>
         <p>Cheryl Aasheim. Univ. Florida. “Use of Vector Space Model in Environmental Scanning via the World Wide Web.”</p>
         <p>Charles Apigian. Toledo. “Internet Strategy: An Integrated Complement to an Organization's Existing Business Practices.”</p>
         <p>Chiu Lung Chau. Univ. Arizona. “Mining the Web for Personalized and Domain‐Specific Information.”</p>
         <p>Dorothea Carol DeLuca. Temple. “Business Process Improvement Using Asynchronous E‐Collaboration: Testing the Compensatory Adaptation Model.”</p>
         <p>Kutsal Dogan. Univ. Florida. “Quantitative Models for Internet Marketing.”</p>
         <p>Robert M. Fuller. Indiana—Bloomington. “Does Fit Matter? A Longitudinal Examination of the Impact of Task‐Technology Fit on Team Performance in Routine Tasks.”</p>
         <p>Gerald Caesar Gonsalves. Kentucky. “Business Process Management: Integration of Quality Management and Reengineering for Enhanced Competitiveness.”</p>
         <p>Pavan Kumar Gundepudi. Rochester. “On Internet Interconnection Agreements and Yield Management of Information Goods.”</p>
         <p>Russell Paton Haines. Houston. “The Impact of Information Technology on the Structuring Processes of Task‐Oriented Groups.”</p>
         <p>Karina Hauser. Univ. Kentucky. “Simulation and Optimization of a Cross‐Docking Operation in a Just‐in‐Time Environment.”</p>
         <p>Mildred Hyde. Southern Illinois at Carbondale. “An Empirical Examination of Inhibitors Affecting Web‐Based Interorganizational Applications.”</p>
         <p>Tabitha James. Univ. Mississippi. “Impact of Shared Memory and Distributed Memory Platforms on the Design and Performance of Parallel Evolutionary Algorithms.”</p>
         <p>Andrew Jansma. Minnesota. “Innovation and Diffusion of Information Technology in Non‐competitive Environments as Typified by County and Local Governments.”</p>
         <p>Vijay Khatri. Univ. Arizona. “Bridging the Spatiotemporal Semantic Gap: A Theoretical Framework, Evaluation, and a Prototype System.”</p>
         <p>Euijin Kim. Southern Illinois at Carbondale. “Factors Impacting Customers' Trust in E‐Businesses: An Empirical Study of Customers' Initial Trust in E‐Businesses.”</p>
         <p>Taeha Kim. Univ. Arizona. “Regulatory Policy and Strategic Innovation in the Digital Economy.”</p>
         <p>Dowan Kwon. Case Western Reserve. “The Effect of Valuation Logics of Information Technology on the Company Performance: Pluralistic Assessment of Paradox.”</p>
         <p>Gwanhoo Lee. Minnesota. “Information Systems Project Flexibility: A Conceptual Development and Empirical Examination.”</p>
         <p>Gondy Leroy. Univ. Arizona. “Knowledge Discovery: The Integration of Human and Machine Generated Knowledge.”</p>
         <p>Abdulnasser Minkara. Univ. Kentucky. “Information Systems Management Issues: An Openness and Resources Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Sandra Obilade. Southern Illinois at Carbondale. Alternative E‐Commerce Business Models and Firm Performance in Competitive and Hypercompetitive Environments.”</p>
         <p>Yangil Park. Univ. Mississippi. “An Empirical Evaluation of the Factors That Impact Perceived Web Usability and User Performance.”</p>
         <p>Nilesh Saraf. USC. “Information Systems Capabilities and Indirect Relational Value.”</p>
         <p>Changsub Shim. Mississippi State. “The Impact of Organizational Context on Data Warehouse Design.”</p>
         <p>Yi Sun. Univ. Florida. “Location Model for Web Services Intermediaries.”</p>
         <p>David S. Taylor. Houston. “Searching for the Antecedents of Voluntary Turnover in Information Systems Personnel: A Concatenation of Competing Models.”</p>
         <p>Hong (Wendy) Wang. Univ. Mississippi. “Optimal Components of Research Publication Abstracts: An Empirical Study on Producing Abstracts That Meet the ANSI Standard.”</p>
         <p>Jianfeng Wang. Univ. Mississippi. “IT over Firm Boundary: Impacts and Strategic Implications.”</p>
         <p>Terry Lynn Wiant. Univ. Kentucky. “Policy and Its Impact on Medical Record Security.”</p>
         <p>Dongsong Zhang. Univ. Arizona. “Virtual Mentor and Media Structurization Theory: Towards an Integrated Approach to Interactive Multimedia‐Based E‐Learning.”</p>
         <p>Huimin Zhao. Univ. Arizona. “Combining Schema and Instance Information for Integrating Heterogeneous Databases: An Analytical Approach and Empirical Evaluation.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Insurance</title>
         <p>Teuta Catas. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Critical Success Factors for E‐Service: An Exploratory Study of Web‐Based Insurance Business.”</p>
         <p>Jiandong Ren. Temple. “Toward a Comprehensive Model of Insurer Net Worth.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc8">
         <title>International Trade and Finance</title>
         <p>Chin‐Chun (Vincent) Hsu. St. Louis. “An Integrated Model of Internationalization‐Performance Relationship.”</p>
         <p>Taewon Suh. St. Louis. “The Role of Knowledge‐Relevant Characteristics of International Project Team on Project Performance.”</p>
         <p>John A. Volkmar. Temple. “The Influence of Institutional Context on Normative Control Structure in Wholly‐Owned Foreign Subsidiaries: Patterns in the Deployment of Expatriate Managers.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc9">
         <title>Management</title>
         <p>Stephen Kent Callaway. Temple. “Pursuing the Exploration of Disruptive Technology: Strategic Management Issues for Internal Corporate Ventures.”</p>
         <p>Kenneth Colwell. Univ. Oregon. “The Structure of Alliance Networks in Nascent Organizational Fields: The Case of Nanotechnology.”</p>
         <p>Vibha Gaba. Univ. Oregon. “Corporate Venture Investing: A Multi‐Level Organizational Change Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Ida Kutschera. Univ. Oregon. “Cognitive Style and Decision Making: Implications of Intuitive and Analytical Information Processing for Decision Quality.”</p>
         <p>Mojgan Soltanpour. Univ. Mississippi. “Undesirable Self‐Presentation: A Laboratory Experiment to Investigate the Avoidance of Aversive Events through Impression Management.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc10">
         <title>Management Organization Theory and Practice</title>
         <p>Richard R. Bacha. Kent State. “Specifying Personality and Self‐Monitoring Effects on Overall, Task and Contextual Job Performance.”</p>
         <p>Xavier Castaner. Minnesota. “Towards a Behavioral Theory of Corporate Development Success: The Performance Effect of Corporate Exploitation and Exploration under Different Environmental States.”</p>
         <p>Lakshman Chandrashekhar. Southern Illinois at Carbondale. “Information and Knowledge Management as a Key Leader Function.”</p>
         <p>Kevin Gene Corley. Pennsylvania State. “Breaking Away: An Empirical Examination of How Organizational Identity Changes during a Spin‐Off.”</p>
         <p>Mourad Dakhli. South Carolina. “Structural Holes and Strong Ties in Organizations: A Cross‐Cultural Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Dirk De Clercq. Minnesota. “Organizational Learning by Venture Capital Firms: The Impact of Prior Experience, Knowledge Overlap, and Social Capital on Investment Success.”</p>
         <p>Dawn Renee DeTienne. Univ. Colorado. “The Fallacy of `Only the Strong Survive': A Social Cognitive Perspective on the Persistence of Underperforming Firms.”</p>
         <p>Jonathan Eckhardt. Maryland. “When the Weak Acquire Wealth: An Examination of Why High Growth New Firms Are Concentrated in Certain Industries.”</p>
         <p>Angelo Fanelli. Univ. Florida. “Securities Analyst Responses to CEO Charismatic Images: A Symbolic Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Erica Gabrielle Foldy. Boston College. “Being All That You Can Be: Identity and Power in Organizations.”</p>
         <p>Megan Gerhardt. Iowa. “Does It Work for Everyone? An Examination of the Moderating Effects of Goal Orientation, Affectivity, and Situational Constraints on Self‐Efficacy Development.”</p>
         <p>Jennifer K. Hartwell. Boston College. “Making Reduced‐Hours Work: The Role of Psychological Contract Fulfillment on Reduced‐Hour Physicians' Intent to Leave Their Professions.”</p>
         <p>Clyde Eirikur Hull. Indiana—Bloomington. “Innovation Strategy: An Empirical Exploration of the Antecedents of the Modes of Innovation.”</p>
         <p>Arzu Ilsev. South Carolina. “Unexpected Behaviors in Supervisor‐Subordinate Relationships: An Investigation of Cognitive Processes and Consequences.”</p>
         <p>Sung Min Kim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Information Technology and Governance: Substitution and Complementary Effects.”</p>
         <p>David R. King. Indiana—Bloomington. “Predicting Post‐acquisition Performance: Focusing on High‐Technology Target Firms.”</p>
         <p>Seok‐Woo Kwon. USC. “Does Fairness Matter in Standardization?”</p>
         <p>Kristy Lauver. Iowa. “The Relationship between HR Safety Practices, Alignment, Decentralization, Legitimation, and Safety Outcomes.”</p>
         <p>Sang‐Gun Lee. Nebraska—Lincoln. “An Integrative Study of Mobile Technology Adoption Based on the Technology Acceptance Model, Theory of Planned Behavior and Diffusion of Innovative Theory.”</p>
         <p>Ray Leuchtefeld. Boston College. “Model II Behavior and Team Performance: An Experimental Design and Intertextual Analysis.”</p>
         <p>Nora Yossif Madjar. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “The Contributions of Support and Information from Work and Non‐work Others to Employees’ Creative Performance.”</p>
         <p>Cade B. Massey. Chicago. “Psychological Influences on Decision‐Making in Organizations.”</p>
         <p>John Francis McCarthy. Boston Univ. “Short Stories and Tall Tales at Work: Organizational Storytelling as a Leadership Conduit during Turbulent Times.”</p>
         <p>Terrence Moore. Cincinnati. “Applying Cognitive Processes to Franchisees: The Use of Entrepreneurial Measures to Study Franchisee Response to Constraints.”</p>
         <p>Yusuf Ahmed Nur. Indiana—Bloomington. “Management‐by‐Virtues: A Comparative Study of Spirituality in the Workplace and Its Impact on Selected Organizational Outcomes.”</p>
         <p>Robert F. Radin. Boston College. “Influence in the Boardroom.”</p>
         <p>Mebane Judith Ray. Pennsylvania State. “Designing a Knowledge Management System: A Sensemaking Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Jenny Rudolph. Boston College. “Into the Big Muddy and Out Again: Error Persistence and Crisis Management in the Operating Room.”</p>
         <p>Leon Schjoedt. Univ. Colorado. “Entrepreneurial Job Satisfaction: An Empirical Investigation of the Situational, Dispositional, and Interactional Approaches to Entrepreneurs' Job Satisfaction.”</p>
         <p>Jeffery Scott. University of Chicago. “Non‐monetary Incentives and Motivation: Why Is Hawaii Better than Cash?”</p>
         <p>Myeong‐Gu Seo. Boston College. “The Role of Affective Experience in Work Motivation.”</p>
         <p>Arthur L. Sherwood. Indiana—Bloomington. “Acquisition of Technological Knowledge from Alliance Partners: The Role of the Organizational Knowledge Interface.”</p>
         <p>Amanuel Tekleab. Maryland. “The Role of Realistic Job Previews and Organizational Socialization on Newcomers' Psychological Contract Development.”</p>
         <p>Robert Ware. South Carolina. “Internationalization Theory and American Internet Firms.”</p>
         <p>Timothy Wilmot. Case Western Reserve. “The Dynamics of Visioning and Social Innovation: A Grounded Theory Study of the Impact of Appreciative Inquiry in Sustaining Long‐Term Organizational Change.”</p>
         <p>Guorong Zhu. Boston Univ. “Psychological Contract Alignment and Repatriation Success.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc11">
         <title>Marketing</title>
         <p>Matthew Bunker. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Examining the Effects of Exit Barriers, Service Failure, and Service Failure Recovery on a Marketing Relationship.”</p>
         <p>Richard Campbell. Univ. Oregon. “Measuring Consumers' Evaluations of the Functional, Symbolic, and Experiential Benefits of Brands.”</p>
         <p>Julien Marc Cayla. Univ. Colorado. “A Passage to India: An Ethnographic Study of the Advertising Agency's Role in Mediating the Cultural Learning and Adaptation of Multinational Corporations.”</p>
         <p>Chiu‐Chi Chang. Indiana—Bloomington. “The Effects of Customer‐Interface Technology on Purchase Deferral and Decision Satisfaction.”</p>
         <p>Glenn Leroy Christensen. Pennsylvania State. “Mental Simulations, Anticipations, and Dreams: Toward a Theory of Consumption Visions in Consumer Behavior.”</p>
         <p>Jennifer D. Christie. Arkansas. “Characteristics of Computer‐Mediated Environments and Their Impact on Spending and Choice.”</p>
         <p>Athinodoros Chronis. Nebraska—Lincoln. “The Consumption Benefits and the Role of Authenticity in the Heritage Experience.”</p>
         <p>Dapeng Cui. Cincinnati. “Product Selection Agent: A Framework and Application Using Simulated Data.”</p>
         <p>Ahmet Ekici. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Trust, Distrust and Consumer Beliefs about Food Safety.”</p>
         <p>Dan J. Fisher. Arkansas. “Music and Identity: Escape, Engagement, and the Quest for Authenticity in a Commodity Culture.”</p>
         <p>Yoshinori Fujikawa. Pennsylvania State. “Consumer Attributions, Mental Simulations, and Specific Emotions: Implications for Multi‐Channel Retailing and New Product Marketing.”</p>
         <p>Kirsten Anne Grasshoff. Pennsylvania State. “Differentiated Fear Appeals: The Role of Secondary Emotions in Motivating Appraisals of Self‐Accountability and Action.”</p>
         <p>Richard Charles Hanna. Boston Univ. “The Optimization of Discount Size and Time Limit for Coupon Promotions: Application to Email Offers.”</p>
         <p>Swati Jantrania. Pennsylvania State. “Customer Value in Organizational Buying: A Means‐End Approach.”</p>
         <p>Junyong Kim. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Counterfactual Thinking: An Underlying Mechanism of Post‐consumption Evaluation and Consumer Satisfaction.”</p>
         <p>John C. Kozup. Arkansas. “An Examination of Task Environment Characteristics and Decision Coping Style on Choice.”</p>
         <p>Monika Kukar‐Kinney. Indiana—Bloomington. “Consumer Response to Characteristics of Price‐Matching Guarantees: The Moderating Role of Consumer and Retailer Characteristics.”</p>
         <p>Dmitri Kuksov. California, Berkeley. “The Role of Search, Information and Strategic Decision‐Making in a Competitive Marketplace.”</p>
         <p>Robert Joseph Kwortnik, Jr. Temple. “The Role of Positive Emotions in Consumer Choice for Experiential Products.”</p>
         <p>Susan Lloyd. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Consumers’ Experiences with E‐Commerce Technologies: Three Essays.”</p>
         <p>Humaira Mahi. Minnesota. “Product Quality Signaling and Extension Warranties Given Consumer Moral Hazard: The Role of High Price.”</p>
         <p>Regina Celeste McNally. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Efficiency Motives and Institutional Considerations in Make‐or‐Buy Decisions.”</p>
         <p>Sangkil Moon. Iowa. “Spatial Choice Models for Product Recommendations.”</p>
         <p>Prokriti Mukherji. USC. “Marketing in the Pharmaceutical Industry.”</p>
         <p>Lan Nguyen. Minnesota. “Growing Up in a `Material World': An Investigation of the Development of Materialism in Children and Adolescents.”</p>
         <p>Martin Phenix Nunlee. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Reputation as a Control Mechanism for Opportunistic Behavior in Supply Chains.”</p>
         <p>Xing Pan. Maryland. “Price Dispersion and Price Competition in Online Retail Markets.”</p>
         <p>Shaoming Qu. USC. “Essays on Innovation and New Product Development Strategies.”</p>
         <p>Kristin Rotte. Cincinnati. “Destination ‘E’: Detecting and Managing Customer Uncertainty in a Forced Migration Initiative within a Business‐to‐Business Market.”</p>
         <p>Nitish Singh. St. Louis. “Analyzing the Web as a Cultural Document: An Exploratory Study of Cultural Values as Depicted on Country‐Specific Websites.”</p>
         <p>Bharadhwaj Sivakumaran. Maryland. “Essays on Variety Seeking and Its Link with Consideration Sets and Order of Entry.”</p>
         <p>Jelena Spanjol. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Idea Generation in New Product Development: A Cognitive Framework of the Fuzzy Front End.”</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Stammerjohan. Mississippi State. “An Empirical Investigation of Husband and Wife Perceptions of Family Purchase Process Participation in Retirement Age Families.”</p>
         <p>Suresh Sundaram. Houston. “Internet Shopping: The Critical Role of Relation‐Based Information in Online Consumer Shopping.”</p>
         <p>Scott Swain. South Carolina. “Weighing Your Options: Consumer Response to Product Mass.”</p>
         <p>Palaniappan Thiagarajan. Mississippi State. “An Empirical Investigation of Effect of Role Strain on Single Parent Households' Purchase Behavior.”</p>
         <p>Scott Thorne. Southern Illinois at Carbondale. “The Antecedents and Consequences of Consumer Fanaticism.”</p>
         <p>Peter Weathers. South Carolina. “Purchase Channel and Product Characteristics Effects on Consumer Risk Perceptions.”</p>
         <p>Rosalind Wyatt. Houston. “The Impact of Hispanic and African American U.S. Subcultures on National versus Private Label Brand Choice.”</p>
         <p>Lan Xia. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “A Multi‐Method Investigation of Consumer Browsing Behaviors and Unintended Information Acquisition: Three Essays.”</p>
         <p>Rui (Juliet) Zhu. Minnesota. “The Influence of Self‐Regulatory Focus on Consumer Information Processing.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc12">
         <title>Operations Research and Management Science</title>
         <p>Ahmad Alshamrani. Case Western Reserve. “Combined Routing and Product Take‐Back Strategies in Reverse Logistics.”</p>
         <p>Chien‐Yu Chen. Maryland. “Optimization‐Based Available to Promise (ATP).”</p>
         <p>Andrew Coleman Corbett. Univ. Colorado. “Opportunity Recognition: A Learning and Cognitive Approach.”</p>
         <p>Haluk Demirkan. Univ. Florida. “Supply Chain Management of Application Providers: Coordination Strategies and Queuing Effects.”</p>
         <p>Janis Grevins. SUNY at Buffalo. “Project Virtuality Effects on Project Team Processes and Project Success.”</p>
         <p>Ahmad Hassan. Mississippi State. “Antecedents and Consequences of Competitive Aggressiveness: An Embeddedness Perspective.”</p>
         <p>Dan Jong Kim. SUNY at Buffalo. “Three Essays on Trust in Business to Consumer Electronic Commerce.”</p>
         <p>YongJin Kim. SUNY at Buffalo. “Measuring Web‐Based Business to Business Support System Success Based on User Satisfaction.”</p>
         <p>Canan Kocabasoglu. SUNY at Buffalo. “An Empirical Investigation of the Impact of Strategic Sourcing and E‐Procurement Practices on Supply Chain Performance.”</p>
         <p>Dongwon Lee. USC. “A Typology of Corporate Environmental Strategy and Its Driving Factors in Multinational Corporations.”</p>
         <p>John K. Mahaney. Kent State. “The Arma (1,1) Model and Outlier Detection in Quality Control.”</p>
         <p>Ismatilla Mardanov. Mississippi State. “A Theoretical Development and Test of the Foreign Market Entry Strategy Process Model: An Integration Using an Example of the Eastern European and Former Soviet Countries.”</p>
         <p>Yin Mo. Pennsylvania State. “A Robust Supply Chain Design under Demand Uncertainty and Hybrid Postponement Strategies.”</p>
         <p>Joseph O'Donnell. SUNY at Buffalo. “Assessment of the Impact of Web Site Design on Consumer Trust and the Purchase Decision.”</p>
         <p>Yahuhiro Ohta. SUNY at Buffalo. “The Forensic‐Type Phase: A Game‐Theoretic Analysis of Fraud Detection in Auditing.”</p>
         <p>James Lewis Sager. Univ. Colorado. “Desktop Virtual Reality and Electronic Commerce: An Empirical Study of the Impact of Realism and Perspective on Usage Intentions.”</p>
         <p>Joseph Szmerekovsky. Case Western Reserve. “Maximizing Project Net‐Present Value and Minimizing Work‐in‐Progress Costs in Projects.”</p>
         <p>Mustafa Ungan. South Carolina. “Best Practices in Manufacturing Organizations: The Adoption Decision, Implementation, Success, and Performance.”</p>
         <p>Bharath Vaidyanathan. Alabama. “A Benders Decomposition Based Solution Procedures to Solve a Finite Horizon, Multi‐Product, Capacitated Production‐Planning Problem with Stochastic Demand.”</p>
         <p>Patricia G. Vidal. Boston Univ. “The Effect of Variation and Learning before Doing on the Learning Curve: An Experimental Design Approach and Evidence from a Case Study.”</p>
         <p>Thomas Vossen. Maryland. “Fair Allocation Methods in Air Traffic Management.”</p>
         <p>Victor Brian Wayhan. Houston. “Supplier Quality Awards and Competitive Advantage: A Partial Test of Deming's Chain Reaction Model.”</p>
         <p>Larry Richard White. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Feedback and Control for Hierarchical Production Planning.”</p>
         <p>Frank E. Ziegler. Kent State. “A Methodology for the Approximation of Discrete Values Using a Minimal Set of Continuous Functions.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc13">
         <title>Personnel and Industrial Relations</title>
         <p>Michael Edward Brown. Pennsylvania State. “Leading with Values: The Moderating Influence of Trust on Values Acceptance by Employees.”</p>
         <p>Susan Jensen. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Entrepreneurs as Leaders: Impact of Psychological Capital and Perspectives of Authenticity on Venture Performance.”</p>
         <p>Ana Leonard. Cincinnati. “The Effects of Ethnicity and Self‐Construal on Friendship Networks: Enabling Career Success in Academia.”</p>
         <p>Shanggeun Rhee. Nebraska—Lincoln. “A Relative Effectiveness of Incentive Motivators: A Field Experiment with Comparison between Korean and American Samples.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc14">
         <title>Production</title>
         <p>Bradley E. Anderson. Indiana—Bloomington. “Solution Approaches for the Parallel Identical Machine Scheduling Problem with Sequence Dependent Setups.”</p>
         <p>Suhong Li. Toledo. “An Integrated Model of Supply Chain Management Practice, Performance and Competitive Advantage.”</p>
         <p>Chong Leng Tan. Toledo. “The Impact of Computer‐Aided Design (CAD) Systems on Firm Performance.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc15">
         <title>Statistics and Econometrics</title>
         <p>Ashwin Alankar. California, Berkeley. “Essays on Financial Econometrics.”</p>
         <p>Carole Marie Amidon. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Robust Estimation of the Cross‐Sections of US Wages and Stock Returns.”</p>
         <p>Christa Pettway Carter. Alabama. “A Bayesian Approach to Control Charting Attribute Data Exhibiting Process Variability.”</p>
         <p>Aurobindo Ghosh. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “Smooth Test and Its Applications in Economics and Finance.”</p>
         <p>Min Li. Cincinnati. “Two Essays in Bayesian Penalized Splines.”</p>
         <p>Luiz Renato Regis de Oliveira Lima. Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign. “A Study on Locally Persistent Time Series.”</p>
         <p>Joseph Brian Thomas. Alabama. “Interpretation of Multivariate Control Chart Signals.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc16">
         <title>Transportation</title>
         <p>Rahul Kale. Maryland. “Impacts of Internet Logistics Exchanges on the Performance of Shippers and Carriers.”</p>
         <p>Kirk Patterson. Maryland. “Antecedents and Benefits of Supply Chain Technology Adoption.”</p>
         <p>Thomas Quasney. Maryland. “Competitive Interaction: A Study of Market, Nonmarket and Integrated Competitive Behavior.”</p>
         <p>Hugh Turner. Maryland. “Infrastructure Productivity in the North American Containerport System: A Longitudinal Study (1984–1997).”</p>
         <p>Yuliang (Oliver) Yao. Maryland. “Measuring Impacts of Electronic Commerce on Supply Chain Management.”</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc17">
         <title>Miscellaneous</title>
         <p>Eduardo Andrade. Univ. Florida. “The Impact of Affect on Decision Processes: Testing a Theoretical Proposition.”</p>
         <p>John Banko. Univ. Florida. “Puttable Corporate Debt: Theory and Evidence.”</p>
         <p>William Matthew Bowler. Univ. Kentucky. “Relationships and Organizational Citizenship Behaviour: A Social Network Approach.”</p>
         <p>Scott Carrell. Univ. Florida. “An Analysis of Military Pay Policy and the Effects on Air Force Reenlistments.”</p>
         <p>Sourav Chatterjee. Univ. Florida. “Consolidations, Efficiency and High Quality in Health Care Markets.”</p>
         <p>Marcus daCunha. Univ. Florida. “Consumer's Evaluations of Time‐Delayed Purchase Opportunities.”</p>
         <p>Els deWilde. Univ. Florida. “The Numbers of Levels Effect: In Search of a Psychological Explanation.”</p>
         <p>Bambi Douma. Univ. Arizona. “The Bases and Impacts of Negative Social Relationships.”</p>
         <p>Scott Bruce Droege. Univ. Kentucky. “Making the Rules as You Go: Characteristics of Incremental Institutions.”</p>
         <p>Rangamohan Venkata Eunni. Boston Univ. “Strategic Adaptation in a Rapidly Changing Industry: An Empirical Study of the Telecommunications Equipment Industry in the United States (1990–1999).”</p>
         <p>Lynn M. Fisher. Pennsylvania State. “Financial Contracting in Real Estate.”</p>
         <p>Jianming Mao. Kent State. “Locational Determinants of Foreign Direct Investment in China on Regional and Provincial Bases.”</p>
         <p>Kenneth C. Rebeck. Nebraska—Lincoln. “Economic Literacy in U.S. High Schools.”</p>
         <p>Tim Silk. Univ. Florida. “Why Do We Buy But Fail to Redeem? The Influence of Pre‐purchase, Post‐purchase and Repeat‐Purchase Factors on Consumer's Subjective and Objective Probability or Redeeming Mail‐In Rebates.”</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
