<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">finamana</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100419</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Financial Management</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Management Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00463892</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">1755053X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">3665944</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Topics in Real Options and Applications</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Value of Flexibility: The Case of a Dual-Fuel Industrial Steam Boiler</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Nalin</given-names>
                  <surname>Kulatilaka</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i284589</issue-id>
         <fpage>271</fpage>
         <lpage>280</lpage>
         <page-range>271-280</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1993 Financial Management Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/3665944"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper employs a general model of flexibility to value a dual-fuel industrial steam boiler. First, we illustrate the shortcomings of conventional capital budgeting techniques to value flexible projects (such as the dual-fuel boiler) and motivate the need for new analytical techniques. Briefly, discounted cash flow methods ignore the "operating flexibilities" that give project managers options to make and revise decisions in response to changing external conditions. For example, when facing uncertain prices, operating flexibilities can protect the firm against some of the adverse price movements by reconfiguring into an alternative "mode of operation" that is less affected by the adverse prices. Next, we present the general model of flexibility where a project can be switched between several operating modes. The model captures the decision-tree nature of the problem and incorporates risk in a manner that is consistent with modern finance theory. The main contribution of this paper is the case study application. Industrial steam boilers provide an ideal context to apply our model of flexibility. They embody a simple technology with a single variable input (fuel) and a single output (steam). Specifically, we consider a 350 hp. Package Firetube Boiler manufactured by Cleaver-Brooks, which is configured to produce steam at a pressure of 125 psig per hour (an annual output rate of approximately 1190 MBtu). This quality and rate of output can be achieved by firing either natural gas or No. 2 fuel oil. However, due primarily to their different combustion temperatures, the two fuel types vary in their burning efficiencies. The flexible boiler adapts to changing prices by utilizing the efficiency differences and the resulting cost differences under the alternative input fuels. This provides a significant source of value that is otherwise ignored in a DCF valuation. In order to estimate the profit functions, we rely on an engineering model which captures heat losses in producing steam as a function of the ambient temperature, flue gases, and the operating pressure. We estimate the stack gas losses and radiation/convection losses under the two alternative fuel burning configurations. Our estimates show that firms would be indifferent between operating the boiler with gas or oil at a relative (Btu-adjusted) oil/gas price ratio of 1.04. Market prices of $0.60 per gallon of No. 2 fuel oil and $1.90/MBtu for natural gas translate into a comparable relative price of approximately 1.2. This suggests that a natural gas boiler would be preferred to one that is fired by oil. However, due to the volatility of the relative price of gas to fuel oil, a decision rule that takes into account the relative price dynamics may make a flexible boiler even more preferable. We then model the evolutionary process of the relative oil/gas price. The high degree of substitution between these two fuel sources suggests a mean-reverting process of relative prices of oil to gas. We set the long-run mean price such that the two boilers could be operated at equal cost. Using prices during the period January 1984 through December 1987. We estimated an annual volatility of 18.1% and a mean-reversion adjustment factor of 36.8%. When switching is costless, the value of flexibility (estimated at $26,000) exceeded the incremental purchase cost ($5200). However, even flexible boilers incur costs to switch between fuel types due to potential work interruptions, re-contracting costs, and costs of physically switching fuel types, and would depend on the specific application. We approximated the switching cost to equal one month's fuel cost. Although the advantage is somewhat attenuated, the flexible boilers still dominate. Perhaps, this explains why over 80% of the boilers sold by major manufacturers are of the dual-fuel type. Finally, we computed the critical relative price at which firms would switch between oil and gas. For our base-case parameter values, the firm would switch from gas to oil if the relative oil price falls below 0.92, and it will switch from oil to gas if the relative price rises above 1.5. Our results have not only the obvious implications for investment in flexible technologies, but may also influence the equilibrium market prices of substitute fuels. For instance, if oil boilers were cheaper to operate under current energy prices, the threat of potential future gas price increases will tend to maintain the status quo and dissuade oil-using firms from switching into gas-operated technologies. However, the introduction of flexible technologies reduces the switching costs and enables firms to choose the lower cost alternative fuel source. Ironically, the very presence of flexible technologies may reduce the volatility of relative price changes and reduce the value of flexibility.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group>
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1e129a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e136" publication-type="other">
Pindyck [13]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e142" publication-type="other">
Kulatilaka and Marcus [9]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e148" publication-type="other">
Mason and Merton [10]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e155a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e162" publication-type="other">
Kulatilaka [7]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e169a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e176" publication-type="other">
Kulatilaka and Marcus [9]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e183a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e190" publication-type="other">
Constantinides [3]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e196" publication-type="other">
McDonald and
Siegel [11]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e207a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e214" publication-type="other">
Provance [14]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e221a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e228" publication-type="other">
Electric Power Research Institute [5]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e235a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e242" publication-type="other">
Caballero [2]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1e258a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e265" publication-type="journal">
M. Brennan and E. Schwartz, "Evaluating Natural Resource Invest-
ments," Journal of Business (April 1985), pp. 135-157.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2352967</object-id>
               <fpage>135</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e281a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e288" publication-type="journal">
R.J. Caballero, "On the Sign of the Investment-Uncertainty Rela-
tionship," American Economic Review (March 1991), pp. 279-288.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2006800</object-id>
               <fpage>279</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e304a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e311" publication-type="journal">
G. Constantinides, "Market Risk Adjustment in Project Valuation,"
Journal of Finance (May 1978), pp. 603-616.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/2326572</object-id>
               <fpage>603</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e327a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e334" publication-type="journal">
J. Cox, J. Ingersoll, and S. Ross, "An Inter-temporal General Equi-
librium Model of Asset Prices," Econometrica (March 1985), pp.
363-384.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/1911241</object-id>
               <fpage>363</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e354a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e361" publication-type="book">
Electric Power Research Institute, "Fuel Switching and Gas Market
Risks: Volumes 1 and 2," EPRI P-6822, Palo Alto, CA, 1990.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Electric Power Research Institute</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <comment content-type="section">Fuel Switching and Gas Market Risks: Volumes 1 and 2</comment>
               <source>EPRI P-6822</source>
               <year>1990</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e390a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e397" publication-type="journal">
B. Kogut and N. Kulatilaka, "Operating Flexibility, Global Manu-
facturing, and the Option Value of a Multinational Network," Man-
agement Science, forthcoming November 1993.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2632849</object-id>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e413a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e420" publication-type="book">
N. Kulatilaka, "The Value of Flexibility I: A General Model of Real
Options," in Real Options in Capital Investment.: New Contributions,
L. Trigeorgis (ed.), Praeger, NY, 1993.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kulatilaka</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <comment content-type="section">The Value of Flexibility I: A General Model of Real Options</comment>
               <source>Real Options in Capital Investment.: New Contributions</source>
               <year>1993</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e452a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e459" publication-type="book">
N. Kulatilaka, "Operating Flexibilities in Capital Budgeting: Substi-
tutability and Complementarity of Real Options," in Real Options
in Capital Investment: New Contributions, L. Trigeorgis (ed.), Prae-
ger, NY, 1993.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kulatilaka</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <comment content-type="section">Operating Flexibilities in Capital Budgeting: Substitutability and Complementarity of Real Options</comment>
               <source>Real Options in Capital Investment: New Contributions</source>
               <year>1993</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e494a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e501" publication-type="journal">
N. Kulatilaka and A. Marcus, "Project Valuation Under Uncertainty:
When Does DCF Fail?," Journal of Applied Corporate Finance (Fall
1992), pp. 92-100.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Kulatilaka</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <issue>Fall</issue>
               <fpage>92</fpage>
               <source>Journal of Applied Corporate Finance</source>
               <year>1992</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e536a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e543" publication-type="book">
S. Mason and R. Merton, "The Role of Contingent Claims Analysis
in Corporate Finance," in Recent Advances in Corporate Finance,
E.I. Altman and M.G. Subrahmanyam (eds.), Homewood, IL, Rich-
ard D. Irwin, 1985, pp. 7-54.<person-group>
                  <string-name>
                     <surname>Mason</surname>
                  </string-name>
               </person-group>
               <comment content-type="section">The Role of Contingent Claims Analysis in Corporate Finance</comment>
               <fpage>7</fpage>
               <source>Recent Advances in Corporate Finance</source>
               <year>1985</year>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e582a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e589" publication-type="journal">
R. McDonald and D. Siegel, "Option Pricing When the Underlying
Asset Earns a Below Equilibrium Rate of Return: A Note," Journal
of Finance (March 1984), pp. 261-265.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/2327682</object-id>
               <fpage>261</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e608a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e615" publication-type="journal">
R. McDonald and D. Siegel, "The Value of Waiting to Invest,"
Quarterly Journal of Economics (November 1986), pp. 707-727.<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/1884175</object-id>
               <fpage>707</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e631a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e638" publication-type="journal">
R.S. Pindyck, "Irreversibility, Uncertainty, and Investment,"Journal
of Economic Literature (September 1991), pp. 1110-1148.<object-id pub-id-type="jstor">10.2307/2727613</object-id>
               <fpage>1110</fpage>
            </mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e654a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <mixed-citation id="d1e661" publication-type="other">
M. Provance, "Industrial Boiler Fuel Cost Model," Draft-Mimeo,
MIT Energy Laboratory, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
