<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816558</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ACA and Incentives to Work (Health)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Affordable Care Act and Trends in Part-Time Employment</article-title>
            <subtitle>2016 Update</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moriya</surname>
                  <given-names>Asako S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>25</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816558"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The Affordable Care Act (ACA)’s provisions, such as an employer mandate and means-tested Medicaid expansion and premium subsidies, could potentially have impacted labor market outcomes. This paper updated the analysis of Moriya, Selden, and Simon (2016) by adding data through mid-2016 and investigated the trend of part-time employment. I found that the ACA continued to have limited impact on part-time employment, even in 2016, after the employer mandate was fully implemented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Baicker, K., Finkelstein, A., Song, J., and Taubman, S. 2014. “The Impact of Medicaid on Labor Market Activity and Program Participation: Evidence from the Oregon Health Insurance Experiment.” American Economic Review, 104(5): 322-328.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Buchmueller, T. C., DiNardo, J., and Valetta, R.G. 2011. “The Effect of an Employer Health Insurance Mandate on Health Insurance Coverage and the Demand for Labor: Evidence from Hawaii.” American Economic Journal-Economic Policy 3(4): 25-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Cohen, R.A., M.E. Martinez, and E.P. Zammitti. 2016. “Health Insurance Coverage: Early Release of Estimates from the National Health Interview Survey, January-March 2016.” Hyattsville, MD: National Center for Health Statistics. Available from: http://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhis/releases.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Dague, L., T. DeLeire, and L. Leininger. Forthcoming. “The Effect of Public Insurance Coverage for Childless Adults on Labor Supply.” American Economic Journal-Economic Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Dick, A. W. 1994. “Will Employer Mandates Really Work? Another Look at Hawaii.” Health Affairs, 13(1): 343-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Dillender, Marcus, Carolyn Heinrich, and Susan Houseman. 2016. “Effects of the Affordable Care Act on Part-Time Employment: Early Evidence.” Upjohn Institute Working Paper 16-258. Kalamazoo, MI: W.E. Upjohn Institute for Employment Research. http://dx.doi.org/10.17848/wp16-258</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Garrett, B., and R. Kaestner. 2015. “ACA Implementation--Monitoring and Tracking: Recent Evidence on the ACA and Employment: Has the ACA Been a Job Killer?” Washington, DC: Urban Institute. http://www.urban.org/sites/default/files/alfresco/publication-pdfs/2000327-Recent-Evidence-on-the-ACA-and-Employment-Has-the-ACA-been-a-Job-Killer.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Garthwaite, C., T. Gross, and M. J. Notowidigdo. 2014. “Public Health Insurance, Labor Supply, and Employment Lock.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 129(2): 653-696.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Gooptu, A., A.S. Moriya, K. Simon, and B.D. Sommers. 2016. “Medicaid Expansion Did Not Result In Significant Employment Changes Or Job Reductions In 2014.” Health Affairs, 35(1): 111-118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Heim, B.T., and I.Z. Lurie. 2015. “Does Health Reform Lead to Increased Job Mobility? Evidence from Massachusetts.” American Journal of Health Economics. 1(3):374-398.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Kaestner, R., B. Garrett, A. Gangopadhyaya, and C. Fleming. 2015. “Effects of ACA Medicaid Expansions on Health Insurance Coverage and Labor Supply.” NBER Working Paper. No. w21836</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Leung, P., and A. Mas. 2016. “Employment Effects of the ACA Medicaid Expansions.” NBER Working Paper. No. w22540.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Madrian, B.C., and L. Lefgren. 1999. “A Note on Longitudinally Matching Current Population Survey (CPS) Respondents.” NBER Technical Working Paper, No. t247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Moriya, A. S., T.M. Selden, and K. Simon. 2016. “Little Change Seen In Part-Time Employment As A Result Of The Affordable Care Act.” Health Affairs, 35(1): 119-123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Thurston, N.K. 1997. “Labor Market Effects of Hawaii’s Mandatory Employer-Provided Health Insurance.” Industrial and Labor Relations Review, 51(1): 117-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working each hour range, 2005-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working 25-29 hours by firm size, overall, and by reasons for part-time employment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working each hour range among those with lower educational attainment, 2005-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working 25-29 hours among those with lower educational attainment by firm size, overall, and by reasons for part-time employment, 2012-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working each hour range among those near retirement age, 2005-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working 25-29 hours among those near retirement age by firm size, overall, and by reasons for part-time employment, 2012-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working each hour range among those who worked 30 hours or more at firms with 100 or more employees and did not report ESI in the prior year ASEC, 2012-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8.</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working each hour range among those who worked 30-34 hours at firms with 100 or more employees and did not report ESI in the prior year ASEC, 2012-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Adjusted probability of working each hour range among those who worked 35-39 hours at firms with 100 or more employees and who reported ESI in own name in the prior year ASEC, 2012-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10.</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Adjusted probabilities of working 26-30 hours by firm size, overall, and by reason for part-time employment, 2012-2016</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics of the Sample of the Main Analysis and the Sample of the Analysis Using Firm Size Information</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Estimates from Figure 1: Adjusted probability of working each hour range, 2005-2016 (in percent)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Estimates from Figure 2. Adjusted probability of working 25-29 hours by firm size, overall, and by reasons for part-time employment (in percent)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Estimates from Figure 3. Adjusted probability of working each hour range among those with lower educational attainment, 2005-2016 (in percent)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Estimates from Figure 4. Adjusted probability of working 25-29 hours among those with lower educational attainment by firm size, overall, and by reasons for part-time employment, 2012-2016 (in percent)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Estimates from Figure 5. Adjusted probability of working each hour range among those near retirement age, 2005-2016 (in percent)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix Table 7.</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Estimates from Figure 6. Adjusted probability of working 25-29 hours among those with near retirement age by firm size, overall, and by reasons for part-time employment, 2012-2016 (in percent)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
