<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909718</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Army Operations Research Symposium 2007</article-title>
            <subtitle>“Operations Research – Meeting the New Challenges of the Warfighter”</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Cook</surname>
                  <given-names>Pat J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mrs Pat Cook is a supervisory operations research analyst with the US Army Materiel Systems Analysis Activity, Aberdeen Proving Ground, MD. She is currently the Chief of the Strategic and Operational Support Division. She started her career with the XM1 Tank, becoming the Test Design and Evaluation Coordinator for the M1 Tank, and then progressing into leadership roles in Command and Control, Survivability and Strategic Planning and Special Projects.</p>
                  <p>Ms Cook received her bachelor’s degree in applied mathematics from Georgia Institute of Technology in 1973 and a master’s degree in management science/operations research from The Johns Hopkins University in 1978. She has attended the Army War College and completed the Defense Leadership and Management Program (DLAMP). She was a recipient of the Vice President’s Heroes of Reinvention Hammer Award for her participation on the DA level Acquisition Systems Oversight and Review Process Action Team and has received the DA Meritorious Civilian Service Award.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2008</year>
            <string-date>March 2008</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909694</issue-id>
         <fpage>29</fpage>
         <lpage>31</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909718"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
