<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="research-article"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/381279</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB770206</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Economic Value of a Trading Floor: Evidence from the American Stock Exchange<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">*</xref>
            </article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Puneet</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Handa</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_1">University of Iowa</aff>
            <x xml:space="preserve"/>
         </contrib-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Robert A.</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Schwartz</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_2">Baruch College, CUNY</aff>
            <x xml:space="preserve"/>
         </contrib-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ashish</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Tiwari</surname>
               </string-name>
               <x xml:space="preserve"/>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_3">University of Iowa</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>04</month>
            <year>2004</year>
            <string-date>April 2004</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>77</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2004.77.issue-2</issue-id>
         <fpage>331</fpage>
         <lpage>355</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2004 by The University of Chicago. All rights reserved.</copyright-statement>
            <copyright-year>2004</copyright-year>
            <copyright-holder>The University of Chicago</copyright-holder>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/381279"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>By comparing execution costs of trades handled by Amex floor brokers with trades entered through its automated post execution reporting (PER) system, this article provides evidence that floor brokers have value. Because they can opportunistically seize liquidity, using a floor broker is equivalent to placing a “smart” limit order. Overall, floor trades have a lower realized half‐spread than PER trades (−3.06 bps vs. 4.43 bps). This finding holds for other measures of execution costs and is consistent across all order‐size categories. The analysis of the value of intermediation in a securities market has implications for automated trading systems.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
      <notes notes-type="footnote">
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn1">
               <label>*</label>
               <p>We would like to thank the American Stock Exchange, especially Brett Redfern and Russ Monahan, for making the necessary data available to us and for providing technical assistance and information. We are also most grateful to the referee for his or her helpful insights and suggestions. We further thank Bill Christie, Hank Bessembinder, Tom George, Bill Lupien, Deniz Ozenbas, Evan Schulman, George Sofianos, Dan Weaver, and seminar participants at Dartmouth College, the OPIM Seminar at the Wharton School, University of Delaware, University of Missouri—Columbia, University of Iowa, and the 1999 WFA meetings for their comments and suggestions. All errors remain ours. Contact the corresponding author, Robert Schwartz, at Robert_Schwartz@baruch.cuny.edu.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </notes>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <label>I.</label>
         <title>Introduction</title>
         <p>In recent years, the trend in equity market structure has been away from floor‐based trading to automated floorless trading systems.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn2">1</xref>But the two national U.S. stock exchanges, the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) and the American Stock Exchange (Amex), still have trading floors. Is this the result of technological inertia and vested interests, or does the floor have economic value? Our objective in this article is to assess the economic raison d’être of a trading floor. To this end, we examine trades on the floor of Amex and contrast them with trades on Amex’s automated post execution reporting (PER) system. We find evidence of intelligent order handling by floor traders that results in reduced execution costs that may offset the higher handling costs of floor trades.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn3">2</xref>
         </p>
         <p>Microstructure economists in the past have paid scant attention to the economic value of a trading floor.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn4">3</xref>Some have simply thought the floor archaic in an electronic environment where participants can work with a bank of computer screens far more easily on the upstairs desks than on the trading floor where space is at a premium.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn5">4</xref>Presumably, the computerization of information dissemination would give electronic trading a strong informational advantage vis‐à‐vis a floor. Nevertheless, Sofianos and Werner (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1997</xref>), in their analysis of floor broker participation on the NYSE, find that floor brokers do contribute additional liquidity. Pagano and Röell (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf23">1992</xref>) point out a further advantage of a floor‐based trading system: it gives participants “the opportunity to observe who trades what with whom, how urgently they seem to want to trade, etc.” (p. 619). There are a number of other ways in which a floor trader may add value: (<italic>a</italic>) the trader might obtain knowledge of the presence of a contra party, mitigating price impact; (<italic>b</italic>) the trader could “round up” multiple counter parties, again cushioning the impact by trading in what may be viewed as a spontaneous call auction; (<italic>c</italic>) the trader could anticipate periods when liquidity is high and trade more often and in larger sizes during such periods; (<italic>d</italic>) the trader could avoid trading in periods when trading is low; and (<italic>e</italic>) the trader may possess superior ability to read momentum in the market and to time trades accordingly.</p>
         <p>A potential drawback of trading via the floor is that handling costs are higher for orders worked on the floor than for orders delivered electronically through PER, and the fixed cost component may be appreciable.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn6">5</xref>Consequently, the floor may be an attractive venue for large, predominantly institutional participants who are concerned with controlling market impact. The PER, on the other hand, may be attractive to small, predominantly retail participants whose orders are not large enough to have market impact or to justify the higher fixed cost component of floor‐based order handling.</p>
         <p>In this article, we focus on comparing execution costs across the two venues (PER and the floor) for orders in the same stock matched by stock and trade characteristics such as execution price, order size, and trade direction. We restrict ourselves to measuring implicit costs of execution such as realized spreads, quoted spreads, and effective spreads.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn7">6</xref>We employ a matched pair technique to control for the self‐selection of trades submitted to the floor or to PER by investors, thereby allowing for a more meaningful comparison of execution costs across the two venues.</p>
         <p>In our data set (October 2001 Trade and Quote Data for 973 Amex stocks), 23.40% of the trading volume was initiated by floor brokers. Using the matched pair technique, we find that floor broker timed order handling generally results in lower execution costs. Overall, trades handled by floor brokers have a significantly smaller realized half‐spread than do PER trades (−3.06 basis points [bps] vs. 4.43 bps). It is interesting to note that the realized half‐spread for floor trades is actually negative. The contrast holds for all trade size categories in our sample. In addition, floor trades have a lower effective half‐spread as compared with PER trades (8.11 bps vs. 10.27 bps). Finally, the quoted half‐spread is also lower when floor orders initiate trades than when PER orders initiate trades (16.23 bps vs. 17.47 bps). These differences are all statistically significant at the 1% level and are economically meaningful.</p>
         <p>Our finding of a lower realized spread for floor trades is robust to controls for the information content of a trade. Specifically, we extend the matched pair technique to control for permanent price effects, and we continue to find that execution costs are lower on the trading floor. We also examine execution costs for SPDRs (Standard &amp; Poor's depository receipts), a security that is not subject to information asymmetries. Our findings on SPDRs provide strong confirmation that the execution cost differentials are driven by the relative efficiency of order handling on the floor rather than by information asymmetries.</p>
         <p>We examine the determinants of trade initiation on the floor versus PER using a probit analysis. Our findings are that the floor trading mechanism is preferred for larger‐sized trades, on occasions when the order flow is in the direction of the initiating trade (but not following a recent large price change), during morning and late afternoon hours, and for less liquid stocks. We further examine the determinants of execution costs on the trading floor by modeling a floor trader’s decision to trade that accounts for the potential selectivity bias in the data.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn8">7</xref>Our major findings are that the execution costs are lower for trades initiated in the direction of the order flow but are higher for trades following large price changes. Together, these findings suggest that floor traders exhibit strategic behavior, becoming more aggressive in response to a thickening of the book on their own side and becoming more patient following large pretrade price changes. It thus appears that floor traders can opportunistically seize liquidity without showing their hands too quickly and that, consequently, using a floor broker is equivalent to placing a “smart” limit order. This implies a standard that electronic trading must meet in order to provide an environment that, from the point of view of institutional investors, is competitive with the trading floor. Currently, an increasing number of institutional investors have their own DOT machines and smart order handling systems and are thereby able, to a limited extent, to handle their orders strategically from their upstairs desks much as they would be worked on the trading floor.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn9">8</xref>
         </p>
         <p>In the next section of this article, we consider order handling mechanisms and price determination in an electronic continuous trading system versus a floor‐based continuous market. In<xref ref-type="sec" rid="sc3">Section III</xref>, we describe the data and methodology used for the study. In<xref ref-type="sec" rid="sc4">Section IV</xref>, we present our empirical results.<xref ref-type="sec" rid="sc5">Section V</xref>contains our conclusions.</p>
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn2">
               <label>1. </label>
               <p>The Toronto Stock Exchange closed its trading floor in May 1997. The London Stock Exchange, which has been floorless since Big Bang in 1996, introduced an electronic limit order book into its quote‐driven market in 1997. Nasdaq now has an electronic platform, Super Montage. Floorless, electronic continuous trading now characterizes the equity markets of Toronto, Paris, Tokyo, Stockholm, Sidney, Switzerland, Madrid, Frankfurt, and elsewhere. In the United States, new alternative trading systems (commonly referred to as ATSs) and Electronic Communications Networks (ECNs) are also electronic, order‐driven systems.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn3">
               <label>2. </label>
               <p>It is important to assess liquidity impact costs in light of studies such as Amihud and Mendelson (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf2">1986</xref>), Brennan and Subrahmanyam (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf5">1996</xref>), and Amihud, Mendelson, and Lauterbach (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf3">1997</xref>), among others, that have provided evidence of a liquidity premium in asset pricing.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn4">
               <label>3. </label>
               <p>Past research has largely focused on comparing execution costs across various market structures such as auction vs. dealer markets. See, e.g., Huang and Stoll (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf11">1996</xref>), Bessembinder and Kaufman (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf4">1997</xref>), and Venkataraman (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf25">2001</xref>).</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn5">
               <label>4. </label>
               <p>Saul Hansell in the<italic>New York Times</italic>, March 16, 1998 (p. D5), wrote, “To compete with electronic markets, the New York Stock Exchange is giving traders on its floors all manner of hand‐held computer and communication devices. ‘The typical broker on the floor is starting to look like a space cadet,’ said Greg Kipness.”</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn6">
               <label>5. </label>
               <p>Explicit commission costs are typically higher for orders that are harder to handle. The fixed cost component is implicit in the fact that a customer must maintain a higher trading volume over time in order for the services of a floor broker to be readily available.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn7">
               <label>6. </label>
               <p>There may be other implicit costs of order handling, such as the cost of delayed execution or nonexecution, that are beyond the scope of this study. In that sense, our analysis may be viewed as comparing execution costs across two venues conditional on trade execution.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn8">
               <label>7. </label>
               <p>For further discussion of this approach, see Maddala (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf20">1996</xref>).</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn9">
               <label>8. </label>
               <p>The NYSE’s Designated Order Turnaround system (DOT) routes orders directly to specialists’ posts on the NYSE trading floor and to the Amex’s PER system, which brings the orders for Amex stocks to the Amex specialists’ posts.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <label>II.</label>
         <title>Order Handling and Price Formation</title>
         <p>Standard limit and market orders are delivered to the Amex specialists through the Amex’s PER system. Market orders sent in electronically over PER typically trigger trades immediately. They are directly routed to the specialist who may execute them at the prevailing quote or at an improved price within the quote. Some large institutional investors have DOT machines on their trading desks and send in system orders that are market timed. Predominantly, however, this is not the case.</p>
         <p>In contrast, an order may be given to a floor broker to be worked on a “not held” (NH) basis. The order is called “NH” because the broker is “not held” to the price existing at the time of the order’s arrival if he or she eventually fills the order at a worse price. Price limits are commonly placed on NH orders. Within these limits, a floor broker has the discretion to market time an NH order. Large floor orders are commonly broken up and presented to the market in smaller tranches in the hope of obtaining more favorable market conditions and in an attempt to minimize price impact.</p>
         <p>Having an NH order worked on the floor of an exchange may have important benefits for the investor. By responding to market events as they occur, a floor broker can better control two polar opposite implicit execution costs: (i) the market impact cost of trading a large order too aggressively and (ii) the opportunity cost of trading it too patiently. One might also use a floor broker to gain access to, and to profit from, the agent’s superior information about latent order flow.</p>
         <p>Comprehensively viewed, the key service provided by floor traders is the timing, sizing, and pricing of the tranches of an order. We expect floor brokers to time NH orders according to current market conditions. This may, in fact, be an important reason why investors submit orders to the floor. In other words, it may be more difficult to work such orders away from the floor.</p>
         <p>The time that an order is actually submitted is not observable from our data. Floor traders disclose neither the time an order is received nor the full size of the order. Our tests focus on the liquidity impact cost at the time when part or all of an order triggers a trade. It would be of some interest to examine the spreads prevailing in the market at the time an order is placed, but unfortunately we are not able to do so. Because floor orders are commonly broken up and presented to the market in smaller tranches, the “full order” that was initially submitted is generally larger than the tranche that triggers a trade at any point in time. This is of no serious consequence for our analysis; we consider the initial order a package of smaller orders, and focus on the timing of the tranches as they are revealed to the market and turned into trades.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <label>III.</label>
         <title>The Data and Test Design</title>
         <sec id="sc3.1">
            <label>A.</label>
            <title>Data</title>
            <p>Our analysis uses October 2001, non–block trade and quote data for 973 Amex stocks. For each stock (ticker symbol), for each day, we have (i) the quote file (for each posted quote, the time of the posting, the posting exchange, the bid price posted, the size of the bid, the ask price posted, and the size of the ask) and (ii) the trade file (for each trade, the time the trade was reported executed, the identification code for the buy account, the quantity purchased, the identification code for the sell account, and the quantity sold).</p>
            <p>In order to classify trades, we first reconstruct the National Best Bid and Offer (NBBO) from the quote file, which is updated each time a new quote is posted by an exchange.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn10">9</xref>In reconstructing the NBBO, we adhere strictly to the Consolidated Tape Association’s price, size, and time priority rules. We follow tradition by using the Lee and Ready algorithm to infer the initiating party.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn11">10</xref>Hence, our master data file contains trades arranged in chronological order and identified as buyer‐ or seller‐initiated, the source of the initiating order (floor vs. PER), and the NBBO at the time of trade execution.</p>
            <p>We are concerned about strategic order splitting by traders and its affect on our measure of execution cost. We measure market impact by the price adjustment that occurs after a trade. Because order splitting can affect prices after a floor trade<italic>t</italic>, it can bias our measure of the market impact of the order that triggered trade<italic>t</italic>. We have information on broker identification. Thus, we eliminate possibly split trades by using the following heuristic rule: for each trade<italic>t</italic>, we examine the 15 trades immediately following it. If a trade during this 15‐trade interval has the same clearing firm on the same side of the trade as trade<italic>t</italic>, it is identified as a “split” trade. If trade<italic>t</italic>has more than three “split” trades during the following 15‐trade interval, we eliminate it from the sample. Our analysis is based on this reduced sample of trade observations.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn10">
                  <label>9. </label>
                  <p>The NBBO consists of the best prevailing bid, the size of the best bid, and the exchange posting best bid, and, similarly, the best prevailing ask, the size of the best ask, and the exchange posting the best ask.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn11">
                  <label>10. </label>
                  <p>The Lee and Ready (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf18">1991</xref>) rule is that if the trade execution price is above the average of the prevailing NBBO bid and ask (the mid‐quote), we classify it as buyer‐initiated, and if the trade execution price is below the mid‐quote we classify it as seller‐initiated. If a trade occurs at the mid‐quote, we use the tick test: if the execution price occurs on a plus tick or a zero‐plus tick (i.e., it is higher than the last nonidentical execution price), the trade is classified as buyer‐initiated, and if the execution price occurs on a minus tick or a zero‐minus tick, the trade is classified as seller‐initiated.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc3.2">
            <label>B.</label>
            <title>Measuring Execution Costs</title>
            <p>Consistent with previous studies (e.g., Huang and Stoll<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf11">1996</xref>; Bessembinder and Kaufman<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf1">1997</xref>), we measure the quoted half‐spread and the effective half‐spread for floor trades and PER trades. Consistent with standard practice, the quoted half‐spread is defined as one‐half of the ratio of the bid‐ask spread to the prevailing mid‐quote. The quoted half‐spread is an appropriate measure of execution cost only if trades are assumed to occur at the posted quotes. However, it is not appropriate if trades occur away from the quotes.</p>
            <p>The relevant measure in the latter case is the effective half‐spread, which is usually defined as the ratio of the difference between the execution price and the prevailing mid‐quote, to the mid‐quote. The effective half‐spread is an accurate measure of the revenue realized by the liquidity provider (and, hence, the cost incurred by the liquidity demander) if the value of the asset is unchanged following the trade. However, there is evidence in the literature that the asset value moves in the direction of the trade following the trade (Hasbrouck<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf9">1988</xref>; Huang and Stoll<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf10">1994</xref>). In other words, the price increases following a market buy and declines following a market sell. Accordingly, a more accurate measure of the execution cost is the realized half‐spread, which is sometimes referred to as the temporary price impact.</p>
            <p>Following Huang and Stoll (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf11">1996</xref>) and Bessembinder and Kaufman (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf4">1997</xref>), we define the realized half‐spread for trade<italic>t</italic>for stock<italic>i</italic>as the negative of the logarithmic return from the transaction to the mid‐quote at the time of the fifteenth trade after the transaction.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn12">11</xref>
            </p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn12">
                  <label>11. </label>
                  <p>Our definition of temporary price impact incorporates one‐half of the spread prevailing at the time of trade execution, a component that we refer to as the spread‐related component of price impact. As a test of robustness, we also measured temporary price impact using the mid‐quote for trade<italic>t</italic>to assess the component that is not spread related. The results were generally consistent with the findings reported here.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc3.3">
            <label>C.</label>
            <title>Matched Pair Sampling Technique</title>
            <p>Our objective is to compare execution costs across the two trading venues, the floor and PER. There are, of course, exogenous factors such as stock‐specific characteristics, order size, trade direction (buy or sell), among others, that affect execution costs. To control for these factors, we use a matched pair sampling technique. For each floor trade, we try to locate a matching PER trade. The matching criteria are (1) trades must be in the same stock, (2) trades must be in the same direction (buy or sell), (3) the execution price of the PER trade must be within 20% of the price of the floor trade, and (4) the size of the PER trade must be within 20% of the size of the floor trade.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn13">12</xref>We present our empirical results by categorizing trades into four groups: trades of less than 500 shares, trades between 500 and 999 shares, trades between 1,000 and 1,499 shares, and trades between 1,500 and 9,999 shares.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn13">
                  <label>12. </label>
                  <p>A similar matched pair technique is also used by Venkataraman (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf25">2001</xref>) and Conrad, Johnson, and Wahal (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf6">2001</xref>).</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc3.4">
            <label>D.</label>
            <title>Determinants of Trade Initiation on the Floor versus PER</title>
            <p>Our hypothesis is that trades executed on the floor are strategically timed to account for order characteristics and to coincide with market conditions that reduce execution costs. We first focus on understanding the determinants of trade initiation on the two venues. Theoretical research on order submission strategies suggests two variables that may be of particular relevance to our study. The first explanatory variable, order size, is suggested by theoretical models such as that of Easley and O’Hara (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf7">1987</xref>). The second explanatory variable, order imbalance, is suggested by market microstructure models such as those of Kyle (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf17">1985</xref>) and Admati and Pfleiderer (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf1">1988</xref>). Glosten and Harris (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf8">1988</xref>), Huang and Stoll (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf12">1997</xref>), and Madhavan, Richardson, and Roomans (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf22">1997</xref>) provide evidence that trade indicator variables (buyer‐initiated and seller‐initiated trades) also explain intraday price movements.</p>
            <p>To obtain a measure of order imbalance for a trade<italic>t</italic>, we begin by dividing each day into 15‐minute intervals. Order imbalance for trade<italic>t</italic>is the aggregate trading volume triggered by orders on the same side of the market (as the order that triggered trade<italic>t</italic>) relative to total trading volume in the stock over the contemporaneous 15‐minute interval.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn14">13</xref>To ensure that the measure is not contaminated by a trader’s own trading volume in that 15‐minute interval, in computing the imbalance, we eliminate all trades that the same trader participates in during that period. Hence, we define the order imbalance for trade<italic>t</italic>as<disp-formula id="df1">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df1"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>For trading intervals during which no trades are recorded for a stock, we set Imb<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>equal to .50.</p>
            <p>It is possible to identify other variables that may affect the order submission strategy. For example, implementing a momentum strategy requires that one react more aggressively to price changes as compared to a value strategy.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn15">14</xref>Hence, recent price changes may be a relevant factor in our analysis. We capture this by incorporating the pretrade price change as an explanatory variable in our model. In addition, the time of day may influence order placement. In particular, as the afternoon progresses, we expect to see participants stepping forward to trade because they do not want to risk carrying unfilled orders into the overnight period. We control for the time of the day effect by dividing the trading day into three periods: an opening period (9:30<sc>a.m.</sc>to 10:00<sc>a.m.</sc>), a mid‐day period (10:00<sc>a.m.</sc>to 3:30<sc>p.m.</sc>), and a closing period (3:30<sc>p.m.</sc>to 4:00<sc>p.m.</sc>).</p>
            <p>We formally model the probability of a trade occurring on PER as follows:<disp-formula id="df2">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df2"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>The variable<italic>q</italic>
               <sub>1<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is a binary indicator variable that takes a value of one if the order size is between 500 and 999 shares and zero otherwise,<italic>q</italic>
               <sub>2<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>takes a value of one if the order size is between 1,000 and 1,499 shares, and<italic>q</italic>
               <sub>3<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>takes a value of one if the order size is between 1,500 and 9,999 shares. The variable Imb<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>captures the trading imbalance in the market, taking a value closer to zero (one) when there is less (more) trading interest on the side of the initiating trade. The variable Preret<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is defined as the absolute value of the return from the mid‐quote prevailing 15 trades prior to trade<italic>t</italic>, to trade<italic>t.</italic>The variable<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>1<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is a binary indicator variable that takes a value of one if the trade occurs between 9:30<sc>a.m.</sc>and 10<sc>a.m.</sc>and zero otherwise, and<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>2<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>takes a value of one if the trade occurs between 3:30<sc>p.m.</sc>and 4:00<sc>p.m.</sc>and zero otherwise. The variable Vol<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is the logarithm of the average daily trading volume during October 2001 for the stock being traded.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn14">
                  <label>13. </label>
                  <p>Our results are robust to several alternative measures of order imbalance. For example, we also examine the ratio of the depth on own side of the book to the total depth at the prevailing inside quotes. Our concern with the latter measure is that it could be corrupted by the possibility of the floor trader’s own order being reflected in the quotes. Nevertheless, the two measures gave very similar results. We also found that changing the length of the window over which imbalance is measured to 5 minutes does not materially alter our results.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn15">
                  <label>14. </label>
                  <p>We thank the referee for this suggestion.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc3.5">
            <label>E.</label>
            <title>Determinants of Execution Costs with Endogenous Trade Initiation by Floor Traders</title>
            <p>We now turn to an analysis of the determinants of execution costs for floor trades when floor traders may time orders to minimize realized costs. To handle the potential selection bias in the data, we model the traders’ decision to initiate trades, that is, the decision to submit or withhold an order given the order characteristics and market conditions. Our model follows the standard treatment of cases involving selection bias with an endogenous event.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn16">15</xref>It is similar in spirit to Madhavan and Cheng (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf21">1997</xref>), who use an endogenous switching regression model to study the price impact of block trades across two venues, namely, the upstairs market and the downstairs market. Both models represent the treatment of cases where data are generated by the self‐selection of traders, that is, by the endogenous choices made by the traders. However, there are important differences. Madhavan and Cheng model the choice of the appropriate venue by an agent and use a two‐stage procedure to estimate the model by using data on block trades executed on both venues. In contrast, we analyze the determinants of the realized half‐spread for floor trades by modeling a floor trader’s decision to execute trades selectively. Since we use data on executed floor trades, two‐stage estimation methods are not appropriate in our context. Accordingly, we use the maximum likelihood method to estimate our model.</p>
            <p>In our model, the floor trader’s decision to initiate trades is dependent on the expected realized half‐spread of a trade. Consider a trader who initiates trade<italic>t</italic>(for simplicity, let<italic>t</italic>also denote that trader) and who faces a realized half‐spread. We express the realized half‐spread as<disp-formula id="df3">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df3"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<italic>f</italic>denotes a floor trade and<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\varepsilon ^{f}_{t}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>is a stochastic error term with variance σ<sup>2</sup>. The explanatory variables are as defined under<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df2">equation (1)</xref>. The order size indicator variables<italic>q</italic>
               <sub>1<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>control for the variations in the realized half‐spread related to the size of the order that the market has to absorb. The order imbalance variable Imb<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>controls for variations in execution costs relative to the costs of waiting. The variable Preret<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>controls for the impact of recent price changes on order placement. The time‐of‐day indicator variables<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>1<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>and<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>2<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>account for intraday effects. The variable Vol<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is a proxy measure of the general level of liquidity of the stock and is expected to be an important determinant of the execution cost.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn17">16</xref>
            </p>
            <p>Note that<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">equation (2)</xref>could not be estimated using standard OLS procedures if floor traders endogenously time their trades. In this case, the data would be subject to a selectivity bias. Hence, the OLS procedure would yield inconsistent parameter estimates since the conditional means of the observed error terms in<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">equation (2)</xref>would be nonzero.</p>
            <p>We expect a floor trader to initiate a trade if and only if the expected realized half‐spread is below a threshold level.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn18">17</xref>We define the latent variable<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $y^{*}_{t}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>as the expected difference between the realized half‐spread for trader<italic>t</italic>and the threshold value<italic>c</italic>
               <sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>:<disp-formula id="df4">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df4"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where Ω<sub>t</sub>is the information set for trader<italic>t</italic>and<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\xi _{t}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>denotes an error term with variance normalized to 1. We can write the above equation in compact form as<disp-formula id="df5">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df5"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<italic>z</italic>
               <sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is the vector of explanatory variables outlined in equation (1) and γ is the vector of coefficients.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn19">18</xref>Floor trader<italic>t</italic>chooses to step forward with an order if<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $y^{*}_{t}\leq 0$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>; otherwise the trader withholds the order. Let<italic>y</italic>
               <sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>represent a variable that takes the value one if the trader chooses to trade and takes the value zero otherwise. Hence, the observable variable is<disp-formula id="df6">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df6"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>We assume that (<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\varepsilon ^{f}_{t}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>, ξ<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>) are jointly normally distributed with means zero and covariance matrix<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\sum $ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>, where<disp-formula id="df7">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df7"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>Using the properties of the normal distribution, we can write the expected realized half‐spread conditional on observing a floor trade as follows:<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn20">19</xref>
               <disp-formula id="df8">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df8"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>Rewriting<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df8">equation (7)</xref>in compact notation, we have<disp-formula id="df9">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df9"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\phi $ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>and Φ are, respectively, the density function and the cumulative distribution function of the standard normal (evaluated at<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\gamma ^{\prime }z_{t}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>) and ρ is the correlation between<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\varepsilon ^{f}_{t}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>and ξ<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>. Note that, in the absence of self‐selection of orders by the traders, ρ would be equal to zero. This allows us to test the null hypothesis that traders do not time their orders.</p>
            <p>We use data on executed floor trades for our analysis.<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df9">Equation (8)</xref>is estimated by maximizing the following likelihood function that takes into account the truncated nature of the data:<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn21">20</xref>
               <disp-formula id="df10">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df10"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>
            </p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn16">
                  <label>15. </label>
                  <p>See Maddala (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf20">1996</xref>) for examples of such applications in finance.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn17">
                  <label>16. </label>
                  <p>There are other possible proxies of a stock’s liquidity, such as price level, value of shares outstanding, etc. In our tests we found these variables to be highly correlated with a stock’s trading volume.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn18">
                  <label>17. </label>
                  <p>The threshold value can be viewed as a constant. A more general interpretation is possible, however. It can be viewed as the cost of waiting to trade later and, hence, as a function of the order characteristics and market conditions at the time of the decision. The model estimates are unaffected by the interpretation.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn19">
                  <label>18. </label>
                  <p>In other words,<disp-formula id="df15">
                        <graphic xlink:href="df15"
                                 mimetype="image"
                                 position="float"
                                 xlink:type="simple"/>
                     </disp-formula>
                  </p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn20">
                  <label>19. </label>
                  <p>See Maddala (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf19">1983</xref>).</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn21">
                  <label>20. </label>
                  <p>For details, see Maddala (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf19">1983</xref>, pp. 266–67).</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <label>IV.</label>
         <title>Results</title>
         <sec id="sc4.1">
            <label>A.</label>
            <title>Characteristics of Trades Executed on the Amex</title>
            <p>
               <xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>presents descriptive statistics for the trades in the sample we have analyzed. Overall, the volume of trades initiated on the floor is 110,489,600, accounting for 23.40% of the total volume. Trading volume initiated on PER accounts for 361,739,540 shares traded, or 76.60% of total volume. In addition to the 23.40% trading volume reported in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">table 1</xref>that is initiated on the floor, there is an additional 10.39% of trading volume in which the trading floor is a passive participant. It is clear that the trading floor is an attractive venue for many non–block trades. Henceforth, we refer to trades initiated on the floor as floor trades and those initiated on PER as PER trades. We classify trades into four categories according to the number of shares transacted at the trade: (i) less than 500 shares, (ii) 500–999 shares, (iii) 1,000–1,499 shares, and (iv) 1,500–9,999 shares.<table-wrap id="tb1" position="float">
                  <label>Table 1</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Sample Statistics: Share Volume, Percent of Volume, Trade Size, and Time between Trades for the Four Trade Size Categories at the American Stock Exchange during October 2001</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb1"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="6" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="4.35pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="24.63pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="21.64pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="14.60pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="13.78pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="6" colname="6" colwidth="11.04pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="top"
                                             morerows="1"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Share Volume</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Less than 500 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">500–999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,000–1,499 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,500–9,999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Total</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3,964,700</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">8,499,700</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4,716,600</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">93,308,600</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">110,489,600</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">58,542,440</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">64,967,400</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">22,765,400</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">215,464,300</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">361,739,540</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">62,507,140</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">73,467,100</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">27,482,000</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">308,772,900</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">472,229,140</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Percent of Total Volume</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Less than 500 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">500–999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,000–1,499 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,500–9,999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Average Order Size</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.84</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1.80</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">19.76</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">23.40</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">12.40</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">13.76</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4.82</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">45.63</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">76.60</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">13.24</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">15.56</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">5.82</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">65.39</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">100.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Trade Size (Shares)</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Less than 500 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">500–999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,000–1,499 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,500–9,999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Average Order Size</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">283.76</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">905.19</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1,358.08</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4,038.46</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2,212.45</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">250.54</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">882.46</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1,346.59</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3,366.31</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">931.85</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">252.42</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">885.03</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1,348.55</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3,544.59</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1,077.82</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Time between Trades −15 and +15 (in Minutes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Less than 500 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">500–999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,000–1,499 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,500–9,999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Average Order Size</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">32.19</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">27.04</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">26.28</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">23.17</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">26.64</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">30.44</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">25.95</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">28.04</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">20.68</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">27.87</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top">All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">30.54</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">26.07</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">27.74</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">21.34</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">27.73</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <p>For trades of fewer than 500 shares, floor trades account for only 3.96 million shares (.84% of total trading volume) and PER trades account for 58.54 million shares (12.40% of total trading volume). The average size of floor trades in this category is 283.76 shares. For PER trades, the average size is slightly smaller at 250.54 shares. As may be seen from the bottom portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">table 1</xref>, the average time spanned by the 30 trades surrounding a typical trade of fewer than 500 shares is 30.54 minutes. For floor trades, this time span is marginally more than the time span for PER trades.</p>
            <p>There are 73.47 million shares traded in the 500–999 trade size category. Floor trades account for 8.50 million shares (1.80% of the total trading volume), while PER trades account for the remaining 64.97 million shares (13.76% of total trading volume). The average size of floor trades is 905.19 shares. For PER trades, the average size is again slightly smaller at 882.46 shares. The average time spanned by the 30 trades surrounding a typical trade of between 500 shares and 999 shares is 26.07 minutes.</p>
            <p>There are only 27.48 million shares traded in the 1,000–1,500 trade size category. Of these, floor trades account for 4.72 million shares (1.00% of total trading volume), while PER trades account for 22.77 million shares (4.82% of total trading volume). As in the other categories, PER trades are smaller‐sized, with an average of 1,346.59 shares as compared to floor trades (1,358.08 shares). The average time spanned by the 30 trades surrounding a typical trade in this category is 27.74 minutes.</p>
            <p>Finally, for the trades between 1,500 and 9,999 shares, floor trades account for 93.31 million shares (19.76% of total trading volume) and PER trades account for 215.46 million shares (45.63% of trading volume). The average size of floor trades of between 1,500 shares and 9,999 shares is 4,038.46 shares. For PER trades, the average size is considerably smaller at 3,366.31 shares. The average time spanned by the 30 trades surrounding a typical trade in this category is only 21.34 minutes.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc4.2">
            <label>B.</label>
            <title>Evidence on Execution Costs</title>
            <p>
               <xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">Table 2</xref>presents our measures of execution costs for a matched sample of floor and PER trades. Using the matching criteria discussed in Section IIIC, we were able to find a matching PER trade for 48,471 floor trades out of a total of 49,940 floor trades (i.e., 97.06%). The matching procedure led to a close match between the trade pairs. Namely, the mean difference in trade execution price between the pairs was 7.04% with a median difference of 5.26%, and the mean difference in trade size between the pairs was 7.09% with a median difference of 2.44%. We present evidence on the following measures of execution cost: the quoted half‐spread, the effective half‐spread, and the realized half‐spread. The trades are classified into four trade size categories: less than 500 shares, 500–999 shares, 1,000–1,499 shares, and 1,500–9,999 shares.<table-wrap id="tb2" position="float">
                  <label>Table 2</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Matched Sample Results, All Trades: Quoted Half‐Spread, Effective Half‐Spread, and Realized Half‐Spread, Reported in Basis Points (bps), for Matched Pairs of Floor‐ and PER‐Initiated Trades Classified by the Four Trade Size Categories at the American Stock Exchange during October 2001</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb2"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="6" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="6" colname="6" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Less than 500 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">500–999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,000–1,499 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,500–9,999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Average</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Quoted half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">17.02</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">16.78</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">16.77</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">15.39</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">16.23</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">18.18</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">18.60</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">19.33</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">16.23</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">17.47</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.16<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.82<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.56<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.84<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.24<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Effective half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">7.26</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">8.08</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">9.38</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">8.47</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">8.11</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">9.69</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">10.97</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">12.16</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">10.04</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">10.27</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.44<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.89<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.78<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.57<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.16<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Realized half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−7.20</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−3.03</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−3.47</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.33</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−3.06</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.51</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3.10</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3.94</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">6.33</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4.43</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−9.71<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−6.13<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−7.41<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−6.67<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−7.49<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
                  <table-wrap-foot>
                     <p>Note.—The quoted half‐spread is defined as<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Quoted}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=\left(\mathrm{Ask}\,-\mathrm{Bid}\,\right)/ \left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right)$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>. The effective half‐spread is defined as<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Effective}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=D_{it}\cdot \left\{\left[P_{0}-\left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right)/ 2\right]/ \left[\left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right)/ 2\right]\right\},$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>where<italic>P</italic>
                        <sub>0</sub>is the transaction price and<italic>D</italic>
                        <sub>
                           <italic>it</italic>
                        </sub>is an indicator variable that is equal to +1 for buyer‐initiated trades and to −1 for seller‐initiated trades. The realized half‐spread for trade<italic>t</italic>for stock<italic>i</italic>is the negative of the logarithmic return from the transaction (with the trade price denoted by<italic>P</italic>
                        <sub>0</sub>) to the mid‐quote at the time of the fifteenth trade after the transaction denoted by<italic>M</italic>
                        <sub>+15</sub>, i.e.,<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Realized}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=D_{it}\cdot \left[\mathrm{ln}\,\left(P_{0}/ M_{+15}\right)\right].$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>The matching is achieved as follows. For each floor trade, we try to locate a matching PER trade. The matching criteria are (1) trades must be in the same stock; (2) trades must be in the same direction, buy or sell; (3) the execution price of the PER trade must be within 20% of the price of the floor trade; and (4) the size of the PER trade must be within 20% of the size of the floor trade.</p>
                     <fn id="tb2fna">
                        <label>**</label>
                        <p>Significant at the 1% level.</p>
                     </fn>
                  </table-wrap-foot>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <p>The top portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">table 2</xref>presents evidence on the quoted half‐spread. Overall, the floor trade sample has an average quoted half‐spread of 16.23 bps as compared to 17.49 bps for the matched PER trade sample. The difference of −1.24 bps is significant at the 1% level of significance. In terms of trade size categories, the quoted half‐spread is significantly lower for floor trades in all of the categories. The difference varies from −.84 bps for large trades to −2.56 bps for the 1,000–1,499 shares category.</p>
            <p>As stated earlier, the quoted half‐spread reflects the true execution cost only if trades occur at the quotes. In the middle portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">table 2</xref>, we present evidence on the effective half‐spread. The effective half‐spread is consistently lower for floor trades across all categories and averages 8.11 bps as compared to 10.27 bps for a matched sample of PER trades. The difference of negative 2.16 bps is significant at the 1% level of significance. It varies from −1.57 bps for large trades to −2.89 bps for the 500–999 shares category. It is significant at the 1% level for all cases.</p>
            <p>In the bottom portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">table 2</xref>, we present evidence on the realized half‐spread. As discussed previously, the realized half‐spread is the most appropriate measure of the compensation realized by a liquidity provider and, hence, the cost to a liquidity seeker. The realized half‐spread is consistently lower for floor trades, averaging −3.06 bps as compared to 4.43 bps for the matched sample of PER trades. The difference of −7.49 bps is significant at the 1% level. This difference is negative and significant for each of the trade size categories. It is interesting to note that the realized spread on floor orders is consistently negative for all trade categories. This suggests that, with effective order handling, trading gains may be realized instead of market impact costs being incurred.</p>
            <p>At this stage, it is worthwhile to ask whether the differences in execution costs across the two venues are economically meaningful. To assess this issue, we can compare the difference in execution costs to the mean quoted half‐spread of 16.85 bps in our matched sample. The differences in realized half‐spreads reported in the bottom portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">table 2</xref>translate to between 36.38% and 57.63% of the mean quoted half‐spread. This suggests that differential execution costs are appreciable and that trading on the more expensive venue can aggregate into major dollar costs for investors. Alternatively stated, bringing orders to the floor can generate savings that justify the higher fees that floor access involves.</p>
            <p>The evidence on realized half‐spreads is consistent with the hypothesis that floor traders time their orders to minimize execution costs by buying (selling) at times of rising (falling) stock prices. This would explain why, in equilibrium, some trades would be submitted to the trading floor in spite of higher access costs (that are not measured in this study). An alternative interpretation of these findings is that floor trades have higher information content. In the next section, we seek to distinguish between these two hypotheses.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc4.3">
            <label>C.</label>
            <title>Evidence on Execution Costs of Trades with Similar Information Content</title>
            <p>We refine our matching technique to control for the information content of trades. Specifically, we expand the matching criteria to include a control for the permanent price impact of a trade, defined as<disp-formula id="df11">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df11"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>
                  <italic>it</italic>
               </sub>is an indicator variable that is equal to +1 for buyer‐initiated trades and is equal to −1 for seller‐initiated trades, and<italic>M</italic>
               <sub>+15</sub>(<italic>M</italic>
               <sub>−15</sub>) refers to the mid‐quote prevailing at the time of the fifteenth trade after (before) trade<italic>t</italic>. The permanent price impact is a measure of the information content of a trade (see, e.g., Kraus and Stoll<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf16">1972</xref>; Madhavan and Cheng<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf21">1997</xref>).</p>
            <p>In addition to the previous matching criteria, we now require the permanent price impact of PER trades to be within 20% of the permanent price impact of floor trades. With this constraint, we obtain matching PER trades for 45,536 floor trades (i.e., 91.18% of all floor trades). The mean difference in the trade execution price between the pairs is 6.79%, with a median difference of 5.69%. The mean difference in trade size between the pairs is 6.70%, with a median difference of 0. Finally, the mean difference in permanent price impact between the pairs is 9.66%, with a median difference of 9.64%.</p>
            <p>We present measures of the execution cost for this reduced sample of matched trades in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">table 3</xref>. The top portion of the table presents the quoted half‐spreads for the matched sample of floor trades and PER trades classified by four trade size categories. The average quoted half‐spread for floor trades is 14.53 bps as compared to 15.38 bps for PER trades. The difference of −0.85 bps is significant at the 1% level. In additon, floor trades have significantly lower quoted half‐spreads for each of the four trade‐size categories.<table-wrap id="tb3" position="float">
                  <label>Table 3</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Matched Sample Results, Trades with Similar Information Content: Quoted Half‐Spread, Effective Half‐Spread, and Realized Half‐Spread, Reported in Basis Points (bps), for Matched Pairs of Floor‐ and PER‐Initiated Trades Classified by the Four Trade Size Categories at the American Stock Exchange during October 2001</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb3"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="6" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="6" colname="6" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Less than 500 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">500–999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,000–1,499 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,500–9,999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Average</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Quoted half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">15.81</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">15.85</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">14.96</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">12.96</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">14.53</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">16.66</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">16.95</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">16.76</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">13.54</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">15.38</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.85<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.10<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.80<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.58<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.85<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Effective half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">6.83</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">7.52</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">7.94</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">7.02</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">7.13</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">8.89</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">10.16</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">10.34</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">8.17</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">8.94</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.06<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.64<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.40<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.15<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.81<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Realized half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−7.14</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−4.61</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−5.81</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.72</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−4.21</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.55</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.53</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.87</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1.17</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.09</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−4.60<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−5.14<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−6.68<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.88<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−4.12<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
                  <table-wrap-foot>
                     <p>Note.—The quoted half‐spread is defined as<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Quoted}\,\,\mathrm{h}\,\mathrm{alf}\,- \mathrm{s}\,\mathrm{pread}\,=\left(\mathrm{Ask}\,-\mathrm{Bid}\,\right)/ \left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right).$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>The effective half‐spread is defined as<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Effective}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=D_{it}\cdot \left\{\left[P_{0}-\left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right)/ 2\right]/ \left[\left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right)/ 2\right]\right\},$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>where<italic>P</italic>
                        <sub>0</sub>is the transaction price and<italic>D</italic>
                        <sub>
                           <italic>it</italic>
                        </sub>is an indicator variable that is equal to +1 for buyer‐initiated trades and −1 for seller‐initiated trades. The realized half‐spread for trade<italic>t</italic>for stock<italic>i</italic>is the negative of the logarithmic return from the transaction (with the trade price denoted by<italic>P</italic>
                        <sub>0</sub>) to the mid‐quote at the time of the fifteenth trade after the transaction denoted by<italic>M</italic>
                        <sub>+15</sub>, i.e.,<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Realized}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=D_{it}\cdot \left[\mathrm{ln}\,\left(P_{0}/ M_{+15}\right)\right].$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>The matching is achieved as follows. For each floor trade, we try to locate a matching PER trade. The matching criteria are (1) trades must be in the same stock; (2) trades must be in the same direction, buy or sell; (3) the execution price of the PER trade must be within 20% of the price of the floor trade; and (4) the size of the PER trade must be within 20% of the size of the floor trade. In addition, the permanent price impact, defined as<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Permanent}\,\,\mathrm{price}\,\,\mathrm{impact}\,=D_{it}\cdot \left[\mathrm{ln}\,\left(M_{+15}/ M_{-15}\right)\right],$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>of the PER trade must be within 20% of that of the floor trade.</p>
                     <fn id="tb3fna">
                        <label>**</label>
                        <p>Significant at the 1% level.</p>
                     </fn>
                  </table-wrap-foot>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <p>Results on effective half‐spreads are presented in the middle portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">table 3</xref>. Similar to the results for the full sample in Section IIIB, effective half‐spreads for floor trades average 7.13 bps as compared to 8.94 bps for the matched sample of PER trades. The difference of −1.81 bps is significant at the 1% level of significance. Also, it is significantly negative for all the trade size categories, varying from −1.15 bps for the large trade category to −2.64 bps points for the 500–999 share category.</p>
            <p>In the bottom portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">table 3</xref>, we present results on the realized half‐spreads. Overall, realized half‐spreads for floor trades average −4.21 bps as compared to −.09 bps for PER trades. The difference of −4.12 bps is significant at the 1% level of significance. The difference is significantly negative for individual trade size categories. Once again, realized spreads are negative for floor trades in all trade size categories, varying from −2.88 bps for large trades to −6.68 bps for the 1,000–1,499 share category. Also, the realized spread is negative for the PER small trades at −2.55 bps.</p>
            <p>Overall, the results for the sample where we control for the permanent price impact are similar to the results for the full sample. We note, however, that, with just one exception, for all three half‐spread measures and four size categories for both floor and PER orders, the half‐spread values are somewhat smaller when we control for the permanent price impact. A higher information content of floor trades could account for this. Nevertheless, all measures of execution costs shown in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">table 3</xref>, including the quoted half‐spread, the effective half‐spread, and the realized half‐spread, are significantly lower for the floor trades. This suggests that we can rule out information differences as the main reason for the lower realized half‐spreads for floor trades. We further test the information content hypothesis by focusing on Standard &amp; Poor's Depository Receipts (SPDRs), a security for which we expect no meaningful informational asymmetries.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc4.4">
            <label>D.</label>
            <title>Evidence on Execution Costs of Trades for SPDRs</title>
            <p>The Amex’s SPDRs are an exchange‐traded fund (ETF) that is potentially subject to little or no information asymmetry.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn22">21</xref>A SPDR represents an ownership interest in the SPDR trust that holds all of the S&amp;P 500 composite stocks, and it is a highly liquid alternative to the S&amp;P index mutual funds. These SPDRs offer us an opportunity to compare execution costs across the floor and PER in a setting that is largely devoid of private information. A finding that execution costs are different across the two venues for SPDR trades would further confirm the hypothesis that these cost differentials are driven by the relative efficiency of order handling in the two venues rather than by informational asymmetries.</p>
            <p>
               <xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">Table 4</xref>presents the evidence on execution costs for SPDRs. The top portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">table 4</xref>presents the quoted half‐spreads for the matched sample of floor trades and PER trades classified by four trade size categories. The average quoted half‐spread for floor trades is 3.93 bps as compared to 4.01 bps for PER trades. The difference of −.08 bps is not significant. Floor trades have lower quoted half‐spreads for the larger trade size categories but a higher quoted spread for the fewer than 500 share trade size category. Even though the differences in these two categories are statistically significant, they do not appear to be economically meaningful.<table-wrap id="tb4" position="float">
                  <label>Table 4</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Matched Sample Results for SPDRs: Quoted Half‐Spread, Effective Half‐Spread, and Realized Half‐Spread, Reported in Basis Points (bps), for Matched Pairs of Floor‐ and PER‐Initiated Trades Classified by the Four Trade Size Categories at the American Stock Exchange during October 2001</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb4"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="6" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="6" colname="6" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Less than 500 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">500–999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,000–1,499 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">1,500–9,999 Shares</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Average</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Quoted half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4.01</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3.91</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3.94</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3.92</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3.93</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">3.90</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4.04</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4.04</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">4.01</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.11<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.09</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.11</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.12<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.08</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Effective half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.13</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.91</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.70</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1.23</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.95</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">1.84</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.15</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.37</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.34</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.23</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.70<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.23<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.66<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.11<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.27<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Realized half‐spread (in bps):</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> Floor</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.43</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.73</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.03</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">.14</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−.09</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> PER</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.11</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.05</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.32</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.02</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">2.06</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"> All trades</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.54<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.78<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.29<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−1.88<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="bottom">−2.16<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">**</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
                  <table-wrap-foot>
                     <p>Note.—The quoted half‐spread is defined as<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Quoted}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=\left(\mathrm{Ask}\,-\mathrm{Bid}\,\right)/ \left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right).$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>The effective half‐spread is defined as<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Effective}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=D_{it}\cdot \left\{\left[P_{0}-\left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right)/ 2\right]/ \left[\left(\mathrm{Bid}\,+\mathrm{Ask}\,\right)/ 2\right]\right\},$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>where<italic>P</italic>
                        <sub>0</sub>is the transaction price and<italic>D</italic>
                        <sub>
                           <italic>it</italic>
                        </sub>is an indicator variable that is equal to +1 for buyer‐initiated trades and −1 for seller‐initiated trades. The realized half‐spread for trade<italic>t</italic>for stock<italic>i</italic>is the negative of the logarithmic return from the transaction (with the trade price denoted by<italic>P</italic>
                        <sub>0</sub>) to the mid‐quote at the time of the fifteenth trade after the transaction denoted by<italic>M</italic>
                        <sub>+15</sub>, i.e.,<inline-formula>
                           <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{Realized}\,\,\mathrm{half}\,- \mathrm{spread}\,=D_{it}\cdot \left[\mathrm{ln}\,\left(P_{0}/ M_{+15}\right)\right].$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                        </inline-formula>The matching is achieved as follows. For each floor trade, we try to locate a matching PER trade. The matching criteria are (1) trades must be in the same direction, buy or sell; (2) the execution price of the PER trade must be within 20% of the price of the floor trade; and (3) the size of the OER must be within 20% of the size of the floor trade.</p>
                     <fn id="tb4fna">
                        <label>**</label>
                        <p>Significant at the 1% level.</p>
                     </fn>
                  </table-wrap-foot>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <p>Results on effective half‐spreads are presented in the middle portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">table 4</xref>. Effective half‐spreads for floor trades average .95 bps as compared to 2.23 bps for the matched sample of PER trades. The difference of −1.27 bps is significant at the 1% level. Also, it is significantly negative for each of the individual trade size categories.</p>
            <p>In the bottom portion of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">table 4</xref>, we present results on the realized half‐spreads. Overall, realized half‐spreads for floor trades average −.09 bps as compared to 2.06 bps for PER trades. The difference of −2.16 bps is negative and significant at the 1% level. Also, the difference is consistently negative and significant at the 1% level across all trade size categories. To benchmark these results, note that the mean quoted half‐spread in our matched sample is 3.97 bps. Hence, the differences in realized half‐spreads that we report in this bottom portion of the table range from 47.36% to 70.03% of the mean quoted half‐spread.</p>
            <p>In contrast to our full sample of stocks, the quoted half‐spreads and effective half‐spreads for SPDRs are substantially smaller across the board. This is also true for the realized half‐spread for SPDR PER trades (though not for floor trades). This finding is consistent with the absence of any meaningful informational asymmetries for SPDRs. Despite the absence of information asymmetries, we observe differences between the execution costs of floor and PER trades reported in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">table 4</xref>that are consistent with our earlier findings. This strongly suggests that the trading floor offers the advantage of lower execution costs through improved order handling.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn22">
                  <label>21. </label>
                  <p>The SPDRs now also trade in appreciable volume on the NYSE, ARCHIPELAGO, and INET.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc4.5">
            <label>E.</label>
            <title>Evidence on Determinants of Order Arrival on Floor versus PER</title>
            <p>We present below the probit estimates based on<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df1">equation (1)</xref>(<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\chi ^{2}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>statistics are in parentheses):<disp-formula id="df12">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df12"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>
            </p>
            <p>The coefficients on the three order size indicator variables are all significantly negative, indicating that larger‐sized orders have a lower probability of being executed on PER and, therefore, a greater probability of execution on the floor. The coefficient on the variable Imb<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is significantly negative, suggesting that, as own‐side order imbalance increases, there is a lower probability of a PER trade and, correspondingly, a higher probability of a floor‐based trade. The coefficient on the variable Preret<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is significantly positive, indicating that a PER trade is more likely following a large pretrade price change. The findings on Imb<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>and Preret<sub>t</sub>imply that floor traders observe and react to order imbalance and that floor trades are more likely when there is more interest on the side of the initiating trade. At the same time, floor traders appear to be relatively patient and to avoid trading after large pretrade price changes. Later on, we show that this behavior is consistent with minimizing execution costs. Conversely, PER traders appear more apt to chase price changes (i.e., to engage in momentum trading), which may explain our earlier findings of higher realized half‐spreads for PER trades.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn23">22</xref>
            </p>
            <p>The morning time of day indicator variable (<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>1<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>) has a negative but insignificant coefficient, and the late afternoon time of day indicator variable (<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>2<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>) has a significantly negative coefficient. This indicates that, relative to mid‐day, floor trades are more likely in the morning and afternoon. There are two factors at play here: (1) there is evidence that the markets are more liquid during the morning and afternoon hours than during midday (see, e.g., Jain and Joh<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf13">1988</xref>), and (2) floor traders who may be willing to be patient earlier in the trading day are more apt to step forth and trade as the closing bell approaches so as to avoid carrying an open position into the overnight period.</p>
            <p>Finally, the coefficient on average trading volume is significantly positive, implying that the probability of a PER trade increases with the average trading volume of the stock (that is a measure of the stock’s liquidity). Conversely, for a given order size, a less liquid stock that requires more special order handling is more likely to be traded via the floor.</p>
            <p>In sum, the probit estimates suggest that the floor trading mechanism is preferred for larger‐sized trades, on occasions when the book is thicker on the side of the trade initiating order (but not following a recent large price change), during the late afternoon hours, and for less liquid stocks.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn23">
                  <label>22. </label>
                  <p>Keim and Madhavan (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf14">1995</xref>) show that traders following momentum‐based strategies trade more aggressively and incur higher trading costs relative to value traders.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc4.6">
            <label>F.</label>
            <title>Evidence on Determinants of Execution Costs</title>
            <p>The estimates of the trade initiation model given by<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df9">equation (8)</xref>are presented below:<disp-formula id="df13">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df13"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<disp-formula id="df14">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df14"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>and<sup>+</sup>indicates significance at the 10% level, * indicates significance at the 5% level, and ** indicates significance at the 1% level</p>
            <p>In<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df13">equation (11)</xref>, the coefficients corresponding to the second through the fourth terms (corresponding to the order‐size indicator variables<italic>q</italic>
               <sub>1<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>,<italic>q</italic>
               <sub>2<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>, and<italic>q</italic>
               <sub>3<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>) are significantly positive, which indicates that the expected realized half‐spread increases with order size. In contrast, the coefficient of Imb<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>in<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df13">equation (11)</xref>is significantly negative, implying that the expected realized half‐spread decreases with order imbalance. The coefficient for Preret<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>in<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df13">equation (11)</xref>is significantly positive, implying that the expected realized half‐spread increases following recent price changes. The results on Imb<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>and Preret<sub>
                  <italic>t</italic>
               </sub>, in conjunction with our earlier probit results, suggest strategic behavior on the part of floor traders who become more aggressive in response to a thickening of the book on their own side and who become patient following large pretrade price changes.</p>
            <p>The coefficient of the morning dummy variable<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>1<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>in<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df13">equation (11)</xref>is significantly negative, implying that the expected realized half‐spread is low in the morning hours, at a time when we expect market liquidity to be higher. The coefficient of the afternoon dummy variable<italic>D</italic>
               <sub>2<italic>t</italic>
               </sub>is positive but insignificant. Given our earlier probit results that the probability of floor‐initiated trades is higher in the afternoons, it appears that, as the day wears on, the traders’ patience wears thin and the desire to complete their orders increases. Finally, the coefficient of average trading volume is positive and significant, which would suggest that the expected cost of trading via the floor is higher for larger volume stocks and that the floor is a relatively more attractive venue for less liquid stocks. The last term of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df13">equation (11)</xref>is commonly referred to as the inverse Mills ratio. The coefficient of this term is insignificant, which indicates that selectivity bias may be absent in the data.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn24">23</xref>
            </p>
            <p>Similarly, the results in<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df14">equation (12)</xref>are economically insightful. The equation presents the relationship between the probability of a floor trade occurring (as opposed to a trade being withheld) and order size, order imbalance, recent price change, time of day, and average trading volume for the stock. This probability increases with order size except for the small share category, for which the coefficient is insignificant. The probability of a floor trade increases with order imbalance as well. With respect to price changes, the results are insignificant. With respect to the time of day, floor trades are more likely in the morning hours. The results are insignificant with respect to the late afternoon. The results are consistent with more liquidity being available in the morning. Finally, the probability of a floor trade increases with average trading volume, indicating that floor traders are more inclined to trade a stock with higher average trading volume quickly than they are to trade a stock with lower average trading volume. As one would expect, more strategic behavior is required for stocks with lower average trading volume.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn24">
                  <label>23. </label>
                  <p>Following this finding, we estimated<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">eq. (2)</xref>using OLS, and the sign and significance of the explanatory variables were virtually identical to those in<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df13">eq. (11)</xref>.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <label>V.</label>
         <title>Conclusion</title>
         <p>For an expanding array of equity markets, including Toronto, Paris, Tokyo, Australia, Madrid, Stockholm, Switzerland, Frankfurt, and London, floorless electronic trading systems have been the wave of the future. In this article, we have focused on the value of a trading floor. Our analysis of non–block trades on the Amex, a floor‐based market, suggests that the floor environment adds value through improved order handling. Consistent with this, we find that 23.40% of the trading volume in our sample is initiated on the trading floor and that, on the passive side, the floor participates in an additional 10.39% of the trading volume.</p>
         <p>Using a matched‐pair technique, we find that floor broker–timed order handling generally results in lower execution costs. Overall, trades handled by floor brokers have a significantly smaller realized half‐spread than do PER trades (−3.06 bps vs. 4.43 bps). This difference of 7.49 bps is equivalent to a savings of 3.94 cents per share for an average priced stock on the Amex.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn25">24</xref>Given the aggregate floor trading volume of 110,489,600 shares in October 2001, this translates to a total savings of $4.36 million for the month. In addition, floor trades have a lower effective half‐spread as compared to PER trades (8.11 bps vs. 10.27 bps). The quoted half‐spread is also lower when floor orders initiate trades than when PER orders initiate trades (16.23 bps vs. 17.47 bps).</p>
         <p>Our finding of a lower realized spread for floor trades is robust to controls for the information content of a trade. Specifically, we examine execution costs for a restricted sample that further controls for the permanent price effect. We continue to find that execution costs are lower on the trading floor.</p>
         <p>Our evidence on SPDRs, a security that is not subject to information asymmetries, further reinforces the above findings. We find that execution costs continue to be lower on the floor despite absence of information differentials for matched trades compared across the two venues. Our findings on SPDRs strongly suggest that the trading floor offers the advantage of reduced execution costs through improved order handling.</p>
         <p>We have examined the determinants of trade initiation on the floor versus PER. Our findings are that the floor trading mechanism is preferred for larger sized trades, on occasions when the order flow is in the direction of the initiating trade (but not following a recent large price change), during morning and late afternoon hours, and for less liquid stocks. Our findings on the determinants of execution costs on the trading floor are that the execution costs are lower for trades initiated in the direction of the order flow but higher for trades that are preceded by large price changes.</p>
         <p>Together, these findings suggest that floor traders exhibit strategic behavior, becoming more aggressive in response to a thickening of the book on their own side and becoming more patient following large pretrade price changes. In contrast, PER traders are more apt to chase recent price changes. This helps explain why floor orders incur lower (and even negative) execution costs, and it sheds light on the role of floor brokers and the value of intermediation in an equity market.</p>
         <p>It is important to point out, however, that, to some extent at least, the functions of a floor trader can be carried out in an electronic environment and that the strategic timing of trades does not necessarily require verbal order entry by human intermediaries. A growing number of institutional investors now have DOT machines and smart order handling systems that give them some ability to work their orders strategically from their upstairs desks. The ECNs show orders away from the best bid and offer (as the New York Stock Exchange now does through its Open Book), and some of the ECNs have reserve book functionality. While this may not yet be enough for buyside traders working their own smart limit orders to compete with floor traders handling not held orders,<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn26">25</xref>with improvements in the technology for order routing and handling and the development of superior market design, one might expect the future to lie with electronic trading.</p>
         <p>Observing that trading costs can be controlled by proper trade initiation underscores the need to design an environment that best presents the relevant information on market conditions to participants. Our analysis suggests a standard that the electronic platforms must meet, especially with regard to institutional order flow.</p>
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn25">
               <label>24. </label>
               <p>In this context, we define the average price as the trade‐weighted transaction price in our sample.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn26">
               <label>25. </label>
               <p>For further discussion of this point, see Keim and Madhavan (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf15">1996</xref>).</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </sec>
   </body>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="rf1">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Admati, Anat R., and Paul Pfleiderer. 1988. A theory of intraday patterns: Volume and price variability.<italic>Review of Financial Studies</italic>1, no. 1:3–40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf2">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Amihud, Yakov, and Haim Mendelson. 1986. Asset pricing and the bid‐ask spread.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>17, no. 2:223–49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf3">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Amihud, Yakov, Haim Mendelson, and Beni Lauterbach. 1997. Market microstructure and securities values: Evidence from the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>45, no. 3:365–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf4">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Bessembinder, Hendrik, and Herbert M. Kaufman. 1997. A cross‐exchange comparison of execution costs and information flow for NYSE‐listed stocks.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>46, no. 3:293–319.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf5">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Brennan, Michael, and Avanidhar Subrahmanyam. 1996. Market microstructure and asset pricing: On the compensation for illiquidity in stock returns.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>41, no. 3:441–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf6">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Conrad, Jennifer, Kevin M. Johnson, and Sunil Wahal. 2001. Alternative trading systems. Working paper, Emory University, Finance Department.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf7">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Easley, David, and Maureen O’Hara. 1987. Price, trade size, and information in securities markets.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>19, no. 1:69–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf8">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Glosten, Lawrence, and Lawrence Harris. 1988. Estimating the components of the bid/ask spread.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>21, no. 1:123–42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf9">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Hasbrouck, Joel. 1988. Trades, quotes, inventories, and information.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>22, no. 2:229–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf10">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Huang, Roger D., and Hans R. Stoll. 1994. Market microstructure and stock return predictions: A paired comparison of execution costs on NASDAQ and the NYSE.<italic>Review of Financial Studies</italic>7, no. 1:179–213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf11">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">———. 1996. Dealer versus auction markets: A paired comparison of execution costs on NASDAQ and the NYSE.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>41, no. 3:313–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf12">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">———. 1997. The components of the bid‐ask spread: A general approach.<italic>Review of Financial Studies</italic>10, no. 4:995–1034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf13">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Jain, Prem, and Gun‐Joh Gun‐Ho. 1988. The dependence between hourly prices and trading volume.<italic>Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis</italic>23, no. 3:269–84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf14">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Keim, Donald B., and Ananth Madhavan. 1995. The anatomy of the trading process.<italic>Journal of Financial Economics</italic>37, no. 3:391–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf15">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">———. 1996. The upstairs market for large‐block transactions: Analysis and measurement of price effects.<italic>Review of Financial Studies</italic>9, no. 1:1–36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf16">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Kraus, Alan, and Hans Stoll. 1972. Price impacts of block trading on the New York Stock Exchange.<italic>Journal of Finance</italic>27, no. 3:569–88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf17">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Kyle, Albert S. 1985. Continuous auctions and insider trading.<italic>Econometrica</italic>53, no. 6:1315–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf18">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Lee, Charles, and Mark Ready. 1991. Inferring trade direction from intraday data.<italic>Journal of Finance</italic>46, no. 3:733–46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf19">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Maddala, Gangadharrao S. 1983.<italic>Limited dependent and qualitative variables in econometrics</italic>. New York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf20">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">———. 1996. Applications of the limited dependent variable models in finance. In<italic>Handbook of statistics</italic>, vol. 14, ed. Gangadharrao S. Maddala and Calyampudi R. Rao, pp. 553–66. Amsterdam: Elsevier/North Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf21">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Madhavan, Ananth, and Minder Cheng. 1997. In search of liquidity: Block trades in the upstairs and downstairs markets.<italic>Review of Financial Studies</italic>10, no. 1:175–204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf22">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Madhavan, Ananth, Matthew Richardson, and Mark Roomans. 1997. Why do security prices change? A transaction‐level analysis of NYSE stocks.<italic>Review of Financial Studies</italic>10, no. 4:1035–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf23">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Pagano, Marco, and Ailsa Röell. 1992. Auction and dealership markets: What is the difference?<italic>European Economic Review</italic>36, nos. 2–3:613–23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf24">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Sofianos, George, and Ingrid M. Werner. 1997. The trades of NYSE floor brokers. Working paper, New York Stock Exchange, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf25">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Venkataraman, Kumar. 2001. Automated versus floor trading: An analysis of execution costs on the Paris and New York exchanges.<italic>Journal of Finance</italic>56, no. 4:1445–85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
