<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277581</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of Performance and Emission Characteristics of a Heavy Duty Natural Gas Engine Operated with Pre-Chamber Spark Plug and Dilution with Excess Air and EGR</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shah</surname>
                  <given-names>Ashish</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tunestal</surname>
                  <given-names>Per</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Bengt</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Lund University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1790</fpage>
         <lpage>1801</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277581"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This article deals with application of turbulent jet ignition technique to heavy duty multi-cylinder natural gas engine for mobile application. Pre-chamber spark plugs are identified as a promising means of achieving turbulent jet ignition as they require minimal engine modification with respect to component packaging in cylinder head and the ignition system. Detailed experiments were performed with a 6 cylinder 9.4 liter turbo-charged engine equipped with multi-point gas injection system to compare performance and emissions characteristics of operation with pre-chamber and conventional spark plug. The results indicate that ignition capability is significantly enhanced as flame development angle and combustion duration are reduced by upto 30 % compared to those with conventional spark plugs at certain operating points. Maximum possible dilution (limited by combustion stability index, Coefficient of Variation (COV) of Gross Indicated Mean Effective Pressure (IMEPg)) with excess air and EGR were investigated experimentally at engine speed of 1500 rpm and 5, 12 and 18 bar IMEPg operating load and results indicate that the lean limit is extended by 0.8-1 Lambda unit and 5-8% EGR rate units. It was also observed that pre-chamber spark plugs cause charge pre-ignition at loads exceeding 10-12 bar IMEPg. To avoid this, the minimum amount of dilution, with excess air and then EGR, which is required to operate above 10 bar IMEPg was estimated experimentally. Finally, to compare performance and emission characteristics of operation with these two ignition techniques, the engine was tested on an ESC-like (European Stationary Cycle) 12 mode cycle. Results indicated marginal reduction in cycle averaged NOx emissions with maximum excess air dilution and about 50% reduction with maximum EGR dilution, whereas CO and HC emissions increased. Other operating characteristics like the flame development angle, combustion duration, brake efficiency etc. are also compared for the tested operating range of the test engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dale, J.D., Checkel, M.D., Smy, P.R., Application of high energy ignition systems to engines, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, Volume 23, Issues 5-6, 1997, Pages 379-398, ISSN 0360-1285, 10.1016/S0360-1285(97)00011-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dale, J., Smy, P., and Clements, R., “Laser Ignited Internal Combustion Engine - An Experimental Study,” SAE Technical Paper 780329, 1978, doi:10.4271/780329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McMillian, M., Richardson, S., Woodruff, S., and McIntyre, D., “Laser- Spark Ignition Testing in a Natural Gas-Fueled Single-Cylinder Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0980, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, GA. Combustion in gas fueled compression: ignition engines of the dual fuel type. J Eng Gas Turb Power 2003; 125:827-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karim, GA. A review of combustion processes in the dual fuel enginethe gas diesel engine. Prog Energy Combust 1980; 6:277-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Schock, H., and Attard, W., “A Review of Pre-Chamber Initiated Jet Ignition Combustion Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2263, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Volvo Trucks Declares Itself First Manufacturer of Efficient Dual-Fuel Euro V Engine”, NGV Global News December 15, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Einewall, P. and Johansson, B., “Combustion Chambers for Supercharged Natural Gas Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 970221, 1997, doi:10.4271/970221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, International edition, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gatowski, J., Balles, E., Chun, K., Nelson, F. et al., “Heat Release Analysis of Engine Pressure Data,” SAE Technical Paper 841359, 1984, doi:10.4271/841359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., “A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi:10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, A., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., “Applicability of Ionization Current Sensing Technique with Plasma Jet Ignition Using Pre-Chamber Spark Plug in a Heavy Duty Natural Gas Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1632, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weng, V., Gindele, J., Töpfer, G., Spicher, U. et al., “Investigation of the Bowl-Prechamber-Ignition (BPI) Concept in a Direct Injection Gasoline Engine at Part Load,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3658, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
