<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794422</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Fungibility, Hassles, and Ordeals in Social Insurance Programs</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Who Is Screened Out? Application Costs and the Targeting of Disability Programs</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Deshpande</surname>
                  <given-names>Manasi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Yue</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>43</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794422"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We study the effect of application costs on the number and composition of disability applicants and recipients using the closings of Social Security Administration field offices, which provide assistance with filing disability applications. Using administrative data from the Social Security Administration, we find that field office closings reduce the number of disability allowances by 13 percent in areas surrounding the closed office and by 10 percent in areas surrounding neighboring offices, with effects persistent for at least two years after a closing. The closings disproportionately reduce applications among potential applicants from lower socioeconomic backgrounds and among those with moderately severe conditions. Our estimates suggest that about three-quarters of the reduction in disability applications in areas around closed field offices is attributable to increased congestion at neighboring offices and the remaining amount to increased travel times and costs of information gathering.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Akerlof, George A., “The Economics of "Tagging" as Applied to the Optimal Income Tax, Welfare Programs, and Manpower Planning,” American Economic Review, 1978, 68 (1), 8–19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alatas, Vivi, Abhijit Banerjee, Rema Hanna, Benjamin A Olken, Ririn Purnamasari, and Matthew Wai-Poi, “Self-Targeting: Evidence from a Field Experiment in Indonesia,” Journal of Political Economy, 2016, 124 (2), 371–427.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Autor, David H., Nicole Maestas, Kathleen Mullen, and Alexander Strand, “Does Delay Cause Decay? The Effect of Administrative Decision Time on the Labor Force Participation and Earnings of Disability Applicants,” 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bertrand, Marianne, Erzo F.P. Luttmer, and Sendhil Mullainathan, “Network Effects and Welfare Cultures,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2000, 115 (3), 1019–1055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bertrand, Marianne, Sendhil Mullainathan, and Eldar Shafir, “A Behavioral-Economics View of Poverty,” American Economic Review: Papers &amp; Proceedings, 2004, 94 (2), 419–423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Besley, Timothy and Stephen Coate, “Workfare versus Welfare: Incentive Arguments for Work Requirements in Poverty-Alleviation Programs,” American Economic Review, 1992, 82 (1), 249-261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bettinger, E. P., B. Terry Long, P. Oreopoulos, and L. Sanbonmatsu, “The Role of Application Assistance and Information in College Decisions: Results from the H&amp;R Block FAFSA Experiment,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2012, pp. 1205–1242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bhargava, Saurabh and Dayanand Manoli, “Psychological Frictions and the Incomplete Take-Up of Social Benefits: Evidence from an IRS Field Experiment,” American Economic Review, 2015, 105 (11), 3489–3529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Black, Dan, Kermit Daniel, and Seth Sanders, “The Impact of Economic Conditions on Participation in Disability Programs: Evidence from the Coal Boom and Bust,” American Economic Review, 2002, 92 (1), 27–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Cohen, Jessica, Pascaline Dupas, and Simone Schaner, “Price Subsidies, Diagnostic Tests, and Targeting of Malaria Treatment: Evidence from a Randomized Controlled Trial,” American Economic Review, 2015, 105 (2), 609–645.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Currie, Janet, “The Take Up of Social Benefits,” 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Dahl, Gordon B, Andreas Kostol, and Magne Mogstad, “Family Welfare Cultures,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2014, 129 (4), 1711–1752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Duggan, Mark and Scott A Imberman, “Why Are the Disability Rolls Skyrocketing? The Contribution of Population Characteristics, Economic Conditions, and Program Generosity,” in “Health at Older Ages: The Causes and Consequences of Declining Disability among the Elderly” number January 2009, pp. 337–379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Ebenstein, Avraham and Kevin Stange, “Does Inconvenience Explain Low Take-Up? Evidence from Unemployment Insurance,” Journal of Policy Analysis and Management, 2010, 29 (1), 111-136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Fadlon, Itzik and Torben Heien Nielsen, “Household Responses to Severe Health Shocks and the Design of Social Insurance,” 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Finkelstein, Amy, Nathaniel Hendren, and Erzo F.P. Luttmer, “The Value of Medicaid: Welfare Analysis of Public Health Insurance Expansions,” 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Golosov, Mikhail and Aleh Tsyvinski, “Designing Optimal Disability Insurance: A Case for Asset Testing,” Journal of Political Economy, 2006, 114 (2), 257–279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Guryan, Jonathan, “Desegregation and Black Dropout Rates,” American Economic Review, 2004, 94 (4), 919–943.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Kopczuk, Wojciech and Cristian Pop-Eleches, “Electronic Filing, Tax Preparers and Participation in the Earned Income Tax Credit,” Journal of Public Economics, 2007, 91 (7-8), 1351–1367.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Madrian, Brigitte C. and Dennis F. Shea, “The Power of Suggestion: Inertia in 401(k) Participation and Savings Behavior,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2001, CXVI (4), 1149–1187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Maestas, Nicole, Kathleen J Mullen, and Alexander Strand, “Does Disability Insurance Receipt Discourage Work? Using Examiner Assignment to Estimate Causal Effects,” American Economic Review, 2013, 103 (5), 1797–1829.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Meyer, Bruce D. and Wallace K.C. Mok, “Disability, Earnings, Income, and Consumption,” 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Nichols, Albert L. and Richard J. Zeckhauser, “Targeting Transfers through Restrictions on Recipients,” American Economic Review, 1982, 72 (2), 372–377.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Nichols, D., E Smolensky, and T N Tideman, “Discrimination by Waiting Time in Merit Goods,” American Economic Review, 1971, 61 (3), 312–323.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Rossin-Slater, Maya, “WIC in Your Neighborhood: New Evidence on the Impacts of Geographic Access to Clinics,” Journal of Public Economics, 2013, 102 (March), 51–69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Timing of Field Office Closings</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Raw Plots of Number of Applications in Control and Treatment ZIPs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Effect of Closings on Number of Disability Applications and Allowances</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Effect of Closings on Number of Disability Applications, by Subgroup</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Robustness: Event Study Specifications, with and without Unaffected ZIPs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Effect of Closings on Measures of Field Office Congestion</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Summary Statistics of Closing, Neighboring, and Unaffected ZIP Codes in Sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Estimates of the Effect of Closings on Disability Applications</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Estimates of the Effect of Closings on Disability Allowances</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Estimates of the Effect of Closings on Types of Application Costs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Estimates of the Effect of Closings on Log Applications, by Education and Health Subgroup</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Costs and Benefits of Field Office Closings</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
