<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">jfinance</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100221</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00221082</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15406261</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">27735172</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Driven to Distraction: Extraneous Events and Underreaction to Earnings News</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
                  <surname>Hirshleifer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Sonya Seongyeon</given-names>
                  <surname>Lim</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Siew Hong</given-names>
                  <surname>Teoh</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date>
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">64</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">5</issue>
         <issue-id>i27735160</issue-id>
         <fpage>2289</fpage>
         <lpage>2325</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2009 The American Finance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/27735172"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Recent studies propose that limited investor attention causes market underreactions. This paper directly tests this explanation by measuring the information load faced by investors. The "investor distraction hypothesis" holds that extraneous news inhibits market reactions to relevant news. We find that the immediate price and volume reaction to a firm's earnings surprise is much weaker, and post-announcement drift much stronger, when a greater number of same-day earnings announcements are made by other firms. We evaluate the economic importance of distraction effects through a trading strategy, which yields substantial alphas. Industry-unrelated news and large earnings surprises have a stronger distracting effect.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group>
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d105e167a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e174" publication-type="other">
Brennan, Jegadeesh, and Swaminathan (1993)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e180" publication-type="other">
Cohen and Frazzini (2008)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e186" publication-type="other">
Hong,
Lim, and Stein (2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e196" publication-type="other">
Hong, Torous, and Valkanov (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e202" publication-type="other">
Hou (2007)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e208" publication-type="other">
Hou and Moskowitz
(2005)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d105e218a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e225" publication-type="other">
Kaniel, Saar, and Titman (2008)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d105e232a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e239" publication-type="other">
http://mba.tuck.dartmouth.edu/pages/faculty/ken.french/data_library.html</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d105e246a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e253" publication-type="other">
http://www.afajof.org/supplements.asp.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d105e261a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e268" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer et al. (2008)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d105e284a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e288" publication-type="other">
Bagnoli, Mark, Michael B. Clement, and Susan G. Watts, 2005, Around-the-clock media coverage
and the timing of earnings announcements, Working paper, Purdue University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e298a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e304" publication-type="other">
Baker, A. G., Pierre Mercier, Frederic Valleettourangeau, Robert Frank, and Maria Pan, 1993,
Selective associations and causality judgments—Presence of a strong causal factor may reduce
judgements of a weaker one, Journal of Experimental Psychology—Learning, Memory and
Cognition 19, 414–432.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e320a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e324" publication-type="other">
Barber, Brad, and Terrance Odean, 2000, Trading is hazardous to your wealth: The common stock
investment performance of individual investors, Journal of Finance 55, 773–806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e334a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e338" publication-type="other">
Barber, Brad, and Terrance Odean, 2008, All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on
the buying behavior of individual and institutional investors, Review of Financial Studies 21,
785–818.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e352a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e356" publication-type="other">
Basu, Sudipta, 1997, The conservatism principle and the asymmetric timeliness of earnings, Jour-
nal of Accounting and Economics 24, 3–37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e366a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e370" publication-type="other">
Bernard, Victor L., and Jacob K. Thomas, 1989, Post-earnings-announcement drift: Delayed price
response or risk premium? Journal of Accounting Research 27, (Supplement), 1–48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e380a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e384" publication-type="other">
Brennan, Michael J., Narasimhan Jegadeesh, and Bhaskaran Swaminathan, 1993, Investment
analysis and the adjustment of stock prices to common information, Review of Financial Studies
6, 799–824.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e397a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e401" publication-type="other">
Brenner, Lyle A., Derek J. Koehler, and Amos Tversky, 1996, On the evaluation of one-sided evi-
dence, Journal of Behavioral Decision Making 9, 59–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e411a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e415" publication-type="other">
Broadbent, Donald E., 1958, Perception and Communication (Pergamon Press, New York, NY).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e422a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e426" publication-type="other">
Busemeyer, Jerome R., In Jae Myung, and Mark A. McDaniel, 1993, Cue competition effects—
Empirical tests of adaptive network learning models, Psychological Science 4, 190–195.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e437a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e441" publication-type="other">
Chambers, Anne E., and Stephen H. Penman, 1984, Timeliness of reporting and the stock price
reaction to earnings announcements, Journal of Accounting Research 22, 21–47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e451a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e455" publication-type="other">
Cherry, E. Colin, 1953, Some experiments on the recognition of speech, with one and two ears,
Journal of the Acoustical Society of America 25, 975–979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e465a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e469" publication-type="other">
Cohen, Lauren, and Andrea Frazzini, 2008, Economic links and predictable returns, Journal of
Finance 63, 1977–2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e479a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e483" publication-type="other">
Coval, Joshua D., and Tyler Shumway, 2005, Do behavioral biases affect prices? Journal of Finance
61, 1–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e493a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e497" publication-type="other">
Damodaran, Aswath, 1989, The weekend effect in information: A study of earnings and dividend
announcements, Review of Financial Studies 4, 607–623.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e507a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e511" publication-type="other">
DeGeorge, Francois, Jayendu Patel, and Richard Zeckhauser, 1999, Earnings management to ex-
ceed thresholds, Journal of Business 72, 1–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e522a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e526" publication-type="other">
DellaVigna, Stefano, and Joshua M. Pollet, 2007, Demographics and industry returns, American
Economic Review 97, 1167–1702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e536a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e540" publication-type="other">
DellaVigna, Stefano, and Joshua M. Pollet, 2009, Investor inattention and Friday earnings an-
nouncements, Journal of Finance 64, 709–749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e550a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e554" publication-type="other">
Desai, Hemang, and Prem C. Jain, 1997, Long-run common stock returns following stock splits and
reverse splits, Journal of Business 70, 409–434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e564a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e568" publication-type="other">
Dichev, Ilia, and Joseph Piotroski, 2001, The long-run stock returns following bond ratings changes,
Journal of Finance 56, 173–203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e578a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e582" publication-type="other">
Francis, Jennifer, Donald Pagach, and Jens Stephan, 1992, The stock market response to earnings
announcements released during trading versus nontrading periods, Journal of Accounting
Research 30, 165–184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e595a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e599" publication-type="other">
Frazzini, Andrea, 2006, The disposition effect and underreaction to news, Journal of Finance 61,
2017–2046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e610a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e614" publication-type="other">
Grossman, Sanford J., and Joseph E. Stiglitz, 1976, Information and competitive price systems,
American Economic Review 66, 246–253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e624a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e628" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, David, and Siew Hong Teoh, 2003, Limited attention, information disclosure, and fi-
nancial reporting, Journal of Accounting and Economics 36, 337–386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e638a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e642" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, David, and Siew Hong Teoh, 2005, Limited investor attention and stock market mis-
reactions to accounting information, Working paper, Ohio State University</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e652a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e656" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, David, James Myers, Linda Myers, and Siew Hong Teoh, 2008, Do individual investors
drive post-earnings announcement drift? Direct evidence from personal trades, Accounting
Review 83, 1521–1550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e669a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e673" publication-type="other">
Ho, Thomas, and Roni Michaely, 1988, Information quality and market efficiency, Journal of Fi-
nancial and Quantitative Analysis 5, 357–386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e683a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e687" publication-type="other">
Hong, Harrison, Terence Lim, and Jeremy Stein, 2000, Bad news travels slowly: Size, analyst
coverage and the profitability of momentum strategies, Journal of Finance 55, 265–295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e698a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e702" publication-type="other">
Hong, Harrison, Walter Torous, and Rossen Valkanov, 2007, Do industries lead stock markets?
Journal of Financial Economics 83, 367–396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e712a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e716" publication-type="other">
Hou, Kewei, 2007, Industry information diffusion and the lead-lag effect in stock returns, Review
of Financial Studies 20, 1113–1138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e726a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e730" publication-type="other">
Hou, Kewei, and Tobias Moskowitz, 2005, Market frictions, price delay, and the cross-section of
expected returns, Review of Financial Studies 18, 981–1020.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e740a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e744" publication-type="other">
Hou, Kewei, Lin Peng, and Wei Xiong, 2008, A tale of two anomalies: The implication of investor
attention for price and earnings momentum, Working paper, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e754a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e758" publication-type="other">
Huberman, Gur, and Tomer Regev, 2001, Contagious speculation and a cure for cancer, Journal of
Finance 56, 387–396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e768a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e772" publication-type="other">
Ikenberry, David, Josef Lakonishok, and Theo Vermaelen, 1995, Market underreaction to open
market share repurchases, Journal of Financial Economics 39, 181–208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e783a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e787" publication-type="other">
James, William, 1890, The Principles of Psychology, vol. 1 (Henry Holt, New York), 403–404.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e794a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e798" publication-type="other">
Jegadeesh, Narasimhan, and Sheridan Titman, 1993, Returns to buying winners and selling losers:
Implications for stock market efficiency, Journal of Finance 48, 65–91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e808a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e812" publication-type="other">
Kaniel, Ron, Gideon Saar, and Sheridan Titman, 2008, Individual investor trading and stock re-
turns, Journal of Finance 63, 273–310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e822a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e826" publication-type="other">
Klibanoff, Peter, Owen Lamont, and Thierry A. Wizman, 1998, Investor reaction to salient news
in closed-end country funds, Journal of Finance 53, 673–699.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e836a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e840" publication-type="other">
Kothari, S. P., 2001, Capital market research in accounting, Journal of Accounting and Economics
31, 105–231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e850a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e854" publication-type="other">
Kruschke, John K., and Mark K. Johansen, 1999, A model of probabilistic category learning, Journal
of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition 25, 1083–1119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e865a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e869" publication-type="other">
Loughran, Tim, and Jay Ritter, 1995, The new issues puzzle, Journal of Finance 50, 23–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e876a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e880" publication-type="other">
McLeod, Peter, 1977, Parallel processing and the psychological refractory period, Acta Psychologica
41, 381–391.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e890a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e894" publication-type="other">
Moray, Neville, 1959, Attention in dichotic listening: Affective cues and the influence of instruc-
tions, Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology 11, 56–60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e904a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e908" publication-type="other">
Pashler, Harold, and James C. Johnston, 1998, Attentional limitations in dual-task performance,
inH. Pashler, ed.: Attention (Psychology Press/Erlbaum Taylor &amp;amp; Francis, Hove, UK).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e922" publication-type="other">
Peng, Lin, 2005, Learning with information capacity constraints, Journal of Financial and Quan-
titative Analysis 40, 307–329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e932a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e936" publication-type="other">
Peng, Lin, and Wei Xiong, 2006, Investor attention, overconfidence and category learning, Journal
of Financial Economics 80, 563–602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e947a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e951" publication-type="other">
Pollet, Joshua M., 2005, Predicting asset returns with expected oil price changes, Working paper,
University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e961a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e965" publication-type="other">
Simons, Daniel J., and Christopher F. Chabris, 1999, Gorillas in our midst: Sustained in attentional
blindness for dynamic events, Perception 28, 1059–1074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e975a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e979" publication-type="other">
Simons, Daniel J., and Daniel T. Levin, 1997, Change blindness, Trends in Cognitive Sciences 1,
261–267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e989a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e993" publication-type="other">
Stroop, J. Ridley, 1935, Studies of interference in serial verbal reactions, Journal of Experimental
Psychology 28, 643–662.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e1003a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e1007" publication-type="other">
Treisman, Ann M., and Alison Davies, 1973, Dividing attention to ear and eye, in Sylvan Kornblum,
ed.: Attention and Performance IV (Academic Press, New York).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d105e1017a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d105e1021" publication-type="other">
Tversky, Amos, and Daniel Kahneman, 1981, The framing of decisions and the psychology of choice,
Science 211, 453–458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
