<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275437</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Energy, Economical and Environmental Analysis of Plug-In Hybrids Electric Vehicles Based on Common Driving Cycles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Stockar</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephanie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zürich</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tulpule</surname>
                  <given-names>Pinak</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Center for Automotive Research, The Ohio State University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Marano</surname>
                  <given-names>Vincenzo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Center for Automotive Research, The Ohio State University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rizzoni</surname>
                  <given-names>Giorgio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Center for Automotive Research, The Ohio State University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>467</fpage>
         <lpage>476</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275437"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The objective draw by this project is to develop tools for Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle (PHEV) design, energy analysis and energy management, with the aim of analyzing the effect of design, driving cycles, charging frequency and energy management on performance, fuel economy, range and battery life.</p>
            <p>A Chevrolet Equinox fueled by bio diesel B20 has been hybridized at the Center for Automotive Research (CAR), at The Ohio State University. The vehicle model has been developed in Matlab/Simulink environment, and validated based on laboratory and test.</p>
            <p>The PHEV battery pack has been modeled starting from Li-Ion batteries experimental data and then implemented into the simulator.</p>
            <p>In order to simulate “real world” scenarios, custom driving cycles/typical days were identified starting from average driving statistics and well-known cycles. The driving cycles are based on commonly accepted standardized cycles (FUDS, FHDS, etc) and then combined to reflect common driving habits, average commute time, thus resulting in an annual distance traveled of about 15.000 miles.</p>
            <p>Several scenarios have been drawn considering different vehicle operation modes, i.e. EV (electric vehicle) and blended, different battery sizes, 6.97 and 8.87 kWh of stored energy and different charging availability, i.e. controlled (once a day, overnight) and uncontrolled (charging is possible whenever the vehicle is parked).</p>
            <p>For a complete assessment of the benefits achievable by PHEVs, results are compared to two other vehicle architectures (equivalent in terms of available power): the hybrid version of the proposed model and the conventional ICE vehicle (stock vehicle converted into B20). Results show significant benefits of PHEVs in terms of petroleum reduction, overall fuel cost and CO₂ emissions; it is also clear that none of the proposed configurations (i.e. different battery sizes) and vehicle operation modes (i.e. EV or blended) represents an absolute optimum, but the analysis strongly depends on the chosen objective function to minimize, vehicle components sizing and adapted strategies, fuel and electricity cost, charging availability and power grid generation mix.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCE</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korpubasi, K.. Modeling and Control of Hybrid- Electric Vehicle for Drivability and Fuel Economy Improvements. Ph.D. Dissertation, The Ohio State University. 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Ohio State University 2006 Challenge X Team. Final Design and Vehicle Technical Specifications, Challenge X 2006 Fall Technical Report, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnett M., Bayar K., Coburn C., Guezennec Y., Koprubasi K., Midlam-Mohler S., Sevel K., Shakiba- Herfeh M., Rizzoni G. Cleaner Diesel Using Model- Based Design and Advanced Aftertreatment in a Student Competition Vehicle. SAE World Congress. Detroit, MI, USA, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gu, B., Supervisory control strategy development for a hybrid electric vehicle. Master’s thesis, The Ohio State Univeristy. 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canova, M., Sevel, K., Guezennec, Y., Yurkovich, S. Control of the Start/Stop of a Diesel Engine in a Parallel HEV: Modeling and Experiments. Chicago, IL, USA : ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GREET 1.8b, Argonne National Laboratory, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sciarretta, A., Guzzella, L., Back M., Optimal Control of Parallel Hybrid Electric Vehicles. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology. 2004. Vol. 2, pp. 352-364.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pisu, P., Rizzoni, G.. A supervisory control strategy for series hybrid electric vehicles with two energy storage systems. September 2005. p. 8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paganelli, G., Ercole, G., Brahma, A., Guezennec, Y., Rizzoni, G., A General Formulation for the Instantaneous Control of the Power Split in Charge- Sustaining Hybrid Electric Vehicles. Ann Arbor, MI (USA) : Proceedings of 5th International Symposium in Advanced Vehicle Control, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paganelli, G., Tateno, M., Brahma, A., Rizzoni, G., Guezennec, Y., Control Development for a Hybrid- Electric Sport-Utility Vehicle: Strategy, Implementation and Field Test Results. VA (USA), 2001. pp. 5064–5069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paganelli, G., Delprat, S., Guerra, T.M., Rimaux, J., Santin, J.J., Equivalent Consumption Minimization Strategy for Parallel Hybrid Powertrains. Proceeding of Conference sponsored by Vehicular Transportation Systems (VTS) and IEEE. 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GAIA Homepage http://www.gaia-akku-online.de.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu, Y., Yurkovich, S., Guezennec, Y., Bornatico, R. Model-Based Calibration for Battery Characterization in HEV Applications, ACC, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tulpule, P., Marano, V., Rizzoni, G., Effect of Different PHEV Control Strategies on Vehicle Performances. American Control Conference, 2009, St. Luis, MO, USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karen R. Genung, Lawrence C. Markel, Shaun C. Hinds, Dr. Ralph McGill, Richard E. Ziegler, David E. Smith (Sentech, Inc.), Daniel Brooks (EPRI), Dr. Stanton W. Hadley, Richard L. Smith, Dr. David L. Greene (ORNL), Herman Wiegman (GE Global Research), Vincenzo Marano (OSU-CAR), “Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle, Value Proposition Study, Phase 1, Task 3: Technical Requirements and Procedure for Evaluation of One Scenario”, OAK RIDGE NATIONAL LABORATORY under contract No. DE-AC05-00OR22725, May 2008 – Final report published in January 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marano V. and Rizzoni G., “Energy and Economic Evaluation of PHEVs and their Interaction with Renewable Energy Sources and the Power Grid”, 2008 IEEE International Conference on Vehicular Electronics and Safety, Columbus, OH, US, September 22-24, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Biodiesel–Clean, Green Diesel Fuel, Departement of Energy, September 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clean Cities Alternative Fuel Price Report, Departement of. Energy, July 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles, IEEE Position Statement. June 15, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nationwide Personal Transportation Survey of 1995. Departement of Transportation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schneider, T.R., Transportation Efficiency Through Electric Drives and the Power Grid. Capitol Hill Forum “Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles: Towarsd Energy Independence". Juli 10, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
