<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308279</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of a Naturally Aspirated Spark Ignition Direct-Injection Flex-Fuel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Marriott</surname>
                  <given-names>Craig D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Advanced Powertrain</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wiles</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Advanced Powertrain</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gwidt</surname>
                  <given-names>J. Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Advanced Powertrain</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Parrish</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Research &amp; Development</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>267</fpage>
         <lpage>295</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308279"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Companion empirical and analytical studies were conducted to assess the feasibility and constraints (hardware and combustion perspectives) associated with operating a Spark Ignition Direct-Injection (SIDI) engine on high ethanol and gasoline mixtures ranging from 0 to 85% by volume. Cold start, part and full-load performance aspects were explored.</p>
            <p>Analytical experiments were performed to correlate with the empirical data using a commercially available single dimensional engine simulation code. Under WOT operating conditions it was found that the engine’s simulated output was overestimated with E85 fuel which was caused by the over prediction of volumetric efficiency. It was necessary to create a sub-routine to accurately model the impingement, vaporization, and heat transfer of fuel on the piston surface. Results could only be correlated after taking fuel impingement into account.</p>
            <p>Spray measurements were conducted including white light illumination and phase Doppler interferometery to study the differences in the spray shape, impingement, and the droplet formation regime between gasoline and E85 fuels. Efforts were taken to study the effects of temperature and back pressure on the spray. The results suggested that the spray properties were quite similar between the fuels, that the penetration lengths and droplet sizes of the fuels were comparable for like conditions, however E85 was more resistant to flash boiling effects for typical engine operating conditions.</p>
            <p>Selected empirical part-load optimization suggested efficiency improvements of 3-6% were possible over the optimized gasoline baseline. These gains were primarily due to a reduction in heat rejection and increased Exhaust Gas Residual (EGR) tolerance. These efficiency gains mildly offset the inherent energy density deficiency of ethanol based gasoline mixtures.</p>
            <p>Full-load empirical data suggested a potential for 13-15% increase in specific output with E85, as compared to a customer intent gasoline baseline fuel. These performance gains were enabled by the anti-knock qualities of the ethanol blends and an increase in volumetric and indicated efficiencies. It was also found that optimized full-load E85 operation was possible with injector hardware that was sized for gasoline (E00) operation. Ultimately, strategies were developed that enabled E85 operation at all operating conditions, as enabled by low smoke operation, improved knock resistance, increased charge cooling, and increased combustion stability.</p>
            <p>Cold startability tests with representative Class 3 E85 fuel were conducted at extreme ambient conditions to assess the cold start performance of the SIDI engine. It was found that a Low Pressure Start (LPS) operating strategy enabled engine starts at ambient conditions as cold as -20C, however, High Pressure Stratified Starts (HPSS) were necessary to meet colder startabilty requirements. Ultimately, a HPSS strategy improved startabilty and reduced enrichment requirements for E85.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">General Motors Corporation, “From Turnaround to ransformation”, General Motors Corporation 2006 nnual Report, p 32, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colwell, J.D., and A. Reza. “Hot Surface Ignition of utomotive and Aviation Fluids,” Fire Technology, 41(2):99-117, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davis, S., Chavez, D. and Kytomaa, H. “Hot Surface gnition of Flammable and Combustible Liquids,” AE Paper 2006-01-1014, SAE World Congress, etroit, MI, April 3-6, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stivender, D. L., ‘Development of a Fuel- Based ass Emission Measurement Procedure’, SAE aper 710604, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R, Cheng, W. K., Summers, T., and Collings, N., ‘The Fast-Response Flame Ionization Detector’, rog. Energy Combust. And Sci., Vol 24, pp. 89-124, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Application Notes AT1007E, “Measurement of moke Values With the Filter Paper Method”, AVL IST GmbH Graz, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Green, G. L., Wallace, D., ‘Correlation Studies of an n-Line, Full-Flow Opacitymeter’, SAE 801373, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ACAP 6.0B, Advanced Combustion Analysis rogram, MTS-DSP Technology Inc., Special GM ersion.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brinkman, N., ‘Exhaust Emissions, Fuel Economy, nd Driveability of Vehicles Fueled with Alcohol- asoline Blends ‘, SAE Paper 750120, 1975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagen, D. L., ‘Methanol as a Fuel: a Review with ibliography’, SAE 770792, 1977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, J., Kazakov, A., Dryer, F. L., ‘Chemical Kinetics of thanol Oxidation’, Proceedings of the European ombustion Meeting, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoo, J.-H., Kim, S.-K., et al., ‘Visualization of Direct- njection Gasoline Spray and Wall-impingement nside a Motoring Engine’, SAE Paper 982702, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turns, S. R., ‘An Introduction to Combustion; oncepts and Applications’, 2nd Edition, McGraw Hill, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, J. W., Cheng, W. K., and Heywood, J. B., ‘A odel for Predicting Residual Gas Fraction in Spark gnition Engines’, SAE Paper-931025, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., “A Universally Applicable Equation for he Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the nternal Combustion Engine,” SAE Paper 670931, 1967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavoie, G. A., Heywood, J. B., and Keck, J. C.: “Experimental and Theoretical Investigation of Nitric xide Formation in Internal Combustion Engines,” ombust. Sci. Technol., vol. 1, pp 313-326, 1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leone, T. G., Christenson, E. J., and Stein, R. A., “Comparison of Variable Camshaft Timing Strategies t Part Load”, SAE 960584, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Price, P., Twiney, B., ‘Particulate and Hydrocarbon missions from a Spray Guided Direct Injection park Ignition Engine with Oxygenate Fuel Blends’, AE Paper-2007-01-0472, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kapus, P.E., Feurhapter, A. et al., ‘Ethanol Direct njection on Turbocharged SI Engines-Potential and hallenges’, SAE 2007-01-1408, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
