<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308307</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling Fresh Air Charge and Residual Gas Fraction on a Dual Independent Variable Valve Timing SI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Leroy</surname>
                  <given-names>T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Alix</surname>
                  <given-names>G.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chauvin</surname>
                  <given-names>J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Duparchy</surname>
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Le Berr</surname>
                  <given-names>F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>IFP, France</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>627</fpage>
         <lpage>635</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308307"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>We propose a model of in-cylinder air mass and residual gas fraction of a turbocharged SI engine with Variable Valve Timing (VVT) actuators. VVT devices are used to produce internal exhaust gas recirculation at part load, providing beneficial effects in terms of fuel consumption and pollutant emissions. At full load, VVT actuators permit to push back knock limit by scavenging fresh air to the exhaust pipes. Modeling in-cylinder composition is an essential task for control purpose. Actually, VVT actuators affect in-cylinder fresh air charge. This has an impact on engine torque output (leading to driveability problems), and on Fuel/Air Ratio (leading to pollution peaks). In this paper, we present a model of in-cylinder air mass and residual gas fraction using only commercial-line sensors (engine speed, intake manifold pressure and VVT actuators positions). It is designed for real-time control purpose. The model does not necessitate a lot of calibration time. The proposed method consists in modeling the quantity of fresh air going through the intake valve. The model is composed of three terms. All these terms have their own physical meaning: first term gives in-cylinder total mass, second term gives the gas mass that goes through both valves during the valve overlap (either backflow of burned gas, or scavenging of fresh air), and last term models the residual gas mass staying in the cylinder from one cycle to the next one.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Cavina, C. Siviero, and R. Suglia. Residual gas fraction stimation: application to a GDI engine with variable alve Timing and EGR. In Proc. of SAE Conference, number 2004-01-2943, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Colin, Y. Chamaillard, G. Bloch, and G. Corde. Neural ontrol of fast nonlinear systems. application to a turbocharged I engine with VCT. In Proc. of Neural Networks or Feedback Control, volume 16, NO. 4, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.W. Fox, W.K. Cheng, and J.B. Heywood. A model for redicting residual gas fraction in spark-ignition engines. n Proc. of SAE Conference, number 931025, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Heywood. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. cGraw-Hill, Inc, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U. Kiencke and L. Nielsen. Automotive Control Systems. pringer, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Le Berr, M. Miche, G. Le Solliec, F-A. Lafossas, and . Colin. Modelling of a turbocharged SI engine with variable amshaft timing for engine control purposes. In Proc. f SAE Conference, number 2006-01-3264, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Lecointe and G. Monnier. Downsizing a gasoline engine sing turbocharging with direct injection. In Proc. of AE Conference, number 2003-01-0542, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T.G. Leone, E.J. Christenson, and R.A Stein. Comparison f variable camshaft timing strategies at part load. In Proc. f SAE Conference, number 960584, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Leroy, J. Chauvin, N. Petit, and G. Corde. Motion planing ontrol of the airpath of an SI engine with valve timing ctuators. In Proc. of IFAC Automotive Control, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Mladek and C.H. Onder. A model for the estimation of nducted air mass and the residual gas fraction using cylinder ressure measurements. In Proc. of SAE Conference, umber 2000-01-0958, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A.G. Stefanopoulou, J.A. Cook, J.W. Grizzle, and J.S. reudenberg. Control-oriented model of a dual equal variable am timing spark ignition engine. In ASME J. Dynamic yst., Measurement Contr., volume 120, pages 257-266, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
