<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i23027481</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23027490</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>SOME LESSONS FROM INFORMAL FINANCIAL PRACTICES IN RURAL TANZANIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A. E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Temu</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>G. P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Hill</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>141</fpage>
         <lpage>166</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23027490"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Efforts to develop rural financial markets in low income countries by using formal banks have experienced many difficulties and failures. Development economists are increasingly recognising the importance of learning from the operations of informal financial markets. This paper explores informal financial practices that take place in the Kilimanjaro region of Tanzania. The aim is to identify operational features of informal financial practices that have implications for the development of formal institutions. Survey data from Kilimanjaro show that rural dwellers successfully resolve financial problems through informal means. Farmers save informally by hoarding crop harvests and by keeping livestock that are low yielding but resistant to diseases and resilient to harsh climatic conditions, eg the short horn-zebu cattle. Informal borrowing, both in cash and kind takes place between friends, relatives and neighbours. A traditional agistment agreement is widely practised and helps farmes to acquire livestock - a lucrative diversification from the low paying major cash crop - coffee. Stereotype money-lenders do not exist in the study area. However, private commercial lenders who also manage other forms of trade or business provide rural dwellers with credit for a wide range of purposes. Most important ones include food for families facing deficits, finances and equipment needed to send children to boarding schools and material for house construction. Advise, counselling and support are important components of such credit. Lessons for formal financial institutions centre on the observed ability and willingness to save, the close relationship between borrowers and lenders, fiduciary elements and trust in credit transactions, the role that traditional leaders play in enforcing financial agreements, strong measures taken on defaulters, the focus on the needs as expressed by the rural dwellers and the apparent importance of consumption credit.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d127e184a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d127e191" publication-type="other">
Temu (1994)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d127e198a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d127e205" publication-type="other">
Norusis (1989)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d127e211" publication-type="other">
Temu (1994)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d127e218a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d127e225" publication-type="other">
STD of 1 -Everitt (1993;46)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d127e232a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d127e239" publication-type="other">
Shipton (1989)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>Reference</title>
        <ref id="d127e255a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e259" publication-type="other">
Adams, D.W. and Fitchett, A. (Eds) (1992) Informal Finance in Low Income Countries, West View Press, San
Francisco, USA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e269a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e273" publication-type="other">
Adams, D.W. (1992) Taking a Fresh look at Informal Finance, in (Ed). Adams and Fitchett, Informal Finance in Low
Income Countries, West View Press, San Francisco, USA. 5:23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e283a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e287" publication-type="other">
Adams, D.W. and Ghate, P.B. (1992) Where to From Here? In (Ed). Adams and Fitchett, Informal Finance in Low
Income Countries, West View Press, San Francisco, USA. 349:363.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e297a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e301" publication-type="other">
Akerlof, G.A. (1970) The Markets for "Lemons": Uncertainty and the Market Mechanism, The Quarterly Journal of
Economics, August, 471:502.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e312a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e316" publication-type="other">
Amani, H.K.R.; Msambichaka, T.A.;Hedlund, S. and Lundahl, M. (1987) Agricultural Credit in Tanzania: A. Peasant
Perspective, Savings and Development, 11 (4) 379:401.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e326a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e330" publication-type="other">
Bardhan, P. (1980) Interlocked Factor Markets and Agrarian Development: A Review of Issues, Oxford Economic
Papers,32; 82:98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e340a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e344" publication-type="other">
Chandavarkar, A.G. (1985) The Non-Institutional Financial Sector in Developing Countries, Macro Economic
Implications for Savings Policies, Savings and Development, 2 (9) 129:141.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e354a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e358" publication-type="other">
Chipeta, C. and Mkandawire, M.L.C. (1992) The Informal Financial Sector in Malawi, A. R. Supplementary Issue
No 2; 121:150.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e372" publication-type="other">
Christensen G. (1993) The Limits of Informal Financial Intermediation, World Development, 21 (5) 721:731.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e379a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e383" publication-type="other">
Coulson, A. (1982) Tanzania: A Political Economy, Oxford University Press, New York, USA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e391a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e395" publication-type="other">
De Lancey, V. (1992) Rural Finance in Somalia, in (Ed) Adams and Fitchet, Informal Finance in Low Income
Countries, West View Press, San Francisco, US, 57:70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e405a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e409" publication-type="other">
Devereux, S. (1990) Kilimanjaro Region, Northern-Tanzania; Accumulation and Survival Under Stress, A Critical
Literature Review accompanying Duncan and Kydd (1990), Food Studies Group, Oxford, England, 52:67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e419a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e423" publication-type="other">
Duncan, A. &amp; Kydd, J. (1990) Review of ODA Support for West Kilimanjaro Livestock Breeding Farm and
Recommendations for Future ODA Support for Smallholder Agriculture in Arumeru and Hai Districts of
Northern Tanzania, A Report to ODA (BDDA), ODA, England.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e440" publication-type="other">
Dundas, C. (1921) Native Laws of Some Bantu Tribes of East Africa, Journal of The Royal Anthropological Institute,
51,217:278.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e454" publication-type="other">
Everitt, B.S. (1993) Cluster Analysis, 3rd Ed, Heinemann, London, England.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e461a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e465" publication-type="other">
FSG-RE SUA (1992) Agricultural Diversification and Intensification Study, Food Studies Group and The Department
of Rural Economy - Sokoine University of Agriculture, A World Bank funded Agricultural Sector Study, FSG,
Oxford, England.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e479a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e483" publication-type="other">
Harris, B. (1983) Money and Commodities: Their Interactions in a Rural Indian Setting, in (Ed) Von Pischke etal,
Rural Financial Markets in Developing Countries, Johns Hopkins Press, London, England, 233:241.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e493a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e497" publication-type="other">
Hyden, G. (1980) Beyond Ujamaa in Tanzania: Underdevelopment and Uncaptured Peasant, Heineman Educa-
tional, London, England.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e507a1310">
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e513" publication-type="other">
Liewellyn, S.S. (1991) Some Explanation for Lack of Borrower Commitment to Specialised Farm Credit Institutions:
A Case Study of the Role of Rural Sri-Lankan Traders in Meeting Credit Needs, Savings and Development,
3 (15) 285:313.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e526a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e530" publication-type="other">
Maro, P.S. (1975) Population Growth and Agricultural Change in Kilimanjaro 1929-1970, BRALUP, Report No 40,
University of Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e540a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e544" publication-type="other">
Mauri, A. (Ed) (1977b) Mobilisation of Household Savings, A Tool for Development, Credit Markets of Africa Series,
(14), Finafrica, Cariplo Milan, Italy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e558" publication-type="other">
Mauri, A. (1977 a) A Policy to Mobilise Rural Savings in Less Developed Countries, Savings and Development, 1
(1)21:57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e569a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e573" publication-type="other">
MDB (1990), Coffee Sub-sector Study, Tanzania, An analysis prepared for African Development Bank, Agland
Investments Services, MALDC, Dar-es-salaam, Tanzania.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e587" publication-type="other">
Moore, S.F. and Puritt, P. (1977) The Chagga and Meru of Tanzania, A Series of Ethno graphic Surveys of Africa,
Edited by Middleton, J., International African Institute, London, England.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e601" publication-type="other">
Norusis, M.J. (1989) SPSS-PS Advanced statistics, New York, USA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e608a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e612" publication-type="other">
Shipton, P. (1989) Time and Money in western Sahel: The Cultural Economy of Interest and Usury in The Gambian
Local Rural Finance, Development Discussion Paper, Harvard Institute of International Development,
Cambridge, England.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e625a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e629" publication-type="other">
Temu, A.E. (1994) A Study of The Rural Financial Market in Tanzania. A PhD thesis submitted to The University
of London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e639a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e643" publication-type="other">
UNECA (1986) Agricultural Credit and The Mobilisation of Resources in Rural Africa, United Nations Economic
Commission for Africa, Research Paper No. E/ECA/PSD.4/7/REV 1, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e658" publication-type="other">
UNICEF/URT (1985) Analysis of the Health Situation of Children and Women, Tanzania Food and Nutrition Centre,
Dar-es-salaam, Tanzania.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e672" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke, J.D. (1991) Finance at the Frontier: Debt Capacity and the Role of Credit in the Private Economy, EDI,
The World Bank, Washington, USA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d127e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d127e686" publication-type="other">
World Bank (1989) World Development Report 1989, WB, Washington, USA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


