<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438348</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>SYMPOSIUM ON TECHNOLOGY, PRODUCTIVITY AND PUBLIC POLICY</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The New Economy: Reality and Policy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>JOHN</given-names>
                  <surname>VAN REENEN</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2001</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438342</issue-id>
         <fpage>307</fpage>
         <lpage>336</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2001</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438348"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper concerns the new economy (alias the knowledge-based economy). I examine the different meanings attached to the new economy term and the evidence surrounding it, concentrating on the upsurge in US productivity growth between 1995 and 2000. I argue that the reports of the death of the new economy have been greatly exaggerated. There is evidence that information technology has transformed the US economy and is thus likely to have a strong impact on the UK economy in coming years. I discuss how elements of public policy should adapt to these economic changes, both in terms of an overall framework and in applications to specific areas (technology policy, human capital policy, competition policy and industrial policy). The new economy is a place of hope and fear. The hope is that policy activism can cement in potential productivity gains; the fear is that government actions will not mitigate the seemingly ineluctable pressures towards social exclusion.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d8e242a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e249" publication-type="other">
This past decade has been extraordinary for the American economy and monetary policy. The synergies of
key technologies markedly elevated prospective returns on high-tech investments, led to a surge in business
capital spending and significantly increased the underlying growth rate of productivity' (Alan Greenspan's
report to the US Congress, 13 February 2001). Full text available on www.ft.com/greenspantext.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e265a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e272" publication-type="other">
For example, Wadhwani (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e279a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e286" publication-type="other">
John Chambers, Chief Executive Officer of Cisco Systems.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e293a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e300" publication-type="other">
A case could be made for some smaller countries (for example, Ireland and Finland), but 1 think there are
special circumstances for these nations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e311a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e318" publication-type="other">
For example: David Ricardo's (1911) chapter 'On machinery' in The Principles of Political Economy and
Taxation; Adam Smith (1776) on the pin factory in The Wealth of Nations', Karl Marx (1859) on the primacy
of the forces of production in the Preface to The Critique of Political Economy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e331a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e338" publication-type="other">
As Flaubert lamented in his Dictionnaire des idées reçue, 'Innovation — Always dangerous. Inventors
They all die in the hospice. Somebody else profits by their discoveries; it is not fair'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e348a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e355" publication-type="other">
Although it is true that Schumpeter has had a long-standing subterranean influence upon the economics
profession, his full impact did not come until the development of endogenous growth theory. Part of this was
due to Schumpeter's rather informal style. Lionel Robbins is reported to have characterised his major work,
Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy, as a 'supremely intelligent after-dinner talk'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e371a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e378" publication-type="other">
One may have expected the importance of brand names to decline and the importance of technical quality and
price to increase. Bresnahan, Stern and Trajtenberg (1997) show that brand is as important as technical
competence even in the personal computer industry. I show in Section 111(3) that the evidence on the
importance of the Internet in stimulating price competition is mixed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e394a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e401" publication-type="other">
In the short run, there can be an impact, of course (see Lynch and Nickell (2001), for example). Even in the
long run, the statement needs some qualification. It may be that the Internet can reduce the level of structural
unemployment, or NADRU, by improving the job search and matching process in the labour market. There were
5,000 job sites and Web-based recruitment agencies in the USA by the end of 2000. Improved information
technology in public employment service may help. The CV of every unemployed person in Germany is
available on the Web for employers to examine.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e424a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e431" publication-type="other">
For evidence on overvaluation, see Shiller (2000) and Bond and Cummins (2000). For a perspective on
rational valuation under conditions of great uncertainty, see Hall (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e442a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e449" publication-type="other">
Kortum and Lerner, 1998.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e456a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e463" publication-type="other">
The other major explanation is that the US courts became more 'patent friendly' following the establishment
of the Courts of Appeals of the Federal Circuit by Congress in 1982. But this would imply that the USA should
have become a more favoured destination for patents from firms in all countries, not just the USA-based firms.
In fact, there appears to have been no major switch towards seeking protection in the USA by foreign firms
post-1982. The increase in patenting appears to be part of a worldwide increase, along with an improvement in
the relative performance of US inventors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e486a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e493" publication-type="other">
See Griliches (1996) for a historical account. He was always amused that economists specialising in
technology placed maximum importance on an object that econometricians had always tried to minimise away
— the residual.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e506a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e515" publication-type="other">
For example, y - m + bh + (l-b)k, where y is the rate of growth of output, m is the growth rate of multifactor
productivity, h is the growth rate of hours, b is the elasticity of output with respect to hours (proxied by the
share of labour in total output) and k is the growth rate of the capital stock. We have assumed constant returns
to scale. Rearranging labour productivity growth, y - h = m + (l-b)(k-h): a weighted sum of the growth of
MFP and capital deepening.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e534a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e541" publication-type="other">
it is conventional to drop 1990-95, as this contained a deep recession, so the two periods 1974-90 and 1995—
99 are more cyclically comparable. If the early 1990s were included in the baseline, the acceleration in 1995—
99 would look slightly larger.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e554a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e561" publication-type="other">
For example, time-limited benefits were introduced under the 1996 Personal Responsibility and Work
Opportunity Reconciliation Act. See Blank and Card (2000) for an extensive discussion of the likely impact of
this reform.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e575a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e582" publication-type="other">
We have presented the results up to 1990 rather than 1995 to avoid a potentially misleading comparison with
the recession of the early 1990s. This makes very little difference.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e592a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e599" publication-type="other">
This is because of genuine uncertainty about whether the organisational changes will work, the need to
introduce many of the changes as a large package of reforms and the resistance from incumbents who will be
displaced by these new methods. See Bresnahan, Brynjolfsson and Hitt (2002) and Caroli and Van Reenen
(2001) for microeconometric evidence in the USA, France and the UK.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e615a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e622" publication-type="other">
Source: Bureau of Labor Statistics, www.stats.bis.gov/lprhome.htm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e629a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e636" publication-type="other">
For a discussion of the impact of the Thatcher administration on productivity, see the contributions to
Blundell, Card and Freeman (2001). Unions are an interesting example. Their influence has dramatically waned
— 53 per cent of workers were in unions in 1980 compared with under 30 per cent today. It is likely that
unions reduced the level of productivity in the UK in the 1970s (Pencavel, 2001), but the evidence does not
suggest that unions significantly reduced the rate of innovation (for example, Menezes-Filho, Ulph and Van
Reenen (1998)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e659a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e666" publication-type="other">
For a recent statement of government analysis and policy, see HM Treasury (2000); for a critical discussion,
see Griffith and Simpson (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e676a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e683" publication-type="other">
For evidence on the effectiveness of the New Deal in stimulating employment, see Bell, Blundell and Van
Reenen (1999) and Van Reenen (2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e694a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e701" publication-type="other">
Crafts and O'Mahony (this issue) estimate that 5 percentage points of the 26 per cent UK-US labour
productivity gap can be accounted for by lower ICT stocks.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e711a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e718" publication-type="other">
See the collection of essays in the Winter 2001 Journal of Economic Perspectives for a longer discussion of
the economics of the Internet.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e728a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e735" publication-type="other">
Wadhwani (2000) reports from a Bank of England survey showing that, while only 28 per cent of UK
businesses currently use the Internet for purchases, 68 per cent expect to do so by the end of 2002.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e745a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e752" publication-type="other">
Litan and Rivlin (2001) offer a similar simulation exercise based on a more rigorous sector-by-sector analysis
of the impact of the Internet. They suggest that the Internet could add 1-2 per cent on US productivity over the
next five years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e765a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e772" publication-type="other">
European countries have suffered from employment inequality — a large fall in the job prospects of less-
skilled individuals.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e782a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e789" publication-type="other">
Another difference is that, although the wage gap between educated and less-educated workers fell in the
1970s in the UK and in the USA, within-educational-group inequality was rising throughout the 1970s in the
USA whereas it was not in the UK.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e803a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e810" publication-type="other">
See Chennells and Van Reenen (2001) for a survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e817a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e824" publication-type="other">
Desjonqueres, Machin and Van Reenen (1999) show that the industries experiencing the fastest shake-outs of
unskilled workers across countries were not those with the greatest exposure to trade, from less-developed
countries or otherwise.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e837a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e844" publication-type="other">
For example, Department of Trade and Industry (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e851a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e858" publication-type="other">
The positive correlation between wage and computer use highlighted by several authors (for example,
Krueger (1994)) is primarily due to the fact that high-wage workers are selected to use new technologies (see
Chennells and Van Reenen (1997 and 2001)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e871a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e878" publication-type="other">
It is based on an endogenous growth model in the spirit of Aghion and Howitt (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e885a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e892" publication-type="other">
For example, Cohen and Levinthal (1989).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e900a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e907" publication-type="other">
For example, Nelson and Phelps (1966) and Benhabib and Spiegel (1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e914a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e921" publication-type="other">
See Sianesi and Van Reenen (2001) for a survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e928a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e937" publication-type="other">
Foreign direct investment is also thought to be a key instrument in spreading new technologies (either
through competition or more directly, by examples of best practice). Yet the data on this are worse than those
on the other factors, and — so far, at least — the empirical evidence is unconvincing. See Griffith and Simpson
(2001) for the latest evidence.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e953a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e960" publication-type="other">
See the survey in Hall and Van Reenen (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e967a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e974" publication-type="other">
Fisher, 2000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e981a1310">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e988" publication-type="other">
The recent decision in the Court of Appeal of US vs. Microsoft vacated the remedy imposed by the District
Court on Microsoft but upheld the finding of fact that Microsoft had indeed abused its position as a monopolist
of PC operating systems to drive out competitors in other markets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e1002a1310">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e1009" publication-type="other">
For example, Blundell, Griffith and Van Reenen (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e1016a1310">
            <label>42</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e1023" publication-type="other">
Griffith, Redding and Van Reenen (2000) find, as one would expect, that the drivers of productivity (frontier,
R&amp;D and human capital) have different effects in different industries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e1033a1310">
            <label>43</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e1040" publication-type="other">
Nickell and Van Reenen, 2001, Table 3.8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e1047a1310">
            <label>44</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e1054" publication-type="other">
The Pharmaceutical Price Regulation Scheme (PPRS) is analysed in detail in Bloom and Van Reenen (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e1061a1310">
            <label>45</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e1068" publication-type="other">
McKinsey Global Institute (1998) comes dangerously close to asserting this in places.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e1075a1310">
            <label>46</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e1082" publication-type="other">
The Pharmaceutical Industry Competitiveness Taskforce (www.doh.gov.uk/pictf/index.html).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d8e1098a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1102" publication-type="other">
Aghion, P. and Howitt, P. (1998), Endogenous Growth Theory, Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1109a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1113" publication-type="other">
Bailey, J. (1998), 'Intermediation and electronic markets: aggregation and pricing in Internet
commerce', Ph.D. thesis, Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science,
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 20 May.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1126a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1130" publication-type="other">
Bailey, M. and Lawrence, R. (2001), 'Do we have a new E-conomyT, American Economic Review,
vol. 91, pp. 308-12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1140a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1144" publication-type="other">
Bell, B., Blundell, R. and Van Reenen, J. (1999), 'Getting the unemployed back to work: the role
of wage subsidies', International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 6, pp. 339-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1155a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1159" publication-type="other">
Benhabib, J. and Spiegel, M. (1994), 'The role of human capital in economic development:
evidence from aggregate cross-country data', Journal of Monetary Economics, vol. 34, pp.
143-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1176" publication-type="other">
Blank, R. and Card, D. (2000), Finding Jobs: Work and Welfare Reform, New York: Russell Sage
Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1190" publication-type="other">
Bloom, N., Griffith, R. and Van Reenen, J. (2001), 'Do R&amp;D tax credits work? Evidence from an
international panel of countries 1979-96', Journal of Public Economics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1200a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1204" publication-type="other">
— and Van Reenen, J. (1998), 'Regulating drug prices: where do we go from here?', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 19, pp. 321-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1214a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1218" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R., Card, D. and Freeman, R. (2001), Seeking a Premier League Economy, Chicago:
University of Chicago Press, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1228a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1232" publication-type="other">
—, Griffith, R. and Van Reenen, J. (1999), 'Market share, market value and innovation in a panel
of British manufacturing firms', Review of Economic Studies, vol. 66, pp. 529-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1243a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1247" publication-type="other">
— and Preston, I. (1998), 'Consumption and income inequality', Quarterly Journal of Economics,
vol. 113, pp. 603-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1257a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1261" publication-type="other">
Bond, S. and Cummins, J. (2000), 'The stock exchange and investment in the new economy: some
tangible facts and intangible fictions', Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, no. 1:2000, pp.
61-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1274a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1278" publication-type="other">
— and Jenkinson, T. (1996), 'The assessment: investment performance and policy', Oxford Review
of Economic Policy, vol. 12, no. 2, pp. 1-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1288a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1292" publication-type="other">
Bresnahan, T., Brynjolfsson, E. and Hitt, L. (2002), 'IT, workplace organization and the demand
for skilled workers: a firm level analysis', Quarterly Journal of Economics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1302a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1306" publication-type="other">
—, Stern, S. and Trajtenberg, M. (1997), 'Market segmentation and the sources of rents from
innovation: personal computers in the late 1980s', RAND Journal of Economics, vol. 28,
Special Issue, pp. S17-S44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1319a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1323" publication-type="other">
Brookes, M. and Wahhaj, Z. (2000), 'The shocking effects of B2B', Goldman Sachs, Global
Economics Paper no. 37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1334a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1338" publication-type="other">
Brown, J. and Goolsbee, A. (2001), 'Does the Internet make markets more competitive? Evidence
from the life insurance industry', Journal of Political Economy, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1348a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1352" publication-type="other">
Brynjolfsson, E. and Hitt, L. (2000), 'Beyond computation: information technology, organizational
transformation and business performance', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 14, no. 4,
pp. 23—47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1365a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1369" publication-type="other">
— and Smith, M. (2000), 'Frictionless commerce? A comparison of Internet and conventional
retailers', Management Science, vol. 46, pp. 563-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1379a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1383" publication-type="other">
Card, D. and Lemieux, T. (2000), 'Can falling supply explain the rising return to college for
younger men? A cohort based analysis', National Bureau of Economic Research, Working
Paper no. 7655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1396a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1400" publication-type="other">
Caroli, E. and Van Reenen, J. (2001), 'Organisational change and human capital: evidence from
British and French enterprises in the 1980s and 1990s', Quarterly Journal of Economics,
forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1413a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1417" publication-type="other">
Chennells, L. and Van Reenen, J. (1997), 'Technical change and earnings in British
establishments', Economica, vol. 64, pp. 587-604.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1428a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1432" publication-type="other">
— and — (2001), 'The effects of technical change on skills, wages and employment: a survey of
the micro-econometric evidence', in N. Greenan and J. Mairesse (eds), The Economic Impact
of Information and Communications Technologies, Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1445a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1449" publication-type="other">
Cohen, W. and Levinthal, D. (1989), 'Innovation and learning: two faces of R&amp;D', Economic
Journal, vol. 99, pp. 569-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1459a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1463" publication-type="other">
Council of Economic Advisors (2000), Economic Report of the President 2000, Washington, DC:
Government Printing Office</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1473a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1477" publication-type="other">
Crafts, N. and O'Mahony, M. (this issue), 'A perspective on UK productivity performance', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 22, pp. 271-306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1487a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1491" publication-type="other">
David, P. (1990), 'The dynamo and the computer: a historical perspective on the modern
productivity paradox', American Economic Review, vol. 80, pp. 355-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1501a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1505" publication-type="other">
Department of Trade and Industry (2000), Closing the Digital Divide: A Report by Policy Action
Team, March, London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1516a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1520" publication-type="other">
Desjonqueres, T., Machin, S. and Van Reenen, J. (1999), 'Another nail in the coffin? Or can the
trade based explanation of changing skill structures be resurrected?', Scandinavian Journal of
Economics, vol. 101, pp. 533-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1533a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1537" publication-type="other">
Fisher, F. (2000), 'Microsoft, monopoly power and leveraging', Massachusetts Institute of
Technology, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1547a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1551" publication-type="other">
Goolsbee, A. (1998), 'Does government R&amp;D policy mainly benefit scientists and engineers?',
American Economic Review, vol. 88, pp. 298-302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1561a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1565" publication-type="other">
Gordon, R. (2000), 'Does the new economy measure up to the great inventions of the past?',
Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 14, no. 4, pp. 48-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1579" publication-type="other">
Gosling, A. and Machin, S. (1995), 'Trade unions and the dispersion of earnings in British
establishments', Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, vol. 57, pp. 167-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1589a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1593" publication-type="other">
—, — and Meghir, C. (2000), 'The changing distribution of male wages in the UK', Review of
Economic Studies, vol. 67, pp. 635-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1604a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1608" publication-type="other">
Griffith, R„ Redding, S. and Van Reenen, J. (2000), 'Mapping the two faces of R&amp;D: productivity
growth in a panel of OECD industries', Centre for Economic Policy Research, Discussion
Paper no. 2457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1621a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1625" publication-type="other">
—, — and — (this issue), 'Measuring the cost-effectiveness of an R&amp;D tax credit for the UK',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 22, pp. 375-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1635a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1639" publication-type="other">
— and Simpson, H. (1998), Productivity and the Role of Government, Commentary no. 73,
London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1649a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1653" publication-type="other">
— and — (2001), 'Did Boskin spoil the game? Foreign direct investment and productivity in the
UK', Institute for Fiscal Studies, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1663a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1667" publication-type="other">
Griliches, Z. (1994), 'Productivity, R&amp;D and the data constraint', American Economic Review, vol.
84, pp. 1-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1677a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1681" publication-type="other">
— (1996), 'The discovery of the residual: a historical note', Journal of Economic Literature, vol.
34, pp. 1324-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1692a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1696" publication-type="other">
Hall, B. and Van Reenen, J. (1999), 'How effective are fiscal incentives for R&amp;D? A review of the
evidence', Research Policy, vol. 29, pp. 449-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1706a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1710" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. (1999), 'The stock market and capital accumulation', National Bureau of Economic
Research, Working Paper no. 7180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1720a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1724" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (2000), Productivity in the UK: The Evidence and the Government's Approach,
London: The Stationery Office (http://www.hm-treasury.gov.uk).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1734a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1738" publication-type="other">
Ip, G. (2000), 'Market on a high wire', Wall Street Journal, 18 January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1745a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1749" publication-type="other">
Jorgenson, D. (2001), 'Information technology and the US economy', American Economic Review,
vol. 91, pp. 1-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1759a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1763" publication-type="other">
— and Stiroh, K. (2000), 'Raising the speed limit: US economic growth in the Information Age',
Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, no. 1, pp. 125-211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1774a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1778" publication-type="other">
Kneller, R. and Young, G. (2001), 'The new British economy', National Institute Economic
Review, no. 177, pp. 70-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1788a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1792" publication-type="other">
Kortum, S. and Lerner, J. (1998), 'Stronger protection or technological revolution: what is behind
the recent surge in patenting?', Carnegie-Rochester Conference Series on Public Policy, no.
48, pp. 247-304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1805a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1809" publication-type="other">
Krueger, A. (1994), 'How computers have changed the wage structure', Quarterly Journal of
Economics, vol. 108, pp. 33-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1819a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1823" publication-type="other">
Layard, R., Nickell, S. and Jackman, R. (1991), Unemployment: Macroeconomic Performance and
the Labour Market, Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1833a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1837" publication-type="other">
Leadbetter, C. (2000), Living on Thin Air, London: Viking.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1844a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1848" publication-type="other">
Lee, H. G. (1997), 'Do electronic marketplaces lower the price of goods?', Communications of the
ACM, vol. 41, pp. 73-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1859a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1863" publication-type="other">
Litan, R. and Rivlin, A. (2001), 'Projecting the economic impact of the Internet', American
Economic Review, vol. 91, pp. 313-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1873a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1877" publication-type="other">
Lynch, L. and Nickell, S. (2001), 'Rising productivity and falling unemployment: can the US
experience be sustained and replicated?', London School of Economics, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1887a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1891" publication-type="other">
Machin, S. and Van Reenen, J. (1998), 'Technology and changes in the skill structure: evidence
from seven OECD countries', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 113, pp. 1215-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1901a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1905" publication-type="other">
McKinsey Global Institute (1998), Driving Productivity Growth in the UK Economy, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1912a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1916" publication-type="other">
Menezes-Filho, N., Ulph, D. and Van Reenen, J. (1998), 'R&amp;D and union bargaining: evidence
from British companies and establishments', Industrial and Labor Relations Review, vol. 52,
pp. 45-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1929a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1933" publication-type="other">
Moser Report (1998), Improving Literacy and Numeracy: A Fresh Start, Report of the Working
Group chaired by Sir Charles Moser, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1944a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1948" publication-type="other">
Nelson, R. and Phelps, E. (1966), 'Investment in humans, technological diffusion and economic
growth', American Economic Review, vol. 56, pp. 69-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1958a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1962" publication-type="other">
Nickeil, S., Jones, T. and Quintini, G. (2000), 'A picture of job insecurity facing British men',
Economic Journal, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1972a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1976" publication-type="other">
— and Van Reenen, J. (2001), 'Technological innovation and economic performance in the United
Kingdom', Centre for Economic Performance, Discussion Paper no. 488.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e1986a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1990" publication-type="other">
Nordaus, W. (2001), 'Productivity growth and the new economy', National Bureau of Economic
Research, Working Paper no. 8097.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2000a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2004" publication-type="other">
Oliner, S. and Sichel, D. (2000), 'The resurgence of growth in the late 1990s: is information
technology the story?', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 14, no. 4, pp. 3-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2014a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2018" publication-type="other">
Oulton, N. (2001), 'ICT and productivity growth in the UK', Bank of England, mimeo, April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2026a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2030" publication-type="other">
Pencavel, J. (2001), 'The surprising retreat of trade union Britain', Stanford University, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2037a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2041" publication-type="other">
Posner, R. (2000), 'Anti-trust in the new economy', John M. Ohlin Law and Economics Working
Paper no. 106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2051a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2055" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R. (2000), Irrational Exuberance, Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2062a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2066" publication-type="other">
Sianesi, B. and Van Reenen, J. (2001), 'Education and economic growth: a review of the
literature', Centre for Economics of Education, Discussion Paper no. 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2076a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2080" publication-type="other">
Sichel, D. (2001), 'Information technology and economic growth in the US: an update and a look
ahead', presentation to the Bank of England, May.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2090a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2094" publication-type="other">
Solow, R. (1957), 'Technical change and the aggregate production function', Review of Economics
and Statistics, vol. 39, pp. 312-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2105a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2109" publication-type="other">
— (1987), 'We'd better watch out', New York Times Book Review, 12 July, p. 36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2116a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2120" publication-type="other">
Van Reenen, J. (1997), 'Why has Britain had slower R&amp;D growth?', Research Policy, vol. 26, pp.
493-507.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2130a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2134" publication-type="other">
— (2001), 'No more skivvy schemes? Active labour market policies and the British New Deal for
Young Unemployed in context', in R. Blundell, D. Card and R. Freeman (eds), Seeking a
Premier League Economy, Chicago: University of Chicago Press, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2147a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2151" publication-type="other">
Wadhwani, S. (2000), 'Monetary challenges in a new economy', HSBC Global Investment
Seminar, October (www.bankofengland.co.uk/speeches/speechl03.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2161a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2165" publication-type="other">
Walton, D. and Broadbent, B. (2000), 'Mismeasuring the economy', Goldman Sachs UK Weekly
Analyst, 27 October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e2175a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e2179" publication-type="other">
Wood, A. (1994), North-South Trade, Employment and Inequality: Changing Fortunes in a Skill-
Driven World, Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
