<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">14</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198602</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44720498</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>POSSIBLE EFFECT OF AIRCRAFT ENGINE DEVELOPMENT ON AUTOMOBILE PRACTICE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Henry M</given-names>
                  <surname>Crane</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1919</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>137</fpage>
         <lpage>145</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright, 1920, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44720498"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>DURING the war a large amount of development work was done on various types of engines suitable for use in aircraft. It is only natural to speculate as to what effect the knowledge thus gained will have on the design of automobiles. A close study of the development in aircraft engines leads the author to believe that there is no reason to expect any radical change in automobile engine design. Nearly every feature of design in the aircraft engines used during the war has been used in automobiles. One line of development which has a very direct bearing on automobile engine design was just coming to the front at the end of the war, and that was the production of composite fuels. Another thing that will no doubt have effect on the future automobile engine design is the question of materials. The advance in aircraft engines can be attributed to a more general knowledge of materials already in use before the war, which was due to greater care and better methods than to any new invention. We will in the future have a continuous and beneficial interchange of information and ideas between the two lines of engineering, but the lines of design will also draw rather widely apart, on account of the very different problems met in the two services.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


