<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jfinancialedu</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007490</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Financial Education</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Education Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00933961</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2332421X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">39</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3/4</issue>
         <issue-id>i23608643</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23608647</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Impact of Personality Types and Learning Styles on Performance of Finance Majors</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Rasha</given-names>
                  <surname>Ashraf</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
                  <surname>Fendler</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Milind</given-names>
                  <surname>Shrikhande</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>47</fpage>
         <lpage>68</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2013 Financial Education</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23608647"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Although the influence of learning styles and personality types on student performance has been extensively debated in the literature, the impact on student performance at different learning levels as per Bloom's taxonomy has received little attention. We find that learning styles and personality types have almost no impact on overall performance of finance majors. However, if we carefully examine their performance at different learning levels, we find that both personality types and learning styles have significant impact, especially at the higher learning levels. Our study has practical implications. Finance instructors can modify their teaching styles to address the varied learning styles and personality profiles of finance majors in order to better engage all students in the learning process. Likewise, students can be made aware that certain learning styles are likely to improve their performance at higher learning levels, thereby encouraging some to consider employing alternative learning style strategies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>ENDNOTES</title>
        <ref id="d379e232a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e239" publication-type="other">
Myers, McCaulley, Quennk and Hammer (1998)</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d379e245" publication-type="other">
Myers (1998)</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d379e251" publication-type="other">
Wheeler (2001).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e258a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e265" publication-type="other">
http://www.engr.ncsu.edu/learningstyles/ilsweb.html</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e272a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e279" publication-type="other">
Felder and Spurlin *(2005)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d379e295a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e299" publication-type="other">
Bisping, T. and H. Patron, 2008. Personality type as a determinant of student
success in introductory general business courses, Academy of Educational
Leadership Journal 12(1), 35-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e312a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e316" publication-type="other">
Bloom, B., 1956. Taxonomy of Educational Objectives, the classification of
educational goals - Handbook I: Cognitive Domain. (David McKay Co., Inc,
New York).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e333" publication-type="other">
Borg, M. and S. Shapiro, 1996. Personality Type and Student Performance in
Principles of Economics, Journal of Economic Education 27: 3-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e343a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e347" publication-type="other">
Borg, M. and H. Stranahan, 2002. Personality Type and Student Performance in
Upper-Level Economics Courses: The Importance of Race and Gender, Journal
of Economic Education 33, 3-14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e361a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e365" publication-type="other">
Felder, R., and L. Silverman, 1988. Learning and Teaching Styles in Engineering
Education, Engineering Education 78(7) 674-681.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e375a1310">
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e381" publication-type="other">
Felder, R. and J. Spurlin, 2005. Applications, Reliability, and Validity of the Index
of Learning Styles, International Journal of Engineering 21(1), 103-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e391a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e395" publication-type="other">
Filbeck, G. and L. Smith, 1996. Learning Styles, Teaching Strategies, and Predictors
of Success for Students in Corporate F inance, Financial Practice and Education
6(1), 74-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e408a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e412" publication-type="other">
Gentry, J. and M. Helgsen, 1999. Using Learning Style Information to Improve the
Core Financial Management Course, Journal of Applied Finance 9, 59-69</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e422a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e426" publication-type="other">
Gregore, A. 1982. Gregore Style Delineator: Developmental Technical and
Administration Manual. (Gabriel Systems, Inc., Maynard, MA).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e440" publication-type="other">
Haider, T., A. Sinha and B. Chaudhary, 2010. An Investigation of relationship
between learning styles and performance of learners, International Journal of
Engineering Science and Technology 2(7), 2813-2819.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e454a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e458" publication-type="other">
Jessee, S., P. O'Neill, and R. Dosch, 2006. Matching student personality types and
learning preferences to teaching methodologies, Journal of Dental Education
70(6), 644-651.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e471a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e475" publication-type="other">
Kolb, D. A., 1984. Experiential Learning, (Prentice Hall, Englewood Cliffs, NJ).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e482a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e486" publication-type="other">
Lawrence, R. and L. Taylor, 2000. Student Personality Type versus Grading
Procedures in Intermediate Accounting Courses. Journal of Education for
Business 76(1), 28-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e499a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e503" publication-type="other">
McKeachie, W., 1995. Learning Styles Can Become Learning Strategies, The
National Teaching and Learning Forum 4(6), 1-3.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e513a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e517" publication-type="other">
Myers, Isabel B. 1998. Introduction to type, (Consulting Psychologists Press, Inc.,
Mountain View, CA), 6th edition.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e531" publication-type="other">
Myers, I., M. McCaulley, N. Quenk, and A. Hammer, 1998. MBTImanual: A guide
to the development and use of the Myers-Briggs type indicator, (Consulting
Psychologists Press, Inc., Mountain View, CA), 3rd edition.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e545a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e549" publication-type="other">
Nourayi, M. and A. Cherry, 1993. Accounting students' performance and
personality types, Journal of Education for Business 2
(November/December), 111-115.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e562a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e566" publication-type="other">
Oswick, C. and P. Barber, 1998. Personality type and performance in an introduct-
ory level accounting course: A research not e, Accounting Education 7,249-254.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e576a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e580" publication-type="other">
Pashler, H., M. McDaniel, D. Rohrer, and R. Bjork, 2009. Learning Styles:
Concepts and Evidence, Psychological Science in the Public Interest 9,105-119.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e590a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e594" publication-type="other">
Rasimah, A., M. Zurina, R. Rohaizad, U. Yeop, and M. Anuar, 2008. Students'
Learning Styles and Academic Performance. Presented at 22nd Annual SAS
Malaysia Forum, Kuala Lumpur Convention Center, July 15, 2008.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e611" publication-type="other">
Wheeler, P., 2001. The Myers-Briggs type indicator and applications to accounting
education research. Issues in Accounting Education, 16 (1), 125-148.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e625" publication-type="other">
Whittingham, K., 2006. Impact of Personality on Academic Performance of MBA
Students: Qualitative Versus Quantitative Courses, Decision Sciences Journal
of Innovative Education 4(2), 175-190.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d379e639a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d379e643" publication-type="other">
Ziegert, A., 2000. The Role of Personality Temperament and Student Learning in
Principles of Economics: Further Evidence, Journal of Economic Education 31,
307-322.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


