<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26142237</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Political Sentiment and Predictable Returns</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Jawad M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Addoum</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Alok</given-names>
                  <surname>Kumar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2016</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26142228</issue-id>
         <fpage>3471</fpage>
         <lpage>3518</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/26142237"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This study shows that shifts in political climate influence stock prices. As the party in power changes, there are systematic changes in the industry-level composition of investor portfolios, which weaken arbitrage forces and generate predictable patterns in industry returns. A trading strategy that attempts to exploit demand-based return predictability generates an annualized risk-adjusted performance of 6% during the 1939 to 2011 period. This evidence of predictability spans 17%–27% of the market and is stronger during periods of political transition. Our demand-based predictability pattern is distinct from cash flow-based predictability identified in the recent literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1177e291a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e298" publication-type="other">
See Santa-Clara and Valkanov (2003), Hill (2012), Zweig (2012), and Hulbert (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e305a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e314" publication-type="other">
For example, in May of 2008, 6 months before the presidential election, Jim Cramer, host of CNBC's Mad
Money, wrote an article in New York Magazine titled "The Presidential Portfolio." In the article, Cramer states
that the secret to investing in the period around presidential elections is "to identify the individual sectors and
stocks that will rise and fall under each hypothetical administration." He goes on to suggest that oil industry
stocks would suffer under an Obama administration, but that solar and wind power companies would benefit.
Further, Cramer suggests that an Obama win would hurt pharmaceuticals. In contrast, he states that a McCain
presidency would help the nuclear power and defense industries. Finally, Cramer instills a sense of urgency in
his readers, directing them to place their bets "before the big gains and losses have been taken."
Similarly, ahead of the 2012 election, Larry McDonald, a political risk expert, managing director, and head
of U.S. Macro Strategy at Société Generale, gave television interviews with Fox Business and CNBC in which he
outlined investment strategies under which investors could make money following either an Obama or a Romney
win. Terming these strategies the "Obama portfolio" and the "Romney portfolio," McDonald suggested that if
President Obama were to win, investors should buy HMO, insurance, food manufacturer, and alcohol stocks. In
contrast, if Romney were to win, McDonald suggested that investors should buy stocks in the financial, medical
devices, and defense industries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e365a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e372" publication-type="other">
Consistent with these findings, a significant proportion of respondents (about 40%) in the 55 to 65 age group of
a recent Allianz Life survey mention that they would choose a more conservative portfolio if the opposing party
wins the election. Also, using brokerage data, Bonaparte, Kumar, and Page (2012) show that when the political
climate is aligned with the political identity of investors, they increase portfolio allocations to risky assets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e388a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e395" publication-type="other">
By "mispricing," we mean that there are predictable patterns in returns that cannot be explained by existing
multifactor asset pricing models used to account for systematic risk.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e406a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e413" publication-type="other">
Although there is likely to be some divergence of opinions on the effect of a given candidate's victory on a
particular industry's fortunes, investors are likely to be influenced by the opinions of authorities in the media.
Thus, the trading activity of institutional and retail investors in politically sensitive sectors is likely to be correlated
around presidential elections. In Section 3.1, using portfolio holdings of retail and institutional investors, we
provide additional evidence of systematic demand shifts induced by changes in the political environment.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e432a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e439" publication-type="other">
Whereas investor demand is likely to be driven by perceived changes in expected cash flows during a new
administration, investors' perceptions in the months surrounding an election may not always reflect the eventual
outcomes of firms in politically sensitive industries. For example, in a Wall Street Journal article, Harder (2015)
asserts that when President Obama first took office in 2009, he was expected to be an adversary of oil and gas
companies. However, not only has he been less adversarial than initially feared, but his repeal of the 40-year-old
ban on oil exports is seen as a significant boon to the industry. Further, even within an industry, there is likely to
be substantial heterogeneity across firms in eventual outcomes during a president's time in office.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e465a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e472" publication-type="other">
We verify the accuracy of our generated stock assignments and benchmark portfolio returns over the 1975 to
2011 period using the data from Russ Wermers's website.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e482a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e489" publication-type="other">
The CQ Press Voting and Elections Collection provides outcome and voting data for presidential and
congressional elections. The collection dates back to 1824 for presidential and House elections, and to 1908
for Senate elections. The data is publicly available at: http://library.cqpress.com/elections/index.php.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e502a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e509" publication-type="other">
We thank Chris Pantzalis for sharing the PAI data with us.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e516a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e523" publication-type="other">
We also estimate political sensitivities with respect to Senate and House party indicators. These indicators are
based on whether the Republican Party holds the majority in the Senate or House, respectively. Similar to
Santa-Clara and Valkanov (2003), we find that the results based on these measures are statistically and
economically insignificant, suggesting that the executive branch has a much stronger effect on political sentiment
than the legislative branch of government, perhaps because it is more salient.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e543a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e550" publication-type="other">
We verify the efficacy of the election prediction model in our sample. Beginning with the 1952 election, we model
the popular vote as a function of GDP growth over the first two quarters of the election year, the incumbent's
June approval rating, and whether it is the incumbent party's first term in office. We use data from past elections
to fit this model. Then, using known values of these predictors in the year of the current election, we predict the
winner. We find that the model's prediction is correct for every election except the 1988 Republican win.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e569a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e576" publication-type="other">
In Appendix Table A. 1, we use a short sample of direct political sentiment measures to validate our key assumption
that the return-based political-sensitivity measures can capture the effects of partisan-based shifts in investor
sentiment. We find that the return-based political-sensitivity estimates capture the effects of political sentiment
on stock returns reasonably well.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e592a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e599" publication-type="other">
While our focus is on the political-sensitivity of domestic industry returns to changes in the U.S. political
environment, we also consider international portfolios. Specifically, we collect level-6 classification industries
from Datastream International for the following countries: Australia, Canada, France, Germany, Japan, and
the United Kingdom. We then estimate the political-sensitivity of each country-specific industry portfolio to
that country's party in power (left- or right-leaning), and subsequently form portfolios in a manner identical to
that in the main results of our paper. In addition, we estimate the political-sensitivity of international industry
portfolio returns to the U.S. presidential party. We find that the domestic political-sensitivity estimates do not
yield significant predictability in any of the six countries. However, we find that in three out of six instances,
the U.S.-based political-sensitivity estimates produce an economically profitable trading strategy, which is also
statistically significant at the 5% level. Further, in two of the remaining three countries, there is evidence of
predictability at the 10% level of statistical significance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e637a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e644" publication-type="other">
This constraint also motivates our choice of measuring political-sensitivity at the industry-level. Specifically,
industry portfolios have valid return observations over long periods of time. In contrast, this is not true for many
stocks in the CRSP universe. For such stocks with insufficient observations, we would be forced to either discard
them from analysis or come up with an ad-hoc alternative measure of political sensitivity. Evidence from the style
investing literature (e.g., Barberis and Shleifer 2003), which shows that investors tend to categorize stocks into
different styles and invest depending on the relative performance of these styles, suggests that our industry-level
approach is reasonable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e670a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e677" publication-type="other">
In untabulated results, we verify that our main results are not affected by this choice. Our results are similar if
we focus on the post-1952 sample period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e687a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e694" publication-type="other">
We experiment with alternative extreme portfolio sizes and find similar results. See Table 4, Panel C.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e702a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e709" publication-type="other">
Before July 1969, classifying firms according to the Fama and French (1997) SIC-code classifications yields
fewer than forty-eight industries. Between January 1939 and June 1963, there are forty-three industries in total
and thirty-three industries sorted across the three middle portfolios. Between July 1963 and June 1969, there are
forty-seven industries in total and thirty-seven industries sorted across the three middle portfolios.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e725a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e732" publication-type="other">
Naturally, this pattern may raise the potential concern that our political-sensitivity prediction model is somehow
repackaging momentum returns. We address this concern in three ways. First, in a related paper, Addoum
et al. (2016) show that holding the political-sensitivity measure constant for successive one year periods, which
effectively purges political sensitivities of price momentum information, still yields a political-sensitivity hedge
portfolio return that can explain a significant portion of momentum alphas. In other words, political-sensitivity
explains momentum returns, and not the other way around. Second, Addoum et al. (2016) show that in November
of switching-party election years, a period that we show is the most profitable for the political-sensitivity hedge
portfolio, past returns are actually monotonically decreasing across the political-sensitivity portfolios instead of
increasing. Third, throughout the paper we report characteristic-adjusted hedge portfolio returns, in addition to
presenting factor model regressions where we control for momentum returns and Fama and MacBeth (1973)
cross-sectional regressions where we control for past returns. Overall, we conclude that our political-sensitivity
prediction model does not indirectly reflect the known evidence on price momentum.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e774a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e781" publication-type="other">
Though there is significant variation in the composition of politically sensitive portfolios across presidential
administrations, the composition of portfolios is relatively stable during a given administration. Specifically, a
given industry currently in the Long (Short) portfolio transitions out of the portfolio with average frequency
of 7.65% (7.01%) in the next month. These transitions are more prevalent during the 6 months surrounding
presidential elections. During these months, a given industry in the Long (Short) portfolio exits the portfolio in
the following month with average frequency of 14.07% (14.26%).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e804a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e811" publication-type="other">
See Barber and Odean (2000) for additional details about the brokerage data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e818a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e825" publication-type="other">
The data are publicly available from Brian Bushee's website (http://acct3.wharton.upenn.edu/faculty/bushee/).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e832a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e839" publication-type="other">
This evidence is consistent with the relatively long-term investment objectives of these investor groups. In
particular, bank trusts, insurance companies, and pension and endowment funds would likely be more interested
in immunizing their long-term liabilities than in responding to the results of presidential elections when making
portfolio decisions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e856a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e863" publication-type="other">
Because we hold stock prices fixed over the sample period, the rebalancing results are driven by changes in the
number of shares held by investors. This admits the possibility that higher portfolio allocations among retail
investors, mutual funds, and investment companies could be driven by an increase (decrease) in the number of
shares outstanding of politically favored (unfavored) firms (e.g., because of strategic IPOs or SEOs). We address
this possibility by removing stocks that have a change in the number of shares outstanding during the ± 12-month
analysis window, and verify that our results are qualitatively unchanged. We thank an anonymous referee for
pointing this out.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e889a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e896" publication-type="other">
We do not attempt to quantify the aggregate reallocations of all U.S. retail investors implied by extrapolating this
estimate. Instead, we argue that the brokerage sample represents the actions of retail traders and that the trading
patterns we identify can influence stock returns. This is consistent with the approach and findings of the prior
literature, which shows that there is a strong correlation between retail trading and stock returns (e.g., Kumar
and Lee 2006; Barber, Odean, and Zhu 2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e915a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e922" publication-type="other">
In untabulated results, we find that the policy and macroeconomic uncertainty measures of Baker, Bloom, and
Davis (2013) and Jurado, Ludvigson, and Ng (2015), respectively, increase significantly during these periods.
This finding also suggests that such periods can be characterized as having increased risks for arbitrageurs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e935a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e942" publication-type="other">
This finding is consistent with those of Kelly, Pastor, and Veronesi (2015), who document that political uncertainty
is priced in equity options, and that options whose lives span elections tend to be more expensive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e952a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e959" publication-type="other">
Because of the inclusion of month fixed effects, we do not include the presidential election period indicator.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e966a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e975" publication-type="other">
In untabulated results, we also consider the role of geography-based political-sensitivity. Specifically, we form
state portfolios by grouping firms sharing a common headquarters state. We then calculate value-weighted state
portfolio returns and estimate the sensitivity of state portfolio returns to the party in power. We perform a
double-sort based on the political-sensitivity of each firm's industry and the political-sensitivity of each firm's
headquarters state. The evidence from the double-sort suggests that there is an interaction between industry-based
and geography-based political sensitivities, with the industry-based sensitivities being more important for return
predictability.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1002a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1009" publication-type="other">
Specifically, we construct characteristic-adjusted industry portfolio returns by matching each stock, in each
quarter, to one of 125 (5x5x5) benchmark portfolios on the dimensions of size, book-to-market ratio, and
momentum, as in Daniel et al. (1997). We then calculate the return of each stock, each month, in excess of
the corresponding passive portfolio return. We aggregate stock-level excess returns to the industry-level using
the SIC code definitions of the forty-eight Fama and French (1997) industry portfolios available from Kenneth
French's website.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1032a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1041" publication-type="other">
In untabulated tests, we follow the approach of Grundy and Martin (2001) and assess how trading costs affect
these results. Specifically, we calculate the levels of roundtrip transaction costs that would render the trading
strategy returns statistically insignificant at the 5% level or would completely dominate the trading strategy
returns. We find that the raw (characteristic-adjusted) Long-Short trading strategy returns remain statistically
significant at the 5% level after roundtrip transaction costs up to 1.93% (1.20%). Further, the trading strategy
remains profitable on average up to roundtrip transaction costs of 3.76% (2.44%). These estimates suggest that
the predictability we document does not exist because of a high-turnover trading strategy that is economically
unsustainable for arbitrageurs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1070a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1077" publication-type="other">
While the years 1999 and 2000 exhibit the strongest Long-Short portfolio returns, they do not drive the results.
Specifically, when we exclude observations in 1999 and 2000 from the sample, the average Long-Short portfolio
return is 0.546% (r-statistic = 3.78).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1090a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1097" publication-type="other">
As a robustness check, we also conduct the analysis in Table 5 using alternative ±3-, 6-, and 12-month windows
surrounding elections. These results are presented in Appendix Table A.3, and they indicate that the basic
conclusions of the analysis in Table 5 hold regardless of the length of the observation window.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1110a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1117" publication-type="other">
We also split the sample of challenger victories on the basis of close versus blowout elections. We find that
our evidence of predictability is stronger in the months surrounding close elections than in periods surrounding
blowouts. Specifically, the monthly Long—Short portfolio return is 1.730% (r-statistic = 2.27) for close elections
versus 0.590% (/-statistic = 1.15) for blowout elections.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1133a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1142" publication-type="other">
The vast majority of firms that contribute to PACs give money to PACs affiliated with both parties. We have
also considered classifying firms as leaning toward the Democratic or Republican party, based on which party's
PACs they contribute more money to. We find that the Long-Short portfolio returns constructed using firms in
the two groups are neither statistically nor economically different. Further, we have also considered classifying
firm-level party affiliation based on the net political contributions of firm executives. Similarly, we find that the
evidence of predictability does not statistically differ between firms with Democrat- and Republican-leaning
executives.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1169a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1176" publication-type="other">
We also conduct the Fama and MacBeth (1973) type regression analysis at the stock-level and find very similar
results. For brevity, we discuss only the industry-level analysis, and present the stock-level results in Appendix
Table A.4.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1189a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1196" publication-type="other">
Kim, Pantzalis, and Park (2012) construct the political alignment index (PAI) based on the location of firm
headquarters, which measures the degree of political alignment between a state's leading politicians and the
presidential party.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1209a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1216" publication-type="other">
We also conduct alternative tests of whether the return predictability we document is distinct from predictability
generated by the cash-flow channels highlighted in related studies. Specifically, we show that trading strategies
constructed using industry-firms with low government spending exposure, headquartered in low federal spending
states, and headquartered in low political alignment states remain profitable. Further, we show that our evidence
of return predictability exists during both Republican and Democratic presidencies and is robust to congressional
gridlock. Thus, our results do not somehow reflect the presidential puzzle identified in Santa-Clara and Valkanov
(2003). See Appendix Tables A.5 and A.6 for details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1242a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1249" publication-type="other">
Whereas investor demand is likely to be driven by perceived changes in expected cash flows during a new
administration, investors' perceptions in the months surrounding an election may not always reflect the eventual
outcomes of firms in politically sensitive industries. For example, in a Wall Street Journal article, Harder (2015)
asserts that when President Obama first took office in 2009, he was expected to be an adversary of oil and gas
companies. However, not only has he been less adversarial than initially feared, but his repeal of the 40-year-old
ban on oil exports is seen as a significant boon to the industry. Further, even within an industry, there is likely to
be substantial heterogeneity across firms in eventual outcomes during a president's time in office.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1177e1275a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1177e1282" publication-type="other">
We cannot perform our asset pricing tests using the direct political sentiment data because they are available
only for the 1997 to 2006 period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1177e1301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1305" publication-type="other">
Abramowitz, A. I. 1988. An improved model for predicting presidential election outcomes. Political Science and
Politics 21:843-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1319" publication-type="other">
. 2008. It's about time: Forecasting the 2008 presidential election with the time-for-change model.
International Journal of Forecasting 24:209-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1329a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1333" publication-type="other">
Addoum, J. M., S. Delikouras, D. Ke, and A. Kumar. 2014. Under-reaction to political information
and price momentum. Working Paper, Cornell University and University of Miami. Available at:
http://ssrn.com/abstract=2425204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1346a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1350" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., and J. Wurgler. 2006. Investor sentiment and the cross-section of stock returns. Journal of Finance
61:1645-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1361a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1365" publication-type="other">
Baker, S. R., N. Bloom, and S. J. Davis. 2013. Measuring economic policy uncertainty. Working Paper, Stanford
University and University of Chicago. Available at: http://ssrn.com/abstract=2198490.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1375a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1379" publication-type="other">
Barber, B. M., and T. Odean. 2000. Trading is hazardous to your wealth: The common stock investment
performance of individual investors. Journal of Finance 55:773-806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1389a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1393" publication-type="other">
Barber, B. M., T. Odean, and N. Zhu. 2009. Do retail trades move markets?. Review of Financial Studies
22:151-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1403a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1407" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., and A. Shleifer. 2003. Style investing. Journal of Financial Economics 68:161-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1414a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1418" publication-type="other">
Belo, F., V. D. Gala, and J. Li. 2013. Government spending, political cycles, and the cross section of stock returns.
Journal of Financial Economics 107:305-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1428a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1432" publication-type="other">
Bollerslev, T.. 1990. Modelling the coherence in short-run nominal exchange rates: A multivariate generalized
arch model. Review of Economics and Statistics 72:498-505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1443a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1447" publication-type="other">
Bonaparte, Y., A. Kumar, and J. Page. 2012. Political climate, optimism, and investment decisions. Working
Paper, University of Miami. Available at: http://ssrn.com/abstract= 1509168.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1457a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1461" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1468a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1472" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., and A. Frazzini. 2008. Economic links and predictable returns. Journal of Finance 63:
1977-2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1482a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1486" publication-type="other">
Cooper, M. J., H. Gulen, and A. V. Ovtchinnikov. 2010. Corporate political contributions and stock returns.
Journal of Finance 65:687-724.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1496a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1500" publication-type="other">
Daniel, K. D., M. Grinblatt, S. Titman, and R. Wermers. 1997. Measuring mutual fund performance with
characteristic-based benchmarks. Journal of Finance 52:1035-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1510a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1514" publication-type="other">
De Long, J. B., A. Shleifer, L. H. Summers, and R. J. Waldmann. 1990. Noise trader risk in financial markets.
Journal of Political Economy 98:703-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1525a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1529" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1992. The cross-section of expected stock returns. Journal of Finance 47:
427-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1539a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1543" publication-type="other">
. 1997. Industry costs of equity. Journal of Financial Economics 43:153-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1550a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1554" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and J. D. MacBeth. 1973. Risk, return, and equilibrium: Empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy
81:607-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1564a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1568" publication-type="other">
Gromb, D., and D. Vayanos. 2010. Limits of arbitrage: The state of the theory. Annual Review of Financial
Economics 2:251-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1578a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1582" publication-type="other">
Grundy, B. D., and J. S. Martin. 2001. Understanding the nature of the risks and the source of the rewards to
momentum investing. Review of Financial Studies 14:29-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1592a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1596" publication-type="other">
Hanson, S. G., and A. Sunderam. 2014. The growth and limits of arbitrage: Evidence from short interest. Review
of Financial Studies 27:1238-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1607a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1611" publication-type="other">
Harder, A. 2015. Obama has been more friend than foe to oil industry. Wall Street Journal. Retrieved from
http://blogs.wsj.com/washwire/2015/12/23/obama-has-been-more-friend-than-foe-to-oil-industry (accessed
February 29, 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1624a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1628" publication-type="other">
Hill, C. 2012. Should the election change your investment mix?. MarketWatch. Retrieved from
http://www.marketwatch.com/story/should-the-election-change-your-investment-mix-2012-10-23 (accessed
February 29, 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1641a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1645" publication-type="other">
Hong, H., and M. Kacperczyk. 2009. The price of sin: The effects of social norms on markets. Journal of Financial
Economics 93:15-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1655a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1659" publication-type="other">
Hong, H. G., and L. Kostovetsky. 2012. Red and blue investing: Values and finance. Journal of Financial
Economics 103:1-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1669a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1673" publication-type="other">
Hulbert, M. 2012. The stock market and election politics: How will market react on day after election?. Market-
Watch. Retrieved from http://www.marketwatch.com/story/the-stock-market-and-election-politics-2012-10-23
(accessed February 29, 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1686a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1690" publication-type="other">
Hutton, I., D. Jiang, and A. Kumar. 2014. Corporate policies of Republican managers. Journal of Financial and
Quantitative Analysis 49: 1279-1310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1701a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1705" publication-type="other">
Jones, J. M. 2009. In U.S., cautious optimism about economy in year ahead. Gallup.com. Retrieved from
http://www.gallup.eom/poll/l 23209/cautious-optimism-about-economy-yearahead.aspx (accessed Fenruary 29,
2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1718a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1722" publication-type="other">
Jurado, K., S. C. Ludvigson, and S. Ng. 2015. Measuring uncertainty. American Economic Review 105:
1177-1216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1736" publication-type="other">
Kelly, B. T., L. Pastor, and P. Veronesi. 2015. The price of political uncertainty: Theory and evidence from the
option market. Working Paper, University of Chicago. Available at: http://ssrn.com/abstract=2356588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1746a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1750" publication-type="other">
Kim, C. F., C. Pantzalis, and J. C. Park. 2012. Political geography and stock returns: The value and risk
implications of proximity to political power. Journal of Financial Economics 106:196-228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1760a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1764" publication-type="other">
Korniotis, G M., and A. Kumar. 2013. State-level business cycles and local return predictability. Journal of
Finance 68:1037-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1774a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1778" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A. 2009. Dynamic style preferences of individual investors and stock returns. Journal of Financial and
Quantitative Analysis 44:607—40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1793" publication-type="other">
Kumar, A. and C. Lee. 2006. Retail investor sentiment and return comovements. Journal of Finance 61:2451—86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1800a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1804" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., and S. Ludvigson. 2001. Consumption, aggregate wealth, and expected stock returns. Journal of
Finance 21:815—49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1814a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1818" publication-type="other">
Newey, W. K., and K. D. West. 1987. A simple, positive semi-definite heteroskedasticity and auto-correlation
consistent variance-covariance matrix. Econometrica 55: 703-08.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1828a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1832" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and P. Veronesi. 2013. Political uncertainty and risk premia. Journal of Financial Economics 110:
520-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1842a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1846" publication-type="other">
Poole, K. T., and H. Rosenthal. 1997. Congress: A political-economic history of roll call voting (Oxford: Oxford
University Press).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1856a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1860" publication-type="other">
. 2001. D-nominate after 10 years: A comparative update to Congress: A political-economic history of
roll-call voting. Legislative Studies Quarterly 26:5-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1871a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1875" publication-type="other">
Santa-Clara, P., and R. Valkanov. 2003. The presidential puzzle: Political cycles and the stock market. Journal
of Finance 58:1841-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1885a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1889" publication-type="other">
Savickas, R. 2003. Event-induced volatility and tests for abnormal performance. Journal of Financial Research
26:165-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1899a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1903" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A. 1986. Do demand curves for stocks slope down? Journal of Finance 41:579-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1177e1910a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1177e1914" publication-type="other">
Zweig, J. 2012. The winner for investors is. Wall Street Journal. Oct. 20. Bl.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
