<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">83</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">287</issue>
         <issue-id>i24488223</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24488274</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MULTILEVEL PRECONDITIONERS FOR DISCONTINUOUS GALERKIN APPROXIMATIONS OF ELLIPTIC PROBLEMS WITH JUMP COEFFICIENTS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>BLANCA AYUSO</given-names>
                  <surname>DE DIOS</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>MICHAEL</given-names>
                  <surname>HOLST</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>YUNRONG</given-names>
                  <surname>ZHU</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>LUDMIL</given-names>
                  <surname>ZIKATANOV</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1083</fpage>
         <lpage>1120</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2014 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24488274"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We introduce and analyze two-level and multilevel preconditioners for a family of Interior Penalty (IP) discontinuous Galerkin (DG) discretizations of second order elliptic problems with large jumps in the diffusion coefficient. Our approach to IPDG-type methods is based on a splitting of the DG space into two components that are orthogonal in the energy inner product naturally induced by the methods. As a result, the methods and their analysis depend in a crucial way on the diffusion coefficient of the problem. The analysis of the proposed preconditioners is presented for both symmetric and non-symmetric IP schemes; dealing simultaneously with the jump in the diffusion coefficient and the non-nested character of the relevant discrete spaces presents additional difficulties in the analysis, which precludes a simple extension of existing results. However, we are able to establish robustness (with respect to the diffusion coefficient) and near-optimality (up to a logarithmic term depending on the mesh size) for both two-level and BPX-type preconditioners, by using a more refined Conjugate Gradient theory. Useful by-products of the analysis are the supporting results on the construction and analysis of simple, efficient and robust two-level and multilevel preconditioners for non-conforming Crouzeix-Raviart discretizations of elliptic problems with jump coefficients. Following the analysis, we present a sequence of detailed numerical results which verify the theory and illustrate the performance of the methods.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d2143228e292a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e299" publication-type="other">
Shmuel Agmon, Lectures on elliptic boundary value problems, Prepared for publication by
B. Frank Jones, Jr. with the assistance of George W. Batten, Jr., Van Nostrand Mathe-
matical Studies, No. 2, D. Van Nostrand Co., Inc., Princeton, N.J.-Toronto-London, 1965.
MR0178246 (31 #2504)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e315a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e322" publication-type="other">
Paola F. Antonietti and Blanca Ayuso, Schwarz domain decomposition preconditioners for
discontinuous Galerkin approximations of elliptic problems: non-overlapping case, M2AN
Math. Model. Numer. Anal. 41 (2007), no. 1, 21-54, DOI 10.1051/m2an:2007006. MR2323689
(2008b:65140)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e338a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e345" publication-type="other">
Paola F. Antonietti and Blanca Ayuso, Multiplicative Schwarz methods for discontinuous
Galerkin approximations of elliptic problems, M2AN Math. Model. Numer. Anal. 42 (2008),
no. 3, 443-469, DOI 10.1051/m2an:2008012. MR2423794 (2009f:65243)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e358a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e365" publication-type="other">
Paola F. Antonietti and Blanca Ayuso, Two-level Schwarz preconditioners for super penalty
discontinuous Galerkin methods, Commun. Comput. Phys. 5 (2009), no. 2-4, 398-412.
MR2513693 (2010d:65310)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e379a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e386" publication-type="other">
Douglas N. Arnold, Franco Brezzi, Bernardo Cockburn, and L. Donatella Marini, Unified
analysis of discontinuous Galerkin methods for elliptic problems, SIAM J. Numer. Anal. 39
(2001/02), no. 5, 1749-1779, DOI 10.1137/S0036142901384162. MR1885715 (2002k:65183)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e399a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e406" publication-type="other">
Owe Axelsson, Iterative solution methods, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, 1994.
MR1276069 (95f:65005)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e416a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e423" publication-type="other">
Owe Axelsson, Iteration number for the conjugate gradient method, Math. Comput. Simula-
tion 61 (2003), no. 3-6, 421-435, DOI 10.1016/S0378-4754(02)00097-6. MODELLING 2001
(Pilsen). MR1984142 (2004g:65031)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e436a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e443" publication-type="other">
B. Ayuso de Dios, F. Brezzi, O. Havle, and L. D. Marini. L2-estimates for the DG IIPG-0
scheme. Numer. Methods Partial Differential Equations, 28(5):1440-1465, 2012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e453a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e460" publication-type="other">
B. Ayuso de Dios, M. Hoist, Y. Zhu, and L. Zikatanov. Multilevel preconditioners for discon-
tinuous Galerkin approximations of elliptic problems with jump coefficients. Arxiv preprint
arXiv:1012.1287, 2010.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e473a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e480" publication-type="other">
Blanca Ayuso de Dios and Ludmil Zikatanov, Uniformly convergent iterative methods for
discontinuous Galerkin discretizations, J. Sci. Comput. 40 (2009), no. 1-3, 4—36, DOI
10.1007/sl0915-009-9293-l. MR2511726 (2010d:65311)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e494a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e501" publication-type="other">
A. T. Barker, S. C. Brenner, E.-H. Park, and L.-Y. Sung, Two-level additive Schwarz pre-
conditioned for a weakly over-penalized symmetric interior penalty method, J. Sci. Comput.
47 (2011), no. 1, 27-49, DOI 10.1007/sl0915-010-9419-5. MR2781147 (2012f:65184)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e514a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e521" publication-type="other">
James H. Bramble, Joseph E. Pasciak, and Alfred H. Schatz, The construction of precondi-
tioned for elliptic problems by sub structuring. IV, Math. Comp. 53 (1989), no. 187, 1-24,
DOI 10.2307/2008346. MR970699 (89m:65098)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e534a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e541" publication-type="other">
James H. Bramble, Joseph E. Pasciak, and Jinchao Xu, Parallel multilevel preconditioners,
Math. Comp. 55 (1990), no. 191, 1-22, DOI 10.2307/2008789. MR1023042 (90k:65170)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e551a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e558" publication-type="other">
James H. Bramble and Jinchao Xu, Some estimates for a weighted L2 projection, Math.
Comp. 56 (1991), no. 194, 463-476, DOI 10.2307/2008391. MR1066830 (91k:65140)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e568a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e575" publication-type="other">
A. Brandt, S. F. McCormick, and J. W. Ruge. Algebraic multigrid (AMG) for automatic
multigrid solution with application to geodetic computations. Tech. Rep., Institute for Com-
putational Studies, Colorado State University, 1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e588a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e595" publication-type="other">
Susanne C. Brenner, Poincare-Friedrichs inequalities for piecewise H1 functions, SIAM J.
Numer. Anal. 41 (2003), no. 1, 306-324, DOI 10.1137/S0036142902401311. MR1974504
(2004d:65140)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e609a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e616" publication-type="other">
S. C. Brenner, J. Cui, and L.-Y. Sung, Multigrid methods for the symmetric interior penalty
method on graded meshes, Numer. Linear Algebra Appl. 16 (2009), no. 6, 481-501, DOI
10.1002/nla.630. MR2522959 (2010f:65248)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e629a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e636" publication-type="other">
Susanne C. Brenner and Luke Owens, A W-cycle algorithm for a weakly over-penalized inte-
rior penalty method, Comput. Methods Appl. Mech. Engrg. 196 (2007), no. 37-40, 3823—3832,
DOI 10.1016/j.cma.2007.02.011. MR2340007 (2008i:65286)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e649a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e656" publication-type="other">
Susanne C. Brenner and Luke Owens, A weakly over-penalized non-symmetric interior
penalty method, JNAIAM J. Numer. Anal. Ind. Appl. Math. 2 (2007), no. 1-2, 35-48.
MR2332345 (2008c:65315)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e669a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e676" publication-type="other">
Susanne C. Brenner and Jie Zhao, Convergence of multigrid algorithms for interior
penalty methods, Appl. Numer. Anal. Comput. Math. 2 (2005), no. 1, 3-18, DOI
10.1002/anac.200410019. MR2157481 (2006c:65116)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e689a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e696" publication-type="other">
F. Brezzi, B. Cockburn, L. D. Marini, and E. Siili, Stabilization mechanisms in discontinuous
Galerkin finite element methods, Comput. Methods Appl. Mech. Engrg. 195 (2006), no. 25-
28, 3293-3310, DOI 10.1016/j.cma.2005.06.015. MR2220920 (2006m:65256)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e709a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e716" publication-type="other">
Kolja Brix, Martin Campos Pinto, and Wolfgang Dahmen, A multilevel preconditioner for
the interior penalty discontinuous Galerkin method, SIAM J. Numer. Anal. 46 (2008), no. 5,
2742-2768, DOI 10.1137/07069691X. MR2421055 (2009c:65069)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e730a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e737" publication-type="other">
Kolja Brix, Martin Campos Pinto, Wolfgang Dahmen, and Ralf Massjung, Multilevel precon-
ditioners for the interior penalty discontinuous Galerkin method. II. Quantitative studies,
Commun. Comput. Phys. 5 (2009), no. 2-4, 296-325. MR2513688 (2010b:65065)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e750a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e757" publication-type="other">
E. Burman and B. Stamm, Low order discontinuous Galerkin methods for second order ellip-
tic problems, SIAM J. Numer. Anal. 47 (2008/09), no. 1, 508-533, DOI 10.1137/070685105.
MR2475950 (2009j:65309)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e770a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e777" publication-type="other">
Erik Burman and Paolo Zunino, A domain decomposition method based on weighted interior
penalties for advection-diffusion-reaction problems, SIAM J. Numer. Anal. 44 (2006), no. 4,
1612-1638 (electronic), DOI 10.1137/050634736. MR2257119 (2007m:65123)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e790a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e797" publication-type="other">
L. Chen, M. Hoist, J. Xu, and Y. Zhu. Local multilevel preconditioners for elliptic equations
with jump coefficients on bisection grids. Arxiv preprint arXiv: 1006.3277, 2010.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e807a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e814" publication-type="other">
Durkbin Cho, Jinchao Xu, and Ludmil Zikatanov, New estimates for the rate of convergence
of the method of subspace corrections, Numer. Math. Theory Methods Appl. 1 (2008), no. 1,
44-56. MR2401666 (2009b:65077)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e827a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e834" publication-type="other">
Philippe G. Ciarlet, The finite element method for elliptic problems, North-Holland Publish-
ing Co., Amsterdam, 1978. Studies in Mathematics and its Applications, Vol. 4. MR0520174
(58 #25001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e848a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e855" publication-type="other">
B. Cockburn, O. Dubois, J. Gopalakrishnan, and S. Tan. Multigrid for an HDG method.
Submitted, 2010.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e865a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e872" publication-type="other">
Daniele A. Di Pietro, Alexandre Ern, and Jean-Luc Guerrnond, Discontinuous Galerkin meth-
ods for anisotropic semidefinite diffusion with advection, SIAM J. Numer. Anal. 46 (2008),
no. 2, 805-831, DOI 10.1137/060676106. MR2383212 (2008k:65240)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e885a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e892" publication-type="other">
Veselin A. Dobrev, Raytcho D. Lazarov, Panayot S. Vassilevski, and Ludmil T. Zikatanov,
Two-level preconditioning of discontinuous Galerkin approximations of second-order elliptic
equations, Numer. Linear Algebra Appl. 13 (2006), no. 9, 753—770, DOI 10.1002/nla.504.
MR2269798 (2007i:65088)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e908a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e915" publication-type="other">
Vi't Dolejsf, Miloslav Feistauer, and Jin Felcman, On the discrete Priedrichs inequality for
nonconforming finite elements, Numer. Funct. Anal. Optim. 20 (1999), no. 5-6, 437—447,
DOI 10.1080/01630569908816904. MR1704954 (2000i:65183)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e928a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e935" publication-type="other">
Maksymilian Dryja, On discontinuous Galerkin methods for elliptic problems with discontinu-
ous coefficients, Comput. Methods Appl. Math. 3 (2003), no. 1, 76-85 (electronic). Dedicated
to Raytcho Lazarov. MR2002258 (2004i:65120)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e948a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e955" publication-type="other">
Maksymilian Dryja, Juan Galvis, and Marcus Sarkis, BDDC methods for discontinuous
Galerkin discretization of elliptic problems, J. Complexity 23 (2007), no. 4-6, 715-739, DOI
10.1016/j.jco.2007.02.003. MR2372024 (2008m:65316)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e969a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e976" publication-type="other">
Maksymilian Dryja, Juan Galvis, and Marcus Sarkis, Neumann-Neumann methods for a
DG discretization on geometrically nonconforming substructures, Numer. Methods Partial
Differential Equations 28 (2012), no. 4, 1194-1226, DOI 10.1002/num.20678. MR2914789</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e989a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e996" publication-type="other">
M. Dryja and M. Sarkis. FETI-DP method for DG discretization of elliptic problems with
discontinuous coefficients. Technical report, Instituto de Matematica Pura e Aplicada, Brazil,
2010. submitted.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1009a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1016" publication-type="other">
Maksymilian Dryja, Barry F. Smith, and Olof B. Widlund, Schwarz analysis of iterative
sub structuring algorithms for elliptic problems in three dimensions, SIAM J. Numer. Anal.
31 (1994), no. 6, 1662-1694, DOI 10.1137/0731086. MR1302680 (95m:65211)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1029a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1036" publication-type="other">
Maksymilian Dryja and Olof B. Widlund, Schwarz methods of Neumann-Neumann type for
three-dimensional elliptic finite element problems, Comm. Pure Appl. Math. 48 (1995), no. 2,
121-155, DOI 10.1002/cpa.3160480203. MR1319698 (96d:65199)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1049a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1056" publication-type="other">
Xiaobing Feng and Ohannes A. Karakashian, Two-level additive Schwarz methods for a dis-
continuous Galerkin approximation of second order elliptic problems, SIAM J. Numer. Anal.
39 (2001), no. 4, 1343-1365 (electronic), DOI 10.1137/S0036142900378480. MR1870847
(2003a:65113)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1072a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1079" publication-type="other">
Juan Galvis and Yalchin Efendiev, Domain decomposition preconditioners for multiscale
flows in high-contrast media, Multiscale Model. Simul. 8 (2010), no. 4, 1461—1483, DOI
10.1137/090751190. MR2718268 (2011h:65246)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1093a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1100" publication-type="other">
G. H. Golub and C. F. Van Loan. Matrix computations. Johns Hopkins Studies in the Math-
ematical Sciences. Johns Hopkins University Press, Baltimore, MD, third edition, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1110a1310">
            <label>42</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1117" publication-type="other">
J. Gopalakrishnan and G. Kanschat, A multilevel discontinuous Galerkin method, Numer.
Math. 95 (2003), no. 3, 527-550, DOI 10.1007/s002110200392. MR2012931 (2004m:65179)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1127a1310">
            <label>43</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1134" publication-type="other">
I. G. Graham and M. J. Hagger, Unstructured additive Schwarz-conjugate gradient method
for elliptic problems with highly discontinuous coefficients, SIAM J. Sci. Comput. 20 (1999),
no. 6, 2041-2066, DOI 10.1137/S1064827596305593. MR1703306 (2000h:65179)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1147a1310">
            <label>44</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1154" publication-type="other">
M. Griebel and P. Oswald, On the abstract theory of additive and multiplicative Schwarz al-
gorithms, Numer. Math. 70 (1995), no. 2, 163-180, DOI 10.1007/s002110050115. MR1324736
(96a:65164)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1167a1310">
            <label>45</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1174" publication-type="other">
Wolfgang Hackbusch, Iterative solution of large sparse systems of equations, Applied Math-
ematical Sciences, vol. 95, Springer-Verlag, New York, 1994. Translated and revised from the
1991 German original. MR1247457 (94k:65002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1187a1310">
            <label>46</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1194" publication-type="other">
Axel Klawonn, Olof B. Widlund, and Maksymilian Dryja, Dual-primal FETI methods
for three-dimensional elliptic problems with heterogeneous coefficients, SIAM J. Numer.
Anal. 40 (2002), no. 1, 159-179 (electronic), DOI 10.1137/S0036142901388081. MR1921914
(2003g:65044)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1211a1310">
            <label>47</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1218" publication-type="other">
Ralf Kornhuber, Ronald Hoppe, Jacques Periaux, Olivier Pironneau, Olof Widlund, and
Jinchao Xu (eds.), Domain decomposition methods in science and engineering, Lecture Notes
in Computational Science and Engineering, vol. 40, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 2005. Papers from
the 15th International Conference on Domain Decomposition held at the Freie Universitat
Berlin, Berlin, July 21-25, 2003. MR2230692 (2007b:65005)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1237a1310">
            <label>48</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1244" publication-type="other">
J. K. Kraus and S. K. Tomar, A multilevel method for discontinuous Galerkin approximation
of three-dimensional anisotropic elliptic problems, Numer. Linear Algebra Appl. 15 (2008),
no. 5, 417-438, DOI 10.1002/nla.544. MR2423513 (2009f:65251)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1257a1310">
            <label>49</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1264" publication-type="other">
Johannes K. Kraus and Satyendra K. Tomar, Multilevel preconditioning of two-dimensional
elliptic problems discretized by a class of discontinuous Galerkin methods, SIAM J. Sci.
Comput. 30 (2008), no. 2, 684-706, DOI 10.1137/060667372. MR2385881 (2009b:65313)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1277a1310">
            <label>50</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1284" publication-type="other">
Jan Mandel and Marian Brezina, Balancing domain decomposition for problems with large
jumps in coefficients, Math. Comp. 65 (1996), no. 216, 1387—1401, DOI 10.1090/S0025-5718-
96-00757-0. MR1351204 (97a:65109)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1297a1310">
            <label>51</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1304" publication-type="other">
Peter Oswald, Multilevel finite element approximation, Teubner Skripten zur Numerik. [Teub-
ner Scripts on Numerical Mathematics], B. G. Teubner, Stuttgart, 1994. Theory and appli-
cations. MR1312165 (95k:65110)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1317a1310">
            <label>52</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1324" publication-type="other">
Clemens Pechstein and Robert Scheichl, Weighted Poincare inequalities and applications in
domain decomposition, Domain decomposition methods in science and engineering XIX, Lect.
Notes Comput. Sci. Eng., vol. 78, Springer, Heidelberg, 2011, pp. 197-204, DOI 10.1007/978-
3-642-11304-8-21. MR2867660</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1341a1310">
            <label>53</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1348" publication-type="other">
C. Pechstein and R. Scheichl. Weighted Poincare inequalities and applications in domain
decomposition, Lect. Notes Comput. Sci. Eng., 78, Springer, Heidelberg, 2011. MR2867660</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1358a1310">
            <label>54</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1365" publication-type="other">
F. Prill, M. Lukacova-Medvidova, and R. Hartmann, Smoothed aggregation multigrid for the
discontinuous Galerkin method, SIAM J. Sci. Comput. 31 (2009), no. 5, 3503-3528, DOI
10.1137/080728457. MR2538866 (2010h:65209)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1378a1310">
            <label>55</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1385" publication-type="other">
Marcus Sarkis, Multilevel methods for P nonconforming finite elements and discontinuous
coefficients in three dimensions, (University Park, PA, 1993), Contemp. Math., vol. 180,
Amer. Math. Soc., Providence, RI, 1994, pp. 119-124, DOI 10.1090/conm/180/01963.
MR1312384</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1401a1310">
            <label>56</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1408" publication-type="other">
Marcus Sarkis, Nonstandard coarse spaces and Schwarz methods for elliptic problems with
discontinuous coefficients using non-conforming elements, Numer. Math. 77 (1997), no. 3,
383-406, DOI 10.1007/s002110050292. MR1469678 (98m:65199)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1421a1310">
            <label>57</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1428" publication-type="other">
Robert Scheichl, Panayot S. Vassilevski, and Ludmil T. Zikatanov, Weak approximation prop-
erties of elliptic projections with functional constraints, Multiscale Model. Simul. 9 (2011),
no. 4, 1677-1699, DOI 10.1137/110821639. MR2861254</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1441a1310">
            <label>58</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1448" publication-type="other">
R. Scheichl, P. S. Vassilevski, and L. T. Zikatanov. Multilevel methods for elliptic prob-
lems with highly varying coefficients on non-aligned coarse grids. To appear in SINUM. Also
available as Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory technical report LLNL-JRNL-404462,
August 2010., 2012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1465a1310">
            <label>59</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1472" publication-type="other">
L. Ridgway Scott and Shangyou Zhang, Finite element interpolation of nonsmooth func-
tions satisfying boundary conditions, Math. Comp. 54 (1990), no. 190, 483—493, DOI
10.2307/2008497. MR1011446 (90j:65021)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1485a1310">
            <label>60</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1492" publication-type="other">
Rolf Stenberg, Mortaring by a method of J. A. Nitsche, Computational mechanics (Buenos
Aires, 1998), Centro Internac. Metodos Numer. Ing., Barcelona, 1998, pp. CD-ROM file.
MR1839048</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1505a1310">
            <label>61</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1512" publication-type="other">
Panayot S. Vassilevski, Multilevel block factorization preconditioners, Springer, New York,
2008. Matrix-based analysis and algorithms for solving finite element equations. MR2427040
(2010b:65007)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1525a1310">
            <label>62</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1532" publication-type="other">
Jinchao Xu, Iterative methods by space decomposition and subspace correction, SIAM Rev.
34 (1992), no. 4, 581-613, DOI 10.1137/1034116. MR1193013 (93k:65029)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1542a1310">
            <label>63</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1549" publication-type="other">
Jinchao Xu and Yunrong Zhu, Uniform convergent multigrid methods for elliptic problems
with strongly discontinuous coefficients, Math. Models Methods Appl. Sci. 18 (2008), no. 1,
77-105, DOI 10.1142/S0218202508002619. MR2378084 (2008k:65271)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1562a1310">
            <label>64</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1569" publication-type="other">
Jinchao Xu and Ludmil Zikatanov, The method of alternating projections and the method of
subspace corrections in Hilbert space, J. Amer. Math. Soc. 15 (2002), no. 3, 573-597, DOI
10.1090/S0894-0347-02-00398-3. MR1896233 (2003f:65095)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1583a1310">
            <label>65</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1590" publication-type="other">
Jinchao Xu and Jun Zou, Some nonoverlapping domain decomposition methods, SIAM Rev.
40 (1998), no. 4, 857-914, DOI 10.1137/S0036144596306800. MR1659681 (99m:65241)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1600a1310">
            <label>66</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1607" publication-type="other">
Yunrong Zhu, Domain decomposition preconditioners for elliptic equations with jump co-
efficients, Numer. Linear Algebra Appl. 15 (2008), no. 2-3, 271-289, DOI 10.1002/nla.566.
MR2397305 (2009a:65084)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1620a1310">
            <label>67</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1627" publication-type="other">
Y. Zhu. Analysis of a multigrid preconditioner for Crouzeix-Raviart discretization of ellip-
tic partial differential equation with jump coefficients. Numer. Linear Algebra Appl., DOI
10.1002/nla.l856, Also available on arXiv.org, arXiv:1110.5159, September 2012.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2143228e1640a1310">
            <label>68</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2143228e1647" publication-type="other">
Ludmil T. Zikatanov, Two-sided bounds on the convergence rate of two-level methods, Nu-
mer. Linear Algebra Appl. 15 (2008), no. 5, 439—454, DOI 10.1002/nla.556. MR2423514
(2009g:65171)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


