<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794497</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Business Taxes and the Real Economy</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Taxing Firms Facing Financial Frictions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wills</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Camilo</surname>
                  <given-names>Gustavo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>33</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794497"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>What is the effect of replacing the corporate income tax by a tax on business owners? To answer this question we construct a model with heterogeneous firms, borrowing constraints, costly equity issuance and endogenous entry and exit. Calibrating the model to the U.S. economy, we find that replacing the corporate income tax with a revenue-neutral common tax on shareholders, steady-state output would increase by 6.8% and total factor productivity (TFP) by 1.7%. Due to financial frictions, taxes levied at the corporate income level and at the shareholder level are not perfect substitutes because they distort different margins. In our model, firms are hit by productivity shocks and aim to adjust their capital stock in pursuit of optimal size. Optimal firm behavior often dictates reliance on retained earnings for growth. The corporate income tax reduces retained earnings available for investment, thereby delaying capital accumulation. As the retained earning are not paid back to shareholders, the friction just described does not occur when taxes are levied at the dividend level. The mechanism is amplified by endogenous entry and exit and by general equilibrium feedback.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Arellano, M. and Bond, S. (1991). Some tests of specification for panel data: Monte carlo evidence and an application to employment equations. The review of economic studies, 58(2):277–297. 23</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Auerbach, A. J. (1979). Share valuation and corporate equity policy. Journal of Public Economics, 11(3):291–305. 3, 15</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Auerbach, A. J. (2002). Taxation and corporate financial policy. Handbook of public economics, 3:1251–1292. 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bradford, D. F. (1981). The incidence and allocation effects of a tax on corporate distributions. Journal of Public Economics, 15(1):1–22. 3, 15</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chetty, R., Guren, A., Manoli, D., and Weber, A. (2011). Are micro and macro labor supply elasticities consistent? a review of evidence on the intensive and extensive margins. The American Economic Review, 101(3):471–475. 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Cooley, T. F. and Quadrini, V. (2001). Financial markets and firm dynamics. American Economic Review, pages 1286–1310. 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Gomes, J. F. (2001). Financing investment. American Economic Review, pages 1263–1285. 4, 20, 25</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Gourio, F. and Miao, J. (2010). Firm heterogeneity and the long-run effects of dividend tax reform. American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics, pages 131–168. 5, 8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Gourio, F. and Miao, J. (2011). Transitional dynamics of dividend and capital gains tax cuts. Review of Economic Dynamics, 14(2):368–383. 5, 8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Greenwood, J., Hercowitz, Z., and Huffman, G. W. (1988). Investment, capacity utilization, and the real business cycle. The American Economic Review, pages 402–417. 20</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Hassett, K. A. and Hubbard, R. G. (2002). Tax policy and business investment. Handbook of public economics, 3:1293–1343. 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Hennessy, C. A. and Whited, T. M. (2005). Debt dynamics. The Journal of Finance, 60(3):1129–1165. 4, 8, 25</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Hennessy, C. A. and Whited, T. M. (2007). How costly is external financing? evidence from a structural estimation. The Journal of Finance, 62(4):1705–1745. 4, 8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Hopenhayn, H. A. (1992). Entry, exit, and firm dynamics in long run equilibrium. Econometrica: Journal of the Econometric Society, pages 1127–1150. 6, 7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">King, M. A. (1974). Taxation and the cost of capital. The Review of Economic Studies, pages 21–35. 3, 15</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Kiyotaki, N. and Moore, J. (1995). Credit cycles. Technical report, National Bureau of Economic Research. 8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Krueger, D. and Ludwig, A. (2016). On the optimal provision of social insurance: Progressive taxation versus education subsidies in general equilibrium. Journal of Monetary Economics, 77:72–98. 9, 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Lee, Y. (2007). The importance of reallocations in cyclical productivity and returns to scale: evidence from plant-level data. US Census Bureau Center for Economic Studies Paper No. CES-WP-07-05, pages 05–09. 20</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Lee, Y. and Mukoyama, T. (2015). Productivity and employment dynamics of us manufacturing plants. Economics Letters, 136:190–193. 23</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Li, S., Whited, T. M., andWu, Y. (2016). Collateral, taxes, and leverage. Review of Financial Studies, page hhw008. 25</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">McKeon, S. B. (2015). Employee option exercise and equity issuance motives. Available at SSRN 1920985. 24</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Mendoza, E. G., Razin, A., and Tesar, L. L. (1994). Effective tax rates in macroeconomics: Cross-country estimates of tax rates on factor incomes and consumption. Journal of Monetary Economics, 34(3):297–323. 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Prescott, E. C. (1986). Theory ahead of business-cycle measurement. In Carnegie-Rochester conference series on public policy, volume 25, pages 11–44. Elsevier. 20</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Yagan, D. (2015). Capital tax reform and the real economy: The effects of the 2003 dividend tax cut. The American Economic Review, 105(12):3531–3563. 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Zwick, E., Mahon, J., et al. (2014). Do financial frictions amplify fiscal policy? evidence from business investment stimulus. Harvard University. 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Effects of Tax Reform</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Capital Accumulation Before and After Reform</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
