<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007090</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Performance Analysis of Unified Doubly-fed Induction Generator for Wind Power Application</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rajpurohit</surname>
                  <given-names>B. S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Singh</surname>
                  <given-names>S. N.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>School of Computing and Electrical Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Mandi, Mandi-175001, H.P., India</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Department of Electrical Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Kanpur-208016, U.P., India</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007085</issue-id>
         <fpage>533</fpage>
         <lpage>548</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007090"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Increasing penetration of the large wind farm in the system has forced the power system policy makers to develop new electricity grid codes which are required for the wind power generator to fulfill the same requirements as conventional power plants. This paper introduces a new solution for doubly fed induction generators (DFIG) to stay connected to the grid during abnormal conditions. The main idea is to provide a series connected grid side converter (SGSC) with conventional DFIG scheme. A new control scheme is then described and analyzed, which allows relatively low-energy ratings in the SGSC, thereby significantly lowering the overall system cost. Analysis is carried out to explore the grid code requirements (GCR) during static and dynamic conditions for the performance of the system along with the controller for abnormal conditions. Reactive power support capability of series converter during steady state condition is also demonstrated. A detailed smallsignal analysis carried out which provides the insight of oscillatory behavior of DFIG. Extensive simulation and analytical results have demonstrated the enhanced performances resulting from the application of the control scheme and in compliance with the new grid codes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>DFIG</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>eigen values</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>reactive power capability</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>small signal stability</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>series grid side converter and unified architecture</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H. and Chen, Z., Overview of different wind generator systems and their comparisons, IET Proceedings of Renewable Power Generation, Vol. 2, No. 2, pp. 123–138, June 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersson, A., Analysis, modeling and control of doubly-fed induction generators for wind turbines, Ph.D. Thesis, Chalmers university of Technology, Goteborg, Sweden, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mei, F. and Pal, B., Modal analysis of grid-connected doubly fed induction generators, IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, Vol. 22, No. 3, September 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, F., Zhang, X. P., Godfrey, K. and Ju, P., Small signal stability analysis and optimal control of a wind turbine with doubly fed induction generator, IET Proceedings of Generation Transmission and Distribution, Vol. 1, No 5, pp. 751–760, September 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, L., Xu, Z., Østergaard, J., Dong, Z. Y., Wong, K. P. and Ma, X., Oscillatory stability and eigenvalue sensitivity analysis of a DFIG wind turbine system, IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, Vol. 26, No. 1, March 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ackermann, T., Editor, Wind power in power system, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd., England, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morren, J. and Haan, S. W. H., Ride through of wind turbines with doubly-fed induction generator during a voltage dip, IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, Vol. 20, No. 2, pp. 435–441, June 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Erlich, I., Wrede, H. and Feltes, C., Dynamic behaviour of DFIG-based wind turbines during grid faults, IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications, Vol. 128, No. 4, pp. 396–401, March 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, S., Tseng, K. J., Choi, S. S., Nguyen, T. D. and Yao, D. L., Advanced control of series voltage compensation to enhance wind turbine ride through, IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, Vol. 26, No. 2, pp. 763–772, Feb. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qiao, W., Harley, R. G. and Venayagamoorthy, G. K., Coordinated reactive power control of a large wind farm and a STATCOM using heuristic dynamic programming, IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, Vol. 24, No. 2, June 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wessels, C., Hoffmann, N., Molinas, M. and Fuchs, F. W., StatCom Control at Wind Farms With Fixed-Speed Induction Generators Under Asymmetrical Grid Faults, IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 60, No. 7, July 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flannery, P. and Venkataramanan, G., A unified architecture for doubly fed induction generator wind turbines using a parallel grid side rectifier and series grid side converter, Power Conversion Conference-Nagoya 2007, pp. 1442–1449, April 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rajpurohit, B. S., Singh, S. N. and Kyriakides, E., Intelligent control of power electronic systems for wind turbines, in Wind Power Systems, L. Wang et. al, Ed. Berlin, Springer- Verlag, 2010, 255–295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baqi, O. A. and Nasiri, A., Series voltage compensation for DFIG wind turbine low-voltage ride-through solution, IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, Vol. 26, No. 1, March 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rajpurohit, B. S., Singh, S. N. and Wang, L., Electric grid connection and system operational aspect of wind power generation, in Wind Energy Conversion Systems, S. M. Muyeen, Ed. London, Springer-Verlag, 2012, 267–293.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pena, R., Clare, J. C. and Asher, G. M., Doubly fed induction generator using back-to-back PWM converters and its application to variable-speed wind-energy generation, IEE Proceedings of Electric Power Applications, Vol. 143, pp. 231–241, May 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Datta, R. and Ranganathan, V. T., Direct power control of grid-connected wound rotor induction machine without rotor position sensors, IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, Vol. 16, pp. 390–399, May 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rajpurohit, B. S. and Singh, S. N., Improved Reactive Power Capability of Grid Connected Doubly Fed Induction Generator, Wind Engineering, Vol. 33, No. 4, pp. 403–416, June 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engelhardt, S., Erlich, I., Feltes, C., Kretschmann, J. and Shewarega, F., Reactive Power Capability of Wind Turbines Based on Doubly Fed Induction Generators, IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion, Vol. 26, No. 1, pp. 364–372, June 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
