<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466821</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466826</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Opacity in Financial Markets</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Yuki</given-names>
                  <surname>Sato</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3502</fpage>
         <lpage>3546</lpage>
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466826"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper studies the implications of opacity in financial markets for investor behavior, asset prices, and welfare. Transparent funds (e.g., mutual funds) and opaque funds (e.g., hedge funds) trade transparent assets (e.g., plain-vanilla products) and opaque assets (e.g., structured products). Investors observe neither opaque funds' portfolios nor opaque assets' payoffs. Consistent with empirical observations, an "opacity price premium" arises: opaque assets trade at a premium over transparent ones despite identical payoffs. This accompanies endogenous market segmentation: transparent (opaque) funds trade only transparent (opaque) assets. The opacity price premium incentivizes financial engineers to render transparent assets opaque deliberately.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d50e132a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e139" publication-type="other">
According to Hedge Fund Research, in 1990 there were only 610 hedge funds managing $39 billion of assets
globally, but in 2013 there are more than 10,000 funds with $2,400 billion of assets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e149a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e156" publication-type="other">
See also Jarrow and O'Hara (1989) and Rogalski and Seward (1991), who find overpricing of Primes and Scores
and foreign currency exchange warrants, respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e166a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e173" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier and Oehmke (2009) refer to this as the information overload problem.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e180a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e187" publication-type="other">
See also Caballero and Simsek (2010), who model complexity as banks' limited knowledge of the interlinkages
between banks in a financial network.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e198a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e205" publication-type="other">
It is not important that only the opaque asset is available for investment. Sections 4 and 5 analyze the cases in
which the transparent asset (with observable 8t ) coexists with the opaque asset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e215a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e222" publication-type="other">
Given the assumption that Pt is observable to investors, a suitable example of opaque assets can be derivatives
traded on exchanges (as opposed to over the counter). Their transaction prices are readily available at the
exchanges' Web sites (e.g., Eurex Group), but their payoff information is difficult to track for most unprofessional
investors. Also, even complicated structured products are traded on secondary markets and the price data are
available at trading platforms' Web sites (e.g., Interactive Investor), whereas their periodic payoffs are hard to
track for most retail investors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e245a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e252" publication-type="other">
If 1 &gt; Ptdi t, then the manager buys the riskless asset; if 1 &lt; PtOi t, then he sells the asset (i.e., borrows funds) to
finance purchasing the risky asset.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e262a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e269" publication-type="other">
The quadratic form is tractable because, as shown in what follows, it will make X,-1 linear in the investors'
expected excess return on the risky asset. As in other standard signal jamming models, preserving a linear
structure is critical for the model's solvability.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e282a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e289" publication-type="other">
For empirical evidence of decreasing returns to scale, see Chen et al. (2004) and Edelen, Evans, and Kadlec
(2007) for mutual funds and Agarwal, Daniel, and Naik (2004) for hedge funds. Given these pieces of evidence,
it is now standard to assume decreasing returns to scale in theoretical models. Besides Berk and Green (2004),
see also Pastor and Stambaugh (2012) and Savov (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e305a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e312" publication-type="other">
It is also possible to assume that each investor actually pays a monetary fee with a proportional rate 0 e (0,1) to
the manager. Although closed-form solutions exist for the model in that setting and the economic insights are
very similar, the solutions are less tractable computationally.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e326a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e333" publication-type="other">
Note that 8t is the estimate not only of 8t but also of its future values 8t+x (r = 1,2,...), future payoffs 8t+r (r =
1,2,...), and future values of «5 itself (i.e., 8t is a martingale). That is, E[6j+tHt]=E[8t+Tl-Lt]=E[8t+T [Ht] = 8t
holds for r = 1,2</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e346a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e353" publication-type="other">
Using (2.1), we obtain /?f+i =5f+i + —(l+r)P/. Because E[8t+l-Lt]=E[8t+i'Ht]=8t, we have
Rt+i = _y _(i +r)Pt. Rearranging it yields the result.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e363a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e370" publication-type="other">
This result means that, despite the positive expected excess return R on the risky asset, the expected excess return
on the fund (from the investors' perspective) is zero in equilibrium. This is because decreasing returns to scale
drive down the after-cost expected fund return to the riskless return 1+r. In relation to this point, it is worth
comparing this model with Berk and Green's (2004) model. Berk and Green (2004) focus only on fund's return
that investors receive, omitting individual asset's market equilibrium. They argue that each fund manager's
skill could potentially generate excess return (alpha) on the fund, but it eventually disappears in equilibrium
because of decreasing returns to scale. In contrast, my model concerns both the fund's and the individual asset's
equilibrium returns. As shown in (2.6), the presence of investment cost (i.e., the manager's risk aversion k) leads
to excess return R on the asset, remaining positive in equilibrium, whereas excess return on the fund disappears
in equilibrium because of decreasing returns to scale.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e405a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e412" publication-type="other">
In asymmetric information models à la Grossman and Stiglitz (1980) or differential information models à la
Grossman (1976), investors should revise their estimates in favor of the price because it reflects superior
information. In the model proposed here, however, no investor has information superior to the other funds'
investors and no one has private information that would be collectively useful. On the equilibrium path, the price
just confirms each investor's estimate. Also note that investors i have no reason to believe that discrepancy in
the estimates is caused by manager i's deviation; after all, it could be other funds' managers or investors who
have deviated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e438a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e445" publication-type="other">
A key for this overshoot of Sj to occur is the out-of-equilibrium belief (3.3), which leads the investors to
stick by their own estimate when it disagrees with the other investors' average estimate sj+r that is revealed by
Pt+X. Note that, on this off-the-equilibrium path, the investors are aware that their estimate &amp;(t+x is higher than
Sj+r but are unaware that it is too high: they (incorrectly) believe that s{ t+x is more accurate than 8j+x.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e461a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e468" publication-type="other">
Intuitively, in period t + z, the investors' high estimate S{ t+T leads them to expect both 8t+x+ and Pt+T+ to be
high; given the observed price Pt+T, they expect that Rt+z+i will also be high.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e479a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e486" publication-type="other">
Using price function (3.1), Rl+l =ä,+i + (|/o â/,+1di -ft+l) ~V+r)P, =Sl+i + i/g1 (x,+1ä/(+(l-X,+1)
ä,+l)di-n+l-(l+f)PI = (l + ^ttl-)ä/+i + ^-/ol^,di-y,+1-(l+r)P(. Thus, +
8- ( + /J 8-1 di — yt+i — (1 +r)Pt. Integrating over i and noting that R- t+i = Rt+i for all i in equilibrium, we
have Rl+i = (l + '~^+1 ) /J ä/( di + fg Sf t di - Yt+ -0 +r)Pt = (*?)*/ "Tr+l -(l+Oflt■ Rearranging
it, the result holds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e505a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e512" publication-type="other">
That £ can exceed unity is a major difference from Holmström's (1999) result. The counterpart of £ in his paper
is the LHS of Equation (22), which is never greater than one. That threshold is crucial for his main result because
it ensures that the labor supply is never greater than the efficient level in the stationary state. The reason why
f &gt; 1 may occur in the model developed here is that the risky asset not only yields 8t but also can be sold at price
Pt. This resale of the asset creates an additional component (captured by the term (1 —X)/r in the definition of
£ in (3.13)) and allows £ to be large.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e535a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e542" publication-type="other">
A story behind this assumption is as follows. There are potentially a large number of transparent assets that are
ex ante distinguishable to the managers, but not to the investors. Hence, only if the manager picks one particular
asset from them the investors can track that asset's periodic payoff.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e555a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e562" publication-type="other">
In Section 5,1 discuss the managers' endogenous choice of fund types. See footnote 27 and the corresponding
discussion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e572a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e579" publication-type="other">
Even if we allow each manager to choose to make this choice observable or unobservable, every manager chooses
to make it observable. A transparent fund manager is indifferent between observable and unobservable choices
because his portfolio is always observable to the investors. An opaque fund manager strictly prefers to make it
observable: if he instead chose to make it unobservable, then the investors would not invest capital in the fund,
anticipating rationally a moral hazard situation in which the manager chooses k=a and then "shirks," that is,
invests no capital in asset a to avoid incurring the personal cost of portfolio formation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e602a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e609" publication-type="other">
For 6?ta =0 to hold, the assumption that investors are short lived plays a role. If they were infinitely lived and
sufficiently patient, they could commit not to invest in the fund in the future if the fund return reveals ex post
that the manager chose oPf =0, and thereby the manager would be incentivized to choose &gt; 0.1 thank an
anonymous referee for pointing this out.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e626a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e633" publication-type="other">
Here, note that none of the funds buys both assets a and b because, by assumption of Decision 1, each fund is
allowed to buy only one risky asset. That is, there is a measure œ*a of transparent funds buying only asset a and
(1 — co*)a of them buying only asset b.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e646a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e653" publication-type="other">
The total assets of mutual funds in 2010 are USD 11,832 billion, according to Investment Company Institute,
whereas those of hedge funds are USD 1,920 billion, according to TheCityUK. Thus, dividing them by the
number of funds, each mutual fund's average size is USD 1.56 billion, whereas that of the hedge fund is only
USD 0.19 billion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e669a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e676" publication-type="other">
Here, the price gap is closed completely because the engineers' asset transformation is costless. If instead it is
costly, then the gap would remain positive, reflecting the transformation cost. I thank an anonymous referee for
pointing this out.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e689a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e698" publication-type="other">
For this result, convexity of the manager's personal cost plays a role. If £ &gt; 1, then XA* &lt;XB* and 0Aa* &lt;
0Bb*.1hus, clearly (J&gt;XA* &lt;(f)XB*. Nevertheless, uMA* &gt; IJMB* holds because ic6Aa*2 is much lower than
^KßBb*2 because of convexity. On the other, if £ &lt; 1, then cpXA* &gt;(f)XB*. Because jk6Au*2 is not so higher
than JicQBb*2 because of convexity, uMA* &gt; UMB* holds again.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e714a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e721" publication-type="other">
Suppose that each manager is allowed to choose the fund's type and that each transparent fund manager needs
to pay a periodic disclosure cost q &gt; 0. In equilibrium, all managers should be indifferent between the two
fund types, that is, uMA*-q = uMB* must hold. Solving this condition for a, we obtain its equilibrium value:
a* = ^ ~^OOS*n^ Parameter values properly, we can ensure that a* e (0,1).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e737a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e744" publication-type="other">
I thank an anonymous referee for suggesting these interpretations of the disclosure cost.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e752a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e759" publication-type="other">
In (C.2), I abuse notation and set Fit«;* t s * •</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e775a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e779" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, C., N. Daniel, and N. Naik. 2004. Rows, performance, and managerial incentives in hedge funds.
Working Paper, Georgia State University and London Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e789a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e793" publication-type="other">
Allen, F., and G Gorton. 1993. Churning bubbles. Review of Economic Studies 60:813-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e800a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e804" publication-type="other">
Aragon, G, M. Hertzel, and Z. Shi. 2013. Why do hedge funds avoid disclosure? Evidence from confidential
13F filings. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 48:1499-518.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e818" publication-type="other">
Arora, S., B. Barak, M. Brunnermeier, and R. Ge. 2009. Computational complexity and information asymmetry
in financial products. Working Paper, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e829a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e833" publication-type="other">
Berk, J., and R. Green. 2004. Mutual fund flows and performance in rational markets. Journal of Political
Economy 112:1269-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e847" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier, M., and M. Oehmke. 2009. Complexity in financial markets. Working Paper, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e854a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e858" publication-type="other">
Caballero, R., and A. Simsek. 2010. Fire sales in a model of complexity. Working Paper, MIT.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e865a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e869" publication-type="other">
Carlin, B. 2009. Strategic price complexity in retail financial markets. Journal of Financial Economics 91:278-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e876a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e880" publication-type="other">
Carlin, B., and G Manso. 2011. Obfuscation, learning, and the evolution of investor sophistication. Review of
Financial Studies 24:754-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e890a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e894" publication-type="other">
Célérier, C., and B. Vallée. 2013. What drives financial complexity? A look into the retail market for structured
products. Working Paper, University of Zurich and HEC Paris.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e905a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e909" publication-type="other">
Chen, Y. 2011. Derivatives use and risk taking: Evidence from the hedge fund industry. Journal of Financial and
Quantitative Analysis 46:1073-106.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e919a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e923" publication-type="other">
Chen, J., H. Hong, M. Huang, and J. Kubik. 2004. Does fund size erode mutual fund performance? The role of
liquidity and organization. American Economic Review 94:1276-302.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e933a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e937" publication-type="other">
Coval, J., J. Jurek, and E. Stafford. 2009. Economic catastrophe bonds. American Economic Review
99:628-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e947a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e951" publication-type="other">
Cuoco, D., and R. Kaniel. 2011. Equilibrium prices in the presence of delegated portfolio management. Journal
of Financial Economics 101:264—96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e961a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e965" publication-type="other">
Dasgupta, A., and A. Prat. 2008. Information aggregation in financial markets with career concerns. Journal of
Economic Theory 143:83-113.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e975a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e979" publication-type="other">
Dasgupta, A., A. Prat, and M. Verardo. 2011. The price impact of institutional herding. Review of Financial
Studies 24:892-925.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e990a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e994" publication-type="other">
Deli, D. 2002. Mutual fund advisory contracts: An empirical investigation. Journal of Finance
57:109-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1004a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1008" publication-type="other">
Deli, D., and R. Varma. 2002. Contracting in the investment management industry: Evidence from mutual funds.
Journal of Financial Economics 63:79-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1018a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1022" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., N. Gârleanu, and H. Pedersen. 2005. Over-the-counter markets. Econometrica 73:1815-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1029a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1033" publication-type="other">
Easley, D., M. O'Hara, and L. Yang. 2012. Opaque trading, disclosure and asset prices: Implications for hedge
fund regulation. Working Paper, Cornell University and University of Toronto.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1043a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1047" publication-type="other">
Edelen, R., R. Evans, and G Kadlec. 2007. Scale effects in mutual fund performance: The role of trading costs.
Working Paper, Boston College and Virginia Tech.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1057a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1061" publication-type="other">
Grossman, S. 1976. On the efficiency of competitive stock markets where trades have diverse information.
Journal of Finance 31:573-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1072a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1076" publication-type="other">
Grossman, S., and J. Stiglitz. 1980. On the impossibility of informationally efficient markets. American Economic
Review 70:393-408.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1086a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1090" publication-type="other">
Guerrieri, V., and P. Kondor. 2012. Fund managers, career concerns, and asset price volatility. American Economic
Review 102:1986-2017.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1100a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1104" publication-type="other">
He, Z., and A. Krishnamurthy. 2012. A model of capital and crises. Review of Economic Studies 79:735-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1111a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1115" publication-type="other">
. 2013. Intermediary asset pricing. American Economic Review 103:732-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1122a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1126" publication-type="other">
Henderson, B. J., and N. D. Pearson. 2011. The dark side of financial innovation: A case study of the pricing of
a retail financial product. Journal of Financial Economics 100:227-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1136a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1140" publication-type="other">
Holmström, B. 1999. Managerial incentive problems: A dynamic perspective. Review of Economic Studies
66:169-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1151a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1155" publication-type="other">
Jarrow, R., and M. O'Hara. 1989. Primes, scores: An essay on market imperfection. Journal of Finance
44:1263-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1165a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1169" publication-type="other">
Kaniel, R., and P. Kondor. 2013. The delegated Lucas tree. Review of Financial Studies 26:929-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1176a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1180" publication-type="other">
Koski, J., and J. Pontiff. 1999. How are derivatives used? Evidence from the mutual fund industry. Journal of
Finance 54:791-816.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1194" publication-type="other">
Kyle, A. S. 1989. Informed speculation with imperfect competition. Review of Economic Studies 56:317-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1201a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1205" publication-type="other">
Malliaris, S., and H. Yan. 2012. Reputation concerns and slow-moving capital. Working Paper, Yale University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1212a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1216" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and R. Stambaugh. 2012. On the size of the active management industry. Journal of Political Economy
120:740-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1231" publication-type="other">
Rogalski, R., and J. Seward. 1991. Corporate issues of foreign currency exchange warrants. Journal of Financial
Economics 30:347-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1241a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1245" publication-type="other">
Savov, A. 2013. The price of skill: Performance evaluation by households. Working Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1252a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1256" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A., and R. Vishny. 1997. The limits of arbitrage. Journal of Finance 52:35-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1263a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1267" publication-type="other">
Stein, J. 1989. Efficient capital markets, inefficient firms: A model of myopic corporate behavior. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 104:655-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1277a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1281" publication-type="other">
Vayanos, D. 2004. Flight to quality, flight to liquidity, and the pricing of risk. Working Paper, London School of
Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1291a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1295" publication-type="other">
Vayanos, D., and P. Woolley. 2013. An institutional theory of momentum and reversal. Review of Financial
Studies 26:1087-145.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


