<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816585</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Political Economy and Local Governments (Political Economy)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Political Economy of Parcel Tax in California School Districts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Soomi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>33</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816585"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper examines determinants of parcel tax adoption in California school districts as a means to supplement local public school funding. A parcel tax is a regressive tax imposed on a unit of property that requires a two-thirds supermajority vote to adopt. Despite its increasing role as a local funding source, the school parcel tax has not been well understood, particularly how this regressive form of property tax is adopted in different local conditions. Unlike previous research that emphasizes income differences across school districts, I predict that the distribution of home prices within a district is an important determinant in parcel tax adoption. Using Heckman selection models and California school district level data, I find that a larger distribution of home values reduces the likelihood of parcel tax adoption.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Baicker, Katherine, and Nora Gordon. 2006. "The Effect of State Education Finance Reform on Total Local Resources." Journal of Public Economics 90: 1519-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Balsdon, Ed, Eric J. Brunner, and Kim Rueben. 2003. “Private Demands for Public Capital: Evidence from School Bond Referenda.” Journal of Urban Economics 54: 610-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bergstrom, Theodore C., and Robert P. Goodman. 1973. "Private Demands for Public Goods." American Economic Review 63: 280-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bergstrom, Theodore, Daniel Rubinfeld, and Perry Shapiro. 1982. “Micro-Based Estimates of Demand Functions for Local School Expenditures.” Econometrica 50: 1183-205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Brunner J. Eric, and Kim Rueben. 2001. “Financing New School Construction and Modernization: Evidence from California.” National Tax Journal 54(September): 527-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Brunner, Eric J. 2001. “The Parcel Tax.” San Francisco, CA: Public Policy Institute of California.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Brunner, Eric J., and Jon Sonstelie. 2006. "California's School Finance Reform: An Experiment in Fiscal Federalism.” Economics Working Papers 200509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Brunner, Eric, and Jon Sonstelie. 1997. “Coping with Serrano: Voluntary Contributions to California’s Local Public Schools.” Paper presented at the Annual Conference on Taxation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Brunner, Eric, and Jon Sonstelie. 2003. “School Finance Reform and Voluntary Fiscal Federalism.” Journal of Public Economics 87:2157-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">California Department of Education, Annual Financial Data, www.cde.ca.gov/ds</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">California Secretary of State, Statement of Vote, November 6, 2012. President by County, http://elections.cdn.sos.ca.gov/sov/2012-general/10-president.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Davis Vanguard, 2016. “Analysis: School Board to Hold Two Special Meetings This Week to Decide the Parcel Tax.” (June 27, 2016)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Foldvary, Fred. 2006. “Circumventing California’s Proposition 13 for the Public Collection of Rent.” Presented at the Eastern Economic Association Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">George Borikas v. Alameda Unified School District (2013) 214 Cal. App. 4th 135, 154 Cal.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Heckman, James. “Sample Selection Bias as a Specification Error.” Econometrica 47(1): 153-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Hill, Sarah A., D. Roderick Kiewiet, and Shelly Arsneault. 2014. “Filling the Gap: the Role of Voluntary Contributions and Parcel Taxes in Supplementing K-12 Spending in California.” Presented at the Western Political Science Association Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Hill, Sarah, and D. Roderick Kiewiet. 2015. “Parcel Tax Elections in California, 1983-2013.”Paper presented at the Southern Political Science Association Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Hoxby, Caroline M. 2001. 1997. “All School Finance Equalization Are Not Created Equal.”Quarterly Journal of Economics 116 (November): 1189-231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Lang, Bree J. and Jon Sonstelie. 2015. “The Parcel Tax as a Source of Local Revenue for California Public Schools.” National Tax Journal 68:3: 545-72</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Oates, Wallace E. 2005. "Property Taxation and Local Public Spending: The Renter Effect." Journal of Urban Economics 57: 419-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Olson, Mancur. 1965. The Logic of Collective Action: Public Goods and the Theory of Groups.Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Poterba, James M. 1997. "Demographic Structure and the Political Economy of Public Education." Journal of Policy Analysis and Management 16: 48-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Wooldridge, Jeffrey M. 2002. Econometric Analysis of Cross Section and Panel Data.Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>B. Variable Description</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>C. Summary Statistics (Mean and standard deviation in parenthesis; no missing values)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Effects of home price gap on the likelihood of parcel tax election (Heckman selection model estimate)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Robustness Checks Effects of home price gap on the likelihood of parcel tax election (Heckman selection model estimate)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Extended models (Heckman selection model estimate)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Conditional Marginal Effect of Home Price Gap on Likelihood of Parcel Tax Adoption (with 95% Confidence Intervals)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Conditional Marginal Effect of Home Price Gap on Likelihood of Parcel Tax Adoption By 33<sup>rd</sup> Percentile Household Income Levels</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
