<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">48568609</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>De Facto Seniority, Credit Risk, and Corporate Bond Prices</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bao</surname>
                  <given-names>Jack</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hou</surname>
                  <given-names>Kewei</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>November 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e48503769</issue-id>
         <fpage>4038</fpage>
         <lpage>4080</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/48568609"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We study the effect of a bond’s place in its issuer’s maturity structure on credit risk. Using a structural model as motivation, we argue that bonds due relatively late in their issuers’ maturity structure have greater credit risk than do bonds due relatively early. Empirically, we find robust evidence that these later bonds have larger yield spreads and greater comovement with equity and that the magnitude of the effects is consistent with model predictions for investment-grade bonds. Our results highlight the importance of bond-specific credit risk for understanding corporate bond prices.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Amihud, Y. 2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: Cross-section and time-series effects. Journal of Financial Markets 5:31–56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Asness, C., and A. Frazzini. 2013. The devil in HML’s details. Journal of Portfolio Management 39:48–68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Baele, L., G. Bekaert, and K. Inghelbrecht. 2010. The determinants of stock and bond return comovements. Review of Financial Studies 23:2374–428.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Baker, M., and J. Wurgler. 2012. Comovement and predictability relationships between bonds and the crosssection of stocks. Review of Asset Pricing Studies 2:57–87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bao, J., J. Chen, K. Hou, and L. Lu. 2014. Prices and volatilities in the corporate bond market. Working Paper, Federal Reserve Board, Peking University, and Ohio State.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bao, J., and J. Pan. 2013. Bond illiquidity and excess volatility. Review of Financial Studies 26:3068–103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Brunnermeier, M. K., and M. Oehmke. 2013. The maturity rat race. Journal of Finance 68:483–521.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Cameron, A. C., J. B. Gelbach, and D. L. Miller. 2011. Robust inference with multiway clustering. Journal of Business &amp; Economics Statistics 29:238–49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Campbell, J. Y., J. Hilscher, and J. Szilagyi. 2008. In search of distress risk. Journal of Finance 63:2899–939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Campbell, J. Y., C. Pflueger, and L. M. Viciera. 2013. Monetary policy drivers of bond and equity risks. Working Paper, Harvard and UBC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Campbell, J. Y., and G. B. Taksler. 2003. Equity volatility and corporate bond yields. Journal of Finance 58: 2321–49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Chava, S., and M. R. Roberts. 2008. How does financing impact investment? The role of debt covenants. Journal of Finance 63:2085–121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Chen, H., Y. Xu, and J. Yang. 2012. Systematic risk, debt maturity, and the term structure of credit spreads. Working Paper, MIT and Bank of Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Collin-Dufresne, P., R. S. Goldstein, and S. Martin. 2001. The determinants of credit spread changes. Journal of Finance 56:2177–207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Cox, J. C., S. A. Ross, and M. Rubinstein. 1979. Option pricing: A simplified approach. Journal of Financial Economics 7:229–63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Daniel, K., and S. Titman. 1997. Evidence on the characteristics of cross sectional variation in stock returns. Journal of Finance 52:1–33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Dick-Nielsen, J., P. Feldhutter, and D. Lando. 2012. Corporate bond liquidity before and after the onset of the subprime crisis. Journal of Financial Economics 103:471–92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Eisdorfer, A. 2008. Empirical evidence of risk shifting in financially distressed firms. Journal of Finance 63: 609–37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Eom, Y. H., J. Helwege, and J. Z. Huang. 2004. Structural models of corporate bond pricing: An empirical analysis. Review of Financial Studies 17:499–544.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1992. The cross-section of expected stock returns. Journal of Finance 47:427–65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Fama, E. F. 1993. Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial Economics 33: 3–56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Fama, E. F. 1995. Size and book-to-market factors in earnings and returns. Journal of Finance 50:131–55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Fama, E. F. 1996. Multifactor explanations of asset pricing anomalies. Journal of Finance 51:55–84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Feldhutter, P. 2012. The same bond at different prices: identifying search frictions and selling pressures. Review of Financial Studies 25:1155–206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Feldhutter, P., and S. Schaefer. 2015. The credit spread puzzle in the Merton model–Myth or reality? Working Paper, London Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Fons, J., B. Havlicek, D. Fanger, D. Gates, E. de Bodard, and L. Exton. 2007. Updated summary guidelines for notching bonds, preferred stocks and hybrid securities of corporate issuers. Moody’s Investor Services.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Geske, R. 1977. The valuation of corporate liabilities as compound options. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 12:541–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Greene, W. H. 2003. Econometric analysis, 5th ed. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Guha, R. 2002. Recovery of face value at default: Theory and empirical evidence. Working Paper, London Business School.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Haugen, R. A. 1995. The new finance–The case against efficient markets. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">He, Z., and K. Milbradt. 2014. Endogenous liquidity and defaultable bonds. Econometrica 82:1443–508.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">He, Z.. 2016. Dynamic debt maturity. Review of Financial Studies 29:2677–736.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">He, Z., and W. Xiong. 2012. Rollover risk and credit risk. Journal of Finance 67:391–429.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Hotchkiss, E. H., and T. Ronen. 2002. The informational efficiency of the corporate bond market: An intraday analysis. Review of Financial Studies 15:1325–54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Huang, J. Z. 1997. Default risk, renegotiation, and the valuation of corporate claims. PhD thesis, NYU.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Huang, J. Z., and M. Huang. 2003. How much of the corporate-treasury yield spread is due to credit risk? Working Paper, Penn State and Stanford.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Huang, J. Z. 2012. How much of the corporate-treasury yield spread is due to credit risk? Review of Asset Pricing Studies 2:153–202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Kennedy, P. 1998. A guide to econometrics, 4th ed. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Lakonishok, J., A. Shleifer, and R. W. Vishny. 1994. Contrarian investment, extrapolation, and risk. Journal of Finance 49:1541–78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Leland, H. E. 1994. Corporate debt value, bond covenants, and optimal capital structure. Journal of Finance 49:157–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Leland, H. E., and K. Toft. 1996. Optimal capital structure, endogenous bankruptcy, and the term structure of credit spreads. Journal of Finance 51:987–1019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">MacKinlay, A. C. 1995. Multifactor models do not explain deviations from the CAPM. Journal of Financial Economics 38:3–28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Masulis, R. W., and A. N. Korwar. 1986. Seasoned equity offerings: An empirical investigation. Journal of Financial Economics 15:91–118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Maxwell, W. F., and R. Rao. 2003. Do spin-offs expropriate wealth from bondholders? Journal of Finance 58:2087–108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Maxwell, W. F., and M. R. Shenkman. 2010. Leveraged financial markets. New York: McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Maxwell, W. F., and C. Stephens. 2003. The wealth effects of repurchases on bondholders. Journal of Finance 58:895–919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Merton, R. C. 1974. On the pricing of corporate debt: The risk structure of interest rates. Journal of Finance 29:449–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Powers, E. A., and S. Tsyplakov. 2008. What is the cost of financial flexibility? Theory and evidence from make-whole call provisions. Financial Management 37:485–512.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Rauh, J. D., and A. Sufi. 2010. Capital structure and debt structure. Review of Financial Studies 23:4242–80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Schaefer, S. M., and I. A. Strebulaev. 2008. Structural models of credit risk are useful: Evidence from hedge ratios on corporate bonds. Journal of Financial Economics 90:1–19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Shimko, D. C., N. Tejima, and D. R. van Deventer. 1993. The pricing of risky debt when interest rates are stochastic. Journal of Fixed Income 3:58–65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Model yield spreads</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Yield spreads and hedge ratios for the Merton and extended Merton models. The cyan surfaces represent the case in which a bond is late in its firm’s maturity structure and the red surfaces with point markers represent the case in which a bond is early in its firm’s maturity structure (B and D).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Model hedge ratios</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Bond summary statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Firm summary statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Yield spreads</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Matched sample analysis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Hedge ratios, baseline</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Hedge ratios</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Model versus empirical estimates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Yield spreads and hedge ratios for the Geske (1977) model. Yield spreads are reported in basis points and hedge ratios in percentage. The cyan surfaces represent the case in which a bond is late in its issuer’s maturity structure and the red surfaces with point markers represent the case in which a bond is early in its issuer’s maturity structure.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Dashed line is the amount that equityholders need to pay-in to continue the firm for different levels of a in the extended Geske model. Dashed curve is the value of the call option that equityholders would hold if they choose to continue the firm.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Yield spreads for the the extended Geske model. The panels plot differences in yield spreads between bonds due late in a firm’s maturity structure and bonds due early in a firm’s maturity structure. a represents the proportion of maturing debt that is paid by liquidating firm assets.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.4</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Hedge Ratios for the the extended Geske model. The panels plot differences in hedge ratios between bonds due late in a firm’s maturity structure and bonds due early in a firm’s maturity structure. a represents the proportion of maturing debt that is paid by liquidating firm assets.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure A.5</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Yield spreads and hedge ratios for the Leland and Toft (1996) model. Yield spreads are reported in basis points and hedge ratios in percentage. The cyan surfaces with circular markers represent cases where a bond is due late in its issuer’s maturity structure and the white surfaces with point markers represent cases where a bond is due early in its issuer’s maturity structure.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Yield spreads with nonlinear controls</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Hedge ratios with nonlinear controls</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
