<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169038</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Power Management of Hybrid Electric Vehicles based on Pareto Optimal Maps</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zaremba</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexander T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Soto</surname>
                  <given-names>Ciro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shakiba-herfeh</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohammad</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jennings</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ford Motor Co.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169031</issue-id>
         <fpage>56</fpage>
         <lpage>63</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169038"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Pareto optimal map concept has been applied to the optimization of the vehicle system control (VSC) strategy for a power-split hybrid electric vehicle (HEV) system. The methodology relies on an inner-loop optimization process to define Pareto maps of the best engine and electric motor/generator operating points given wheel power demand, vehicle speed, and battery power. Selected levels of model fidelity, from simple to very detailed, can be used to generate the Pareto maps. Optimal control is achieved by applying Pontryagin's minimum principle which is based on minimization of the Hamiltonian comprised of the rate of fuel consumption and a co-state variable multiplied by the rate of change of battery SOC. The approach delivers optimal control for lowest fuel consumption over a drive cycle while accounting for all critical vehicle operating constraints, e.g. battery charge balance and power limits, and engine speed and torque limits. The methodology has been verified through comparison with the production VSC strategy of the 2013 HEV Fusion and it shows comparable performance. The approach is effective for evaluation of new system configurations and for early analysis of next generation HEV systems before VSC calibrations are developed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.C., Peng, H., Grizzle, J.W., and Kang, J., “Power Management Strategy for a Parallel hybrid Electric Truck,” IEEE Trans Control Syst. Technol. Vol. 11, No., 6, Nov. 2003, pp.839-849.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.C., and Peng, H., “Control Optimization for a Power- Split Hybrid vehicle,” In Proc. 2006 American Control Conf., Minneapolis, Minnesota, 2006, pp. 466-471.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.C., Peng, H., and Grizzle, J.W., “A Stochastic Control Strategy for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” in Proc. 2004 American Control Conf., Boston, MA, 2004, pp. 4710-4715.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paganelli, G., Delprat, S., Guerra, T.M., Rimaux, J., et al., “Equivalent Consumption Minimization Strategy for Parallel Hybrid Powertrains,” in Proc. CTV Spring 2002, IEEE, 2002, pp. 2076-2081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musardo, G., Rizzoni, G., and Staccia, B., “A-ECMS: An Adaptive Algorithm for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Management,” in proc. 44th IEEE Conf. Decision Control, 2005 European Control Conf., Seville, Spain, 2005, pp. 1816-1823.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guzella, L., and Sciarretta, Vehicle Propulsion Systems. Introduction to Modeling and Optimization. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, 2005, pp. 208-225.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, X., Guzella, L., Utkin, V.I., and Rizzoni, “Model-Based Fuel Optimal Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicle Using Variable Structure Control Systems,” ASME J. Dynamic Syst., Meas., Control, vol. 129, No. 1, January 2007, pp. 13-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N., Cha S., and Peng, H., “Optimal Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicles based on Pontryagin's Minimum Principle,” IEEE Trans. Control System Technol. Vol. 19, Issue 5, 2011, pp. 1279-1287.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N. and Rousseau, A., “Comparison between Rule-Based and Instantaneous Optimization for a Single-Mode, Power-Split HEV,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0873, 2011, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tribioli, L., and Onori, S., “Analysis of Energy Management Strategies in Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles: application to the GM Chevrolet Volt,” In Proc. 2013 American Control Conf., Washington, DC, June 17-19, 2013, pp. 5986-5991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Che, J., Jennings, M., and Zaremba, A., “Vehicle System Modeling for Computer-Aided Chassis Control Development,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1432, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1432.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meng, Y., Jennings, M., Tsou, P., Brigham, D., et al., “Test Correlation Framework for Hybrid Electric Vehicle System Model,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1046-1057, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0881.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahn, K., and Papalambros, P.Y., “Engine optimal operation lines for power-split hybrid electric vehicles,” Proc. IMechE Vol.223, part D: J. Automotive Engineering, 2009, pp. 1149-1162. DOI:10.1243/095 44070JAUTO1124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N., Rousseau, A., Lee, D., “A jump condition of PMP-based control for PHEVs,” Journal of Power Sources, Vol. 196, 2011, pp. 2090-10386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N., Cha, S.W., Peng, H., “Optimal Equivalent Fuel Consumption for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” IEEE Transactions on Controls Systems Technology, Vol. 20, No. 3, 2012, pp. 817-825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
