<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308486</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Design of a Milner CVT using Simulation Based Design of Experiments</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Akehurst</surname>
                  <given-names>S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Powertrain &amp; Vehicle Research Centre, University of Bath</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1508</fpage>
         <lpage>1519</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308486"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The Milner continuously variable transmission (MCVT) is a traction drive transmission based on rolling contacts analogous to those found in angular contact roller bearings. The MCVT is applicable to very high power density applications or those with demanding packaging constraints, due primarily to the existence of multiple traction contacts on each of the rolling elements.</p>
            <p>The transmission has been modelled analytically and then Design of Experiments (DoE) techniques have been applied to create response surface model sets describing performance criteria over a wide range of design input factors. The response surface models have then been interrogated to find optimal solutions. The results show that it is possible to create a transmission with a significantly higher ratio range (10:1), compared with 5:1 that is typical for existing designs [1]. The results also indicated that the traction patch spin factor could also be reduced over the existing designs and it is hypothesised that this should lead to an increase in efficiency.</p>
            <p>Finally, research into the stresses set up by the rolling contact indicated that stress is highest at the greatest reductions in ratio and that maximum stress appears to be proportional to the ratio range of the transmission. Hence a design optimisation tool has been developed allowing engineers to rapidly optimise geometries of the MCVT to achieve desired trade-offs between ratio range, ratio position, transmission life/durability and transmission efficiency.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akehurst S, Brace CJ, Vaughan ND, Milner P, Hosoi Y, 2001. Performance Investigations of a Novel Rolling Traction CVT, SAE Paper No. 2001-01-0874</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akehurst, S, Parker, D &amp; Schaaf, S, 2005. CVT Rolling Traction Drives – A Review of Research Into Their Design, Functionality and Modeling. Transactions of the ASME, Journal of Mechanical design, vol. 176, 1165-1176.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akehurst, S, Parker, D, Schaaf, S, 2007. Dynamic Modelling of the Milner Continuously Variable Transmission – The Basic Kinematics. Transactions of the ASME, Journal of Mechanical Design. Nov 2007 Vol. 129 Issue 11, p1170-1178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hunt, A., Akehurst, S., Schaaf, S., 2006. Design consideration and potential of the Milner CVT. In: IPDS 2006: Integrated Powertrain and Driveline Systems 2006, Dunton, Essex, United Kingdom. Woodhead Publishing Ltd., Cambridge, CB1 6AH, United Kingdom, pp. 51-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Akehurst, A. Hunt, S. Schaaf “Latest Developments in Modelling and Optimisation of the Milner CVT”, JSAE CVT-HYBRID Conference, 2007, Yokohama, Japan</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hamrock B.J. Fundamentals of Fluid Film Lubrication, McGraw Hill, 1994, ISBN 0071133569</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson K.L. Contact mechanics, Cambridge University Press, ISBN 0521347963</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tevaarwerk, J. L. Traction drive performance prediction for the Johnson and Tevaarwerk traction model, NASA Technical publication 19790025304, 1979</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tevaarwerk, J. L., and Johnson, K. L., 1979, ‘‘The Influence of Fluid Rheology on the Performance of Traction Drives,’’ ASME J. Lubr. Technol., 101, pp. 266–274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
