<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812204</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Thoughts on Shifts in Tax Structure, Business Activity and Implementing a Fiscal Union</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>JUST ROUND THE CORNER? PROS, CONS, AND IMPLEMENTATION ISSUES OF A FISCAL UNION FOR THE EURO AREA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Balassone</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabrizio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Momigliano</surname>
                  <given-names>Sandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Romanelli</surname>
                  <given-names>Marzia</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tommasino</surname>
                  <given-names>Pietro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>24</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812204"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The experience of other successful monetary unions and economic theory suggest that the euro area would benefit from the establishment of a supranational fiscal capacity (a fiscal union), to buffer country-specific shocks. The reforms prompted by the crisis (e.g., the European Stability Mechanism and the banking union) are introducing – though to a limited extent – elements of cross-country risk sharing. In particular, the banking union will help smoothing out some of the most relevant asymmetric shocks that can affect the euro area, i.e., the financial crises. Nevertheless, further elements of risk sharing are probably needed. Proposals to create a sort of rainy-day fund for the euro area present major practical difficulties – associated, inter alia, to the uncertainty characterising the identification of shocks in real time. A more appropriate solution, consistent with how risk sharing operates in existing federations – though not without implementation issues – may be centralizing specific public functions. We argue that, among these, consideration should also be given to the creation of a euro-wide, notional-defined contribution pension scheme.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Afonso, A. and D. Furceri (2008), “EMU Enlargement, Stabilization Costs And Insurance Mechanisms”, Journal of International Money and Finance, Vol. 27, No. 2, pp. 169-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Algan, Y., P. Cahuc and M. Sangnier (2011), “Efficient and Inefficient Welfare States”, CEPR, Discussion Paper, No. 8229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Allard, C., P.K. Brooks, J.C. Bluedorn, F. Bornhorst, F. Ohnsorge, K.M. Christopherson Puh (2013), “Towards a Fiscal Union for the Euro Area”, IMF, SDN/13/09.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Artus, P., A. Bénassy-Quéré, L. Boone, J. Cailloux, J. Delpla, E. Farhi, P. Gourinchas, J. Tirole and G. Wolff (2013), “Completing the Euro”, Les notes du Conseil d’Analyse Économique, No. 3, April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Asdrubali, P., B.E. Sorensen and O. Yosha (1996), “Channels of Interstate Risk Sharing: United States 1963-90”, Quarterly Journal of Economics, Vol. 111, No. 4, pp. 1081-110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Atkeson, A. and T. Bayoumi (1993), “Do Private Capital Markets Insure Regional Risk? Evidence from the United States and Europe”, Open Economies Review, Vol. 4, No. XXX, pp. 303-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Auerbach, A. and Y. Gorodnichenko (2013), “Output Spillovers from Fiscal Policy”, American Economic Review P&amp;P, Vol. 103, pp. 141-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bayoumi, T. and B. Eichengreen (1992), “Shocking Aspects of European Monetary Unification”, NBER, Working Paper, No. 3949, National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Beck, T. (ed.) (2012), Banking Union for Europe: Risks and Challenges, Centre for Economic Policy Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Beetsma, R., M. Giuliodori and F. Klaasen (2006), “Trade Spillovers of Fiscal Policy in the European Union: A Panel Analysis”, Economic Policy, Vol. 21, No. 48, pp. 640-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Buetzer, S., C. Jordan and L. Stracca (2013), “Macroeconomic Imbalances: A Question of Trust?”, ECB, Working Paper, No. 1584.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Caudal, N., N. Georges, V. Grossmann-Wirth, J. Guillaume, T. Lellouch and A. Sode (2013), “A Budget for the Euro Area”, Trésor-Economics, No. 120, October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Camussi, S., A. Linarello, A.L. Mancini and P. Tommasino (2013), “Does Trust Influence Social Expenditures? Evidence form Local Governments”, Bank of Italy, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Cwik, T. and V. Wieland (2011), “Keynesian Government Spending Multipliers and Spillovers in the Euro Area”, Economic Policy, Vol. 26, No. 67, pp. 493-549.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">De Grauwe, P. (2012), Economics of the Monetary Union, Oxford University Press, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Dellas, H. and G.S. Tavlas (2009), “An Optimum-Currency-Area Odyssey”, Journal of International Money and Finance, Vol. 28, No. 7, pp. 1117-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Doluca, H., M. Hübner, D. Rumpf and B. Weigert (2012), “The European Redemption Pact: An Illustrative Guide”, German Council of Economic Experts, Working Paper, No. 02/2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Draghi, M. (2014), “Financial Integration and Banking Union”, speech held at the conference for the 20th anniversary of the establishment of the European Monetary Institute, Brussels, February 12, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Eichengreen, B.J. (1998), “European Monetary Unification: A Tour d’Horizon”, Oxford Review of Economic Policy, Vol. 14, No. 3, pp. 24-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">European Commission (1993a), Stable Money, Sound Finances. Community Public Finances in the perspective of the EMU, European Economy, no. 53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">European Commission (1993b), The economics of community public finance, European Economy - Report and Studies, no. 5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Farhi, E. and Werning, I. (2012), "Fiscal Unions", NBER Working Papers, no. 18280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Furceri, D. and A. Zdzienicka (2013), “The Euro Area Crisis: Need for a Supranational Fiscal Risk Sharing Mechanism?”, IMF, Working Paper, No. 13/198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Goyal, R., B.P. Koeva, M. Pradhan, T. Tressel, G. Dell’Ariccia, C. Pazarbasioglu (2013), “A Banking Union for the Euro Area”, IMF, Staff Discussion Note, No. 13/1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Gros, D. (2014), “A fiscal shock absorber for the euro zone? Lessons from the economics of insurance”, www.VoxEU.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Guiso, L., H. Herrera and M. Morelli (2013), “A Cultural Clash View of the EU Crisis”, EIEF, Working Paper, No. 1321.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Hammond, G. and J. von Hagen (1998), “Insurance Against Asymmetric Shocks: An Empirical Study for the European Community”, The Manchester School, Vol. 66, No. 3, pp. 331-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Holzmann, R. (2006), “Toward a Coordinated Pension System in Europe: Rationale and Potential Structure”, in R. Holzmann and E. Palmer (eds.), Pension Reform. Issues and Prospects for NDC schemes, The World Bank, Washington (DC).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">IMF (2010), “Unemployment Dynamics During Recessions and Recoveries: Okun’s Law and Beyond”, in IMF, World Economic Outlook, April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">IMF (2010), “Will It Hurt? Macroeconomic Effects of Fiscal Consolidation”, World Economic Outlook, October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Jerome, H., Hernandez de Cos, P. and Momigliano, S. (2004), “The short term impact of government budgets on prices. Evidence from macroeconometric models”, ECB Working Paper, No. 396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Kalemli-Ozcan, S., E. Luttini and B. Sørensen (2014), “Debt Crises and Risk-Sharing: The Role of Markets Versus Sovereigns”, Scandinavian Journal of Economics, Vol. 116, No. 1, pp. 253-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Kalemli-Ozcan, S., B. Sørensen and O. Yosha (2005), “Asymmetric Shocks and Risk-sharing in a Monetary Union: Updated Evidence and Implications for Europe”, in H. Huizinga and L. Jonung (eds.), The Internationalization of Asset Ownership in Europe, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge (UK).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Kenen, P. (1969), “The Theory of Optimum Currency Areas: An Eclectic View”, in R.A. Mundell and A.K. Swoboda (eds.), Monetary Problems in the International Economy, University of Chicago Press, Chicago (IL).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Krugman, P. (2013), “The Revenge of the Optimum Currency Area”, in D. Acemoglu, J. Parker and M. Woodford (eds.), NBER Macroeconomics Annual 2012, University of Chicago Press, Chicago (IL).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">McKinnon, R. (1963), “Optimum Currency Area”, American Economic Review, Vol. 53, pp. 717-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Mélitz, J. and F. Zumer (1999) “Interregional and International Risk-sharing and Lessons for EMU”, Carnegie-Rochester Conference Series on Public Policy, Elsevier, Vol. 51, No. 1, pp. 149-88, December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Mélitz, J.(2002), “Regional redistribution and stabilization by the center in Canada, France, the UK and the US: a reassessment and new tests", Journal of Public Economics, vol. 86(2), pp. 263-286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Mody, A. (2013), “A Schuman Compact For The Euro Area”, Bruegel, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Mongelli, F.P. (2005), “What Is European and Monetary Union Telling Us About the Properties of Optimal Currency Areas?”, Journal of Common Markets Studies, Vol. 43, No. 3, pp. 607-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Mundell, R. (1961), “A Theory of Optimum Currency Areas”, American Economic Review, Vol. 51, pp. 657-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Mundell, R.(1973), “Uncommon Arguments for Common Currencies”, in H.G. Johnson and A.K. Swoboda (eds.), The Economics of Common Currencies, George Allen and Unwin Ltd., London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Musgrave, R.A. and P.B. Musgrave (1973), Public Finance in Theory and Practice, McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Oates, W. (1972), Fiscal Federalism, Harcourt Brace.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Obstfeld, M. and G. Peri (1999), “Regional Non-adjustment and Fiscal Policy: Lessons for EMU”, NBER, Working Paper, No. 6431, National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Palmer, E. (2006), “What is NDC?”, in R. Holzmann and E. Palmer (eds.), Pension Reform. Issues and Prospects for NDC schemes, The World Bank, Washington (DC).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Persson, T. and G. Tabellini (1996a), “Federal Fiscal Constitutions: Risk Sharing and Moral Hazard”, Econometrica, Vol. 64, No. 3, pp. 623-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Persson, T.(1996b), “Federal Fiscal Constitutions: Risk Sharing and Redistribution”, Journal of Political Economy, Vol. 104, No. 5, pp. 979-1009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Rey, H. (2013), “Fiscal Union in the Eurozone?”, in F. Allen, E. Carletti and J. Gray (eds.), Political, Fiscal and Banking Union in the Eurozone?, FIC Press, Wharton Financial Institution Center.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Richardson, P., L. Boone, C. Giorno, M. Meacci, D. Rae and D. Turner (2000), “The Concept, Policy Use and Measurement of Structural Unemployment: Estimating a Time Varying NAIRU Across 21 OECD Countries”, OECD, Economics Department, Working Paper, No. 250, OECD Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Roth, F., F. Nowak-Lehmann and T. Otter (2013) “Crisis and Trust in National and European Union Institutions. Panel Evidence for the EU, 1999 to 2012”, EUI, Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Sorensen, B. and O. Yosha (1998), “International Risk Sharing and European Monetary Unification”, Journal of International Economics, Vol. 45, No. 2, pp. 211-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Spolaore, E. (2013), “What Is European Integration Really About? A Political Guide for Economists”, Journal of Economic Perspectives, Vol. 27, No. 3, pp. 125-44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Trichet, J.C. (2013), “International Policy Coordination in the Euro Area: Toward an Economic and Fiscal Federation by Exception”, Journal of Policy Modeling, Vol. 35, No. 3, pp. 473-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Visco, I. (2013), “The Exit from the Euro Crisis: Opportunities and Challenges of the Banking Union”, Istituto Affari Internazionali and Council on Foreign Relations, Rome, available at: http://www.bancaditalia.it/interventi/integov/2013/IAI_farnesina/Visco_IAI__09092013.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Von Hagen, J. (1993), “Monetary Union and Fiscal Union: A Perspective from Fiscal Federalism”, in P. Masson and M. Taylor (eds.), Policy Issues in the Operation of Currency Unions, Chapter 10, Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Wallis, J.J. (1984), “The Birth of the Old Federalism: Financing the New Deal, 1932-1940”, Journal of Economic History, Vol. 44, No. 1, pp. 139-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Wolff, G.B. (2012), “A Budget for Europe’s Monetary Union”, Bruegel Policy contribution, Issue 2012/22, Bruegel, Brussels, December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>OECD indicators on Employment Protection Legislation 2013</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Net Replacement Rates for Single Earner, 2011: Initial Phase of Unemployment (available euro-area countries)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Public Expenditures on Old-age and Survivors’ Benefits</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
