<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277752</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Numerical Simulation Study on Improving the Thermal Efficiency of a Spark Ignited Engine --- Part 1</article-title>
            <subtitle>Modeling of a Spark Ignited Engine Combustion to Predict Engine Performance Considering Flame Propagation, Knock, and Combustion Chamber Wall ---</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kikusato</surname>
                  <given-names>Akira</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jin</surname>
                  <given-names>Kusaka</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Daisho</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Waseda University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>96</fpage>
         <lpage>105</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277752"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The first objective of this work is to develop a numerical simulation model of the spark ignited (SI) engine combustion, taking into account knock avoidance and heat transfer between in-cylinder gas and combustion chamber wall. Secondly, the model was utilized to investigate the potential of reducing heat losses by applying a heat insulation coating to the combustion chamber wall, thereby improving engine thermal efficiency. A reduction in heat losses is related to important operating factors of improving SI engine thermal efficiency. However, reducing heat losses tends to accompany increased combustion chamber wall temperatures, resulting in the onset of knock in SI engines. Thus, the numerical model was intended to make it possible to investigate the interaction of the heat losses and knock occurrence. The present paper consists of Part 1 and 2. Part 1 deals with the description of the numerical model and the fundamental characteristics of instantaneous temperature swings in the combustion chamber wall.</p>
            <p>The numerical model is developed by utilizing GT-POWER combined with three sub-models; a non-dimensional two-zone combustion model, an autoignition model in the unburned gas and an instantaneous heat transfer model in the combustion chamber wall. The combustion model considers the flame speeds affected by the in-cylinder conditions. The Shell model was utilized to predict autoignition. The heat transfer model in the combustion chamber wall calculates the instantaneous one-dimensional thermal conductivity, and further predicts wall surface and inside temperatures. The fluctuation range of calculated temperature swings is reasonably similar to measured data obtained in previous studies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawamura, H., Matsuoka, H. and Hara, S., “Construction of Heat- Insulated Engine with Large Heat-Insulation Rate (in Japanese)”, JSME Transaction, No. 93-0702, 4059-4063, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xin, J., Shih, S., Itano, E., and Maeda, Y., “Integration of 3D Combustion Simulations and Conjugate Heat Transfer Analysis to Quantitatively Evaluate Component Temperatures,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3128, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shih, S., Itano, E., Xin, J., Kawamoto, M. et al., “Engine Knock Toughness Improvement Through Water Jacket Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3259, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Mizuta, J., Fuyuto, T., Hashizume, T. et al., “Low Emissions and High-Efficiency Diesel Combustion Using Highly Dispersed Spray with Restricted In-Cylinder Swirl and Squish Flows,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):2065-2079, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1393.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujimoto, H., Yamamoto, H., Fujimoto, M., and Yamashita, H., “A Study on Improvement of Indicated Thermal Efficiency of ICE Using High Compression Ratio and Reduction of Cooling Loss,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1872, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01- 1872.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Das, S. and Roberts, C., “Factors Affecting Heat Transfer in a Diesel Engine: Low Heat Rejection Engine Revisited,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0875, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0875.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nomura, K., Tanaka, K., Sakai, S., Kusaka, J. and Daisho, Y., “Improving Thermal Efficiency of an SI engine by Avoiding Knock Occurrence (in Japanese)”, JSAE Transaction, Vol.42, no.4, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kikusato, A., Kusaka, J. and Daisho, Y., “A Numerical Study on Evaluating the Performance of a Turbocharged Spark Ignition Natural Gas Engine (in Japanese)”, JSAE Transaction, Vol.44, no.3, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Rackmil, C., Keribar, R., and Jennings, M., “Model for Heat Transfer and Combustion In Spark Ignited Engines and its Comparison with Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 880198, 1988, doi:10.4271/880198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., International Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Halstead, M. P., Kirsch, L. J. and Quinn, C. P., “The autoignition of hydrocarbon fuels at high temperatures and pressures - Fitting of a mathematical model”, Combustion and Flame 30, 45-60, 1977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golovichev, V. I., “Compression Ignited Engine Modeling - A Possible “Road Map” in Solving New Problems”, Lecture for ICE2003 Italy, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morgan, N., Smallbone, A., Bhave, A., Markus, K. et al., “Mapping surrogate gasoline compositions into RON/MON space”, Combustion and Flame 157, 1122-1131, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patankar, S. V., “Numerical Heat Transfer and Fluid Flow”, Taylor &amp; Francis, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colburn, A. P., “A Method of Correlating Forced Convection Heat Transfer Data and a Comparison with Fluid Friction”, Int. J. Heat Mass Transfer, Vol.7, 1359-1384, 1964.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dittus, F. W. and Boelter, L. M. K., “Heat Transfer in Automobile Radiators of the Tubular Type”, Int. Comm. Heat Mass Transfer, Vol.12, 3-22, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Enomoto, Y. and Furuhama, S., “A Study of the Local Heat Transfer Coefficient on the Combustion Chamber Walls of a 4-Stroke Gasoline Engine (in Japanese)”, JSME Transaction, No.86-1451A, 3835-3843, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, J., Güralp, O., Filipi, Z., Assanis, D. et al., “New Heat Transfer Correlation for an HCCI Engine Derived from Measurements of Instantaneous Surface Heat Flux,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2996, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C. D., Giakoumis, E. G. and Rakopoulos, D. C., “Study of the short-term cylinder wall temperature oscillations during transient operation of a turbo-charged diesel engine with various insulation schemes”, Int. J. Eng. Res., Vol.9, 177-193, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
