<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100238</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">jmonecredbank</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Money, Credit and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00222879</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15384616</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley (Variant)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26614929</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Impact of Housing Markets on Consumer Debt</article-title>
            <subtitle>Credit Report Evidence from 1999 to 2012</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>BROWN</surname>
                  <given-names>META</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>STEIN</surname>
                  <given-names>SARAH</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>ZAFAR</surname>
                  <given-names>BASIT</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>March-April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">47</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">S1</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Supplement 1</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26614915</issue-id>
         <fpage>175</fpage>
         <lpage>213</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Federal Reserve Bank of New York</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26614929"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We estimate the response of consumer debt portfolios to pronounced housing market swings from 1999 to 2012 using Equifax-sourced credit report data and a variety of identification approaches. We find: (i) the extraordinary climb in home equity debt from 2002 to 2006 is an expression of a stable, longer-term relationship between house price growth and home equity borrowing; (ii) all preboom homeowners, and older and prime postboom homeowners, demonstrate near dollar-for-dollar substitution between (expensive) credit card and (cheap) home equity debt in response to home equity changes; and (iii) little evidence of substitution between home equity and student loan debt.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>LITERATURE CITED</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Aron, Janine, John V. Duca, John Muellbauer, Keiko Murata, and Anthony Murphy. (2012) “Credit, Housing Collateral, and Consumption: Evidence from Japan, the U.K., and the U.S.” Review of Income and Wealth, 58, 397–423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bhutta, Neil, and Benjamin J. Keys. (2014) “Interest Rates and Equity Extraction During the Housing Boom.” Public Law and Legal Theory Working Paper Series, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Brady, Peter, Glenn Canner, and Dean Maki. (2000) “The Effects of Recent Mortgage Refinancing.” Federal Reserve Bulletin, 86, 441–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Brown, Meta,AndrewHaughwout,Donghoon Lee, andWilbert van derKlaauw. (2011a) “Have Consumers Been Deleveraging?” Liberty Street Economics [blog], Federal Reserve Bank of New York, March 21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Brown, Meta, Andrew Haughwout, Donghoon Lee, andWilbert van der Klaauw. (2011b) “Do We Know What We Owe? A Comparison of Borrower- and Lender-Reported Consumer Debt.” Federal Reserve Bank of New York Staff Reports Paper No. 523.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Brown, Meta, Andrew Haughwout, Donghoon Lee, and Wilbert van derKlaauw. (2013) “The Financial Crisis at the Kitchen Table: Trends in Household Debt and Credit.” Current Issues in Economics and Finance, 19, 1–10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bucks, Brian, and Karen Pence. (2008) “Do Borrowers Know their Mortgage Terms?” Journal of Urban Economics, 64, 218–33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Buiter, Willem. (2010) “Housing Wealth Isn’t Wealth.” Economics 3, 2010–22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Canner, Glenn, Karen Dynan, and Wayne Passmore. (2002) “Mortgage Refinancing in 2001 and Early 2002.” Federal Reserve Bulletin, 88, 469–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Charles, Kerwin K., Erik Hurst, and Matt Notowidigdo. (2013) “Manufacturing Declines, Housing Booms and Non-Employment” Manuscript, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Charles,Kerwin K., ErikHurst, and Matt Notowidigdo. (2014) “HousingBooms, Labor Market Outcomes, and Educational Attainment” Manuscript, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Chetty, Raj, and Adam Szeidl. (2012) “The Effect of Housing on Portfolio Choice” NBER Working Paper No. 15998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Clingingsmith, David, Daniel Hartley, and Justin Sydnor. (2012) “Biting Off More than They CanChew? Debt-Delinquency Patterns for NewHomecomers.” Manuscript, FederalReserve Bank of Cleveland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Davidoff, Thomas. (2013) “Supply Elasticity and the Housing Cycle of the 2000s.” Real Estate Economics, 41, 793–813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Duca, John V., John Muellbauer, and Anthony Murphy. (2011) “House Prices and Credit Constraints: Making Sense of the US Experience.” The Economic Journal, 121, 533–51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Dynan, Karen. (2012) “Is a Household Debt Overhang Holding Back Consumption?” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Spring, 299–344.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Federal Reserve Bank of New York. (2014) Quarterly Report on Household Debt and Credit. http://www.newyorkfed.org/householdcredit/2014-q3/data/pdf/HHDC 2014Q3.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gerardi, Christopher, Chris Foote, and Paul Willen. (2012) “Why Did So Many People Make So Many Ex Post Bad Decisions? The Causes of the Foreclosure Crisis.” In Rethinking the Financial Crisis, edited by Alan Blinder, Andrew Lo, and Robert Solow, pp. 136–86. New York: Russell Sage Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gropp, Reint, John Krainer, and Elizabeth Laderman. (2013) “Do Consumers Want Less Debt?” Manuscript, Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Halket, Jonathan. (2012) “Do Households Use Homeownership to Insure Themselves: Evidence Across U.S. Cities.” Manuscript, University of Essex.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Haughwout, Andrew, Donghoon Lee, Joelle Scally, and Wilbert van derKlaauw. (2012) “Has Household Deleveraging Continued?” Liberty Street Economics [blog], Federal Reserve Bank of New York, August 29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Lee, Donghoon, and Wilbert van derKlaauw. (2010), “An Introduction to the FRBNY Consumer Credit Panel.” Federal Reserve Bank of New York Staff Report No. 479.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Lehnert, Andreas. (2004) “Housing, Consumption, and Credit Constraints.” Finance and Economics Discussion Series No. 2004-63, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Lovenheim,Michael F. (2011) “The Effect of Liquid HousingWealth on College Enrollment.” Journal of Labor Economics, 29, 741–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Lovenheim, Michael F., and C. Lockwood Reynolds. (2012) “The Effect of Housing Wealth on College Choice: Evidence from the Housing Boom.” NBER Working Paper No. 18075.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Lovenheim, Michael F., and Kevin Mumford. (2013) “Do Family Wealth Shocks Affect Fertility Choices? Evidence from the Housing Market.” Review of Economics and Statistic, 95, 464–475.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Mian, Atif, Kamalesh Rao, and Amir Sufi. (2013) “Household Balance Sheets, Consumption, and the Economic Slump.” Manuscript, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Mian,Atif, and Amir Sufi. (2009) “The Consequences of Mortgage Credit Expansion: Evidence from the U.S. Mortgage Default Crisis.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 124, 1449–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Mian, Atif, and Amir Sufi. (2011) “House Prices, Home Equity-Based Borrowing, and the US Household Leverage Crisis.” American Economic Review, 101, 2132–56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Mian, Atif, and Amir Sufi. (2012) “What Explains High Unemployment? The Aggregate Demand Channel.” NBER Working Paper No. 17830.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Palmer, Christopher. (2014) “Why Did So Many Subprime Borrowers Default During the Crisis: Loose Credit or Plummeting Prices?” Manuscript, University of California, Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Saiz, Albert. (2010) “The Geographic Determinants of Housing Supply.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 125, 1253–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Scholz, John Karl, Ananth Seshadri , and Surachai Khitatrakun. (2006) “AreAmericans Saving ‘Optimally’ for Retirement?” Journal of Political Economy, 114, 607–43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Stock, James H., Jonathan H. Wright, and Motohiro Yogo. (2002) “A Survey of Weak Instruments and Weak Identification in Generalized Method of Moments.” Journal of Business and Economic Statistics, 20, 518–29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Stock, James H., and Motohiro Yogo. (2005) “Testing for Weak Instruments in Linear IV Regression.” In Identification and Inference for Econometric Models: Essays in Honor of Thomas Rothenberg, edited by Donald W. K. Andrews and James H. Stock, pp. 80–108. New York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Whitehouse, Mark. (2010) “Defaults Account for Most of Pared Down Debt.” Real Time Economics [blog], September 18. http://blogs.wsj.com/economics/2010/09/18/ number-of-the-week-defaults-account-for-most-of-pared-down-debt/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>U.S. Nonmortgage Consumer Debt, 1999–2012.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics for the Three Estimation Samples</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>First-Differenced Instrumental Variables Estimates of the Effect of House Price Changes on Auto, Credit Card, and Student Loan Balances</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>First-Differenced Instrumental Variables Estimates of the Effect of House Price Changes on Auto, Credit Card, and Student Loan Balances, by Risk Score</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>First-Differenced Instrumental Variables Estimates of the Effect of House Price Changes on Auto, Credit Card, and Student Loan Balances, by Age</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Zip Code Aggregate First-Differenced Instrumental Variables Estimates of the Effects of House Price and HELOC Changes on Student Loan Balances</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Mean Home Equity Debt Among Homeowners in High and Low House Price Appreciation Zip Codes.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Mean Nonmortgage Debt among Owners and Renters in High and Low House Price Appreciation Zip Codes.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Uncontrolled Difference-in-Differences Estimates of the Effect of House Price Appreciation Quartile on Consumer Debts.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Difference-in-Differences Estimates of the Effect of Home Price Appreciation on Total Nonmortgage Debt.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A1</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>First-Stage Regression of House Price Index Change on Land Supply Elasticity Instrument</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A2</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>First-Differenced OLS Estimates of the Effect of House Price Changes on Auto, Credit Card, and Student Loan Balances, by Risk Score</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A3</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>First-Differenced OLS Estimates of the Effect of House Price Changes on Auto, Credit Card, and Student Loan Balances, by Age</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
