<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308256</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Dual Phase High Temperature Heat Release Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shibata</surname>
                  <given-names>Gen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Central Technical Research Laboratory</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Nippon Oil Corporation</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Urushihara</surname>
                  <given-names>Tomonori</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Nissan Research Center</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Nissan Motor Co., Ltd.</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>12</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308256"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>To allow the HCCI vehicles to enter the market in the future, it is important to investigate the combustion deviations and operational range differences between the same research octane number fuels. In this paper, eighteen kinds of two hydrocarbon blended fuels, which were composed of n-heptane and another hydrocarbon, such as iso-octane, diisobutylene, 4-methyl-1-pentene, toluene or cyclopentane, were evaluated. Those fuels were blended to have the same research octane numbers of 75, 80, 85 and 90 by changing the blending volume ratio of n-heptane and counterpart hydrocarbon. Intake air was supercharged to 155 kPa abs and its temperature was kept at 58 °C. The HCCI engine was operated at 1000 rpm. Neither hot EGR, nor any other combustion stratification system was utilized in order to investigate the purely hydrocarbon effects on HCCI combustion. In-cylinder pressure data were taken at 7 different maximum pressure rise rate conditions, which were 900, 800, 700, 600, 500, 400 and 300 kPa/deg of 400 cycles averaged in-cylinder pressure traces, by changing the fuel injection quantity. The test results showed that the engine operational range of n-heptane and iso-octane blended fuels (PRF) were the same as those of n-heptane and diisobutylene blended fuels (NDB), and n-heptane and 4-methyl-1-pentene blended fuels (NMP). The operational ranges of n-heptane and toluene blended fuels (NTL) were at high IMEP conditions, but those of n-heptane and cyclopentane blended fuels (NCP) were only at low IMEP conditions, compared with the cases of PRF series fuels, NDB series fuels and NMP series fuels. To investigate those operational range differences, heat release data were analyzed at the same HTHR CA50 (the crank angle of 50 % burn of high temperature heat release) and IMEP conditions. As NTL fuels show the largest low temperature heat release (LTHR), high temperature heat release (HTHR) starts earlier than the other fuels. Furthermore, the HTHR combustion period of the NTL fuels was longer than the other fuels since the NTL fuels displayed dual phase high temperature heat release (DP-HTHR) combustion. The first part of the HTHR is caused by n-heptane, and second is caused by benzyl radicals and aromatics produced from toluene. Therefore the maximum pressure rise rate can be reduced, and NTL fuel is effective in achieving low combustion noise and high IMEP engine operation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFFRENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aroonsrisopon, T., Nitz, D., Waldman, T., and Foster, D., “A Computational Analysis of Direct Fuel Injection uring the Negative Valve Overlap period in an so-Octane Fueled HCCI Engine”, SAE Technical Paper, o. 2007-01-0227, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M., and Dec, J., “Combined Effect of Fuel- ype and Engine Speed on Intake Temperature equirement completeness of Bulk-Gas Reactions”, AE Technical Paper, No. 2003-01-3173, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., and Sjoberg, M., “Isolating the Effects of Fuel hemistry on Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine nd the Potential of Fuel Stratification for Ignition ontrol”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2004-01-0557, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M., and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI eat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification ith Two-Stage Ignition Fuels”, SAE Technical Paper, o. 2006-01-0629, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P., Schleyer, C., Duffy, K., Hardy, W., and iechty, M., “Effects of Fuel Property Changes on eavy-Duty HCCI Combustion”, SAE Technical Paper, o. 2007-01-0191, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryan, T., and Matheaus, A., “Fuel Requirements for CCI Engine”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2003-01-1813, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryan III, T., Callahan, T., and Mehta, D., “HCCI in a ariable Compression Ratio Engine-Effects of Engine ariables”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2004-01-1971, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shibata, G., Oyama, K., Urushihara, T., and Nakano, T., “The Effect of Fuel Properties on Low and High emperature Heat Release and Resulting Performance f an HCCI Engine”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2004-01-0553, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L., Stromberg, E., and Denbratt, I., “The nfluence of PRF and Commercial Fuels with High ctane Number on the Auto-ignition Timing of an ngine Operated in HCCI Combustion Mode with egative Valve Overlap”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2004-01-1967, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leppard, W., “A Comparison of Olefin and Paraffin utoignition Chemistries: A Motored Engine Study”, AE Technical Paper 892081, 1989</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunting, B., “Combustion, Control, and Fuel Effects in a park Assited HCCI Engine Equipped with Variable alve Timing”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2006-01-0872, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Orlandini, I., Kulzer, A., Weberbauer, F., and Rauscher, ., “Simulation of Self Ignition in HCCI and Partial CCI Engines Using a Reduced Order Model”, SAE echnical Paper, No. 2005-01-0159, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sato, S., Jun, D., Kweon, S., Yamashita, D., and Iida, N., “Basic Research on the Suitable Fuel for HCCI Engine rom the Viewpoint of Chemical Reaction”, SAE echnical Paper, No. 2005-01-0149, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konno, M., and Chen, Z., “Ignition Mechanisms of HCCI ombustion Process Fueled with Methane/DME omposite Fuel”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2005-01-0182, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamada, H., Sakanashi, H., Choi, N., and Tezaki, A., “Simplified Oxidation Mechanism of DME applicable for ompression Ignition”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2003-01-1819, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamada, H., Yoshii, M., and Tezaki, A., “Chemical echanistic analysis of additive effects in omogeneous charge compression ignition of dimethyl ther”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 30 (2005) 2773-2780</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamada, H., Ohtomo, M., Yoshii, M., and Tezaki, A., “Controlling mechanism of ignition enhancing and uppressing additives in premixed compression gnition”, Int. J. Engine Res. Vol. 6, PP 331-340, ER02705 IMechE 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Miyamoto, N., Kaneko, N. and Ando, H., “Combustion Control and Operating Range Expansion n an HCCI engine with Selective Use of Fuels with ifferent Low-Temperature Oxidation Characteristics”, AE Technical Paper, No. 2003-01-1827, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Miyamoto, N., Kaneko, N., and Ando, H., “Combustion Control and Operating Range Expansion n an HCCI Engine with Reaction Inhibitors”, nternational Journal of Engine Research, IMechE, 6:342-359 (2005)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Kaneko, N., Ando, H., and Miyamoto, N., “Combustion Control and Operating Range Expansion ith Direct Injection of Reactions Suppressors in a remixed DME HCCI Engine”, SAE Technical Paper, o. 2003-01-0746, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., “Fuel Anti-Knock Quality-Part I, Engine tudies”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2001-01-3584, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., “Fuel Anti-knock Quality-Part II, Vehicle tudies-How Relevant is Motor Octane Number (MON) n Modern Engines?”, SAE Technical Paper No. 2001-01-3585, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Risberg, P., and Angstrom, H., “A Method f Defining Ignition Quality of Fuels in HCCI Engines”, AE Technical Paper, No. 2003-01-1816, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., and Head, R., “The Available and equired Autoignition Quality of Gasoline-like Fuels in CCI Engines at High Temperatures”, SAE Technical aper, No. 2004-01-1969, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Risberg, P., Kalghatgi, G., and Angstrom, H., “The nfluence of EGR on Auo-ignition Quality of asoline-like Fuels in HCCI Engines”, SAE Technical aper, No. 2004-01-2952, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aroonsrisopon, T., Foster, D., Morikawa, T., and Iida, M., “Comparison of HCCI Operating Range for ombinations of Intake Temperature, Engine Speed nd Fuel Composition”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2002-01-1924, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shibata, G., Oyama, K., Urushihara, T., and Nakano, T., “Correlation of Low Temperature Heat Release with uel Composition and HCCI Engine Combustion”, SAE echnical Paper, No. 2005-01-0138, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westbrook, C., “Chemical Kinetics of Hydrocarbon gnition in Practical Combustion Systems”, Proceeding f the Combustion Institute, Vol. 28, pp1563-1577, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka, S., Ayala, F., and Keck, J., “A reduced chemical inetic model for HCCI combustion of primary reference uels in a rapid compression machine”, Combustion and lame, 133 pp 467-481, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., Leppard, W., and Sloane, T., “The Effect of POx n the Autoignition Chemistry of n-Heptane and sooctane in an HCCI Engine”, SAE Technical Paper, o. 2002-01-2861, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tezaki, A., “Diesel Combustion: Chemical Kinetics”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 20054246, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamada, H., Yoshii, M., and Tezaki, A., “A Chemical echanistic Analysis on Compression Ignition Process f Straight Chain Alkanes”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2004-01-1912, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shibata, G., and Urushihara, T., “The Interaction etween Fuel Chemicals and HCCI Combustion haracteristics Under Heated Intake Air Conditions”, AE Technical Paper, No. 2006-01-0207, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shibata, G., and Urushihara, T., “Auto-Ignition haracteristics of Hydrocarbons and Development of CCI Fuel Index”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2007-01-0220, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiraya, K., Hasegawa, K., Urushihara, T., Iiyama, A., nd Itoh, T., “A Study on Gasoline Fueled Compression gnition Engine: A Trial of Operation Region Expansion”, AE Technical Paper, No. 2002-01-0416, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steeper, R., and Zilwa, S., “Improving the NOx-CO2 rade- Off of an HCCI Engine Using a Multi-Hole njector”, SAE Technical Paper, No. 2007-01-0180, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berntsson, A., and Denbratt, I., “HCCI Combustion sing Charge Stratification for Combustion Control”, AE Technical Paper, No. 2007-01-0210, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Compton, G., and Hancock, “Low Temperature ombustion and Autoignition”, page 115, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
