<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812228</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Taxation and Corporate Investment</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Dividend Taxation and Merger Behavior</article-title>
            <subtitle>A New View Explanation For The Post-Merger Performance Puzzle</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ohrn</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Seegert</surname>
                  <given-names>Nathan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>42</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812228"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Mergers and acquisitions are a large part of the United States economy. Between 2000 and 2012, the dollar value of merger and acquisition activity was $12.78 trillion. Mergers are critical to economic growth because, done well, they can capitalize on positive synergies and economies of scale, thereby increasing efficiency and creating value for shareholders. However, executed poorly, mergers can dampen innovation, decrease efficiency, and destroy shareholder value. Because of the scale and significance of this topic, large literatures in finance and economics have developed that discuss possible mechanisms which distort merger and acquisition behavior. We follow in this tradition by examining dividend taxation and its affect on merger behavior. We develop a “new view” of corporate taxation model in which dividend taxation causes inefficient mergers. We find strong empirical support for the model, demonstrating long run returns are 8 to 10 percent higher for dividend paying firms following the 2003 US dividend tax reform. These results suggest the tax mechanism we propose may be able to explain, at least in part, the post-merger performance puzzle in the finance literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Agrawal, Anup and G.N. Madelker, “Large Sheholders and the Monitoring of Managers: The Case of Anti-takeover Charter Amendments,” Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 1990, 25(2), 143–161.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Agrawal, Anup and G.N. Madelkerand J. Jaffee, “The Post-Merger Performance Puzzle,” in Cary Cooper and Alan Gregory, eds., Advances in Mergers and Acquistions, Elsevier Science, 2000, pp. 7–41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Agrawal, Anup and G.N. Madelker and G.N. Madelker, “The Post-Merger Performance of Acquiring Firms: A Reexamination of an Anomoly,” Journal of Finance, 1992, 47, 1605–1621.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Auerbach, Alan J., “Wealth Maximiation and the Cost of Capital,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1979, 93(3), 433–436.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Auerbach, Alan J., David Reishus, “The Impact of Taxation on Mergers and Acquisitions,” in Alan J.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Auebach, ed., Mergers and Acquistions, UMI, 1987, pp. 69–82. and , “The Effects of Taxation on the Merger Decision,” in J. Auerbach, Alan, ed., Corporate Takovers: Causes and Consequences, UMI, 1988, pp. 157–190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bessembinder, Hendrik and Feng Zhang, “Firm characteristics and long-run stock returns after corporate events,” Journal of Financial Economics, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Chetty, Raj and Emmanuel Saez, “Dividend Taxes and Corporate Behavior: Evidence from the 2003 Dividend Tax Cut,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 2005, 120(3), 791–833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Chetty, Raj and Emmanuel Saez , “An Agency Theory of Dividend Taxation,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2010, 2(3), 1–21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Fama, Eugene F. and Kenneth French, “The Cross-Section of Expected Stock Returns, Journal of Finance, 1992, 47, 427–465.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Fama, Eugene F. and Kenneth French and , “Common Risk Factos in the Returns on Stock and Bonds,” Journal of Financial Economics, 1993, 33, 3–56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Franks, Julian, Robert Harris, and Sheridan Titman, “The Postmerger Share-Price Performance of Acquring Firms,” Journal of Financial Economics, 1991, 29, 81–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Gregory, Alan, “An Examination of the Long Run Performance of UK Acquiring Firms, Journal of Business Finance and Accounting, 1997, 24, 971–1002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Lakonishok, Josef and Theo Vermaelen, “Tax-induced trading around ex-dividend days,” Journal of Financial Economics, 1986, 16 (3), 287–319.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Loughran, Tim and Anand M. Vijh, “Do Long-Term Shareholders Benefit from Corporate Acquisitions,” Journal of Finance, 1997, 52, 1765–1790.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Majluf, Nicholas S. Myers Stewart C.and, “Corporate Financing and Investment Decisions when Firms have Information that Investors Do Not Have,” Journal of Financial Economics, 1984, 13, 187–221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Martin, Kenneth J, “The method of payment in corporate acquisitions, investment opportunities, and management ownership,” The Journal of Finance, 1996, 51 (4), 1227–1246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Michaely, Roni, “Ex-Dividend Day Stock Price Behavior: The Case of the 1986 Tax Reform Act*,” The Journal of Finance, 1991, 46 (3), 845–859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Rau, Raghavendra P. and Theo Vermaelen, “Glamour, value and the post-acquistions performance of acquiring firms,” Journal of Financial Economics, 1998, 49(2), 223–253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Robin, Ashok J, “The impact of the 1986 tax reform act on ex-dividend day returns,”Financial Management, 1991, pp. 60–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Sinn, Hans-Werner, “Taxation and the cost of capital: The” old” view, the” new” view, and another view,” in “Tax Policy and the Economy, Volume 5,” The MIT Press, 1991, pp. 25–54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Stephens, Clifford P and Michael S Weisbach, “Actual share reacquisitions in openmarket repurchase programs,” The Journal of Finance, 1998, 53 (1), 313–333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Travlos, Nickolaos G, “Corporate takeover bids, methods of payment, and bidding firms’ stock returns,” The Journal of Finance, 1987, 42 (4), 943–963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Wansley, James W, William R Lane, and Ho C Yang, “Abnormal returns to acquired firms by type of acquisition and method of payment,” Financial management, 1983, pp. 16–22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Common Trend Assumption</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Returns Means</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Difference-in-Difference Estimates: Low Institutional Firms Sub-Sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Difference-in-Difference-in-Difference Estimates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Difference High-Tax and Low-Tax Time Periods</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Robustness: New Data Set 1992-2012</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Alternative Explanation: Method of Payment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Alternative Method: Firm Monitoring</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Robustness: Varying Performance Outcome Time Horizons</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Robustness: Eliminating Mergers in Quick Succession</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
