<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">19</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3/4</issue>
         <issue-id>i20060477</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">20060486</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1007/s10590-006-9015-5</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Hybrid Data-Driven Models of Machine Translation</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Declan</given-names>
                  <surname>Groves</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Andy</given-names>
                  <surname>Way</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2005</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>301</fpage>
         <lpage>323</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2006 Springer Science+Business Media B.V.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/20060486"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper presents an extended, harmonised account of our previous work on combining subsentential alignments from phrase-based statistical machine translation (SMT) and example-based MT (EBMT) systems to create novel hybrid data-driven systems capable of outperforming the baseline SMT and EBMT systems from which they were derived. In previous work, we demonstrated that while an EBMT system is capable of outperforming a phrase-based SMT (PBSMT) system constructed from freely available resources, a hybrid 'example-based' SMT system incorporating marker chunks and SMT subsentential alignments is capable of outperforming both baseline translation models for French-English translation. In this paper, we show that similar gains are to be had from constructing a hybrid 'statistical' EBMT system. Unlike the previous research, here we use the Europarl training and test sets, which are fast becoming the standard data in the field. On these data sets, while all hybrid 'statistical' EBMT variants still fall short of the quality achieved by the baseline PBSMT system, we show that adding the marker chunks to create a hybrid 'example-based' SMT system outperforms the two baseline systems from which it is derived. Furthermore, we provide further evidence in favour of hybrid systems by adding an SMT target-language model to the EBMT system, and demonstrate that this too has a positive effect on translation quality. We also show that many of the subsentential alignments derived from the Europarl corpus are created by either the PBSMT or the EBMT system, but not by both. In sum, therefore, despite the obvious convergence of the two paradigms, the crucial differences between SMT and EBMT contribute positively to the overall translation quality. The central thesis of this paper is that any researcher who continues to develop an MT system using either of these approaches will benefit further from integrating the advantages of the other model; dogged adherence to one approach will lead to inferior systems being developed.</p>
          </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>Hybrid</kwd>
            <kwd>Example-based MT</kwd>
            <kwd>Statistical MT</kwd>
            <kwd>Statistical language models</kwd>
            <kwd>Convergence</kwd>
            <kwd>Chunk coverage</kwd>
            <kwd>Europarl corpus</kwd>
          </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
        
         <fn-group>
            <title>[Footnotes]</title>
            <fn id="d1460290e154a1310">
               <label>1</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e161" publication-type="other">
http://www.isi.edu/licensed-sw/pharaoh/</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e167" publication-type="other">
http://
www.isi.edu/licensed-sw/rewrite-decoder/</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d1460290e177a1310">
               <label>3</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e184" publication-type="other">
http://www.isi.edu/~och/Giza++.html</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d1460290e191a1310">
               <label>5</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e198" publication-type="other">
Available at http://www.statmt.org/europarl</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d1460290e205a1310">
               <label>8</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e212" publication-type="other">
Available at http://www.speech.sri.com/projects/srilm/</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      
        
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d1460290e228a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e232" publication-type="other">
Aue A, Menezes A, Moore R, Quirk C, Ringger E (2004) Statistical machine translation using labeled
semantic dependency graphs. In: Proceedings of the tenth conference on theoretical and method-
ological issues in machine translation TMI-04, Baltimore, Maryland, pp. 125-134</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e245a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e249" publication-type="other">
Bangalore S, Murdock V, Riccardi G (2002) Boostrapping bilingual data using consensus translation
for a multilingual instant messaging system. In: Coling 2002 Proceedings of the 19th international
conference on computational linguistics, Taipei, Taiwan, pp. 1-7</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e262a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e266" publication-type="other">
Brown PF, Cocke J, Delia Pietra SA, Delia Pietra VJ, Jelinek F, Lafferty JD, Mercer RL, Roossin PS
(1990) A statistical approach to machine translation. Comput Ling 16:79-85</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e275" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg
et al. (2002), pp. 355-362</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e285a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e289" publication-type="other">
Brown PF, Delia Pietra SA, Delia Pietra VJ, Mercer RL (1993) The mathematics of statistical machine
translation: Parameter estimation. Comput Ling 19:263-311</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e300a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e304" publication-type="other">
Brown RD (1999) Adding linguistic knowledge to a lexical example-based translation system. In:
Proceedings of the 8th international conference on theoretical and methodological issues in
machine translation (TMI-99), Chester, England, pp. 22-32</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e317a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e321" publication-type="other">
Callison-Burch C, Osborne M, Koehn P (2006) Re-evaluating the role of bleu in machine translation
research. In: 11th conference of the European Association for Computational Linguistics, Trento,
Italy, pp. 249-256</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e334a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e338" publication-type="other">
Carl M, Hansen S (1999) Linking translation memories with example-based machine translation. In:
Proceedings of MT Summit VII "MT in the great translation era", Singapore, pp. 617-624</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e348a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e352" publication-type="other">
Carl M, Way A (eds) (2003) Recent advances in example-based machine translation, Kluwer
Academic Publishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e362a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e366" publication-type="other">
Germann U, Jahr M, Knight K, Marcu D, Yamada K (2001) Fast decoding and optimal decoding for
machine translation. In: Association for Computational Linguistics: 39th annual meeting and 10th
conference of the European chapter, Toulouse, France, pp. 228-235</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e379a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e383" publication-type="other">
Goodman J (2001) A bit of progress in language modeling. Comput Speech Lang 15:403-434</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e391a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e395" publication-type="other">
Gough N (2005) Example-based machine translation using the marker hypothesis. PhD Thesis, Dublin
City University, Dublin, Ireland</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e405a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e409" publication-type="other">
Gough N, Way A (2004a) Example-based controlled translation. In: Proceedings of the 9th EAMT
workshop: Broadening horizons of machine translation and its applications, Valetta, Malta,
pp. 73-81</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e422a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e426" publication-type="other">
Gough N, Way A (2004b) Robust large-scale EBMT with marker-based segmentation. In: Proceedings
of the tenth conference on theoretical and methodological issues in machine translation TMI-04,
Baltimore, MD, pp. 95-104</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e439a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e443" publication-type="other">
Green T (1979) The necessity of syntax markers: Two experiments with artificial languages. J Verb
Learn Behav 18:481-496</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e453a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e457" publication-type="other">
Groves D, Way A (2005) Hybrid example-based SMT: The best of both worlds? In: Proceedings of
the ACL 2005 workshop on building and using parallel texts: Data-driven machine translation
and beyond, Ann Arbor, MI, pp. 183-190</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e470a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e474" publication-type="other">
Hearne M, Way A (2003) Seeing the wood for the trees: Data-oriented translation. In: MT Summit
IX: Proceedings of the ninth machine translation summit, New Orleans, USA, pp. 165-172</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e485a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e489" publication-type="other">
Imamura K, Okuma H, Watanabe T, Sumita E (2004) Example-based machine translation based
on syntactic transfer with statistical models. In: Coling: 20th international conference on
computational linguistics, Geneva, Switzerland, pp. 99-105</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e502a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e506" publication-type="other">
Koehn P (2004a) Statistical significance tests for machine translation evaluation. In: Conference on
empirical methods in natural language processing, Barcelona, Spain, pp. 388-395</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e516a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e520" publication-type="other">
Koehn P (2004b) Pharaoh: A beam search decoder for phrase-based statistical machine translation
models. In: Frederking RE, Taylor KB (eds) Machine translation: From real users to research;
6th conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas, AMTA 2004,
Washington, DC, USA, September/October 2004, Springer, Berlin, Germany, pp. 115-124</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e536a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e540" publication-type="other">
Koehn P (2005) Europarl: A parallel corpus for statistical machine translation. In: MT Summit X:
The tenth machine translation summit, Phuket, Thailand, pp. 79-86</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e550a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e554" publication-type="other">
Koehn P, Och FJ, Marcu D (2003) Statistical phrase-based translation. In: HLT-NAACL:
Human language technology conference of the North American chapter of the Association for
Computational Linguistics, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada, pp. 127-133</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e567a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e571" publication-type="other">
Langlais P, Simard M (2002) Merging example-based and statistical machine translation. In: Richard-
son SD (ed) Machine translation: From research to real users, 5th conference of the Association
for Machine Translation in the Americas (AMTA-2002), Tiburon, CA, USA, October 2002
proceedings, Springer, Berlin, Germany, pp. 104-113</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e588a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e592" publication-type="other">
Marcu D (2001) Towards a unified approach to memory- and statistical-based machine translation.
In: Association for Computational Linguistics: 39th annual meeting and 10th conference of the
European chapter, Toulouse, France, pp. 378-385</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e605a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e609" publication-type="other">
Marcus M, Kim G, Marcinkiewicz MA, MacIntyre R, Ferguson M, Katz K, Schasberger B (1994) The
Penn Treebank: Annotating predicate argument structure. In: Proceedings of the ARPA human
language technology workshop, Princeton, NJ, pp. 110-115</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e622a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e626" publication-type="other">
Nagao M (1984) A framework of a mechanical translation between Japanese and English by analogy
principle. In Elithorn A, Banerji R (eds) Artificial and human intelligence (Edited review papers
presented at the international NATO symposium on artificial and human intelligence), North-
Holland, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 173-180</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e641" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg et al. (2002), pp. 351-354</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e648a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e652" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg S, Somers H, Wilks Y (eds) (2003) Readings in machine translation. MIT Press, Cambridge,
MA</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e662a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e666" publication-type="other">
Och FJ (2003) Minimum error rate training in statistical machine translation. In: 41st annual meeting
of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Sapporo, Japan, pp. 160-167</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e676a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e680" publication-type="other">
Och FJ, Ney H (2003) A systematic comparison of various statistical alignment models. Comput Ling
29:19-51</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e691a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e695" publication-type="other">
Papineni K, Roukos S, Ward T, Zhu W-J (2002) Bleu: A method for automatic evaluation of
machine translation. In: 40th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics,
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, pp. 311-318</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e708a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e712" publication-type="other">
Paul M, Doi T, Hwang Y, Imamura K, Sumita E (2005a) Nobody is perfect: ATR's hybrid approach to
spoken language translation. In: Proceedings of the international workshop on spoken language
translation (IWSLT 2005), Pittsburgh, PA, pp. 55-62</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e725a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e729" publication-type="other">
Paul M, Sumita E, Yamamoto S (2005b) A machine learning approach to hypothesis selection of
greedy decoding for SMT. In: MT Summit X workshop: Second workshop on example-based
machine translation, Phuket, Thailand, pp. 117-124</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e742a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e746" publication-type="other">
Planas E, Furuse O (2003) Formalizing translation memory. In Carl and Way (2003), pp. 157-188</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e753a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e757" publication-type="other">
Quirk C, Menezes A (2006) Dependency treelet translation: The convergence of statistical and
example-based machine-translation? Mach Translat 20:45-66</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e767a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e771" publication-type="other">
Turian JP, Shen L, Melamed ID (2003) Evaluation of machine translation and its evaluation. In: MT
Summit IX: Proceedings of the ninth machine translation summit, New Orleans, USA, pp. 386-393</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e782a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e786" publication-type="other">
Vogel S, Ney H (2000) Construction of a hierarchical translation memory. In: Proceedings of the 18th
international conference on computational linguistics: COLING 2000 in Europe, Saarbrücken,
Germany, pp. 1131-1135</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e799a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e803" publication-type="other">
Watanabe H, Kurohashi S, Aramaki E (2003) Finding translation patterns from paired source and
target dependency structures. In Carl and Way (2003), pp. 397-420</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e813a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e817" publication-type="other">
Way A, Gough N (2003) wEBMT: Developing and validating an example-based machine translation
system using the World Wide Web. Comput Ling 29:421-457</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e827a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e831" publication-type="other">
Way A, Gough N (2005a) Comparing example-based and statistical machine translation. Nat Lang
Eng 11:295-309</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e841a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e845" publication-type="other">
Way A, Gough N (2005b) Controlled translation in an example-based environment: What do
automatic evaluation metrics tell us? Mach Translat 19:1-36</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d1460290e855a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d1460290e859" publication-type="other">
Wu D (2006) MT model space: Statistical vs. compositional vs. example-based machine translation.
Mach Translat 19:213-228</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      </back>
</article>
