<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812158</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Family Dynamics and Tax Policy</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>EFFECTS OF MARRIAGE PENALTY RELIEF TAX POLICY ON MARRIAGE TAXES AND MARGINAL TAX RATES OF COHABITING COUPLES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lin</surname>
                  <given-names>Emily Y.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tong</surname>
                  <given-names>Patricia K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>3</lpage>
         <page-range>1-23, 1-3</page-range>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812158"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper examines how marriage penalty relief tax provisions affect potential marriage taxes and marginal tax rates of cohabiting couples. We find that while these policies improve horizontal equity between cohabiting and married couples, the effect varies substantially by income. For example, tax neutrality rates fall among low-income couples because EITC marriage penalty relief causes many to switch from a tax neutral to a marriage bonus position. In addition, most cohabiting individuals would face a different marginal tax rate upon marriage, and marriage penalty relief policies reduce the proportion of individuals in specific income groups who would experience an increase in marginal tax rates when filing joint instead of separate returns.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Acs, Gregory, and Elaine Maag, 2005. “Irreconcilable Differences?: The Conflict between Marriage Promotion Initiatives for Cohabiting Couples with Children and Marriage Penalties in Tax and Transfer Programs.” Paper No. B-66 in New Federalism: National Survey of America’s Families. The Urban Institute, Washington, DC, http://www.urban.org/UploadedPDF/311162_B-66.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alm, James, Leslie A. Whittington, and Jason Fletcher, 2002. “Is There a “Singles Tax”? The Relative Income Tax Treatment of Single Households.” Public Budgeting and Finance 22(2), 69-86, Summer 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Alm, James, and Leslie A. Whittington, 1995a. “Income Taxes and the Marriage Decision.” Applied Economics 27 (1), 25–31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Alm, James, and Leslie A. Whittington, 1995b. “Does the Income Tax Affect Marital Decisions?” National Tax Journal 48 (4), 565–572.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Alm, James, and Leslie A. Whittington, 1997a. “‘Till Death or Taxes Do Us Part: The Effect of Income Taxation on Divorce.” Journal of Human Resources 32 (2), 388–412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Alm, James, and Leslie A. Whittington, 1997b. “Income Taxes and the Timing of Marital Decisions.” Journal of Public Economics 64 (2), 219–240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Alm, James, and Leslie A. Whittington, 1999. “For Love or Money? The Impact of Income Taxes on Marriage.” Economica 66 (263), 297–316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Alm, James, and Leslie A. Whittington, 2001. “Tax Reduction, Tax Change, and the Marriage Penalty.” National Tax Journal 54 (3), 455–472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bakija, Jon M, 2009. Documentation for a Comprehensive Historical U.S. Federal and State Income Tax Calculator Program. Williams College, Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Blau, Francine D. and Lawrence M. Kahn, 2007. “Changes in the Labor Supply Behavior of Married Women: 1980-2000. Journal of Labor Economics 25(3), 393-438.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Blundell, Richard and Thomas MaCurdy, 1999. “Labor Supply: A Review of Alternative Approaches.” In Orley C. Ashenfelter and David Card (eds), Handbook of Labor Economics, volume 3, 1559-1695.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Bull, Nicholas, Janet Holtzblatt, James R. Nunns, and Robert Rebelein, 1999. “Defining and Measuring Penalties and Bonuses.” OTA Paper No. 82. U.S. Department of the Treasury, Office of Tax Analysis, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Eissa, Nada, 1995. “Taxation and Labor Supply of Married Women: The Tax Reform Act of 1986.” NBER Working Paper No. 5023. National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Eissa, Nada, and Hillary W. Hoynes, 2000. “Tax and Transfer Policy and Family Formation: Marriage and Cohabitation.” Unpublished Manuscript. University of California, Berkeley, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Eissa, Nada and Hilary Williamson Hoynes, 2004. “Taxes and the Labor Market Participation of Married Couples: The Earned Income Tax Credit.” Journal of Public Economics, 88(9-10), 1931-1958.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Feenberg, Daniel R., and Harvey S. Rosen, 1995. “Recent Developments in the Marriage Tax.” National Tax Journal 48 (1), 91–101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Gillette, Robert, Janet Holtzblatt, and Emily Y. Lin, 2005. “Marriage Penalties and Bonuses: A Longer Term Perspective.” In Proceedings of Ninety-Seventh Annual Conference on Taxation, 468–478. National Tax Association, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Heim, Bradley T., 2007. “The Incredible Shrinking Elasticities: Married Female Labor Supply, 1979- 2003.” Journal of Human Resources 42(4), 881-918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Holtzblatt, Janet, and Robert Rebelein, 2000. “Measuring the Effect of the EITC on Marriage Penalties and Bonuses.” National Tax Journal 53 (4), 1107–1133.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">LaLumia, Sara, 2008. “The Effects of Joint Taxation of Married Couples on Labor Supply and Non-Wage Income.” Journal of Public Economics, 92(7), 1698-1719.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Lin, Emily Y., and Patricia K. Tong, 2012. “Marriage and Taxes: What Can We Learn from Tax Returns Filed by Cohabiting Couples.” National Tax Journal 65(4), 807-826.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">McClelland, Robert and Shannon Mok, 2012. “A Review of Recent Research on Labor Supply Elasticities.” Working Paper 2012-12, CBO Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Moffitt, Robert A. and Mark Wilhelm, 2000. “Labor Supply Decisions of the Affluent.” In Joel Slemrod (Ed.), Does Atlas Shrug: The Economic Consequences of Taxing the Rich. Harvard University Press, Cambridge, MA</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Rosen, Harvey, 1987. “The Marriage Tax is Down But Not Out.” National Tax Journal 40 (4), 567–576.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Sjoquist, David L., and Mary Beth Walker, 1995. “The Marriage Tax and the Rate and Timing of Marriage.” National Tax Journal 48 (4), 547–558.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>No Tax Change Rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Marriage Bonus Rates</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Marginal Tax Rate Changes for Secondary Earners</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Marginal Tax Rate Changes for Primary Earners</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Cohabiting Couple Sample Comparison</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Summary Statistics of Separately Filed Tax Returns under Current Law</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Effects of Marriage Penalty Relief Policies on Marriage Penalties and Bonuses</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Marriage Penalty and Bonus Rates by Demographic Characteristics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Marriage Penalty and Bonus Rates by Joint Adjusted Gross Income Share of Couples</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Individual Marginal Tax Rate (MTR) Changes for Primary and Secondary Earners Share of Individuals</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Effects of Marriage Penalty Relief Polices on Joint Tax Variables by Joint Adjusted Gross Income</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
