<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277568</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study of Unconventional Cycles (Atkinson and Miller) with Mixture Heating as a Means for the Fuel Economy Improvement of a Throttled SI Engine at Part Load</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miklanek</surname>
                  <given-names>Lubomir</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vitek</surname>
                  <given-names>Oldrich</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gotfryd</surname>
                  <given-names>Ondrej</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Klir</surname>
                  <given-names>Vojtech</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Czech Technical University in Prague</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1624</fpage>
         <lpage>1636</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277568"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This contribution is focused on an investigation of two well-known techniques, i.e. the modified Atkinson working cycle with a late intake valve closing (LIVC) and the Miller working cycle with an extreme early intake valve closing (EIVC) in order to increase the fuel economy of a throttled SI engine at a part load (high throttled mode). However, the application of the Atkinson and Miller cycle causes a decrease in the in-cylinder charge temperature before the compression stroke. In the case of a constant value of the geometric compression ratio, the in-cylinder charge temperature at the beginning of the combustion is also decreased and the combustion is then slower (compared to a standard Otto cycle). This could negatively influence the indicated efficiency of the unconventional cycle. In order to avoid this, increase in the in-cylinder charge temperature was provided due to mixture heating in the intake manifold of the engine.</p>
            <p>A commercial 1-D code was utilized in order to calculate the in-cylinder pressure and the fuel economy improvement for both unconventional cycles with and without mixture heating. Numerical simulations were carried out in two various engine speeds. A predictive turbulent flame model for SI engine, as a part of applied 1-D code, was used for combustion calculation. Data from experiments carried out on the SI engine with the Otto cycle were used for calibration of the engine model as well as of the predictive model of combustion.</p>
            <p>Based on results from simulations, a significant increase in fuel economy improvement has been observed compared to the Otto cycle, especially due to the application of the Miller cycle. Further fuel economy improvement has been achieved due to a combination of both unconventional cycles and the mixture heating. During simulations certain limits have been observed at both Atkinson and Miller cycles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">KUTLAR, A., O., ARSLAN, H., CALIK, T., A.: Methods to Improve Efficiency of Four Stroke Spark Ignition Engines at part Load, Elsevier Ltd., 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brehob, D. and Amlee, D., “Effects of Inlet Air Heating and EGR on Thermal Efficiency of a SI Engine at Part Load,” SAE Technical Paper 901713, 1990, doi: 10.4271/901713.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MIKLÁNEK, L'. Tools for Optimization of SI engine at Part Load (in Czech), Dissertation Theses, CTU in Prague, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BOHAC, V., S. Low Temperature Combustion. VECOM Workshop, March 14-15, Prague, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fontana, G., Galloni, E., Palmaccio, R., and Torella, E., “The Influence of Variable Valve Timing on the Combustion Process of a Small Spark- Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0445, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0445.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blakey, S., Saunders, R., Ma, T., and Chopra, A., “A Design and Experimental Study of an Otto Atkinson Cycle Engine Using Late Intake Valve Closing,” SAE Technical Paper 910451, 1991, doi: 10.4271/910451.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boggs, D., Hilbert, H., and Schechter, M., “The Otto-Atkinson Cycle Engine-Fuel Economy and Emissions Results and Hardware Design,” SAE Technical Paper 950089, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950089.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goto, T., Hatamura, K., Takizawa, S., Hayama, N. et al., “Development of V6 Miller Cycle Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 940198, 1994, doi: 10.4271/940198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, M., Assanis, D., and Filipi, Z., “First and Second Law Analyses of a Naturally-Aspirated, Miller Cycle, SI Engine with Late Intake Valve Closure,” SAE Technical Paper 980889, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980889.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., Gianoglio Bernardi, M., and Delneri, D., “Computational Analysis of Internal and External EGR Strategies Combined with Miller Cycle Concept for a Two Stage Turbocharged Medium Speed Marine Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1319-1330, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies Inc.: GT-POWER, User's Manual And Tutorial, GT-Suite TM version 6.2, Westmont, IL, USA, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Rackmil, C., Keribar, R., and Jennings, M., “Model for Heat Transfer and Combustion In Spark Ignited Engines and its Comparison with Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 880198, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880198.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
