<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278083</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Investigation and 1D Simulation of a Turbocharger Compressor Close to Surge Operation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Bellis</surname>
                  <given-names>Vincenzo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Naples</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bozza</surname>
                  <given-names>Fabio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Naples</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Marelli</surname>
                  <given-names>Silvia</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Genoa</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Capobianco</surname>
                  <given-names>Massimo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Genoa</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278043</issue-id>
         <fpage>1866</fpage>
         <lpage>1878</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278083"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Downsizing is widely considered one of the main path to reduce the fuel consumption of spark ignition internal combustion engines. As known, despite the reduced size, the required torque and power targets can be attained thanks to an adequate boost level provided by a turbocharger. However, some drawbacks usually arise when the engine operates at full load and low speeds. In fact, in the above conditions, the boost pressure and the engine performance is limited since the compressor experiences close-to-surge operation. This occurrence is even greater in case of extremely downsized engines with a reduced number of cylinders and a small intake circuit volume, where the compressor works under strongly unsteady flow conditions and its instantaneous operating point most likely overcomes the steady surge margin.</p>
            <p>In the paper, both experimental and numerical approaches are followed to describe the unsteady behavior of a small in-series turbocharger compressor. Measurements are carried out at the test facility of the University of Genoa. The compressor is included in the in-series intake circuit and a pulsating flow is generated by a motor-driven cylinder head fitted with a variable valve actuation system. Different rotational speeds and various valve opening strategies, characterized by different opening durations, are considered. Among the tested operating conditions, close-to-surge operation is also analyzed. The unsteady compressor behavior is investigated in terms of instantaneous inlet and outlet static pressures, and mass flow rate.</p>
            <p>The numerical activity is performed at the University of Naples. The experimental test-rig is schematized in a commercial 1D code. The compressor is described following an enhanced map-based approach, where proper capacities are placed upstream and downstream the compressor to take into account the mass and energy storage effects. The model is validated for various rotational speeds and valve lift strategies, the numerical/experimental comparisons denoting a quiet good agreement.</p>
            <p>After being validated, the methodology is employed to analyze the effect of the equivalent engine speed and valve strategy on the surge resistance. The results show that, for the higher speeds, the compressor only experiences soft-surge phenomena. On the contrary, below a specific speed, flow reversal within the intake system occurs and typical deep-surge cycles arise. In addition, valve lift strategies characterized by shorter opening durations seem to most likely promote the surge onset.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EEA Technical report No 9/2014, Annual European Union greenhouse gas inventory; 1990-2012 and inventory report 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw- Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wirth, M., Schulte, H., “Downsizing and Stratified Operation - An Attractive Combination Based on a Spray-guided Combustion System”, ICAT 2006, International Conference on Automotive Technologies Istanbul, November 17, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraser, N., Blaxill, H., Lumsden, G., and Bassett, M., “Challenges for Increased Efficiency through Gasoline Engine Downsizing,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):991-1008, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bandel, W., Fraidl, G., Kapus, P., Sikinger, H. et al., “The Turbocharged GDI Engine: Boosted Synergies for High Fuel Economy Plus Ultra-low Emission,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1266, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza, F., De Bellis, V., Marelli, S., and Capobianco, M., “1D Simulation and Experimental Analysis of a Turbocharger Compressor for Automotive Engines under Unsteady Flow Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1365-1384, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galindo, J., Climent, H., Guardiola, C., Tiseira, A., “On the effect of pulsating flow on surge margin of small centrifugal compressors for automotive engines”. Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 33 (8), 1163-1171, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2009.07.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marelli, S., Carraro, C., and Capobianco, M., “Effect of Pulsating Flow Characteristics on Performance and Surge Limit of Automotive Turbocharger Compressors,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):596-601, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0715.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marelli, S., Capobianco, M., Zamboni, G., “Pulsating flow performance of a turbocharger compressor for automotive application”, International Journal of Heat and Fluid Flow, 45: 158-165, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.ijheatfluidflow.2013.11.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, G., Talon, V., Higelin, P., Charlet, A. et al., “Implementing Turbomachinery Physics into Data Map-Based Turbocharger Models,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):211-229, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0310.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Macek, J., Vítek, O., Burič, J., and Doleček, V., “Comparison of Lumped and Unsteady 1-D Models for Simulation of a Radial Turbine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):173-188, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiong, M.S., Rajoo, S., Martinez-Botas, R.F., Costall, A.W., “Engine turbocharger performance prediction: One-dimensional modeling of a twin entry turbine”, Energy Conversion and Management, 57:68-78, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2011.12.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greitzer, E.M.: “Surge and Rotating Stall in Axial Flow Compressors”, Part I. Trans. ASME Journal of Engineering for Power, 98(2): 190-198, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greitzer, E.M.: “Surge and Rotating Stall in Axial Flow Compressors”, Part II. Trans. ASME Journal of Engineering for Power, 98(2): 199-217, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mizuki, S., Asaga, Y., Ono, Y., Tsujita, H., “Investigation of Surge Behavior in a Micro Centrifugal Compressor”, J. of Thermal Science,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Helvoirt, J. “Centrifugal Compressor Surge Modeling and Identification for Control”. PhD thesis, Eindhoven University of Technology, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnulfi, G., Giannattasio, P., Giusto, C., Massardo, A. F., et al., “Multistage Centrifugal Compressor Surge Analysis: Part II-Numerical Simulation and Dynamic Control Parameters Evaluation”, ASME Transactions, Journal of Turbomachinery, vol.121, 312-320, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnulfi, G., Giannattasio, P., Micheli, D., Pinamonti, P., “An Innovative Device for Passive Control of Surge in Industrial Compression Systems” ASME Transactions, Journal of Turbomachinery, vol.123, 473-482, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marelli, S., Carraro, C., Marmorato, G., Zamboni, G., Capobianco M., “Experimental Analysis on Steady Flow Performance under Unstable Operating Conditions and on Surge Limit of a Turbocharger Compressor”, Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 53:154-160, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2013.11.025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galindo, J., Serrano, J.R., Climent, H., Tiseira, A., “Experiments and modelling of surge in small centrifugal compressor for automotive engines”, Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 32: 818-826, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2007.10.001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Capobianco, M., Marelli, S., “Experimental Investigation into the Pulsating Flow Performance of a Turbocharger Turbine in the Closed and Open Waste-Gate Region”, 9th International Conference on Turbochargers and Turbocharging, London, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza, F. and De Bellis, V., “Steady and Unsteady Modeling of Turbocharger Compressors for Automotive Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1536, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Bellis, V., Bozza, F., Bevilacqua, M., Bonamassa, G. et al., “Validation of a 1D Compressor Model for Performance Prediction,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(3):1786-1800, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leonard O., Adam O., “A Quasi-One Dimensional CFD Model for Multistage Turbomachines”, Journal of Thermal Science, 17(1): 7-20, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Traupel, W., Die Theorie der Strömung durch Radialmaschinen, Braun, Karlsruhe, 1962;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dubitsky, O., Japikse, D., Vaneless Diffuser Advanced Model, ASME Journal of Turbomachinery, 130, 011020, 2008;</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qiu, X., Japikse, D., Zhao, J., Anderson, M., R., Analysis and Validation of a Unified Slip Factor Model for Impellers at Design and Off-Design Conditions, ASME J. Turbomach., 133, 041018-1, 2011, doi:10.1115/1.4003022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiesner F., J., A review of slip factors for centrifugal compressors, ASME J. of Eng. Power, ASME Transaction, 89, 558-72, 1967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gnielinski, V., New equations for heat and mass transfer in turbulent pipe and channel, Int. Chemical engineering, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pelton R., J., One-Dimensional Radial Flow Turbomachinery Performance Modeling, Master Thesis, Science Department of Mechanical Engineering, Brigham Young University, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Japikse, D., Turbomachinery Performance Modeling, SAE Paper 2009- 01-0307, Cliff Garrett Turbomachinery and Applications Engineering Award, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eynon, P., A., Whitfield, A., Pressure recovery in a turbocharger compressor volute, Proc IMechE Vol 214 Part A, 599-609, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gravdahl, J.T., Egeland, O., Vatland, S.O., “Active surge control of centrifugal compressors using drive torque”, Proceedings of the 40th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, pp. 1286 - 1291, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C.D., Michos, C.N., Giakoumis, E.G.,“A computational study of compressor surge during transient operation of turbocharged diesel engines”, Int. J. Alternative Propulsion 1(2):250-273, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leufven, O., Eriksson, L., “Surge and Choke Capable Compressor Model”, Proceedings of the 18th IFAC World Congress, 10653-10658, 2011, http://dx.doi.org/10.3182/20110828-6-IT-1002.00694</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GT-Power V.7.3, User's Manual, Gamma Technology Inc., 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galindo, J., Serrano, J.R., Guardiola, C., Cervelló, C., “Surge limit definition in a specific test bench for the characterization of automotive turbochargers”, Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 30 (5): 449-462, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
