<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26142234</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Industry Window Dressing</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Huaizhi</given-names>
                  <surname>Chen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Lauren</given-names>
                  <surname>Cohen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Dong</given-names>
                  <surname>Lou</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2016</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26142228</issue-id>
         <fpage>3354</fpage>
         <lpage>3393</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/26142234"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>We explore a new mechanism by which investors take correlated shortcuts and present evidence that managers—using sales management—take advantage of these shortcuts. Specifically, we exploit a regulatory provision wherein a firm's primary industry is determined by the highest sales segment. Exploiting this regulation, we provide evidence that investors classify operationally nearly identical firms as starkly different depending on their placement around this sales cutoff. Moreover, managers appear to exploit this by manipulating sales to be just over the cutoff in favorable industries. Further evidence suggests that managers engage in activities to realize large, tangible benefits from this opportunistic action.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1156e293a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e300" publication-type="other">
We use "nearly identical" but on the either side of the threshold throughout the paper to refer to two firms
that operate in two identical segments, but that sit on opposite sides of the 50% threshold within a 5% band
of that threshold. While we control for observable characteristics, there are many potentially unobservable firm
attributes among the two firms that may be related to the choice of primary industry classification.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e316a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e323" publication-type="other">
Throughout the paper, when using "just above" or "just below" the 50% industry classification threshold, we
are referring to firms in the 5% bands on either side of the 50% threshold (i.e., 45.00%-49.99%, just below, and
50.00%-54.99%, just above).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e336a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e343" publication-type="other">
The Rock of Ages Corporation (ROAC) is an example of this. ROAC engaged in mining materials and
manufacturing headstones and tombstones, which they sold directly to cemeteries. Their main line of business
and sales revenue (and therefore primary SIC code) was Retail. In 2008, the mining sector became favorable,
partly due to soaring commodity prices. Consequently, mining funds received large fund inflows. Rock of Ages,
at the same time, shifted some of its sales to the mining sector—enough to be barely over the 50% classification
threshold as a mining firm. In 2008, in fact, the firm received 50.7% of its sales from the mining industry, officially
shifting to a Mining sector firm classification.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e369a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e376" publication-type="other">
Relatedly, in the asset management setting, Bollen and Pool (2009,2012) exploit discontinuity at 0% for reported
returns by hedge funds (i.e., investors view 0% as a natural benchmark for evaluating hedge fund performance).
They first document a discontinuous jump in capital flows to hedge funds around this zero return cutoff and then
provide evidence that disproportionately more hedge funds cluster just to the right of this return threshold than
to the left of it.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e396a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e403" publication-type="other">
In fact, the only friction needed throughout the paper is that investors use the shortcut of categorizing firms by
the primary industry instead of by the underlying economic operation. In the presence of this, regardless of the
reason of the higher valuation, managers have an incentive to be classified into higher valued industries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e416a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e423" publication-type="other">
A number of other papers examine firm entry and exit, both proposing theoretical dynamics and establishing
empirical regularities (e.g., Hopenhayn 1992; Ericson and Pakes 1995; Agarwal and Gort 1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e433a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e440" publication-type="other">
We also complement the literature on laddering down earnings forecasts (e.g., Richardson, Teoh, and Wysocki
2004; Ke and Yu 2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e450a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e459" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Aboody and Kasznik 2000, Cooper, Dimitrov, and Rau 2001, Baker, Stein, and Wurgler 2003,
Baker and Wurgler 2004a, 2004b, Gilchrist, Himmelberg, and Huberman 2005, Baker, Greenwood, and Wurgler
2009, Polk and Sapienza 2008, Greenwood 2009, and Lou 2014. Baker, Ruback, and Wurgler 2012 provide
an excellent review of this topic. There is a related strand of literature in management that shows that firm
classification impacts how market participants view these firms (Zuckerman 2000, 2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e478a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e485" publication-type="other">
Other examples in the empirical literature include Froot and Dabora ( 1999), Cooper, Gulen, and Rau (2005), Boyer
(2011), and Kruger, Landier, and Thesmar (2012), who find that mutual fund styles, industries, and countries all
appear to be categories that have a substantial impact on investor behavior (and asset price movements).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e498a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e505" publication-type="other">
There is also a growing literature on investors' limited attention to information and asset prices. For example,
Huberman and Regev (2001), DellaVigna and Pollet (2006), Menzly and Ozbas (2006), Hong, Torous, and
Valkanov (2007), Hou (2007), Barber and Odean (2008), Cohen and Frazzini (2008), Cohen, Diether, and
Malloy (2013), Cohen and Lou (2012), and Dechow, Lawrence, and Ryans (2015) find that investors respond
quickly to information that attracts their attention (in our case, the primary industry classification) but tend to
ignore information that is less salient yet material to firm values (in our case, the actual operations of different
segments).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e532a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e539" publication-type="other">
We also check that the primary SIC code of the firm matches the SIC code of the firm's largest segment. We find
that this holds 95% of the time. In addition, we also run our discontinuity tests. The results become stronger in
magnitude and significance when we remove a small percentage of non-matches.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e552a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e559" publication-type="other">
This also ensures that the larger of the two segments will determine the primary industry of the firm. For
robustness, we have experimented with this percentage from two-thirds (the lower bound to ensure that this is
true) through 85%, and the results are unchanged in magnitude and significance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e572a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e579" publication-type="other">
FLOW is a measure of flow-induced trading defined as dollar flows, multiplied by portfolio weight, and summed
across all mutual funds for that firm-quarter.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e589a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e596" publication-type="other">
Lou (2012) shows that sixty-two cents of each dollar of inflows goes into scaling up current positions; for
outflows, mutual funds scale down their current positions dollar for dollar.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e606a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e613" publication-type="other">
We have experimented with defining favorable industries as the top 20%, 25%, 30%, 35%, and 40%, and the
results are very similar in both magnitude and significance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e623a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e630" publication-type="other">
We focus on two-segment firms in this analysis because the presence of a third segment adds noise to our
estimation of industry betas. For instance, consider a firm that receives 34%, 34%, and 32% from industries A,
B, and C, respectively, and another firm that receives 45%, 45%, and 10% from the same three industries. While
both firms receive equal fractions of the total sales from the top two segments, the industry loadings of the two
firms' returns on industries A and B can be very different.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e650a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e657" publication-type="other">
Given that nearly all mutual funds have concentration limits on individual positions of 5% or less, 50% does
require the mutual fund to take, for instance, ten maximally concentrated positions in the same industry, suggesting
that the fund is concentrating investment efforts there. We exclude the firm in question from this exercise to avoid
any mechanical relation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e673a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e680" publication-type="other">
We focus on the number of sector funds holding the stock rather than the total value invested, because the latter
also reflects fund managers' views on the stock's future returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e690a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e697" publication-type="other">
We use coverage data provided by IBES in the previous five years for each analyst (our results are robust if we
use coverage information in the previous one to four years). For instance, using a three-year definition of analyst
covering, the jump at the 50% cutoff is large and significant 0.175 (r = 2.07). We exclude the stock in question in
the procedure of analyst industry assignments to ensure that our results are not mechanically driven.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e713a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e720" publication-type="other">
The sum of the two fractions is less than one because firms are also covered by analysts from outside the two
segments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e730a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e737" publication-type="other">
We are grateful to the referee for suggesting this framing.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e744a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e751" publication-type="other">
The sharply increasing cost of manipulating sales as a firm moves away from the threshold is driven by a number
of factors. For instance, we discuss two potential mechanisms through which firms can industry window dress:
(1) price discounts and (2) inflated sales reporting, which requires future restatements. Both of these mechanisms
are locally feasible for small manipulations of sales (e.g., 49% sales to 50%), but are much more costly for larger
magnitudes of sales manipulation (e.g., 30% sales to 50%) due to, for example, the probability of being caught
for larger manipulations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e775a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e782" publication-type="other">
We have used a number of methods of adjusting these standard errors from the McCrary procedure; for instance,
clustering by year or bootstrapping. The standard errors using these methods are a bit lower, resulting in larger
t-statistics of 3.52 and 3.40, respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e795a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e802" publication-type="other">
In addition to getting in favorable industries, firms may want to avoid being classified in the least favorable
industries (e.g., the bottom twenty industries ranked by industry flows). We test this idea by looking at
the difference in distribution jumps between the two scenarios (a negative jump versus a positive jump in
distributions). We see both of these in the data, and the difference between the two is strongly statistically
significant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e821a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e828" publication-type="other">
These results, particularly those based on segment profits, also help rule out an alternative explanation of
tournament behavior by divisional managers to be promoted. First, a nuanced version of the tournament
explanation would be needed to predict a stronger desire (or ability) of managers in favorable industry segments
to engage in this behavior relative to all other segment managers. Even if this were true, however, prior evidence
shows that segment sales have no clear impact on the promotion of divisional managers (Cichello et al. 2009);
instead, segment profits are the only statistically and economically relevant predictor. However, as shown in
Table 3, we see no evidence of discontinuous jumps when sorting firms on segment profits, but solely when
sorting on segment sales. This is inconsistent with the tournament explanation, but consistent with the industry
window dressing motive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e860a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e867" publication-type="other">
The implicit assumption here is that the price elasticity of demand is below -1 for an average industry.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e874a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e881" publication-type="other">
Throughout the empirical analysis, when using "just above" or "just below" the 50% industry classification
threshold, we are referring to firms in the 5% bands on either side of the 50% threshold (i.e., 45.00% - 49.99%,
just below, and 50.00%-54.99%, just above).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e894a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e901" publication-type="other">
Like inventories, R&amp;D expenditures are sparsely populated, so we aggregate at the 10% bin level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e909a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e916" publication-type="other">
Restatement data begin in 1994, cutting our sample (which begins in 1980) roughly by half.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e923a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e930" publication-type="other">
We find that investors behave similarly to these switching firms as they do around the discontinuity point (shown
in Table 2 and Figure 1). For instance, in the analog to the test in Table 2, we find that the industry beta of
switchers increases by 0.046 (r = 2.53), representing a more than 20% increase in beta.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e943a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e950" publication-type="other">
This test provides a lower bound for the return effect of industry switching, as annual sales information is
gradually disseminated to the market (over the prior three quarters), and so may be partially anticipated before
the official financial statements are released.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e963a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e970" publication-type="other">
When we merge with the IBES data (which is needed to calculate SUEs), the cross-section is reduced, as not all
firms are covered by analysts.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e980a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e987" publication-type="other">
Merging in the insider trading data from Thomson Reuters cuts our sample period start date to the beginning of
that dataset (1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e997a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e1004" publication-type="other">
We use a dummy for net insider trading following prior literature (Jeng, Metrick, and Zeckhauser 2003; Cohen,
Malloy, and Pomorski 2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e1015a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e1022" publication-type="other">
When we run this same regression on cash-financed M&amp;A activity (as opposed to stock-financed activity), we
find no significant impact, suggesting it is something unique to using the higher-valued currency of favorable
industry equity in these transactions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e1035a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e1042" publication-type="other">
We repeat the analysis on insider trading and firm benefits for the tighter switching sample of solely those firms
tightly surrounding the discontinuity (45%-55% sales in the favorable industry). We find that the economic
significance in this cleaner sample is larger (reported in Appendix Tables A5 and A6).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e1055a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e1062" publication-type="other">
The return is large and of a roughly similar magnitude as all switchers, but it is not significant, due to the sample
size.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e1072a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e1079" publication-type="other">
We further repeat our analyses of manager and firm benefits focusing on placebo switchers. As shown in Appendix
Table A7, there is no significant difference between these placebo switchers and other firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1156e1089a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1156e1096" publication-type="other">
We also run these tests for placebo switchers as a falsification test, finding that—as expected—they exhibit no
commensurate increase in industry word usage following their switch (Table 11, Columns 5 and 6).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1156e1115a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1119" publication-type="other">
Aboody, D., and R. Kasznik. 2000. CEO stock option awards and the timing of voluntary corporate disclosures.
Journal of Accounting and Economics 29:73-100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1129a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1133" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, R., and M. Gort. 1996. The evolution of markets and entry, exit and survival of firms. Review of
Economics and Statistics 78:489-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1143a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1147" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., R. Greenwood, and J. Wurgler. 2009. Catering through nominal share prices. Journal of Finance
64:2559-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1157a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1161" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., R. Ruback, and J. Wurgler. 2012. Behavioral corporate finance: A survey. In Handbook of empirical
corporate finance. Eds. G M. Constantinides, M. Harris, and R. M. Stulz. Amsterdam: Elsevier Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1172a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1176" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., J. Stein, and J. Wurgler. 2003. When does the market matter? Stock prices and the investment of
equity-dependent firms. Quarterly Journal of Economics 118:969-1005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1186a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1190" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., and J. Wurgler. 2004a. A catering theory of dividends. Journal of Finance 59:1125-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1197a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1201" publication-type="other">
. 2004b. Appearing and disappearing dividends: The link to catering incentives. Journal of Financial
Economics 73:271-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1211a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1215" publication-type="other">
Barber, B., and T. Odean. 2008. All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on the buying behavior of
individual and institutional investors. Review of Financial Studies 21:785-818.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1225a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1229" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., and A. Shleifer. 2003. Style investing. Journal of Financial Economics 68:161-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1236a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1240" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., A. Shleifer, and J. Wurgler. 2005. Comovement. Journal of Financial Economics 75:283-317.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1248a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1252" publication-type="other">
Berry, S. 1992. Estimation of a model of entry in the airline industry. Econometrica 60:889-917.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1259a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1263" publication-type="other">
Boni, L., and K. L. Womack. 2006. Analysts, industries, and price momentum. Journal of Financial and
Quantitative Analysis 41:85—109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1273a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1277" publication-type="other">
Bollen, N., and V. Pool. 2009. Do hedge fund managers misreport returns? Evidence from the pooled distribution.
Journal of Finance 64:2257-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1287a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1291" publication-type="other">
. 2012. Suspicious patterns in hedge fund returns and the risk of fraud. Review of Financial Studies
25:2673-702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1305" publication-type="other">
Boyer, B. 2011. Style-related comovement: Fundamentals or labels? Journal of Finance 66:307-332.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1312a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1316" publication-type="other">
Bresnahan, T., and P. Reiss. 1991. Entry and competition in concentrated markets. Journal of Political Economy
99:977-1009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1327a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1331" publication-type="other">
Burgstahler, D., and I. Dichev. 1997. Earnings management to avoid earnings decreases and losses. Journal of
Accounting and Economics 24:99-126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1341a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1345" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., K. Diether, and C. Malloy. 2013. Misvaluing innovation. Review of Financial Studies 26:635-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1352a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1356" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., and A. Frazzini. 2008. Economic links and predictable returns, Journal of Finance 63:1977-2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1363a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1367" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., and D. Lou. 2012. Complicated firms. Journal of Financial Economics 104:383^400.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1374a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1378" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., C. Malloy, and L. Pomorski. 2012. Decoding inside information. Journal of Finance 67:1009-1044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1385a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1389" publication-type="other">
Cooper, M., O. Dimitrov, and R. Rau. 2001. A rose.com by any other name. Journal of Finance 56:2371-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1397a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1401" publication-type="other">
Cooper, M., H. Gulen, and R. Rau. 2005. Changing names with style: Mutual fund name changes and their effects
on fund flows. Journal of Finance 60:2825-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1411a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1415" publication-type="other">
Coval, J., and E. Stafford. 2007. Asset fire sales (and purchases) in equity markets. Journal of Financial Economics
86:479-512.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1425a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1429" publication-type="other">
Dechow, P., A. Lawrence, and J. Ryans. 2015. SEC comment letters and insider sales. Working Paper, UC
Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1439a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1443" publication-type="other">
Degeorge, F., J. Patel, and R. Zeckhauser 1999. Earnings management to exceed thresholds. Journal of Business
72:1-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1453a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1457" publication-type="other">
DellaVigna, S., and J. Pollet. 2006. Investor inattention, firm reaction, and Friday earnings announcements.
Journal of Finance 64:709-749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1467a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1471" publication-type="other">
Domowitz, I., R. G Hubbard, and B. Petersen. 1986. Business cycles and the relationship between concentration
and price-cost margins. RAND Journal of Economics 17:1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1482a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1486" publication-type="other">
Doraszelski, U., and S. Markovich. 2007. Advertising dynamics and competitive advantage, RAND Journal of
Economics 38:557-592.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1496a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1500" publication-type="other">
Dunne, T., M. Roberts, and L. Samuelson. 1988. Patterns of firm entry and exit in U.S. manufacturing industries.
RAND Journal of Economics 19:495-515.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1510a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1514" publication-type="other">
Ericson, R., and A. Pakes. 1995. Markov-perfect industry dynamics: A framework for empirical work. Review
of Economic Studies 62:53-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1524a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1528" publication-type="other">
Frazzini, A., and O. Lamont. 2008. Dumb money: Mutual fund flows and the cross-section of stock returns.
Journal of Financial Economics 88:299-322.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1538a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1542" publication-type="other">
Froot, K., and E. Dabora. 1999. How are stock prices affected by the location of trade? Journal of Financial
Economics 53:189-216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1552a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1556" publication-type="other">
Gilchrist, S., C. Himmelberg, and G Huberman. 2005. Do stock price bubbles influence corporate investment?
Journal of Monetary Economics 52:805-27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1567a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1571" publication-type="other">
Greenwood, R. 2009. Trading restrictions and stock prices. Review of Financial Studies 22:509-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1578a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1582" publication-type="other">
Hopenhayn, A. 1992. Entry, exit, and firm dynamics in long run equilibrium. Econometrica 60:1127-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1589a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1593" publication-type="other">
Hou, K. 2007. Industry information diffusion and the lead-lag effect in stock returns. Review of Financial Studies
20:1113-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1603a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1607" publication-type="other">
Huberman, G., and T. Regev. 2001. Contagious speculation and a cure for cancer: A nonevent that made stock
prices soar. Journal of Finance 56:387-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1617a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1621" publication-type="other">
Jeng, L., A. Metrick, and R. Zeckhauser. 2003. Estimating the returns to insider trading: A performance-evaluation
perspective. Review of Economics and Statistic 85:453-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1631a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1635" publication-type="other">
Jovanovic, B. 1982. Selection and the evolution of industry. Econometrica 50:649-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1643a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1647" publication-type="other">
Kruger, P., A. Landier, and D. Thesmar. 2012. Categorization bias in the stock market. Unpublished Working
Paper, University of Geneva, Toulouse School of Economics, and HEC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1657a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1661" publication-type="other">
Lou, D. 2012. A flow-based explanation for return predictability. Review of Financial Studies 25:3457-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1668a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1672" publication-type="other">
. 2014. Attracting investor attention through advertising. Review of Financial Studies 27:1797-829.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1679a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1683" publication-type="other">
McCrary, J. 2008. Manipulation of the running variable in the regression discontinuity design: A density test.
Journal of Econometrics 142:698-714.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1693a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1697" publication-type="other">
Menzly, L., and O. Ozbas. 2006. Cross-industry momentum. Unpublished Working Paper, University of Southern
California.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1707a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1711" publication-type="other">
Polk, C., and P. Sapienza. 2008. The stock market and corporate investment: A test of catering theory. Review of
Financial Studies 22:187-217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1722a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1726" publication-type="other">
Rhodes-Kropf, M., D. T. Robinson, and S. Viswanathan. 2005. Valuation waves and merger activity: The empirical
evidence. Journal of Financial Economics 77:561-603.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1736a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1740" publication-type="other">
Richardson, S., S. H. Teoh, and P. Wysocki. 2004. The walk-down to beatable analyst forecasts: The role of
equity issuance and insider trading incentives. Contemporary Accounting Research 21:885-924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1750a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1754" publication-type="other">
Roychowdhury, S. 2006. Earnings management through real activities manipulation. Journal of Accounting and
Economics 42:335-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1764a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1768" publication-type="other">
Samaniego, R. 2010. Entry, exit, and investment-specific technical change. American Economic Review 100:
164-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1778a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1782" publication-type="other">
Stein, J. 1996. Rational capital budgeting in an irrational world. Journal of Business 69:429-55,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1793" publication-type="other">
Vijh, A. 1994. S&amp;P 500 trading strategies and stock betas. Review of Financial Studies 7:215-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1801a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1805" publication-type="other">
Zuckerman, E. 2000. Focusing the corporate product: Securities analysts and de-diversification. Administrative
Science Quarterly 45:591-619.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1156e1815a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1156e1819" publication-type="other">
. 2004. Structural incoherence and stock market activity. American Sociological Review 69:405^432.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
