<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169109</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Technical Development of Electro Magnetic Compatibility for Plug-in Hybrid Vehicle / Electric Vehicle Using Wireless Power Transfer System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mori</surname>
                  <given-names>Akira</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Motor Corporation</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>May 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169099</issue-id>
         <fpage>87</fpage>
         <lpage>93</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169109"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In 2007, researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology successfully completed a Wireless Power Transfer (WPT) experiment. Ever since, interest in WPT has been growing. At Toyota, we have been developing the underlying technology of a WPT system. Simultaneously we have been working with regulatory committees to create a standard for WPT. In particular, there are concerns that WPT’s radiated emissions could cause harm to humans and the neighboring electronic equipment. There are many challenges that need to be overcome, but a key concern is understanding WPT’s electromagnetic compatibility (EMI: Electro-Magnetic Interference and EMF: Electro-Magnetic Field). In this paper, we show the technical issues, the evaluation method, and the development status of EMI and EMF on PHVs/EVs when using WPT.</p>
            <p>• For Electromagnetic interference (EMI) performance, we investigated both an open area test site and an electromagnetic anechoic chamber as evaluation environments. Through these tests, we found that we could evaluate the fundamental frequency of WPT’s radiated emissions at an open area test site. In addition, we found that we could evaluate the harmonics of WPT in an electromagnetic anechoic chamber.</p>
            <p>• We developed some countermeasure materials made of different magnetized materials to reduce the fundamental frequency’s radiated emissions. As a result, we confirmed that higher magnetic permeability materials have larger effects to reduce the fundamental frequency’s radiated emissions.</p>
            <p>• To address EMF concerns, we investigated the possibility that the human body and active implantable medical devices were affected by the radiated emissions of WPT. We introduced an evaluation method to investigate these claims using a torso phantom. Our results found no adverse effects to the human body or active implantable medical devices (AIMD) and that users can use WPT safely.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kurs A. et al., "Wireless Power Transfer via Strongly Coupled Magnetic Resonances", Science, Vol.317, no.5834, pp.84-86, July 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">WPC, http://www.wirelesspowerconsortium.com/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">TOYOTA Global Newsroom, http://newsroom.toyota.co.jp/jp/detail/961756/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abe S. et al., "Technology Trends of Contactless Power Transfer Systems for Electric Vehicle", JIASC2011, 2-S11-6, pp • 205-· 210, September 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shoki H., "Trends and Activities for Commercialization of Wireless Power Transfer Technologies ", The Institute of Electronics, Information and Communication Engineers of Japan, Technical Report, vol. 114, no. 399, WPT2014-84, pp. 37-42, January 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BWF, http://bwf-yrp.net/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">JP-MIC, http://www.soumu.go.jp/main_sosiki/joho_tsusin/policyreports/joho_tsusin/denpa_kankyou/wpt.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IEC TC 69 Work program, http://www.iec.ch/dyn/www/f?p=103:23:0::::FSP_ORG_ID,FSP_LANG_ID:1255,25</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE J2954 Wireless Charging Task Force, http://www.sae.org/works/committeeHome.do?comtID=TEVH YB10</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ehara N. et al., "Characteristics of Contactless Power Transfer System Equipped with Aluminum-plate Leakage Flux Shield", The Institute of Electrical Engineers of Japan, National Congress, 4-196, March 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Japanese patent application No. 2014-059719</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ICNIRP standard, http://www.icnirp.de/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirata A., "Confirmation of quasi-static approximation in SAR evaluation for a wireless power transfer system", Physics in Medicine and Biology, vol. 58 (2013) N241-N249</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laakso I., "Evaluation of induced electric field and compliance procedure for wireless power transfer system in an electrical vehicle", Physics in Medicine and Biology, vol.58, no.21, pp. 7583-7594, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimamoto T. et al., " Variability of the Induced Electric Field in Human Body Models with Different Postures by Wireless Power Transfer System in Electric Vehicle", The Institute of Electronics, Information and Communication Engineers of Japan, Technical Report, vol. 114, no. 143, EST2014-32, pp. 127-131, July 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimamoto T. et al., " Analysis of induced electric field in the human body models for different coil shapes of wireless power transfer system in electric vehicle", The Institute of Electronics, Information and Communication Engineers of Japan, Technical Report, vol. 114, no. 398, EMCJ2014-90, pp. 31-34, January 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Guidelines on the use of radio communication equipment such as cellular telephones - Safeguards for electric medical equipment", presented at the EMC Conf. Japan, Electromagnetic Medical Equipment Study Group, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Active Implantable Medical Device - Electromagnetic Compatibility - EMC Test Protocols for Implantable Cardiac Pacemakers and Implantable Defibrillators, AAMI Standard PC69, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"Guidelines on the use of radio communications equipment for implanted medical devices", Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communication of Japan, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IrnichW. et al., "Electromagnetic interference of pacemakers by mobile phones", J. Pacing and Clinical Electrophysiology, vol.19, no. 10, pp. 1431-1446, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hikage T. et al., "In-vitro Assessment of Electromagnetic Interference Due to Electric Vehicle Wireless Power Transfer System on Active Implantable Medical Devices", proc. of 9th International Symposium on Medical Information and Communication Technology (ISMICT2015), pp.59-62, March 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
