<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422583</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Heat Loss Analysis of a Steel Piston and a YSZ Coated Piston in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Using Phosphor Thermometry Measurements</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Binder</surname>
                  <given-names>Christian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Scania CV AB</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Nada</surname>
                  <given-names>Fahed Abou</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Richter</surname>
                  <given-names>Mattias</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Cronhjort</surname>
                  <given-names>Andreas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>KTH Royal Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Norling</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Scania CV AB</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>1954</fpage>
         <lpage>1968</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422583"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Diesel engine manufacturers strive towards further efficiency improvements. Thus, reducing in-cylinder heat losses is becoming increasingly important. Understanding how location, thermal insulation, and engine operating conditions affect the heat transfer to the combustion chamber walls is fundamental for the future reduction of in-cylinder heat losses. This study investigates the effect of a 1<italic>mm</italic>-thick plasma-sprayed yttria-stabilized zirconia (YSZ) coating on a piston. Such a coated piston and a similar steel piston are compared to each other based on experimental data for the heat release, the heat transfer rate to the oil in the piston cooling gallery, the local instantaneous surface temperature, and the local instantaneous surface heat flux. The surface temperature was measured for different crank angle positions using phosphor thermometry. The fuel was chosen to be n-heptane to facilitate surface temperature measurements during non-skip-fire, thermally stabilized operating conditions. Assuming one-dimensional heat transfer inside each piston, the local instantaneous surface heat flux was calculated using the heat transfer rate to the oil in the piston cooling gallery and the surface temperature measurements. The results from this study show that the surface temperature variation is similar for both pistons. The instantaneous heat flux during combustion is however significantly greater for the steel piston than the coated piston. The heat release analysis also indicates that combustion is slower for the piston with the yttria-stabilized zirconia coating.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Energy Agency (IEA), “World Energy Outlook 2015,” ISBN 978-92-64-24366-8, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jia, M., Gingrich, E., Wang, H., Li, Y., Ghandhi, J.B., and Reitz, R.D., “Effect of combustion regime on in-cylinder heat transfer in internal combustion engines,” Int. J Engine Res. 17(3):331-346, 2016, doi:10.1177/1468087415575647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borman, G. and Nishiwaki, K., “Internal Combustion Engine Heat Transfer,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 13:1-46, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dickey, D., "The Effect of Insulated Combustion Chamber Surfaces on Direct-Injected Diesel Engine Performance, Emissions and Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 890292, 1989, doi:10.4271/890292.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Modi, A. and Gosai, D., "Experimental Study on Thermal Barrier Coated Diesel Engine Performance with Blends of Diesel and Palm Biodiesel," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):246-259, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1519.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Wahiduzzaman, S., and Fort, E., "Heat Transfer Experiments in an Insulated Diesel," SAE Technical Paper 880186, 1988, doi:10.4271/880186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thring, R., "Low Heat Rejection Engines," SAE Technical Paper 860314, 1986, doi:10.4271/860314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Matsui, Y., and Itoh, T., "Effects of Combustion Chamber Insulation on the Heat Rejection and Thermal Efficiency of Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 920543, 1992, doi:10.4271/920543.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Algotsson, M., Knappe, C., Tunér, M., Richter, M., Johansson, B., and Aldén, M., “In-cylinder surface thermometry using laser induced phosphorescence (new measurements and comparisons of alternative approaches),” Proc. 8th Int. Conf. Model. Diagnostics Adv. Engine Syst. COMODIA 2012 (Comodia):482-487, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fukui, K., Wakisaka, Y., Nishikawa, K., Hattori, Y., Kosaka, H., and Kawaguchi, A., High Response Surface Temperature Measurement by Laser-Induced Phosphorescence, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fukui, K., Wakisaka, Y., Nishikawa, K., Hattori, Y. et al., "Development of Instantaneous Temperature Measurement Technique for Combustion Chamber Surface and Verification of Temperature Swing Concept," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0675, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0675.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuhrmann, N., Litterscheid, C., Ding, C.-P., Brübach, J., Albert, B., and Dreizler, A., “Cylinder head temperature determination using high-speed phosphor thermometry in a fired internal combustion engine,” Appl. Phys. B 116(2):293-303, 2013, doi:10.1007/s00340-013-5690-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuhrmann, N., Schneider, M., Ding, C.-P., Brübach, J., and Dreizler, a., “Two-dimensional surface temperature diagnostics in a full-metal engine using thermographic phosphors,” Meas. Sci. Technol. 24(9):95203, 2013, doi:10.1088/0957-0233/24/9/095203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luo, X., Yu, X., and Jansons, M., "Simultaneous In-Cylinder Surface Temperature Measurements with Thermocouple, Laser-induced Phosphorescence, and Dual Wavelength Infrared Diagnostic Techniques in an Optical Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1658, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kashdan, J. and Bruneaux, G., "Laser-Induced Phosphorescence Measurements of Combustion Chamber Surface Temperature on a Single-Cylinder Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2049, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2049.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deutsche Edelstahlwerke, “1.5231, 38MnSiVS5, 7Mn-Si-V-legierter AFP-Stahl,” https://www.dew-stahl.com/fileadmin/files/dew-stahl.com/documents/Publikationen/Werkstoffdatenblaetter/Baustahl/1.5231_de.pdf, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Z., Kulkarni, A., Deshpande, S., Nakamura, T., and Herman, H., “Effects of pores and interfaces on effective properties of plasma sprayed zirconia coatings,” Acta Mater. 51(18):5319-5334, 2003, doi:10.1016/S1359-6454(03)00390-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tojo, T., Atake, T., Mori, T., and Yamamura, H., “Heat capacity and thermodynamic functions of zirconia and yttria-stabilized zirconia,” J. Chem. Thermodyn. 31:831-845, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson, Ö., “Experiment!: Planning, Implementing and Interpreting,” John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd, ISBN 9780470688267, 2012, doi:10.1002/9781118311059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendricks, T. and Ghandhi, J., "Estimation of Surface Heat Flux in IC Engines Using Temperature Measurements: Processing Code Effects," SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1268-1285, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Overbye, V., Bennethum, J., Uyehara, O., and Myers, P., "Unsteady Heat Transfer in Engines," SAE Technical Paper 610041, 1961, doi:10.4271/610041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundementals,” ISBN 007028637X, 1988, doi:10987654.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gingrich, E., Ghandhi, J., and Reitz, R., "Experimental Investigation of Piston Heat Transfer in a Light Duty Engine Under Conventional Diesel, Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition, and Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Combustion Regimes," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):375-386, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hendricks, T., Brossman, J., and Ghandhi, J., “Instantaneous local heat flux measurements in a small utility engine,” ASME ICES2009 1-12, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morel, T., Keribar, R., and Blumberg, P., "Cyclical Thermal Phenomena in Engine Combustion Chamber Surfaces," SAE Technical Paper 850360, 1985, doi:10.4271/850360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronsson, U., Solaka, H., Lequien, G., Andersson, O. et al., "Analysis of Errors in Heat Release Calculations Due to Distortion of the In-Cylinder Volume Trace from Mechanical Deformation in Optical Diesel Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 5(4):1561-1570, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1604.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brunt, M. and Platts, K., "Calculation of Heat Release in Direct Injection Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0187, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tunestål, P., “TDC Offset Estimation from Motored Cylinder Pressure Data based on Heat Release Shaping,” Oil Gas Sci. Technol. - Rev. IFP Energies Nouv. 66(4):705-716, 2011, doi:10.2516/ogst/2011144.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Köck, E.-M., Kogler, M., Bielz, T., Klötzer, B., and Penner, S., “In Situ FT-IR Spectroscopic Study of CO 2 and CO Adsorption on Y2O , ZrO2 , and Yttria-Stabilized ZrO2,” J. Phys. Chem. C 117(34):17666-17673, 2013, doi:10.1021/jp405625x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Tree, D., "Diffusion-Flame / Wall Interactions in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1295, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
