<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277840</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Control of a Combined SCR on Filter and Under-Floor SCR System for Low Emission Passenger Cars</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Balland</surname>
                  <given-names>Jean</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Parmentier</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schmitt</surname>
                  <given-names>Julien</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Delphi Automotive</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1252</fpage>
         <lpage>1261</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277840"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Similar to single-brick SCR architectures, the multi-brick SCR systems described in this paper require urea injection control software that meets the NOₓ conversion performance target while maintaining the tailpipe NH₃ slip below a given threshold, under all driving conditions.</p>
            <p>The SCR architectures containing a close-coupled SCRoF and underfloor SCR are temperature-wise more favorable than the under-floor location and lead to significant improvement of the global NOₓ conversion, compared to a single-brick system. But in order to maximize the benefit of close-coupling, the urea injection control must maximize the NH₃ stored in the SCRoF.</p>
            <p>The under-floor SCR catalyst can be used as an NH₃ slip buffer, lowering the risk of NH₃ slip at the tailpipe with some benefit on the global NOₓ conversion of the system. With this approach, the urea injection strategy has a limited control on the NH₃ coverage of the under-floor SCR catalyst.</p>
            <p>To take more advantage of the under-floor SCR catalyst for improving the NOₓ conversion, the NH₃ coverage of the under-floor SCR must be taken into account, and therefore a combined control of both catalysts is required. This paper presents a control strategy proposal for such multi-brick SCR systems: the NH₃ coverage of the SCRoF is optimized while taking into account the current states of front and rear SCR catalysts. The strategy focuses on achieving highest NOₓ conversion efficiency while preventing excessive tailpipe NH₃ slip, even in the worst driving conditions, such as sudden full-load acceleration.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dieterle, M., Boorse, S., Voss, K., Stiebels, S. et al., “Two in One: SCR on Filter”, MinNOx conference 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Worldwide Emissions Standards”, Delphi booklet, http://delphi. com/emissions-pc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bremm, S., Pfeifer, M., Leyrer, J., Mueller, W. et al., “Bluetec Emission Control System for the US Tier 2 Bin 5 Legislation,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1184, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Needham, D., Schiffgens, H.-J., Spadafora, P., “Delphi SCR Dosing System - An Alternative Approach”, MinNOx conference 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cavataio, G., Girard, J., Patterson, J., Montreuil, C. et al., “Laboratory Testing of Urea-SCR Formulations to Meet Tier 2 Bin 5 Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1575, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1575.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, D., Yao, S., Shost, M., Yoo, J. et al., “Ammonia Sensor for Closed-Loop SCR Control,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Electron. Electr. Syst. 1(1):323-333, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlé, M., “NH3 sensor for future HD, MD and LD diesel emission regulations”, 9th International CTI Conference SCR Systems.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laemmerhirt, T., Schmitt, D., Heidtkamp, C., Lemire, B., “Smart Nox Sensor: Functionality and Applications in HDT and LDT Vehicles”, MinNOx conference 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shost, M., Noetzel, J., Wu, M., Sugiarto, T. et al., “Monitoring, Feedback and Control of Urea SCR Dosing Systems for NOx Reduction: Utilizing an Embedded Model and Ammonia Sensing,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1325, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01- 1325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurzenberger, J. and Wanker, R., “Multi-Scale SCR Modeling, 1D Kinetic Analysis and 3D System Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0948, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0948.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chi, J. and DaCosta, H., “Modeling and Control of a Urea-SCR Aftertreatment System,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0966, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0966.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
