<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277953</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Sliding Mode Observers to Detect and Isolate Faults in a Turbocharged Gasoline Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Salehi</surname>
                  <given-names>Rasoul</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Alasty</surname>
                  <given-names>Aria</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vossoughi</surname>
                  <given-names>Gholam-Reza</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sharif University of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>399</fpage>
         <lpage>410</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277953"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a novel model-based algorithm which is able to detect and isolate major faults assigned to the gas exchange path of a gasoline engine both in the intake and exhaust sides. The diagnostics system is developed for detection and isolation of these faults: air leakage fault between the compressor and the air throttle, exhaust manifold pressure sensor fault, wastegate stuck-closed fault and wastegate stuck-open fault. Sliding mode observers (SMOs) are the core detection algorithms utilized in this work. A first order SMO is designed to estimate the turbocharger rotational dynamics. The wastegate displacement dynamics coupled to the exhaust manifold pressure dynamics is estimated using a second order SMO. Verified with experimental data from a modern TC gasoline engine running in a test cell, the two sliding mode observers are then used in a strategy to detect the faults in the gas exchange path. The proposed diagnostics system shows successful results in isolation of the four faults for gasoline engines without requiring a hot-film air-flow meter (HFM).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mohammadpour, J, Franchek M, and Grigoriadis K. “A Survey on Diagnostic Methods for Automotive Engines.” International Journal of Engine Research 13, no. 1 (2012): 41-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Isermann R., Model-based fault-detection and diagnosis - status and applications, annual reviews in control, (2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Djemili I., Boulkroune B., Aitouche A., Cocquempot V., Nonlinear unknown input observer for intake leakage estimation in diesel engines, in: Control &amp; Automation (MED), 2012 20th Mediterranean Conference on, 2012, pp. 978-983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slotine J.J.E., Hedrick J.K., Misawa E.A., On Sliding Observers for Nonlinear Systems, in: American Control Conference, 1986, 1986, pp. 1794-1800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spurgeon S.K., Sliding mode observers: a survey, International Journal of Systems Science, 39 (2008) 751-764.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shatnawi Y., Al-khassaweneh M., Fault diagnosis in internal combustion engines using extension neural network, IEEE Transactions On Industrial Electronics, 61 (2014) 1434-1443</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ceccarelli R., Canudas-de-Wit C., Moulin P., Sciarretta A., Model-based adaptive observers for intake leakage detection in diesel engines, in: American Control Conference, 2009. ACC '09., 2009, pp. 1128-1133.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ceccarelli, R., Moulin, P., and Canudas de Wit, C., “Turbine Efficiency Estimation for Fault Detection Application,” SAE Technical Paper 2010- 01-0568, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0568.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu D., Bohliga A., Gomm B., Singha M., Dynamic Fault Detection and Isolation For Automotive Engine Air Path By Independent Neural Network Model, International Journal of Engine Research, (2012).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sidorow, A., Eck, C., Isermann, R., and Konigorski, U., “Model Based Fault Diagnosis of the Intake and Exhaust Path of Turbocharged Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0148, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011- 24-0148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang Y.-Y., Haskara I., Exhaust Pressure Estimation and Its Application to Detection and Isolation of Turbocharger System Faults for Internal Combustion Engines, Journal of Dynamic Systems, Measurement, and Control, 134 (2012) 021002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nyberg M., Stutte T., Model based diagnosis of the air path of an automotive diesel engine, Control Engineering Practice, 12 (2004) 513-525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salehi, R., Alasty, A., and Vossoughi, G., “Air Leak Detection for a Turbocharged SI Engine using Robust Estimation of the Turbocharger Dynamics,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Electron. Electr. Syst. 7(1):157- 165, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salehi R., Vossoughi G.R., Alasty A., Modeling and Estimation of Unmeasured Variables in a Wastegate Operated Turbocharger., Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 136 (2013) 052601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salehi R., Shahbakhti M., Alasty A., Vossoughi G.R., Control oriented modeling of a radial turbine for a turbocharged gasoline engine, in: American Control Conference (ACC), Washington, DC, USA, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salehi R., Shahbakhti M., Alasty A., Vossoughi G.R., Nonlinear Observer Design for Turbocharger in a SI Engine, in: American Control Conference (ACC), Washington, DC, USA, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guzzella L., Onder C.H., Introduction to Modeling and Control of Internal Combustion Engine Systems, Springer, Berlin, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salehi R., Shahbakhti M., Alasty A., Vossoughi G., On-Line Fault Detection and Isolation (FDI) for the Exhaust Path of a Turbocharged SI Engine, in: ASME DSCC, Palo Alto, CA, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fridman L., Shtessel Y., Edwards C., Yan X.-G., Higher-order slidingmode observer for state estimation and input reconstruction in nonlinear systems, International Journal of Robust and Nonlinear Control, 18 (2008) 399-412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nuñez S., De Battista H., Garelli F., Vignoni A., Picó J., Secondorder sliding mode observer for multiple kinetic rates estimation in bioprocesses, Control Engineering Practice, 21 (2013) 1259-1265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahmed F.S., Laghrouche S., El Bagdouri M., Second-order sliding mode based output-feedback control of an engine air path actuator in presence of uncertainties, in: Control and Fault-Tolerant Systems (SysTol), 2010 Conference on, 2010, pp. 50-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartolini G., Ferrara A., Levant A., Usai E., On Second Order Sliding Mode Controllers, in: Thoma M. (Ed.) Variable Structure Systems, Sliding Mode and Nonlinear Control, Springer, London, 1999, pp. 329-350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davila J., Fridman L., Levant A., Second-order sliding-mode observer for mechanical systems, Automatic Control, IEEE Transactions on, 50 (2005) 1785-1789.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Floquet T., Barbot J.-P., Super twisting algorithm based step-by-step sliding mode observers for nonlinear systems with unknown inputs, International Journal of Systems Science, (2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
