<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">intejhealeconman</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50020182</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>International Journal of Health Economics and Management</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21999023</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21999031</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i40228136</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/45273477</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>RESEARCH ARTICLE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Have health insurance reforms in Tunisia attained their intended objectives?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Khaled</given-names>
                  <surname>Makhloufi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Bruno</given-names>
                  <surname>Ventelou</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mohammad</given-names>
                  <surname>Abu-Zaineh</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>29</fpage>
         <lpage>51</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/45273477"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>A growing number of developing countries are currently promoting health system reforms with the aim of attaining 'universal health coverage' (UHC). In Tunisia, several reforms have been undertaken over the last two decades to attain UHC with the goals of ensuring financial protection in health and enhancing access to healthcare. The first of these goals has recently been addressed in a companion paper by Abu-Zaineh et al. (Int J Health Care Financ Econ 13(1):73—93, 2013). The present paper seeks to assess whether these reforms have in fact enhanced access to healthcare. The average treatment effects of two insurance schemes, formal-mandatory (MHI) and state-subsidized (MAS) insurance, on the utilization of outpatient and inpatient healthcare are estimated using propensity score matching. Results support the hypothesis that both schemes (MHI and MAS) increase the utilization of healthcare. However, significant variations in the average effect of these schemes are observed across services and areas. For all the matching methods used and compared with those the excluded from cover, the increase in outpatient and inpatient services for the MHI enrollees was at least 19 and 26 %, respectively, in urban areas, while for MAS beneficiaries this increase was even more pronounced (28 and 75 % in the urban areas compared with 27 and 46 % in the rural areas for outpatient and inpatient services, respectively). One important conclusion that emerges is that the current health insurance schemes, despite improving accessibility to healthcare services, are nevertheless incapable of achieving effective coverage of the whole population for all services. Attaining the latter goal requires a strategy that targets the "trees" not the "forest".</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d768e214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e218" publication-type="other">
Abu-Zaineh, M., Arfa, C, Ventelou, B., Romdhane, H. B., &amp; Moatti, J.-P. (2014). Fairness in healthcare
finance and delivery: What about Tunisia? Health Policy and Planning, 29(4), 433-442.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e228a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e232" publication-type="other">
Abu-Zaineh, M., Romdhane, H. B., Ventelou, B., Moatti, J.-P, &amp; Chokri, A. (2013). Appraising financial
protection in health: The case of Tunisia. International Journal of Health Care Finance and Economics,
13(1),73-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e249" publication-type="other">
Abu-Zaineh, M., Mataria, A., Moatti, J.-P, &amp; Ventelou, B. (2011)-Measuring and decomposing socioeco-
nomic inequality in health care delivery: A micro-simulation approach with application to the Palestinian
conflict-affected fragile setting. Social Science and Medicine, 72(2), 133-141.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e262a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e266" publication-type="other">
Abu-Zaineh, M., Mataria, A., Luchini, S., &amp; Moatti, J.-P. (2009). Equity in health care finance in Palestine:
The triple effects revealed. Journal of Health Economics, 28(6), 1071-1080.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e277a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e281" publication-type="other">
Acharya, A., Vellakkal, S., Taylor, F., Masset, E., Satija, A., Burke, M., et al. (2012). Impact of national health
insurance for the poor and the informal sector in low-and middle-income countries: a systematic review.
London: EPPI-Centre, Social Science Research Unit, Institute of Education, University of London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e298" publication-type="other">
Achour, N. (2011). Tunisian health system: Current situation and challenges. United Nations Fund for Popu-
lation (UNFPA), Tunis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e312" publication-type="other">
Arfa, C., &amp; Achouri, H. (2008). Tunisia: Good Practise in expanding health coverage: Lessons reforms in
a country in transition. In P. Gottret, G. J. Schieber, &amp; H. R. Waters (Eds.), Good practice in health
financing: Lessons from reforms in low and middle-income countries. Washington DC: The World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e329" publication-type="other">
Arfa, C., &amp; Elgazzar, H. (2013). UNICO studies series 4 Consolidation and transparency: Transforming
Tunisia's health care for the poor. Washington DC: The World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e339a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e343" publication-type="other">
Arfa, C., Souidene, A., &amp; Achour, N. (2008). National Health Accounts Report for the years 2004 and 2005.
Tunis: National Institute of Public Health, Ministry of Public Health.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e357" publication-type="other">
Becker, S. O., &amp; Ichino, A. (2002). Estimation of average treatment effects based on propensity scores. The
Stata Journal, 2(4), 358-377.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e372" publication-type="other">
Benyamini, Y. (2008). Self-ratings of health and longevity: A health psychologist's viewpoint on epidemio-
logical findings. The European Health Psychologist, 10(1), 10-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e386" publication-type="other">
Bonjour, D., Knight, G., &amp; Lissenburgh, S. (2002). Evaluation of New Deal for Young People in Scotland
Phase 2. Scottish Executive Central Research Unit. Retrieved May 30, 2012 from http://scotland.gov.uk/
Resource/Doc/156692/0042112.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e403" publication-type="other">
Bryson, A., Dorsett, R., &amp; Purdon, S. (2002). The Use of Propensity Score Matching in the Evaluation of
Active Labour Market Policies. Department for Work and Pensions, Working Paper No. 4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e417" publication-type="other">
Burtless, G. (1995). The case for randomized field trials in economic and policy research. Journal of Economic
Perspectives, 9(2), 63-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e431" publication-type="other">
Caliendo, M., &amp; Kopeinig, S. (2008). Some practical guidance for the implementation of propensity score
matching. Journal of Economic Surveys, 22(1), 31-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e445" publication-type="other">
De Allegri, M., Sanon, M., &amp; Sauerborn, R. (2006). To enrol or not to enrol? A qualitative investigation of
demand for health insurance in rural West Africa. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 62(6), 1520-1527.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e456a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e460" publication-type="other">
Dorsett, R. (2004). The new deal for young people: Effect of the options on the labour market status of young
men. London: Policy Studies Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e470a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e474" publication-type="other">
Ensor, T. (2008). Universal Coverage in Developing Countries. In H. Kris (Ed.), International Encyclopedia
of Public Health (pp. 441-452). Oxford: Oxford Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e484a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e488" publication-type="other">
Giedion, U., Alfonso, E. A., &amp; Diaz, Y. (2013). UNICO studies series 25 the impact of universal coverage
schemes in the developing world: A review of the existing evidence. Washington DC: The World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e502" publication-type="other">
Gnawali, D. P., Pokhrel, S., Sié, A., Sanon, M., De Allegri, M., Souares, A., et al. (2009). The effect of
community-based health insurance on the utilization of modern health care services: Evidence from
Burkina Faso. Health Policy, 90(2-3), 214-222.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e515a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e519" publication-type="other">
Galarraga, O., Sosa-Rubí, S. G., Salinas-Rodríguez, A., &amp; Sesma-Vázquez, S. (2010). Health insurance for the
poor: Impact on catastrophic and out-of-pocket health expenditures in Mexico. The European Journal of
Health Economics, 11(5), 437-447.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e532a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e536" publication-type="other">
Gregg, P., &amp; Wadsworth, J. (1996). How effective are state employment agencies? jobcentre use and job
matching in Britain. Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 58(3), 443-467.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e551" publication-type="other">
Hadley, J. (2003). Sicker and poorer-the consequences of being uninsured: A Review of the research on
the relationship between health insurance, medical care use, health, work, and income. Medical Care
Research and Review, 60(2), 3S-75S.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e564a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e568" publication-type="other">
Hartley, D., Quam, L., &amp; Lurie, N. (1994). Urban and rural differences in health insurance and access to care.
The Journal of Rural Health, 10(2), 98-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e582" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J., LaLonde, R., &amp; Smith, J. (1999). The economics and econometrics of active labor market
programs. In Ashenfelter, O. and Card, D. (Eds): The Handbook of Labor Economics, Vol III, pp. 1 865-
2097.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e595a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e599" publication-type="other">
Jütting, J. (2005). Health insurance for the poor in developing countries. New York: Ashgate Publisher.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e606a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e610" publication-type="other">
Koch, S., &amp; Alaba, O. (2010). On health insurance and household decisions: A treatment effect analysis. Social
Science &amp; Medicine, 70(2), 175-182.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e620a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e624" publication-type="other">
Leuven, E., Sianesi, B. (2003). PSMATCH2: Stata module to perform full Mahalanobis and propensity score
matching, common support graphing and covariate imbalance testing. Retrieved May 30, 2012 from
http://ideas.repec.Org/c/boc/bocode/s432001.html.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e638a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e642" publication-type="other">
Mensah, J., Oppong, J. R., &amp; Schmidt, C. M. (2010). Ghana's National Health Insurance Scheme in the context
of the health MDGs: An empirical evaluation using propensity score matching. Health Economics, 19(S1),
95-106.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e655a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e659" publication-type="other">
Ministry of Public Health. (2009). Health insurance statistics. Tunis: Tunisia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e666a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e670" publication-type="other">
Ministry of Social Affairs. (2012). Main social Development Indicators in Tunisia 2012. Tunis: Tunisia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e677a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e681" publication-type="other">
Ministry of Public Health. (2008). National survey on morbidity and health care utilization: Epidemiological
transition and health impact in North Africa (TAHINA). Ministry of Public Health. Tunisia: Tunis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e691a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e695" publication-type="other">
National Institute of Statistics Tunisia (NIS). (2011). First Results of Employment -National Survey second
quarter 2011. Tunis: Tunisia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e705a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e709" publication-type="other">
National Health Insurance Fund (NHIF). (2012). Statistics of National Health Insurance Fund -January 2012.
Tunis: Tunisia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e720a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e724" publication-type="other">
Nishtar, S. (2010). The mixed health systems syndrome. Bulletin of the World Health Organization, 88(1),
74-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e734a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e738" publication-type="other">
Nyman, J. A. (2003). The Theory of Demand for Health Insurance. Stanford: Stanford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e745a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e749" publication-type="other">
Nyman, J. A. (2004). Is 'Moral Hazard' inefficient? The policy implications of a new theory. Health Affairs,
23(5), 194-199.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e763" publication-type="other">
O'Connell, T., Rasanathan, K., &amp; Chopra, M. (2014). What does universal health coverage mean ? The Lancet,
383(9913), 277-279.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e773a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e777" publication-type="other">
O'Donnell, O., van Doorslaer, E., Wagstaff, A., &amp; Lindelow, M. (2007). Analyzing health equity using house-
hold survey data: A guide to techniques and their implementation. Washington DC: The World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e791" publication-type="other">
Pauly, M. V., Zweifel, P., Scheffler, R. M., Preker, A. S., &amp; Bassett, M. M. (2006). Private health insurance in
developing countries. Health Affairs, 25(2), 369-379.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e802a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e806" publication-type="other">
Robyn, P. J., Hill, A., Liu, Y., Souares, A., Savadogo, G., Sié, A., et al. (2012). Econometric analysis to evaluate
the effect of community-based health insurance on reducing informal self-care in Burkina Faso. Health
Policy and Planning, 27(2), 156-165.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e819a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e823" publication-type="other">
Rosenbaum, P. R., &amp; Rubin, D. B. (1983). The central role of the propensity score in observational studies for
causal effects. Biometrika, 70(1), 41-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e833a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e837" publication-type="other">
Rosenbaum, P. R., &amp; Rubin, D. B. (1985). The bias due to incomplete matching. Biometrics, 41(1), 103-116.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e844a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e848" publication-type="other">
Rubin, D. B. (1974). Estimating causal effects of treatments in randomised and non-randomised studies.
Journal of Educational Psychology, 66(5), 688-701.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e862" publication-type="other">
Sen, A. (2002). Health: Perception versus observation. British Medical Journal, 524(7342), 860-861.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e869a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e873" publication-type="other">
Sianesi, B. (2004). An evaluation of Swedish system of active labor market programs in the 1990s. The Review
of Economics and Statistics, 86(1), 133-155.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e884a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e888" publication-type="other">
Sinha, T., Ranson, M., Chatterjee, M., Acharya, A., &amp; Mills, A. (2006). Barriers faced by the poor in benefiting
from community-based insurance services: lessons learnt from SEWA Insurance, Gujarat. Health Policy
and Planning, 21(2), 132-142.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e901a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e905" publication-type="other">
Smolderen, K. G., Spertus, J. A., Tang, F., Oetgen, W., Borden, W. B., Ting, H. H., et al. (2013). Treatment
differences by health insurance among outpatients with coronary artery disease insights from the national
cardiovascular data registry. Journal of the American College of Cardiology, 61(10), 1069-1075.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e918a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e922" publication-type="other">
Subramanian, S. V., Subramanyam, M. A., Selvaraj, S., &lt;&amp; Kawachi, I. (2009). Are self-reports of health and
morbidities in developing countries misleading? Evidence from India. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 68(2),
260-265.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e935a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e939" publication-type="other">
Thanh, N. X., Lofgren, C., Phuc, H. D., Chuc, N. T., &amp; Lindholm, L. (2010). An assessment of the implemen-
tation of the health care funds for the poor policy in rural Vietnam. Health Policy, 98(1), 58-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e949a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e953" publication-type="other">
Trujillo, A. J., Portillo, J. E., &amp; Vernon, J. A. (2005). The impact of subsidized health insurance for the poor:
Evaluating the Colombian experience using propensity score matching. International Journal of Health
Care Finance and Economics, 5(3), 211-239.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e970" publication-type="other">
Van Doorslaer, E., &amp; Jones, A. M. (2003). Inequalities in self-reported health: Validation of a new approach
to measurement. Journal of Health Economics, 22(1), 61-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e985" publication-type="other">
White, M., Lissenburgh, S., &amp; Bryson, A. (1997). The Impact of Public Job Placing Programmes. Policy
Studies Institute Report No. 846, London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e995a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e999" publication-type="other">
Wagstaff, A., &amp; Yu, S. (2007). Do health sector reforms have their intended impacts?: The World Bank's
Health VIII project in Gansu province, China. Journal of Health Economics, 26(3), 505-535.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e1009a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e1013" publication-type="other">
Wagstaff, A. (2010). Social health insurance reexamined. Health Economics, 19(5), 503-517.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e1020a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e1024" publication-type="other">
(2006). Republic of Tunisia Health sector Study. Human Development Group Middle East and North Africa
Region. Washington DC: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e1034a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e1038" publication-type="other">
World Bank. (2011). Striving for better jobs: The challenge of informality in the middle east and north africa
region: Overview. Washington DC: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e1048a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e1052" publication-type="other">
World Health Organization (WHO). (2013). The World Health Report 2013, Research for Universal Health
Coverage.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d768e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d768e1067" publication-type="other">
World Health Organization (WHO). (2010). The World Health Report: Health Systems Financing: the path to
universal coverage. Geneva: World Health Organization.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


