<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277583</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Influence of Hot Gas Jet on Combustion Enhancement for Lean Mixture in Plasma Jet Ignition</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sasaki</surname>
                  <given-names>Ryo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iijima</surname>
                  <given-names>Akira</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shoji</surname>
                  <given-names>Hideo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoshida</surname>
                  <given-names>Koji</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Nihon University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277559</issue-id>
         <fpage>1812</fpage>
         <lpage>1820</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International and Copyright © 2012 SAE Japan</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277583"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study clarified the influence of hot gas jet on combustion enhancement effect for lean mixture in the plasma jet ignition. The hot gas jet was generated by the high temperature plasma and was ejected from igniter after plasma jet finished issuing. In combustion tests, propane-air mixture at equivalence ratio of 0.6 was used and the mixture was filled in the combustion chamber at atmosphere pressure and room temperature. For generation of the hot gas jet, the standard air was filled in chamber at same conditions and the hot gas jet was visualized by schlieren method in the absence of combustion. The combustion development processes were also visualized and the combustion pressure was measured. The discharge voltage, discharge current and the plasma luminescence were also measured. The plasma luminescence disappeared within 0.05 ms for any experimental conditions. When cavity depth was deep and orifice diameter was small, the maximum plasma luminescence height was short. However, the hot gas jet ejection velocity was increased as the cavity volume increased and orifice diameter decreased. At 0.5 ms after the ignition, both initial flame kernel and hot gas jet were similarly developed. However, the combustion was continuously enhanced after the hot gas jet disappeared. This is because the initial flame kernel was enlarged and turbulence was generated on flame front by the hot gas jet effect. In case of a large volume cavity and small diameter orifice of igniter, the flame propagation was enhanced and combustion duration was shortened. The high voltage discharge duration was very short as compared with combustion period and the initial flame kernel was similarly developed as hot gas jet, therefore the combustion enhancement effect of plasma jet ignition was mainly caused by the hot gas jet effect.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IPCC Fourth Assessment Report: Climate Change 2007, http://www.ipcc.ch/pdf/assessment-report/ar4/wg3/ar4-wg3-spm.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamakawa, M., Youso, T., Fujikawa, T., Nishimoto, T. et al., “Combustion Technology Development for a High Compression Ratio SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):98-105, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1871.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamakawa, M., Youso, T., Fujikawa, T., Nishimoto, T. et al., “Combustion Technology Development for a High Compression Ratio SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):98-105, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1871.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakamura, N., Baika, T., and Shibata, Y., “Multipoint Spark Ignition for Lean Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 852092, 1985, doi: 10.4271/852092.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Kohn, J., and Parsons, P., “Ignition Energy Development for a Spark Initiated Combustion System Capable of High Load, High Efficiency and Near Zero NOx Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2): 481-496, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-32-0088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Nakada, T., Kakuhou, A., and Takagi, Y., “Effects of Swirl/Tumble Motion on In-Cylinder Mixture Formation in a Lean-Burn Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 961994, 1996, doi: 10.4271/961994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lawton, J., Payne, K.G., Weinberg, F. J.: “Flame-Arc Combination”, Nature 193, pp.736-738 (1962).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cetegen, B., Teichman, K., Weinberg, F., and Oppenheim, A., “Performance of a Plasma Jet Igniter,” SAE Technical Paper 800042, a1980, doi: 10.4271/800042.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murase, E., Ono, S., Hanada, K., and Nakahara, S., “Plasma Jet Ignition in Turbulent lean Mixtures,” SAE Technical Paper 890155, 1989, doi: 10.4271/890155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshida, K., Shoji, H., and Saima, A., “Influence of the Characteristic Length on Performance of Plasma Jet Igniters,” SAE Technical Paper 942051, 1994, doi: 10.4271/942051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Japan Society of Mechanical Engineers, “JSME Mechanical Engineers Handbook α4, Fluids Engineering”, p.6 (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
