<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422539</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Study on High-Load Extension of Gasoline/PODE Dual-Fuel RCCI Operation Using Late Intake Valve Closing</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Hu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tong</surname>
                  <given-names>Laihui</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Zheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Zunqing</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yao</surname>
                  <given-names>Mingfa</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tianjin Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>1482</fpage>
         <lpage>1490</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422539"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The dual-fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) combustion could achieve high efficiency and low emissions over a wide range of operating conditions. However, further high load extension is limited by the excessive pressure rise rate and soot emission. Polyoxymethylene dimethyl ethers (PODE), a novel diesel alternative fuel, has the capability to achieve stoichiometric smoke-free RCCI combustion due to its high oxygen content and unique molecule structure. In this study, experimental investigations on high load extension of gasoline/PODE RCCI operation were conducted using late intake valve closing (LIVC) strategy and intake boosting in a single-cylinder, heavy-duty diesel engine. The experimental results show that the upper load can be effectively extended through boosting and LIVC with gasoline/PODE stoichiometric operation. With the retarding of LIVC timing and increase of cyclic fuel quantity, higher boosting pressure and lower Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) ratio were required to maintain sufficient available oxygen. The upper load of gasoline/PODE RCCI operation could be extended up to 23 bar indicated mean effective pressure (IMEP), while still maintaining ultra-low smoke/NOx emissions and acceptable peak in-cylinder pressure and pressure rise rate (PRR). In addition, stoichiometric combustion also enables the application of a low-cost three-way catalyst to further reduce HC and CO emissions. However, LIVC results in slight reduction of indicated thermal efficiency (ITE) due to the lower effective compression ratio and more incomplete combustion with stoichiometric operation, thus further combustion optimization is necessary for ITE improvement. The study reveals that gasoline/PODE RCCI offers a very competitive pathway to achieve clean and highly efficient combustion over the full load conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. D. Directions in internal combustion engine research. Combustion and Flame, 160(1), 1-8, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2012.11.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, B., Li, S., Zheng, Z., Yao, M. et al., "A Comparative Study on Different Dual-Fuel Combustion Modes Fuelled with Gasoline and Diesel," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0694, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. D., Duraisamy, G. Review of high efficiency and clean reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI) combustion in internal combustion engines. Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 46(0), 12-71, 2015, doi: 10.1016/j.pecs.2014.05.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L., Hanson, R. M., Splitter, D. A. et al., Fuel reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI): a pathway to controlled highefficiency clean combustion. International Journal of Engine Research, 12(3), 209-226, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411401548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., "Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Heavy-Duty Engine Operation at Mid-and High-Loads with Conventional and Alternative Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0363, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, G., Shen, Y., Zhang, Q. et al., Experimental study on combustion and emission characteristics of a diesel engine fueled with 2,5-dimethylfuran-diesel, n-butanol-diesel and gasoline-diesel blends. Energy, 54(0), 333-342, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2013.02.069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma, S., Zheng, Z., Liu, H. et al., Experimental investigation of the effects of diesel injection strategy on gasoline/diesel dual-fuel combustion. Applied Energy, 109(0), 202-212, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.04.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Y., Jia, M., Chang, Y. et al., Parametric study and optimization of a RCCI (reactivity controlled compression ignition) engine fueled with methanol and diesel. Energy, 65, 319-332, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2013.11.059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Molina, S., García, A. et al., Effects of low reactivity fuel characteristics and blending ratio on low load RCCI (reactivity controlled compression ignition) performance and emissions in a heavyduty diesel engine. Energy, 90, Part 2, 1261-1271, 2015, doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2015.06.088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L., Musculus, M. P. B., Reitz, R. D. Evaluating temperature and fuel stratification for heat-release rate control in a reactivitycontrolled compression-ignition engine using optical diagnostics and chemical kinetics modeling. Combustion and Flame, 162(6), 2729-2742, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2015.04.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D. A., Reitz, R. D. Fuel reactivity effects on the efficiency and operational window of dual-fuel compression ignition engines. Fuel, 118(0), 163-175, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.10.045.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Wissink, M., DelVescovo, D., and Reitz, R., "RCCI Engine Operation Towards 60% Thermal Efficiency," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0279, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0279.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. B., Walker, N. R., Gingrich, E. et al., Comparison of Low Temperature Combustion Strategies for Advanced Compression Ignition Engines with a Focus on Controllability. Combustion Science and Technology, 186(2), 210-241, 2013, doi:10.1080/00102202.2013.858137 .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H., Zheng, Z., Liu, H. et al., Combustion Mode Design with High Efficiency and Low Emissions Controlled by Mixtures Stratification and Fuel Reactivity. Frontiers in Mechanical Engineering, 1, 2015, doi: 10.3389/fmech.2015.00008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lim, J. H., Reitz, R. D. High Load (21 Bar IMEP) Dual Fuel RCCI Combustion Using Dual Direct Injection. Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 136(10), 101514-101514, 2014, doi: 10.1115/1.4027361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nieman, D., Dempsey, A., and Reitz, R., "Heavy-Duty RCCI Operation Using Natural Gas and Diesel," SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):270-285, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A., Walker, N., and Reitz, R., "Effect of Cetane Improvers on Gasoline, Ethanol, and Methanol Reactivity and the Implications for RCCI Combustion," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):170-187, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H., DelVescovo, D., Yao, M., and Reitz, R., "Numerical Study of RCCI and HCCI Combustion Processes Using Gasoline, Diesel, iso-Butanol and DTBP Cetane Improver," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):831-845, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0850.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tong, L., Wang, H., Zheng, Z. et al., Experimental study of RCCI combustion and load extension in a compression ignition engine fueled with gasoline and PODE. Fuel, 181, 878-886, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2016.05.037.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J., Wang, H., Li, Y. et al., Effects of diesel/PODE (polyoxymethylene dimethyl ethers) blends on combustion and emission characteristics in a heavy duty diesel engine. Fuel, 177, 206-216, 2016, doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2016.03.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jia, M., Li, Y., Xie, M. et al., The Potential of High-load Extension by Using Late Intake Valve Closing for a Diesel Premixed Charge Compression Ignition (PCCI) Engine. Energy Procedia, 66, 33-36, 2015, doi: 10.1016/j.egypro.2015.02.018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, X., Wang, H., Zheng, Z. et al., Effects of late intake valve closing (LIVC) and rebreathing valve strategies on diesel engine performance and emissions at low loads. Applied Thermal Engineering, 98, 310-319, 2016, doi: 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2015.12.045.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
