<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277812</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>On-Board Fuel Identification using Artificial Neural Networks</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mocanu</surname>
                  <given-names>Florin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Wayne State Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>937</fpage>
         <lpage>946</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277812"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>On-board fuel identification is important to ensure engine safe operation, similar power output, fuel economy and emissions levels when different fuels are used. Real-time detection of physical and chemical properties of the fuel requires the development of identifying techniques based on a simple, non-intrusive sensor. The measured crankshaft speed signal is already available on series engine and can be utilized to estimate at least one of the essential combustion parameters such as peak pressure and its location, rate of cylinder pressure rise and start of combustion, which are an indicative of the ignition properties of the fuel.</p>
            <p>Using a dynamic model of the crankshaft numerous methods have been previously developed to identify the fuel type but all with limited applications in terms of number of cylinders and computational resources for real time control.</p>
            <p>The purpose of the current work is to overcome these limitations and to present how Artificial Neural Networks expand the capability of utilizing engine speed signal for fuel identification by using main combustion characteristics such as firing peak cylinder pressure and peak pressure rise rate.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taglialatela, F., Cesario, N., Lavorgna, M., Merola, S. et al., “Use of Engine Crankshaft Speed for Determination of Cylinder Pressure Parameters,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0108, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guezennec, Y. and Gyan, P., “A Novel Approach to Real- Time Estimation of the Individual Cylinder Combustion Pressure for S.I. Engine Control,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0209, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taraza, D., Henein, N., and Bryzik, W., “Determination of the Gas- Pressure Torque of a Multicylinder Engine from Measurements of the Crankshaft's Speed Variation,” SAE Technical Paper 980164, 1998, doi:10.4271/980164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taraza, D., “Quantifying Relationships Between the Crankshaft's Speed Variation and the Gas Pressure Torque,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1007, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taraza, D., “Statistical Model and Simulation of Engine Torque and Speed Correlation,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3686, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taraza, D., “Accuracy Limits of IMEP Determination from Crankshaft Speed Mesurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01- 0331, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taraza Dinu, Henein Naeim A., Gade Mangesh J., Bryzik Walter, “Cylinder Pressure Reconstruction from Crankshaft Speed Measurements in a Four-Stroke Single Cylinder Diesel Engine”, ASME 2005 Internal Combustion Engine Division Spring Technical Conference (ICES2005)/1023 pp. 387-395 doi:10.1115/ICES2005-1023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ponti, F., Ravaglioli, V., Serra, G., and Stola, F., “Instantaneous Engine Speed Measurement and Processing for MFB50 Evaluation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):235-244, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2747.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brand, D., Onder, C., and Guzzella, L., “Estimation of the Instantaneous In-Cylinder Pressure for Control Purposes using Crankshaft Angular Velocity,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0228, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kallenberger, C., Hamedović, H., Raichle, F., Breuninger, J. et al., “Estimation of Cylinder-Wise Combustion Features from Engine Speed and Cylinder Pressure,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):198-207, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mocanu, F. and Taraza, D., “Estimation of Main Combustion Parameters from the Measured Instantaneous Crankshaft Speed,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0326, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01- 0326.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jayakumar Chandrasekharan, Nargunde Jagdish, Sinha Anubhav, Bryzik Walter et. al. “Effect of Biodiesel, JP-8 and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel on Autoignition, Combustion, Performance and Emissions in a Single Cylinder Diesel Engine”, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, February 2012, Vol. 134/022801-11, 10.1115/1.4003971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nargunde, J., Jayakumar, C., Sinha, A., Acharya, K. et al., “Comparison between Combustion, Performance and Emission Characteristics of JP-8 and Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel Fuel in a Single Cylinder Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jayakumar, C., Zheng, Z., Joshi, U., Bryzik, W. et al., “Effect of Intake Pressure and Temperature on the Auto- Ignition of Fuels with Different Cetane Number and Volatility,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1317, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1317.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCormick Bob, National Renewable Energy Laboratory, “Effects of biodiesel on pollutant emissions”, March 16, 2005, Golden, Colorado, U.S.A.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haykin Simon, “Neural Networks - A Comprehensive Foundation”, McMaster University, Ontario, Canada, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehrotra K, Mohan CK, Ranka S. “Elements of artificial neural networks”, Cambridge, Massachusets, USA, Bradford Book, MIT Press, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hornik K, Stinchcomb X, White X., “Multilayer feedforward networks as universal approximators”, Neural Networks 1989</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dayhoff JE/New York: Van Nostrand Reinhold, “An introduction to neural network architectures”, 1990</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park J, Sandberg I., “Approximation and radial-basis-function networks”, Neural Computation/1993; 5: 305-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stone, M., “Embedded Neural Networks in Real Time Controls,” SAE Technical Paper 941067, 1994, doi:10.4271/941067.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fahlman S., “An empirical study of learning speed in backpropagation networks”, Technical Rep. CMU-CS-88-162. Pittsburgh: Carnegie-Mellon University, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cybenko G, “Approximation by superposition of sigmoidal functions in neural networks”, Math Control Signals Systems 1989; 2: 303- 14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rogers, S., “Adaptive Neural Network Control of Engine RPM,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2680, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01- 2680.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., He, Y., and Rutland, C., “Improvement of Neural Network Accuracy for Engine Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3227, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitsuhashi, K., Tsuchiya, T., Morishita, S., Shiraishi, T. et al., “Revolution Control for Diesel Engines by Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1361, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller, R. and Schneider, B., “Approximation and Control of the Engine Torque Using Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0929, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayeb, M., Lichtenthäler, D., Winsel, T., and Theuerkauf, H., “SI Engine Modeling Using Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 980790, 1998, doi:10.4271/980790.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gnanam, G., Burton, R., Habibi, S., and Sulatisky, M., “Neural Network Control of a Bi-Fuel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004- 01-1360, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, Y. and Rutland, C., “Modeling of a Turbocharged DI Diesel Engine Using Artificial Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2772, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Traver, M., Atkinson, R., and Atkinson, C., “Neural Network- Based Diesel Engine Emissions Prediction Using In-Cylinder Combustion Pressure,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1532, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I. and Rutland, C., “Optimization of Diesel Engine Operating Parameters Using Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3228, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Longwic, R., “Modelling the Combustion Process in the Diesel Engine with the Use of Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2446, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ouenou Gamo, S., Ouladsine, M., and Rachid, A., “Diesel Engine Exhaust Emissions Modelling Using Artificial Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1163, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01- 1163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nareid, H. and Lightowler, N., “Detection of Engine Misfire Events using an Artificial Neural Network,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01- 1363, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jarrett, R. and Clark, N., “Weighting of Parameters in Artificial Neural Network Prediction of Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2878, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2878.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusca, S., Lanzafame, R., and Messina, M., “A Combustion Model for ICE by Means of Neural Network,” SAE Technical Paper 2005- 01-2110, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stone, M., “Embedded Neural Networks in Real Time Controls,” SAE Technical Paper 941067, 1994, doi:10.4271/941067.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, Z. and Lee, A., “Misfire Detection Using a Dynamic Neural Network with Output Feedback,” SAE Technical Paper 980515, 1998, doi:10.4271/980515.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Syntroleum material safety data sheet: S-8 Synthetic jet fuel http://www.syntroleum.com/profiles/investor/fullpage.asp?f=1&amp;BzID=202 9&amp;to=cp&amp;Nav=0&amp;LangID=1&amp;s=0&amp;ID=11912</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Southwest Research Institute - Petroleum products research department test report/June 7, 2007 (26)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Southwest Research Institute - Petroleum products research department test report/Nov 4, 2011 (27)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
