<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465393</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465697</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Preventing Zombie Lending</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Max</given-names>
                  <surname>Bruche</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gerard</given-names>
                  <surname>Llobet</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>923</fpage>
         <lpage>956</lpage>
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465697"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Because of limited liability, insolvent banks have an incentive to continue lending to insolvent borrowers, in order to hide losses and gamble for resurrection, even though this is socially inefficient. We suggest a scheme that regulators could use to solve this problem. The scheme would induce banks to reveal their bad loans, which can then be dealt with. Bank participation in the scheme would be voluntary. Even though banks have private information on the quantity of bad loans on their balance sheets, the scheme avoids creating windfall gains for bank equity holders. In addition, some losses can be imposed on debt holders.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d22e144a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e151" publication-type="other">
"Instead of disclosing troubled credit, many Spanish lenders have chosen to refinance loans that could still prove
faulty and to report foreclosed or unsold homes as assets, often without posting their drop in market value." See
"Zombie Buildings Shadow Spain's Economic Future," The Wall Street Journal, September 16, 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e164a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e171" publication-type="other">
See "Zombie Hotels Arise in Ireland as Recession Empties Rooms," http://www.bloomberg.com, August 30,
2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e181a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e188" publication-type="other">
See the Bank of England's Financial Stability Report, June 2011, especially Section 2.2 and Box 2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e195a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e202" publication-type="other">
The model could also be interpreted as describing a situation in which the regulator has received a signal on the
solvency of a single bank.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e213a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e220" publication-type="other">
Note that again, if the regulator implements the scheme in a way that allows observing the actual recoveries
when loans are foreclosed or modified immediately, this information could be used to make inferences about the
quality of the underlying collateral, which might be useful for estimating the recoveries that could have been
obtained if action on the bad loans had been delayed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e236a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e243" publication-type="other">
Interestingly, Giannetti and Simonov (2013) show that many of the equity injections carried out in Japan were
relatively small and were not conditional on a change of behavior of banks, and therefore in many cases did not
prevent further zombie lending.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e256a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e263" publication-type="other">
More generally, managers might hide information about the true profitability of projects from investors. In the
literature on managerial incentives, papers such as Levitt and Snyder (1997), Eisfeldt and Rampini (2008), and
Inderst and Mueller (2010) characterize the payment schemes that investors can use to elicit information about
the profitability of a project from a risk-averse manager.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e279a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e286" publication-type="other">
The Online Appendix is available on the Review of Financial Studies web site.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e293a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e300" publication-type="other">
As noted in the introduction, insolvent borrowers whose loans are rolled over (or not modified) are likely to have
incentives to extract value, whatever the cost to the bank. This is likely to destroy value overall, as could be
demonstrated via a model in which the borrower has to make an effort to maintain the value of collateral.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e313a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e320" publication-type="other">
A sufficient condition that ensures that 6 &lt; 1 would be that p&lt; D, which ensures that banks with 6 = 1 obtain a
value of equity of 0 from taking immediate action on all bad loans.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e331a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e338" publication-type="other">
Note also that in this setup, we do not allow banks to foreclose or modify good loans. For the discussion of the
case where this is possible, see the discussion below and the Online Appendix, Section Al.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e348a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e355" publication-type="other">
Could Coasian bargaining between private parties without the involvement of the regulator solve the gambling
problem by a reorganization of the capital structure (Haugen and Senbet 1978)? Here, the fact that equity holders
have private information can mean that such negotiations might not take place, as in Giammarino (1989). In
addition, it is reasonable to believe that banks would have incentives ex ante to choose debt structures that would
make such ex post bargaining impossible, as argued by Bolton and Scharfstein (1996). That is, even though in
the baseline model there are no externalities, it is plausible to assume that private parties would not solve the
gambling problem ex ante or ex post.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e381a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e388" publication-type="other">
We restrict ourselves to deterministic mechanisms. From a purely technical point of view, stochastic mechanisms
that improve welfare exist, but they are very implausible.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e398a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e405" publication-type="other">
Note that since we restrict ourselves to schemes with voluntary participation, the minimum expected value of
equity to which the regulator could hold banks even with full information would be the level they obtain outside
the scheme, as described by the participation constraint.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e418a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e425" publication-type="other">
In the class of schemes with voluntary participation, the only general way of improving on the incentives
produced by our scheme would be to reward banks that end up having a low proportion of bad loans with
positive information rents. It can be shown that due to global incentive compatibility constraints, this necessarily
also implies paying positive (although smaller) information rents to all banks that have a larger proportion of
bad loans, reducing the appeal of such a mechanism. Under schemes with mandatory participation, incentives
could be improved without necessarily increasing cost, but the improvement would be limited by the necessary
convexity of participation profits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e451a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e458" publication-type="other">
As highlighted in Remark 1, for positive transfers F{6), participating banks foreclose all bad loans and hence
participation profits are determined by (16). Starting from this expression, the conditions can be derived in the
standard way [see, for example the description in Fudenberg and Tirole (1991), section 7.3].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e472a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e479" publication-type="other">
This is a special case of the argument of Maggi and Rodriguez-Clare (1995), who point out that, in general,
decreasing convex outside opportunities can lead to optimal contracts that eliminate information rents for a
range of agents. Remarkably, in our model this property holds globally due to the convexity of the participation
value of equity in y.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e495a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e502" publication-type="other">
The role of the same three properties of the model can also be observed in the proof of Proposition 1 in the
Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e512a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e519" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Alan Greenspan's proposal mentioned in "Hire the A-Team," The Economist, August 7, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e526a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e533" publication-type="other">
Equivalently, the regulator can offer to exchange the old debt claim for a new debt claim that is equivalent in all
respects except that it includes the call option.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e543a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e550" publication-type="other">
Although it would be possible to condition the haircut on the 0 revealed by the participating bank, doing so
would not allow the regulator to extract additional rents, since debt holders are assumed to possess no private
information.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e563a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e570" publication-type="other">
A more complicated version of the welfare function would arise if B, the social cost of bank failure, were to
depend on the number (or type) of failing banks, as it plausibly might if the regulator is worried about an element
of systemic risk. This would produce yet another set of banks that should optimally participate in the scheme.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e584a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e591" publication-type="other">
Note that a scheme that induces modification would avoid this problem. Since our model does not make a
distinction between foreclosure and modification, a full discussion of the trade-offs between foreclosure and
modification goes beyond the scope of this paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e604a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e611" publication-type="other">
This could plausibly arise in a bank run model based on a global game (Goldstein and Pauzner 2005), where the
publicly perceived probability of default plays the role of the "fundamental."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e621a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e628" publication-type="other">
More specifically, the Hessian implied by (6) has one positive eigenvalue, and one zero eigenvalue.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d22e644a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e648" publication-type="other">
Aghion, P., P. Bolton, and S. pries. 1999. Optimal design of bank bailouts: The case of transition economies.
Journal of Institutional and Theoretical Economics 155:51-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e658a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e662" publication-type="other">
Ausubel, L. M., and P. Cramton. 2008. A troubled asset reverse auction. Working Paper, University of
Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e676" publication-type="other">
Baron, D., and R. Myerson. 1982. Regulating a monopolist with unknown cost. Econometrica 50:911-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e687" publication-type="other">
Bhattacharya, S., and K. G Nyborg. 2010. Bank bailout menus. Working Paper, Swiss Finance Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e695a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e699" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., and D. S. Scharfstein. 1996. Optimal debt structure and the number of creditors. Journal of Political
Economy 104:1-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e709a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e713" publication-type="other">
Caballero, R. J., T. Hoshi, and A. K. Kashyap. 2008. Zombie lending and depressed restructuring in Japan.
American Economic Review 98:1943-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e723a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e727" publication-type="other">
Corbett, J., and J. Mitchell. 2000. Banking crises and bank rescues: The effect of reputation. Journal of Money,
Credit, and Banking 32:474-512.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e737a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e741" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D. W., and R. G Rajan. 2011. Fear of fire sales, illiquidity seeking, and credit freezes. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 126:557-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e751a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e755" publication-type="other">
Eisfeldt, A. L., and A. A. Rampini. 2008. Managerial incentives, capital reallocation, and the business cycle.
Journal of Financial Economics 87:177-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e765a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e769" publication-type="other">
Flannery, M. J. 2009. Stabilizing large financial institutions with contingent capital certificates. Working Paper,
SSRN.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e780a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e784" publication-type="other">
Fudenberg, D., and J. Tirole. 1991. Game Theory. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e791a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e795" publication-type="other">
Giammarino, R. 1989. The resolution of financial distress. Review of Financial Studies 2:25-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e802a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e806" publication-type="other">
Giannetti, M., and A. Simonov. 2013. On the real effects of bank bailouts: Micro-evidence from Japan. American
Economic Journal: Macroeconomics 5:135-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e816a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e820" publication-type="other">
Goldstein, I., and A. Pauzner. 2005. Demand-deposit contracts and the probability of bank runs. Journal of
Finance 60:1293-327.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e830a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e834" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and L. Huang. 2004. Liquidity, efficiency and bank bailouts. American Economic Review 94:455-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e841a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e845" publication-type="other">
Haugen, R. A., and L. W. Senbet. 1978. The insignificance of bankruptcy costs to the theory of optimal capital
structure. Journal of Finance 33:383-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e856a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e860" publication-type="other">
House, C. L., and Y. Masatlioglu. 2010. Managing markets for toxic assets. Working Paper, NBER.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e871" publication-type="other">
Inderst, R., and H. M. Mueller. 2010. CEO replacement under private information. Review of Financial Studies
23:2935-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e885" publication-type="other">
Jullien, B. 2000. Participation constraints in adverse selection models. Journal of Economic Theory 93:1—47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e892a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e896" publication-type="other">
Klemperer, P. 2010. The product-mix auction: A new auction design for differentiated goods. Journal of the
European Economic Association 8:526-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e906a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e910" publication-type="other">
Levitt, S. D., and C. M. Snyder. 1997. Is no news bad news? Information transmission and the role of "early
warning" in the principal-agent model. RAND Journal of Economics 28:641-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e924" publication-type="other">
Lewis, T., and D. Sappington. 1989. Countervailing incentives in agency models. Journal of Economic Theory
49:294-313.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e935a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e939" publication-type="other">
Maggi, G, and A. Rodriguez-Clare. 1995. On countervailing incentives. Journal of Economic Theory
66:238-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e949a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e953" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, J. 1998. The problem of bad debts: Cleaning banks' balance sheets in economies in transition. Discussion
Paper, CEPR.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e963a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e967" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, J. 2001. Bad debts and the cleaning of banks' balance sheets: An application to transition economies.
Journal of Financial Intermediation 10:1-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e977a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e981" publication-type="other">
Peek, J., and E. S. Rosengren. 2005. Unnatural selection: Perverse incentives and the misallocation of credit in
Japan. American Economic Review 95:1144—66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e991a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e995" publication-type="other">
Philippon, T., and P. Schnabl. 2013. Efficient recapitalization. Journal of Finance 68:1-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1002a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1006" publication-type="other">
Philippon, T., and V. Skreta. 2012. Optimal interventions in markets with adverse selection. American Economic
Review 102:1-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1017a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1021" publication-type="other">
Sekine, T., K. Kobayashi, and Y. Saita. 2003. Forebearance lending: The case of Japanese firms. Monetary and
Economic Studies 21:69-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1031a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1035" publication-type="other">
Tirole, J. 2012. Overcoming adverse selection: How public intervention can restore market functioning. American
Economic Review 102:29-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


