<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285125</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Energy Analysis of Low-Load Low-Temperature Gasoline Combustion with Auxiliary-Fueled Negative Valve Overlap</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ekoto</surname>
                  <given-names>Isaac</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wolk</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Northrop</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Minnesota</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>1238</fpage>
         <lpage>1255</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285125"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In-cylinder reforming of injected fuel during an auxiliary negative valve overlap (NVO) period can be used to optimize main-cycle auto-ignition phasing for low-load Low-Temperature Gasoline Combustion (LTGC), where highly dilute mixtures can lead to poor combustion stability. When mixed with fresh intake charge and fuel, these reformate streams can alter overall charge reactivity characteristics. The central issue remains large parasitic heat losses from the retention and compression of hot exhaust gases along with modest pumping losses that result from mixing hot NVO-period gases with the cooler intake charge. Accurate determination of total cycle energy utilization is complicated by the fact that NVO-period retained fuel energy is consumed during the subsequent main combustion period. For the present study, a full-cycle energy analysis was performed for a single-cylinder research engine undergoing LTGC with varying NVO auxiliary fueling rates and injection timing.</p>
            <p>A custom alternate-fire sequence with 9 pre-conditioning cycles was used to generate a common exhaust temperature and composition boundary condition for a cycle-of-interest, with performance metrics recorded for each custom cycle. The NVO-period reformate stream and main-period exhaust stream of the cycles-of-interest were separately collected, with sample analysis by gas chromatography used to identify the retained and exhausted fuel energy in the respective periods. To facilitate gas sample analysis, experiments were performed using a 5-component gasoline surrogate (iso-octane, n-heptane, ethanol, 1-hexene, and toluene) that matched the molecular composition, 50% boiling point, and ignition characteristics of a research gasoline. The highest total cycle thermodynamic efficiencies occurred when auxiliary injection timings were early enough to allow sufficient residence time for slow reforming reactions to take place, but late enough to prevent significant fuel spray crevice quench. Increasing the fraction of total fuel energy injected into the NVO-period was also found to increase total cycle thermal efficiencies, in part due to a modest reduction in NVO-period heat loss from a combination of fuel-spray charge cooling and endothermic fuel decomposition by pyrolysis. The effect was most pronounced at the lowest loads where larger charge mass reformate fractions increased overall specific heat ratios and main-period combustion phasing advanced closer to top dead center. These effects improved both expansion efficiency and combustion stability.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saxena S, Bedoya ID, "Fundamental phenomena affecting low temperature combustion and HCCI engines, high load limits and strategies for extending these limits," Prog Energ Combust, 39 (5):457- 88, 2013, doi: DOI 10.1016/j.pecs.2013.05.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Speth RL, Chow EW, Malina R, Barrett SRH, Heywood JB, Green WH, "Economic and Environmental Benefits of Higher-Octane Gasoline," Environ Sci Technol, 48 (12):6561-8, 2014, doi: 10.1021/es405557p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Reitz, R., and Hanson, R., "High Efficiency, Low Emissions RCCI Combustion by Use of a Fuel Additive," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):742-756, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavoie GA, Martz J, Wooldridge M, Assanis D, "A multi-mode combustion diagram for spark assisted compression ignition," Combustion and Flame, 157 (6):1106-10, 2010, doi: 10.1016/j.combustflame.2010.02.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kodavasal J, Lavoie GA, Assanis DN, Martz JB, "The effects of thermal and compositional stratification on the ignition and duration of homogeneous charge compression ignition combustion," Combustion and Flame, 162 (2):451-61, 2015, doi: 10.1016/j.combustflame.2014.07.026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Yang, Y., Dernotte, J., and Ji, C., "Effects of Gasoline Reactivity and Ethanol Content on Boosted, Premixed and Partially Stratified Low-Temperature Gasoline Combustion (LTGC)," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):935-955, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Wermuth, N., and Najt, P., "High Load HCCI Operation Using Different Valving Strategies in a Naturally-Aspirated Gasoline HCCI Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1190-1201, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011- 01-0899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steeper, R. and Davisson, M., "Analysis of Gasoline Negative-Valve- Overlap Fueling via Dump Sampling," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):762-771, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1273.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wermuth, N., Yun, H., and Najt, P., "Enhancing Light Load HCCI Combustion in a Direct Injection Gasoline Engine by Fuel Reforming During Recompression," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):823-836, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Peterson, B., Szybist, J., and Northrop, W., "Analysis of Thermal and Chemical Effects on Negative Valve Overlap Period Energy Recovery for Low-Temperature Gasoline Combustion," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(5):2227-2239, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2451.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolk B, Ekoto I, Northrop WF, Moshammer K, Hansen N, "Detailed speciation and reactivity characterization of fuel-specific incylinder reforming products and the associated impact on engine performance," Fuel, 185:348-61, 2016, doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2016.07.103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EKOTO, I., Skeen, S., Steeper, R., and Hansen, N., "Detailed Characterization of Negative Valve Overlap Chemistry by Photoionization Mass Spectroscopy," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(1):26-38, 2016, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1804.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto I, Wolk B, Northrop W, Moshammer K, Hansen N, "Tailoring Charge Reactivity Using In-Cylinder Generated Reformate for Gasoline Compression Ignition Strategies," International Combustion Engine Fall Technical Conference, Greenville, South Carolina, ASME ICEF2016- 9458, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T. and Mangold, B., "Dedicated EGR: A New Concept in High Efficiency Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):620-631, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dernotte, J., Dec, J., and Ji, C., "Energy Distribution Analysis in Boosted HCCI-like/LTGC Engines - Understanding the Trade-Offs to Maximize the Thermal Efficiency," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):956-980, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0824.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolk, B., Ekoto, I., and Northrop, W., "Investigation of Fuel Effects on In-Cylinder Reforming Chemistry Using Gas Chromatography," SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):964-978, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0753.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl M, Chen JY, Pitz WJ, Sarathy SM, Westbrook CK, "An Approach for Formulating Surrogates for Gasoline with Application toward a Reduced Surrogate Mechanism for CFD Engine Modeling," Energ Fuel, 25 (11):5215-23, 2011, doi: 10.1021/ef201099y.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lemmon EW, Huber ML, McLinden MO, Nist reference fluid thermodynamic and transport properties-REFPROP, version 8 user's guide, U.S. Department of Commerce Technology Administration, National Institute of Standards and Technology, Gaithersburg, MD, April, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fitzgerald, R., Steeper, R., Snyder, J., Hanson, R. et al., "Determination of Cycle Temperatures and Residual Gas Fraction for HCCI Negative Valve Overlap Operation," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):124-141, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0343.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., "A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine," SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi:10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, J., Güralp, O., Filipi, Z., Assanis, D. et al., "New Heat Transfer Correlation for an HCCI Engine Derived from Measurements of Instantaneous Surface Heat Flux," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2996, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puranam, S. and Steeper, R., "The Effect of Acetylene on Iso-octane Combustion in an HCCI Engine with NVO," SAE Int. J. Engines 5(4):1551-1560, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1574.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl, M., Pitz, W., Sarathy, M., Yang, Y. et al., "Detailed Kinetic Modeling of Conventional Gasoline at Highly Boosted Conditions and the Associated Intermediate Temperature Heat Release," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1109, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kodavasal J, Lavoie GA, Assanis DN, Martz JB, "The effect of diluent composition on homogeneous charge compression ignition auto-ignition and combustion duration," P. Combust. Inst., 35:3019-26, 2015, doi: 10.1016/j.proci.2014.06.152.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
