<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816551</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Risks in Pensions and Retirement (Pensions)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The interplay between retirement plan funding policies, contribution volatility, and funding risk</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boyd</surname>
                  <given-names>Don</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yin</surname>
                  <given-names>Yimeng</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>49</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816551"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper examines the interplay between retirement plan funding policies, employer contribution volatility, and funding risk in an uncertain investment return environment. Using a stochastic simulation model of pension fund finances, it examines how funding policy choices affect the volatility of governmental contributions and the likelihood that plan funded ratios will fall below certain thresholds. The most-common funding policies and practices reduce contribution volatility at the expense of increasing the likelihood of low funded ratios. These policies are unlikely to bring underfunded plans to full funding within 30 years, even if investment-return assumptions are met every single year and employers make full actuarially determined contributions. For example, a 75 percent funded plan using 30-year level-percent amortization with 5-year asset smoothing (a common policy) would only reach 85 percent funding after 30 years even if it earned 7.5 percent every year. When investment returns are variable, plans and their sponsors face substantial risk of potential crises: the same plan would face a one in six chance of falling below 40 percent funding within 30 years if its investment return assumption is correct on average but has a 12 percent standard deviation. If sponsors do not pay full actuarial contributions or if reasonable expected returns are less than 7.5 percent, the risk of severe underfunding would be greater. There is no easy way out of the situation. Pension plans can de-risk, reducing the volatility of their assets and reducing the volatility of contributions. However, reducing risk almost certainly will require lowering earnings assumptions, which will drive actuarially determined contributions upward immediately.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Alan Milligan. 2013. “Annual Review of Funding Levels and Risks as of June 30, 2012.” Report for Finance and Administration Committee, March 18, 2013. California Public Employees’ Retirement System. http://www.calpers.ca.gov/eip-docs/about/pubs/employer/2012-report.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alan Milligan. 2014. “Annual Review of Funding Levels and Risks, 2014.” California Public Employees’ Retirement System.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">American Academy of Actuaries. 2014. “Objectives and Principles for Funding Public Sector Pension Plans.” Issue Brief. American Academy of Actuaries. http://www.nasra.org/files/Topical%20Reports/Funding%20Policies/Public-Plans_IB-Funding-Policy_02-18-2014.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Biggs, Andrew G. 2014. “The Public Pension Quadrilemma: The Intersection of Investment Risk and Contribution Risk.” The Journal of Retirement.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bohn, Henning. 2011. “Should Public Retirement Plans Be Fully Funded?” Journal of Pension Economics and Finance 10 (2): 195-219. doi:10.1017/S1474747211000096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Bonafede, Julia K., Steven J. Foresti, and Russell J. Walker. 2015. “2015 Report on State Retirement Systems: Funding Levels and Asset Allocation.” Wilshire Consulting.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Boyd, Donald J., and Yimeng Yin. 2016. “By The Numbers: State and Local Government Unfunded Pension Liabilities Rise by $268 Billion in the Third Quarter of 2015.” Rockefeller Institute of Government. http://www.rockinst.org/pdf/government_finance/2016-01-20_By_the_Numbers_Brief_No4.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Brown, Jeffrey R, and David W Wilcox. 2009. “Discounting State and Local Pension Liabilities.” American Economic Review 99 (2): 538-42. doi:10.1257/aer.99.2.538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Governmental Accounting Standards Board. 1994. “Statement No. 25 of the Governmental Accounting Standards Board: Financial Reporting for Defined Benefit Pension Plans and Note Disclosures for Defined Contribution Plans.” NO. 116-A. Governmental Accounting Standards Board.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">“LAGERS Forty-Fourth Comprehensive Annual Financial Report Fiscal Year Ended June 30, 2012.” 2012. Missouri Local Government Employees Retirement System. http://www.molagers.org/assets/cafr-2012.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Lenze, David G., and others. 2013. “State and Local Government Defined Benefit Pension Plans: Estimates of Liabilities and Employer Normal Costs by State, 2000-2011.” Bureau of Economic Analysis. http://192.149.12.20/papers/pdf/State-and-Local-Government-Defined-Benefit-Pension-Plans.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Maurer, Raimond, Olivia S. Mitchell, and Ralph Rogalla. 2009. “Reforming the German Civil Servant Pension Plan.” In The Future of Public Employee Retirement Systems, edited by Olivia S Mitchell and Gary J Anderson. Oxford; New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Moody’s Investors Service. 2013. “Adjustments to US State and Local Government Reported Pension Data.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Munnell, Alicia H., and Jean-Pierre Aubry. 2015. “The Funding of State and Local Pensions: 2014-2018.” SLP#45. Center for State and Local Government Excellence. http://slge.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/15-07-SLGE-Funding-of-State-and-Local-Pensions-2014-2018_web-final.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Munnell, Alicia H., Jean-Pierre Aubry, Anek Belbase, and Joshua Hurwitz. 2013. “State and Local Pension Costs: Precrisis, Post-Crisis, and Post-Reform.” Number 30. Center for Retirement Research at Boston College. http://crr.bc.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/slp_30.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Munnell, Alicia H., Jean-Pierre Aubry, and Josh Hurwitz. 2013. “How Sensitive Is Public Pension Funding to Investment Returns?” http://crr.bc.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/slp_34-508.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Novy-Marx, R., and J. Rauh. 2011. “Public Pension Promises: How Big Are They and What Are They Worth?” The Journal of Finance 66 (4): 1211-1249.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Shnitser, Natalya. 2015. “Funding Discipline for U.S. Public Pension Plans: An Empirical Analysis of Institutional Design.” Iowa Law Review 100: 663-714.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Society of Actuaries. 2014a. “Report of the Blue Ribbon Panel on Public Pension Plan Funding.” Society of Actuaries.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Society of Actuaries. 2014b. “Report of the Blue Ribbon Panel on Public Pension Plan Funding.” Society of Actuaries.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">“Statement No. 67 of the Governmental Accounting Standards Board: Financial Reporting for Pension Plans, an Amendment of GASB Statement No. 25.” 2012. Governmental Accounting Standards Board.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Risk-free returns have declined substantially but assumed returns of public pensions have not</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Prevalence of amortization methods among major public pension plans</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Open amortization methods pay down liabilities very slowly, or not at all</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Simulated returns are extremely volatile from year to year, even if assumed return is achieved at 30 years</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Employer contribution rates vary dramatically even for simulations that have the same compound average return</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Funded status varies dramatically for simulations that have the same compound average return</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Funded ratios, employer contributions, and the cumulative present value of employer contributions vary even when compound returns are the same</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Initial employer contribution rates are highest under the SOA Benchmark, and second-highest under 15-year level dollar closed amortization</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>30-year open level-percent funding has virtually no chance of an employer contribution above 30% of payroll</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Closed funding methods have a greater chance of contribution increases of more than 10% of payroll</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Median funded ratio can remain below 100% or rise substantially above, depending on funding policy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>30-year open level-percent funding runs far greater risks of severe underfunding than the other funding policies</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>A typical plan that starts out 75% funded and uses a common funding policy has more than a 50% chance of falling below 60 percent funding within 20 years</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Funding risk rises over time</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Contribution underpayment (modeled as a cap on employer contributions) has a larger impact on funded status under bad return scenarios (e.g., at the 25th percentile) than under better scenarios (e.g., at the median)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Contribution smoothing policies reduce contribution volatility but increase the risk of severe underfunding</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Funded ratio risk and contribution volatility for selected funding policies</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
