<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i23026376</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23026378</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FINANCIAL LIBERALISATION AND THE GROWTH OF THE CAPITAL MARKET IN NIGERIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>S. I.</given-names>
                  <surname>Ikhide</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>37</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23026378"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Attempts at evaluating the impact of reform measures on the financial sector in Nigeria have often focussed on the banking sub-sector. Recent studies have however been emphasising the relevance of the liberalization of the capital market sub-sector for a successful programme. This work examines the impact of policy measures such as privatisation, debt-conversion programmes, interest rate deregulation, regulatory and taxation reforms on the institution and asset-pricing characteristics of the capital market. The results show that there is a significant improvement in these characteristics for the period immediately following the implementation of the programmes, although this has not been sustained for the post-reform period. Thus, the paper concludes that the observed changes could not have resulted from any internal, fundamental reforms of the capital market per se and suggests the need to design policies that will target this sector of the economy. Les efforts pour évaluer l'impact mesures de réforme sur le sous-secteur financier au Nigéria ont été centrés sur le sous-secteur bancaire. Cependant, des études récentes mettent l'accent sur la pertinence de la libéralisation du sous-secteur du marché de capital comme un programme couronné de succès. Ce travail étudie l'impact des mesures politiques, á savoir, les privatisations, les programmes de conversion de dettes, le déréglage des taux d'intérêt, d'intérêt, des réformes de réglage et de charges fiscales sur l'institution et les caractéristiques d'évaluation des actifs du marché de capital. Les résultats moutrent que, pour période la suivant de trés près la mise en pratique des programmes, il y a une amélioration significative en ce qui concerne ces caractéristiques, même si ceci n'a pas été soutenu pour la période après la reforme. Donc, l'article conclut que les changements constatés ne proviennent nullement des réformes internes et fondamentales du marché de capital en tant que tel, et suggère qu'il est nécessaire d'élaborer des systèmes visant ce secteur de l'économie.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d757e190a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e194" publication-type="other">
Akingbohungbe, S. (1994): 'Meeting the Registration Requirements of the Securities and Exchange Commission',
Securities and Exchange Monthly (SEC, Lagos).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e204a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e208" publication-type="other">
Bhattacharyay, B. (1988): 'Development of Financial Infrastructure: An International Comparison', Saving and
Development, 4(XII).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e218a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e222" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria, CBN (1992): Annual Report and Statement of Accounts, December.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e229a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e233" publication-type="other">
Cho, Yoon Je (1986): 'Inefficiencies from Financial Liberalization in the Absence of Well-Functioning Equity
Markets', Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, 18(2): 191-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e244a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e248" publication-type="other">
Cottani, J. and D. Cavallo (1993): 'Financial Reform and Liberalization' in Policymaking in the Open Economy,
Concepts and Case Studies in Economic Perfomance, ed. Rudiger Dornbusch.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e258a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e262" publication-type="other">
Dornbusch, R. and A. Reynoso (1993): 'Financial Factors in Economic Development', in Policymaking in the Open
Economy: Concepts and Case Studies in Economic Performance, ed. by Rudiger Dornbusch.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e272a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e276" publication-type="other">
Elbadawi, I.A., G. Dhaneshaw and G. Uwujaren (1992): 'Why Sub-Saharan African has not succeeded in the
Structural Adjustment Programme', World Bank, Policy Research Working Papers, WPS 1000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e290" publication-type="other">
Fry Maxwell, J. (1988):Money, Interest and Banking in Economic Development, The John Hopkins University Press,
Baltimore and London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e304" publication-type="other">
Ikhide, S. I. (1995): 'Financial Sector Reforms and the Growth of the Capital Market in Nigeria', Institute of Developing
Economies, Tokyo, Japan (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e318" publication-type="other">
Ikhide, S.I. and A. Alawode (1995): Financial Sector Reforms, Banking Crisis and the Order of Economic
Liberalization', World Development (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e333" publication-type="other">
McKinnon, R. (1973): Money and Capital in Economic Development, Washington DC, Brookings Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e340a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e344" publication-type="other">
Modigliani. F. and M. Miller (1958): The Cost of Capital, Corporation Finance and The Theory of Investment',
American Economic Review, 48 (June): pp. 261-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e354a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e358" publication-type="other">
Molho, L.E. (1986): Interest Rates, Savings and Investment in Developing Countries: A Re-examination of the
McKinnon-Shaw Hypotheses, IMF Staff Papers Vol. 33, No. 1: pp. 90-116.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e372" publication-type="other">
Ojo, M. 0. (1993): A Review and Appraisal of Nigeria's Experience with Financial Sector Reform', Research
Department Occasional Paper No. 8, Central Bank of Nigeria, August.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e386" publication-type="other">
Oriole, D. and A. Falokun (1994): 'Financial Liberalization and the Financing Strategies of Corporate Firms in
Nigeria', Final Project Report submitted to the African Economic Research Consortium, Nairobi, Kenya.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e400" publication-type="other">
Popiel, P. (1990): 'Developing Financial Markets in Sub-Saharan Africa' Financial Systems and Development in
Africa, in Phillip Callier (ed). EDI Seminar Series, World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e411a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e415" publication-type="other">
Popiel, P. (1994): Financial Systems in Sub-Saharan Africa: A Comparative Study, World Bank Discussion Papers
260: Africa Technical Department Series.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e429" publication-type="other">
Shaw, E. (1973): Financial Deepening in Economic Development, New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e440" publication-type="other">
Sundararajan, V. (1987): The Debt-Equity Ratio of Firms and the Effectiveness of Interest Rate Policy, IMF Staff
Papers, Vol. 34, No. 2 (June).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e454" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J. and A. Weiss (1981): 'Credit Rationing in Markets with Imperfect Information', American Economic
Review, Vol. 71, No. 3 (June).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e464a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e468" publication-type="other">
Versluysen, E. (1988): 'Financial Deregulation and The Globalisation of Capital Markets', PPR Working Papers,
WPS 40, World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d757e478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d757e482" publication-type="other">
Versluysen, E. (1989): A Review of Alternative Debt Strategies', PPR Working Papers, World Bank, Washington
DC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


