<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277556</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis of Thermodynamic Characteristics of Diesel Engine Emission Control Strategies Using a Multi-Zone Combustion Model</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Poetsch</surname>
                  <given-names>Christoph</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Virtual Vehicle</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ofner</surname>
                  <given-names>Herwig</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AVL LIST GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cartellieri</surname>
                  <given-names>Wolfgang</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>AVL LIST GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1498</fpage>
         <lpage>1523</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277556"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The paper describes a zero-dimensional crank angle resolved combustion model which was developed for the analysis and prediction of combustion in compression ignition (CI) engines. The model relies on the multi zone combustion model (MZCM) approach of Hiroyasu. The main sub-models were taken from literature and extended with additional features described in this paper.</p>
            <p>A special procedure described in a previous paper is used to identify the mechanisms of the combustion process on the basis of the measured cylinder pressure trace. Based on the identified mechanisms the present work concentrates on the analysis of the causal effects that predominantly control the combustion process and the formation of NOx and Soot. The focus lies on the changes of the thermodynamic states and the composition of the reaction zones caused by different emission control strategies.</p>
            <p>Finally this knowledge is applied to predict the characteristics of cycle related data such as thermal efficiency, process temperatures, pressures and combustion emissions as function of changes in engine settings. Based on this data procedures for minimization of fuel consumption and emissions are discussed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hrauda, G., Strasser, R., Aschaber, M.: Gas Exchange Simulation from Concept to Start of Production - AVL's Tool Chain in the Engine Development Process, THIESEL, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, D. and Assanis, D., “Multi-Zone DI Diesel Spray Combustion Model for Cycle Simulation Studies of Engine Performance and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1246, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-1246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger, R., Klell, M., Sams, T.: Thermodynamik der Verbrennungskraftmaschine, Springer, Wien, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., Kadota, T., Arai, M.: Development and Use of a Spray Combustion Modeling to Predict Diesel Engine Efficiency and Pollutant Emissions, Part I: Combustion Modeling, Bulletin of the JSME, Vol. 26, pp.569-575, 1983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reinhardt, H.: Modellierung des Zündverzuges bei Mehrfacheinspritzungen aufgeladener Dieselmotoren mit Direkteinspritzung innerhalb der thermodynamischen Prozessrechnung. Abschlussbericht. FVV Heft 870, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stiesch, G.: Modeling Engine Spray and Combustion Processes. Springer, Berlin, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krueger, C.: Validierung eines 1D-Spraymodells zur Simulation der Gemischbildung in direkteinpritzenden Dieselmotoren. Dissertation, Aachen, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, C. and Hountalas, D., “Development and Validation of a 3- D Multi-Zone Combustion Model for the Prediction of DI Diesel Engines Performance and Pollutants Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 981021, 1998, doi: 10.4271/981021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borman, G. and Johnson, J., “Unsteady Vaporization Histories and Trajectories of Fuel Drops Injected into Swirling Air,” SAE Technical Paper 620271, 1962, doi: 10.4271/620271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gosman, A. and Johns, R., “Computer Analysis of Fuel-Air Mixing in Direct-Injection Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 800091, 1980, doi: 10.4271/800091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B.: Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. McGraw- Hill, 1989</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, F., Srinivas, S., Reitz, R. D., Foster, D. E.: Comparison of Three Soot Models Applied to Multi-Dimensional Diesel Combustion Simulations, JSME International, Series B, Vol 48, No. 4, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser- Sheet Imaging*,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hountalas, D., Lamaris, V., Pariotis, E., and Ofner, H., “Parametric Study Based on a Phenomenological Model to Investigate the Effect of Post Fuel Injection on HDDI Diesel Engine Performance and Emissions-Model Validation Using Experimental Data,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0641, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0641.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schubiger, R. A., Boulouchos, K. Eberle, M. K.: Rußbildung und Oxidation bei der dieselmotorischen Verbrennung, MTZ Fachartikel 05/2002, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertola, A. and Boulouchos, K., “Oxygenated Fuels for Particulate Emissions Reduction in Heavy-Duty DI-Diesel Engines with Common- Rail Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2885, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-2885.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., “A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi: 10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woschni, G., Einfluß von Rußablagerungen auf den Wärmeübergang zwischen Arbeitsgas und Wand im Dieselmotor, in proceedings to ‘Der Arbeitsprozeß des Verbrennungsmotors’, Graz 1991</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AVL List GmbH. BOOST Interfaces Manual, v2009 Edition, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hountalas, D., Lamaris, V., and Pariotis, E., “Identification of the Error Introduced in DI Diesel Engine Phenomenological Multi-Zone Models from Assumptions Related to the Initial Conditions at the Nozzle Exit,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0153, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allmer, I., Petutschnig, H., Sams, T.: Modellbasiertes Thermomanagement zur Verbrauchs- und Emissionsoptimierung für NFZ-Anwendungen. Der Arbeisprozess des Verbrennungsmotors, Graz 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poetsch, C., Ofner, H., and Schutting, E., “Assessment of a Multi Zone Combustion Model for Analysis and Prediction of CI Engine Combustion and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1439, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1439.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sams, T., Glensvig, M., Theissl, H.: Arbeitsprozess des Verbrennungsmotors 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Varde, K., Popa, D., and Varde, L., “Spray Angle and Atomization in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 841055, 1984, doi: 10.4271/841055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolfer, H.: Der Zündverzug im Dieselmotor. VDI Forschungsheft Nr. 392, 1938</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
