<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277694</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investigation of Key Mechanisms for Liquid Length Fluctuations in Transient Vaporizing Diesel Sprays</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaclyn</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ge</surname>
                  <given-names>Hai-Wen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ESI Mindware Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Naber</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeffrey</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Seong-Young</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kurtz</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Co</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Robarge</surname>
                  <given-names>Nan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Co</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1202</fpage>
         <lpage>1212</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277694"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Diesel combustion and emissions formation is spray and mixing controlled and understanding spray parameters is key to determining the impact of fuel injector operation and nozzle design on combustion and emissions. In this study, both spray visualization and computational fluid dynamics (CFD) modeling were undertaken to investigate key mechanisms for liquid length fluctuations. For the experimental portion of this study a common rail piezoelectric injector was tested in an optically accessible constant volume combustion vessel. Liquid penetration of the spray was determined via processing of images acquired from Mie back scattering under vaporizing conditions by injecting into a charge gas at elevated temperature with a 0% oxygen environment. Tests were undertaken at a gas density of 34.8 kg/m³, 2000 bar injection pressure, and at ambient temperatures of 900, 1100, and 1300 K. Under these conditions there are noticeable fluctuations in liquid phase penetration once the steady state liquid length has been established, on the order of 10% of the mean liquid length. These fluctuations in penetration were seen in each plume. An analysis of the experimental data, along with CFD modeling of the liquid spray is undertaken to identify the key mechanisms for liquid length fluctuations. Results are presented comparing experimental and CFD results of the liquid spray and its fluctuations, including a quantification of fluctuation magnitude. Based on the experimental and CFD analysis it is concluded that a key mechanism for liquid length fluctuations in a transient diesel spray is due to spray induced turbulent eddies near the edge of spray plume.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Caton, J.A., Musculus, M.P.B., and Lutz, A.E., “Evaluation of the Equivalence Ratio-Temperature Region of Diesel Soot Precursor Formation using a Two- Stage Lagrangian Model,” International Journal of Engine Research 7: 349-370, 2006, doi: 10.1243/14680874JER00606.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, J., Naber, J., Lee, S., Kurtz, E. et al., “Investigation of Diesel Liquid Spray Penetration Fluctuations under Vaporizing Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0455, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0455.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., Mueller, C., and Siebers, D., “Measurements of Fuel Effects on Liquid-Phase Penetration in DI Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0519, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0519.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kurvers, C. and Luijten, C., “Real Gas Effects in Siebers' Mixing- Limited Spray Vaporization Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1497, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1497.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Som, S., and Longman, D.E., “Numerical Study Comparing the Combustion and Emission Characteristics of Biodiesel to Petrodiesel,” Energy and Fuels 25(4):1373-1386, 2011, doi: 10.1021/ef101438u.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, R. “Penetration and Dispersion Research of Non- Reacting Evaporating Diesel Sprays,” Master's thesis, Mechanical Engineering Department, Eindhoven University of Technology, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crua, C., “Combustion Processes in a Diesel Engine,” Ph.D thesis, School of Engineering, University of Brighton, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Kook, S., and Williams, T., “Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool-Flame, Ignition, High-Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High-Speed Imaging,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 439-459, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arora, R.A., Morgan, C.J., Naber, J.D., and Lee, S.-Y., “Flash Boiling Spray Characterization of a Gasoline Multi-Hole Injector in a Heated Pressure Vessel,” Proceedings of the 2011 ILASS Americas 23rd Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems Paper No. 162, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nesbitt, J.E., “Diesel Spray Mixing Limited Vaporization with Non- Ideal and Multi-Component Fuel Thermophysical Property Effects,” Ph.D thesis, Mechanical Engineering Department, Michigan Technological University, Houghton, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nesbitt, J.E., Naber, J.D., Lee, S.Y., Kurtz, E., Robarge, N., and Ge, H.W., “Investigation of Vaporizing Diesel Liquid Spray Plume to Plume Penetration Variations,” Proceedings of the 2011 ILASS Americas 23rd Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems Paper No. 131, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z.Y., and Reitz, R. D., “Turbulence Modeling of Internal Combustion Engines Using RNG κ-ε Models,” Combustion Science and Technology 106: 267-295, 1995, doi: 10.1080/00102209508907782.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pomraning, E., and Rutland, C.J., “Dynamic One-Equation Nonviscosity Large-Eddy Simulation Model,” AIAA Journal 40(4):689-701, 2002, doi: 10.2514/2.1701.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R.D., “Modeling Atomization Processes in High- Pressure Vaporizing Sprays,” Atomization and Spray Technology 3:309-337, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patterson, M. and Reitz, R., “Modeling the Effects of Fuel Spray Characteristics on Diesel Engine Combustion and Emission,” SAE Technical Paper 980131, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, D. P., and Rutland, C. J., “A New Droplet Collision Algorithm,” Journal of Computational Physics 164(1):62-80, 2000, doi: 10.1006/jcph.2000.6568.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richards, K. J., Senecal, P. K., and Pomraning, E., CONVERGE™ (Version 1.3), Computer Software, Convergent Science, Inc., Middleton, WI, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blessing, M., König, G., Krüger, C., Michels, U. et al., “Analysis of Flow and Cavitation Phenomena in Diesel Injection Nozzles and Its Effects on Spray and Mixture Formation,” SAE Technical Paper a2003-01-1358, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1358.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martynov, S., “Numerical Simulation of the Cavitation Process in Diesel Fuel Injectors”, Ph.D. Thesis, University of Brighton, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bharadwaj, N., Rutland, C.J., Chang, S., “Large Eddy Simulation Modelling of Spray-Induced Turbulence Effects,” International Journal of Engine Research 10: 97-119, 2009, doi: 10.1243/14680874JER02309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., Ge, H., and Reitz, R., “Validation of Meshand Timestep- Independent Spray Models for Multi-Dimensional Engine CFD Simulation,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):277-302, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0626.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
