<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277942</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of NOx Production Rate in Diesel Combustion Based on Measurement of Time Histories of NOx Concentrations and Flame Temperature</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nada</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuzuru</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Komatsubara</surname>
                  <given-names>Yusuke</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pham</surname>
                  <given-names>Thang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoshii</surname>
                  <given-names>Fumiya</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kidoguchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yoshiyuki</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>The University of Tokushima</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>January 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277910</issue-id>
         <fpage>303</fpage>
         <lpage>313</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International and Copyright © 2014 SAE Japan</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277942"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In this study, we evaluated NOx production rates of diesel combustions occurred in a constant volume chamber of a rapid compression machine in order to investigate relationship between flame behaviors and NOx emissions. A total gas sampling device was used to measure the NOx concentration in total gases existing in the chamber at a designated time. An EINOx (Emission Index of NOx) production rate was evaluated on the time history of NOx concentration. Temporal temperature distributions in the chamber were measured with a high speed 2-color thermometry. Gas oil (JIS #2) was used as the fuel. The EINOx production rate increases with increasing injection pressure through temperature rises in flames due to enhanced mixing of fuel vapor with ambient air. An increase in the ambient pressure causes overlaps between flames formed around the nozzle, which reduces the flame temperature. Nevertheless, high reactant concentrations resulting from the elevated ambient pressure slightly increase the net EINOx production rate. A reduction of number of injection holes decreases the total surface area of flames formed in the chamber, and then decreasing the EINOx production rate. In this study, the EINOx production rate was modeled in terms of the ambient air density, flame volume and reaction rate coefficient of an elementary reaction in the Zel'dovich mechanism. There is a correlation between the results obtained from the prediction model and the EINOx production rate even though a large derivation remains in the result obtained under the high ambient pressure condition.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamimoto, T. and Kobayashi, H., “Combustion Processes in Diesel Engines” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 17:163-189, 1991, doi:10.1016/0360-1285(91)90019-J.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kohketsu, S., Mori, K., Kato, T., and Sakai, K., “Technology for Low Emission, Combustion Noise and Fuel Consumption on Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 940672, 1994, doi:10.4271/940672.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakisaka, Y., Hotta, Y., Inayoshi, M., Nakakita, K. et al., “Emissions Reduction Potential of Extremely High Boost and High EGR Rate for an HSDI Diesel Engine and the Reduction Mechanisms of Exhaust Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):611-623, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fischer, S. and Stein, J., “Investigation on the Effect of Very High Fuel Injection Pressure on Soot-NOx Emissions at High Load in a Passenger Car Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1737- 1748, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shundoh, S., Kakegawa, T., Tsujimura, K., and Kobayashi, S., “The Effect of Injection Parameters and Swirl on Diesel Combustion with High Pressure Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 910489, 1991, doi:10.4271/910489.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoyagi, Y., Kunishima, E., Asaumi, Y., Aihara, Y. et al., “Diesel Combustion and Emission Using High Boost and High Injection Pressure in a Single Cylinder Engine: Effects of Boost Pressure and Timing Retardation on Thermal Efficiency and Exhaust Emissions” Int. J. JSME series B 48(4):648-655, 2005, doi:10.1299/jsmeb.48.648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montgomery, D., Chan, M., Chang, C., Farrell, P. et al., “Effect of Injector Nozzle Hole Size and Number on Spray Characteristics and the Performance of a Heavy Duty D.I. Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 962002, 1996, doi:10.4271/962002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Canaan, R., “PLIF Imaging of NO Formation in a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 980147, 1998, doi:10.4271/980147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging*,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rao, V. and Honnery, D., “A Comparison of Two NOx Prediction Schemes for use in Diesel Engine Thermodynamic Modelling” Fuel 107:662-670, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.01.071.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donahue, R., Borman, G., and Bower, G., “Cylinder-Averaged Histories of Nitrogen Oxide in a D.I. Diesel with Simulated Turbocharging,” SAE Technical Paper 942046, 1994, doi:10.4271/942046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, S., Mohammadi, A., Kidoguchi, Y., and Miwa, K., “Effects of Aromatic Hydrocarbons on Fuel Decomposition and Oxidation Processes in Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01- 2086, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, S., Mohammadi, A., Hirano, H., Kidoguchi, Y. et al., “Experimental Study on Combustion Characteristics and Emissions Reduction of Emulsified Fuels in Diesel Combustion Using a Rapid Compression Machine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1792, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1792.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hottel, H. C. and Broughton F. P., “Determination of True Temperature and Total Radiation from Luminous Gas Flames” Industrial and Engineering Chemistry 4(2):166-174, 1932, doi:10.1021/ac50078a004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turns, S. R. and Myhr, F. H., “Oxides of Nitrogen Emissions from Turbulent Jet Flames: Part I-Fuel Effects and Flame Radiation” Combust. Flame 87:319-335, 1991, doi:10.1016/0010- 2180(91)90116-S.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rajalingam, B. and Farrell, P., “The Effect of Injection Pressure on Air Entrainment into Transient Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0523, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0523.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Easley, W., Mellor, A., and Plee, S., “NO Formation and Decomposition Models for DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0582, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0582.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Psota, M. and Mellor, A., “Dynamic Application of a Skeletal Mechanism for DI Diesel NOX Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1984, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
