<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277610</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Design Features on Dynamic Characteristics of VCC Piston for I. C. Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dong</surname>
                  <given-names>Jian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ouyang</surname>
                  <given-names>Lin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhou</surname>
                  <given-names>Yue</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>He</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuhai</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pan</surname>
                  <given-names>Qingchuan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Wuhan Univ of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>209</fpage>
         <lpage>216</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277610"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>VCC (variable combustion chamber) piston technology would be one of the best substitutes for VCR (variable compression ratio) technology due to its extremely fast dynamic response with simple structure. One of the key issues of VCC piston technology is its dynamic response, which means fast, timely and enough variation of the combustion chamber volume during combustion in each working cycle while excess in-cylinder pressure occurs.</p>
            <p>Two key design features, ball-profiles and a reset cam, are introduced in order to ensure the availability of transient dynamic characteristics of VCC piston. Several formulas are derived from the structural analysis on VCC piston to describe the relationship between VCC piston design and its dynamic characteristics.</p>
            <p>By means of ADAMS dynamic simulation, the affecting factors on the dynamic characteristics of VCC piston, including stiffness, friction, damping, contacting conditions and engine working conditions, are investigated, and the effects of pre-tightening force and the design features on the dynamic response are also investigated.</p>
            <p>The research indicates that (1) the dynamic response of VCC piston is very fast due to the design features of both ball-profiles and reset cam, and (2) by means of VCC displacement (the relative movement between the piston crown and the piston skirt), excessive in-cylinder pressure would be limited effectively in each working cycle while a spark-ignition engine running with higher CR (compression ratio), and (3) the dynamic response of VCC piston can be improved by reducing the pre-tightening force of the disc springs properly.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS:</label>
            <kwd>variable combustion chamber (VCC)</kwd>
            <kwd>variable compression ratio (VCR)</kwd>
            <kwd>dynamic characteristics</kwd>
            <kwd>dynamic response</kwd>
            <kwd>internal combustion engine</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dong J., Ouyang, L., Zhou, Y., and Pan, Q., “Study on Variable Combustion Chamber (VCC) Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1607, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Will, F. and Mayson, D., “Combustion Simulations for a Self Controlling Variable Compression Ratio Connecting Rod,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1154, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roberts, M., “Benefits and Challenges of Variable Compression Ratio (VCR),” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0398, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0398.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rabhi, V., Beroff, J., and Dionnet, F., “Study of a Gear-Based Variable Compression Ratio Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2931, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christoph Bollig, Stolberg, et al. Combustion engine having a variable compression ratio[p]. US patent 5595146.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wittek, K., Tiemann, C., and Pischinger, S., “Two-Stage Variable Compression Ratio with Eccentric Piston Pin and Exploitation of Crank Train Forces,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1304-1313, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1457</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LARSEN GREGORY J, et al. Reciprocating piston engine with a varying compression ratio[P]. US Patent 5025757,1991.06</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">anaka, Y., Hiyoshi, R., Takemura, S., Ikeda, Y. et al., “A Study of a Compression Ratio Control Mechanism for a Multiple-Link Variable Compression Ratio Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3547, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sato, Y., Masahiko, K., and Masayuki, H., “A Study Concerning Booming Noise of a Multi-link Type Variable Compression Ratio Engine,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 2(1):832-840, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0772</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishikawa, S., Kadota, M., Yoshida, K., Takahashi, K. et al., “Advanced Design of Variable Compression Ratio Engine with Dual Piston Mechanism,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):982-990, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Bortoli Cassiani, M., Bittencourt, M., Galli, L., and Villalva, S., “Variable Compression Ratio Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-36-0245, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-36-0245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dong Jian, Li Gesheng, Ouyang, L., et al. Improved Variable Compression Ratio Piston in Internal Combustion Engine [P], Chinese Patent CN102364076A, 2012.02</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jian, Dong, Gesheng, Li, Qijiagn, Luo, et al. Telescopic Piston in Internal Combustion Engine. Chinese Patent CN1719012, 2005.08.27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jian, Dong, Gesheng, Li, Zhixiang, Pan, et al. Variable Compression Ratio Piston in Internal Combustion Engine. Chinese Patent CN101900056A, 2010.07.27</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jian, Dong, Gesheng, Li, Zhixiang, Pan, et al. Improved Variable Compression Ratio Piston in Internal Combustion Engine. Chinese Patent CN102269076 2011.06.29</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
