<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278124</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of n-Butanol and Isobutanol on Particulate Matter Emissions from a Euro 6 Direct-injection Spark Ignition Engine During Laboratory and on-Road Tests</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vojtisek-Lom</surname>
                  <given-names>Michal</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Czech Technical University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Beranek</surname>
                  <given-names>Vit</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Czech Technical University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Stolcpartova</surname>
                  <given-names>Jitka</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute of Experimental Medicine, AVCR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pechout</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Technical University of Liberec</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Klir</surname>
                  <given-names>Vojtech</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Czech Technical University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>November 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278095</issue-id>
         <fpage>2338</fpage>
         <lpage>2350</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278124"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>N-butanol and isobutanol are alcohols that can be produced from biomass by fermentation and are possibly more compatible with existing engines than ethanol. This work reports on the effects of these two isomers on exhaust emissions of an unmodified direct injection spark ignition (DISI) engine. A Ford Focus car with a 1.0-liter Euro 6 Ecoboost DISI engine has been tested on a chassis dynamometer using WLTP and Artemis driving cycles, and on the road on a one-hour test loop containing urban, rural and motorway driving. Two isomers of butanol, 1-butanol and 2-methyl-propanol, were each blended with gasoline at 25% volume. Non-oxygenated gasoline and 15% ethanol in gasoline (E15) were used as reference fuels.</p>
            <p>The vehicle performed well in terms of cold start, drivability, general performance, and off-cycle particle emissions, staying within several mg of particle mass and about 2×10<sup>12</sup>particles (per PMP procedure) per km during laboratory tests. While E15 had little effect, both butanol blends have decreased PN emissions by about one half; effects on other pollutants were less consistent or not significant. Only roughly one half of particles was larger than 23 nm, and of these, only about half were non-volatile. Particle emissions during real driving were unevenly distributed, were not excessively different from the Artemis cycle, and were highest for gasoline, lower for E15, lower for 25% n-butanol, and lowest for 25% isobutanol, with most of the reductions taking place during high-power operation.</p>
            <p>Overall, both n-butanol and isobutanol blends yielded a considerable reduction in particle number emissions relative to both gasoline and E15.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, L., Tan, E.C.D., McCormick, R.L., Zhang, M. et al., “Technoeconomic analysis and life-cycle assessment of cellulosic isobutanol and comparison with cellulosic ethanol and n-butanol,” Biofuels Bioprod. Biorefin. 8(1): 30-48, 2014, doi:10.1002/bbb.1431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue, C., Zhao, X.Q., Liu, C.G., Chen, L.J. and Bai F.W., “Prospective and development of butanol as an advanced biofuel,” Biotechnol Adv. 31(8): 1575-84, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.biotechadv.2013.08.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cascone, R. “Biobutanol: a replacement for bioethanol?” Chem. Eng. Prog. 104(4)” S4-S9, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patakova, P., Maxa, D., Rychtera, M., Linhova, L. et al., “Perspectives of biobutanol production and use,” in Biofuel's engineering process technology, ed. Bernandes M.A.D.S., 243-266, 2011, InTech, Rijeka, Croatia, doi:10.5772/961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karavalakis, G., Short, D., Vu, D., Russell, R. L. et al., “The impact of ethanol and iso-butanol blends on gaseous and particulate emissions from two passenger cars equipped with spray-guided and wall-guided direct injection SI (spark ignition) engines,” Energy. in print: 2015, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2015.01.023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stansfield, P., Bisordi, A., OudeNijeweme, D., Williams, J. et al., “The Performance of a Modern Vehicle on a Variety of Alcohol-Gasoline Fuel Blends,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):813-822, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012- 01-1272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szwaja, S. and Naber, J. D. “Combustion of n-butanol in a sparkignition SI engine,” Fuel, 89(7): 1573-1582, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2009.08.043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dernotte, J., Mounaim-Rousselle, C., Halter, F. and Seers, P., “Evaluation of butanol-gasoline blends in a port fuel-injection, sparkignition engine,” Oil Gas Sci. Technol. - Rev. IFP 65(2): 345-351, 2010, doi:10.2516/ogst/2009034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gu, X., Huang, Z., Cai, J., Gong, J. and Lee, Ch., “Emission characteristics of a spark-ignition engine fuelled with gasoline-nbutanol blends in combination with EGR,” Fuel 93(1): 611-617, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2011.11.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wigg, B., Coverdill, R., Lee, C., and Kyritsis, D., “Emissions Characteristics of Neat Butanol Fuel Using a Port Fuel-Injected, Spark-Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0902, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0902.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallner, T. and Frazee, R., “Study of Regulated and Non-Regulated Emissions from Combustion of Gasoline, Alcohol Fuels and their Blends in a DI-SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1571, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1571.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thewes, M., Muther, M., Brassat, A., Pischinger, S. et al., “Analysis of the Effect of Bio-Fuels on the Combustion in a Downsized DI SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):274-288, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pechout, M., Dittrich, A., and Vojtisek-Lom, M., “Operation of an Ordinary PFI Engine on n-butanol and Iso-butanol and Their Blends with Gasoline,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2618, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2618.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersen, V.F., Anderson, J.E., Wallington, T.J., Mueller, S.A. et al., “Vapor Pressures of Alcohol-Gasoline Blends,” Energ. Fuel. 24(6): 3647-3654, 2010, doi:10.1021/ef100254w.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aleiferis P.G. and van Romunde Z.R., “An analysis of spray development with iso-octane, n-pentane, gasoline, ethanol and n-butanol from a multi-hole injector under hot fuel conditions,” Fuel 105: 143-168, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.07.044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merola, S., Tornatore, C., Valentino, G., Marchitto, L. et al., “Optical Investigation of the Effect on the Combustion Process of Butanol- Gasoline Blend in a PFI SI Boosted Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0057, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tornatore C., Marchitto L., Valentino G., Corcione F.E. et al., “Optical diagnostics of the combustion process in a PFI SI boosted engine fueled with butanol-gasoline blend,” Energy 45(1): 277-287, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2012.03.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vojtisek-Lom, M., Pechout, M., and Mazac, M., “Real-World On-Road Exhaust Emissions from an Ordinary Gasoline Car Operated on E85 and on Butanol-Gasoline Blend,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0102, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Regalbuto, C., Pennisi, M., Wigg, B., and Kyritsis, D., “Experimental Investigation of Butanol Isomer Combustion in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1271, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karavalakis, G., Short, D., Vu, D., Villela, M. et al., “Evaluating the regulated emissions, air toxics, ultrafine particles, and black carbon from SI-PFI and SI-DI vehicles operating on different ethanol and iso-butanol blends,” Fuel 128: 410-421, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2014.03.016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ratcliff, M.A., Luecke, J., Williams, A., Christensen, E. et al., “Impact of higher alcohols blended in gasoline on light-duty vehicle exhaust emissions,” Environ. Sci. Technol. 47(23), 13865-13872, 2013, doi:10.1021/es402793p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, E., Yanowitz, J., Ratcliff, M. and McCormick, R. L., “Renewable oxygenate blending effects on gasoline properties,” Energ. Fuel. 25(10), 4723-4733, 2011, doi:10.1021/ef2010089.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tornatore C., Irimescu A., Marchitto L., Merola S. S. and Valentino G. “Combustion Process Analysis in a DISI Engine Fuelled with N-Butanol through UV-VIS Emission Spectroscopy,” IJET 7(3): 242-248, 2015, doi:10.7763/IJET.2015.V7.799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Irimescu, A., Marchitto, L., Merola, S.S., Tornatore, C. and Valentino, G., “Combustion process investigations in an optically accessible DISI engine fuelled with n-butanol during part load operation,” Renew. Energ. 77, 363-376, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.renene.2014.12.029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pechout, M., Trnka, M., Novotny, M. and Vojtisek, M., “Adaptation of Small Spark Ignition Engine to Alcohol Fuels,” Listy Cukrovarnicke a Reparske, 130(7-8): 262-267. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polcar, A., Cupera, J. and Sedlak, P., “Exhaust emissions of sparkignition engine fuelled by E85,” Listy Cukrovarnicke a Reparske, 130(4): 149-153, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United Nations Economic Commission for Europe (UNECE) Working Group 29, materials online at https://www2.unece.org/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=2523179 and http://www.unece.org/trans/main/welcwp29.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andre, M., “The ARTEMIS European driving cycles for measuring car pollutant emissions,” Sci. Total Environt, 334-335:73-84, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.scitotenv.2004.04.070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DieselNet - driving cycle defitions. Online at https://www.dieselnet.com/standards/cycles/wltp.php and https://www.dieselnet.com/standards/cycles/artemis.php</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vojtisek-Lom, M., “Assessment of Low Levels of Particulate Matter Exhaust Emissions Using Low-Cost Ionization-Type Smoke Detectors,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0168, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0168.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park K., Cao F., Kittelson D.B., McMurry P.H.: Relationship between Particle Mass and Mobility for Diesel Exhaust Particles. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2003, 37, 577-583.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park K., Cao F., Kittelson D.B., McMurry P.H.: Structural Properties of Diesel Exhaust Particles Measured by Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM): Relationships to Particle Mass and Mobility, Aerosol Science and Technology, 38:9, 2004, 881-889, DOI: 10.1080/027868290505189</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burtscher H.: Physical characterization of particulate emissions from diesel engines: a review. Aerosol Science 36 (2005) 896-932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rissler J., Abdulhamid H., Pagels J., Nilsson P., ati M., Boghard M.: Mass-mobility relationship of soot generator and diesel soot. European Aerosol Conference 2009, Karlsruhe, Abstract T083A09, http://www. gaef.de/eac2009/EAC2009abstracts/T08%20High%20temperature%20 aerosols/T083A09.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mamakos A., Gieschaskiel B., Drossinos Y., Lesuer D., Martini D., Krasenbrink A.: Calibration and Modeling of PMP compliant Condensation Particle Counters. European Commission Joint Research Center, Institute for Energy and Transport document JRC 67661, EUR 25145 EN, ISBN 978-92-79-22610-6, 2011, http://publications. jrc.ec.europa.eu/repository/bitstream/JRC67661/reqno_jrc67661_calibration%20and%20modeling%20of%20pmp-compliant%20 condensation%20particle%20counters%20_%20online%20version.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Bergmann A.: Validation of 14 used, recalibrated and new TSI 3790 condensation particle counters according to the UN-ECE Regulation 83. Journal ofAerosolScience 42(2011)195-203.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Price, P., Twiney, B., Stone, R., Kar, K. et al., “Particulate and Hydrocarbon Emissions from a Spray Guided Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine with Oxygenate Fuel Blends,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0472, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen L., Stone R., Richardson D.: A study of mixture preparation and PM emissions using a direct injectionengine fuelled with stoichiometric gasoline/ethanol blends. Fuel 96 (2012) 120-130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
