<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">84</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">291</issue>
         <issue-id>i24488615</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/24488643</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FINITE ELEMENT ERROR ESTIMATES ON THE BOUNDARY WITH APPLICATION TO OPTIMAL CONTROL</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>THOMAS</given-names>
                  <surname>APEL</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>JOHANNES</given-names>
                  <surname>PFEFFERER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>ARND</given-names>
                  <surname>RÖSCH</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>33</fpage>
         <lpage>70</lpage>
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24488643"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper is concerned with the discretization of linear elliptic partial differential equations with Neumann boundary condition in polygonal domains. The focus is on the derivation of error estimates in the L²-norm on the boundary for linear finite elements. Whereas common techniques yield only suboptimal results, a new approach in this context is presented which allows for quasi-optimal ones, i.e., for domains with interior angles smaller than 2π/3 a convergence order two (up to a logarithmic factor) can be achieved using quasi-uniform meshes. In the presence of internal angles greater than 2π/3 which reduce the convergence rates on quasi-uniform meshes, graded meshes are used to maintain the quasi-optimal error bounds. This result is applied to linear-quadratic Neumann boundary control problems with pointwise inequality constraints on the control. The approximations of the control are piecewise constant. The state and the adjoint state are discretized by piecewise linear finite elements. In a postprocessing step approximations of the continuous optimal control are constructed which possess superconvergence properties. Based on the improved error estimates on the boundary and optimal regularity in weighted Sobolev spaces almost second order convergence is proven for the approximations of the continuous optimal control problem. Mesh grading techniques are again used for domains with interior angles greater than 2π/3. A certain regularity of the active set is assumed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d3633e168a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e175" publication-type="other">
Thomas Apel, Johannes Pfefferer, and Arnd Rosch, Finite element error estimates for Neu-
mann boundary control problems on graded meshes, Comput. Optim. Appl. 52 (2012), no. 1,
3-28, DOI 10.1007/sl0589-011-9427-x. MR2925763</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e188a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e195" publication-type="other">
Thomas Apel, Arnd Rosch, and Dieter Sirch, L°°-error estimates on graded meshes with
application to optimal control, SIAM J. Control Optim. 48 (2009), no. 3, 1771-1796, DOI
10.1137/080731724. MR2516188 (2010f:49064)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e208a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e215" publication-type="other">
Thomas Apel, Arnd Rosch, and Gunter Winkler, Optimal control in non-convex domains: a
priori discretization error estimates, Calcolo 44 (2007), no. 3, 137-158, DOI 10.1007/sl0092-
007-0133-0. MR2352719 (2008j:49083)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e228a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e235" publication-type="other">
Thomas Apel and Dieter Sirch, L2-error estimates for Dirichlet and Neumann prob-
lems on anisotropic finite element meshes, Appl. Math. 56 (2011), no. 2, 177-206, DOI
10.1007/sl0492-011-0002-7. MR2810243 (2012e:65258)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e249a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e256" publication-type="other">
Susanne C. Brenner and L. Ridgway Scott, The Mathematical Theory of Finite Ele-
ment Methods, 3rd ed., Texts in Applied Mathematics, vol. 15, Springer, New York, 2008.
MR2373954 (2008m:65001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e269a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e276" publication-type="other">
Eduardo Casas and Mariano Mateos, Error estimates for the numerical approximation
of Neumann control problems, Comput. Optim. Appl. 39 (2008), no. 3, 265-295, DOI
10.1007/sl0589-007-9056-6. MR2396868 (2009a:49055)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e289a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e296" publication-type="other">
Eduardo Casas, Mariano Mateos, and Fredi Troltzsch, Error estimates for the numerical
approximation of boundary semilinear elliptic control problems, Comput. Optim. Appl. 31
(2005), no. 2, 193-219, DOI 10.1007/sl0589-005-2180-2. MR2150243 (2006d:49077)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e309a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e316" publication-type="other">
Monique Dauge, Elliptic Boundary Value Problems on Corner Domains, Lecture Notes in
Mathematics, vol. 1341, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 1988. Smoothness and asymptotics of solu-
tions. MR961439 (91a:35078)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e329a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e336" publication-type="other">
Alan Demlow, Johnny Guzman, and Alfred H. Schatz, Local energy estimates for the fi-
nite element method on sharply varying grids, Math. Comp. 80 (2011), no. 273, 1-9, DOI
10.1090/S0025-5718-2010-02353-1. MR2728969 (2012a:65324)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e349a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e356" publication-type="other">
J. Deny and J. L. Lions, Les espaces du type de Beppo Levi (French), Ann. Inst. Fourier,
Grenoble 5 (1953), 305-370 (1955). MR0074787 (17,646a)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e367a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e374" publication-type="other">
P. Grisvard. Elliptic Problems in Nonsmooth Domains. Pitman, Boston, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e381a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e388" publication-type="other">
M. Hinze, A variational discretization concept in control constrained optimization: the linear-
quadratic case, Comput. Optim. Appl. 30 (2005), no. 1, 45-61, DOI 10.1007/sl0589-005-4559-
5. MR2122182 (2005i:49034)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e401a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e408" publication-type="other">
Michael Hinze and Ulrich Matthes, A note on variational discretization of elliptic Neumann
boundary control, Control Cybernet. 38 (2009), no. 3, 577-591. MR2650352 (2011c:49059)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e418a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e425" publication-type="other">
M. Hinze, R. Pinnau, M. Ulbrich, and S. Ulbrich, Optimization with PDE constraints, Math-
ematical Modelling: Theory and Applications, vol. 23, Springer, New York, 2009. MR2516528
(2010h:49002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e438a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e445" publication-type="other">
David S. Jerison and Carlos E. Kenig, The Neumann problem on Lipschitz domains, Bull.
Amer. Math. Soc. (N.S.) 4 (1981), no. 2, 203-207, DOI 10.1090/S0273-0979-1981-14884-9.
MR598688 (84a:35064)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e458a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e465" publication-type="other">
V. A. Kozlov, V. G. Maz'ya, and J. Rossmann, Elliptic Boundary Value Problems in Do-
mains with Point singularities, Mathematical Surveys and Monographs, vol. 52, American
Mathematical Society, Providence, RI, 1997. MR1469972 (98f:35038)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e479a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e486" publication-type="other">
V. A. Kozlov, V. G. Maz'ya, and J. Rossmann, Spectral Problems Associated with Corner Sin-
gularities of Solutions to Elliptic Equations, Mathematical Surveys and Monographs, vol. 85,
American Mathematical Society, Providence, RI, 2001. MR1788991 (2001i:35069)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e499a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e506" publication-type="other">
Alois Kufner and Anna-Margarete Sandig, Some Applications of Weighted Sobolev Spaces,
Teubner-Texte zur Mathematik [Teubner Texts in Mathematics], vol. 100, BSB B. G. Teubner
Verlagsgesellschaft, Leipzig, 1987. With German, French and Russian summaries. MR926688
(89h:35096)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e522a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e529" publication-type="other">
Hengguang Li, Anna Mazzucato, and Victor Nistor, Analysis of the finite element method for
transmission/mixed boundary value problems on general polygonal domains, Electron. Trans.
Numer. Anal. 37 (2010), 41-69. MR2777235 (2012c:65195)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e542a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e549" publication-type="other">
Mariano Mateos and Arnd Rosch, On saturation effects in the Neumann boundary control
of elliptic optimal control problems, Comput. Optim. Appl. 49 (2011), no. 2, 359-378, DOI
10.1007/sl0589-009-9299-5. MR2795722 (2012e:49067)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e562a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e569" publication-type="other">
Vladimir Maz'ya and Jiirgen Rossmann, Elliptic Equations in Polyhedral Domains, Mathe-
matical Surveys and Monographs, vol. 162, American Mathematical Society, Providence, RI,
2010. MR2641539 (2011h:35002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e582a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e589" publication-type="other">
V. G. Maz'ya and B. A. Plamenevsky, Weighted spaces with nonhomogeneous norms and
boundary value problems in domains with conical points. American Mathematical Society
Translations, 123(2):89-107, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e603a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e610" publication-type="other">
J. M. Melenk and B. Wohlmuth, Quasi-optimal approximation of surface based Lagrange
multipliers in finite element methods, SIAM J. Numer. Anal. 50 (2012), no. 4, 2064-2087,
DOI 10.1137/110832999. MR3022210</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e623a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e630" publication-type="other">
C. Meyer and A. Rosch, Superconvergence properties of optimal control problems, SIAM J.
Control Optim. 43 (2004), no. 3, 970-985 (electronic), DOI 10.1137/S0363012903431608.
MR2114385 (2005i:49024)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e643a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e650" publication-type="other">
Sergey A. Nazarov and Boris A. Plamenevsky, Elliptic Problems in Domains with Piecewise
Smooth Boundaries, de Gruyter Expositions in Mathematics, vol. 13, Walter de Gruyter &amp;
Co., Berlin, 1994. MR1283387 (95h:35001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e663a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e670" publication-type="other">
J. Pfefferer and K. Krumbiegel, Superconvergence for Neumann boundary control problems
governed by semilinear elliptic equations, arXiv:1311:6282 [math.NA].</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e680a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e687" publication-type="other">
J. RoBmann. Gewichtete Sobolev-Slobodetskij-Raume und Anwendungen auf elliptische
Randwertprobleme in Gebieten mit Kanten. Habilitationsschrift, Universitat Rostock, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e697a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e704" publication-type="other">
A. H. Schatz and L. B. Wahlbin, Interior maximum norm estimates for finite element meth-
ods, Math. Comp. 31 (1977), no. 138, 414-442. MR0431753 (55 #4748)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e715a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e722" publication-type="other">
A. H. Schatz and L. B. Wahlbin, Maximum norm estimates in the finite element method
on plane polygonal domains. /, Math. Comp. 32 (1978), no. 141, 73—109. MR0502065
(58 #19233a)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e735a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e742" publication-type="other">
A. H. Schatz and L. B. Wahlbin, Maximum norm estimates in the finite element method
on plane polygonal domains. II. Refinements, Math. Comp. 33 (1979), no. 146, 465-492.
MR0502067 (58 #19233b)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e755a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e762" publication-type="other">
Fredi Troltzsch, Optimal Control of Partial Differential Equations, Graduate Studies in Math-
ematics, vol. 112, American Mathematical Society, Providence, RI, 2010. Theory, methods
and applications; Translated from the 2005 German original by Jiirgen Sprekels. MR2583281
(2011h:49004)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d3633e778a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d3633e785" publication-type="other">
Lars B. Wahlbin, Local behavior in finite element methods, Handbook of numerical analysis,
Vol. II, Handb. Numer. Anal., II, North-Holland, Amsterdam, 1991, pp. 353-522. MRU 15238</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


