<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278213</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Boosted HCCI - Controlling Pressure-Rise Rates for Performance Improvements using Partial Fuel Stratification with Conventional Gasoline</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dec</surname>
                  <given-names>John E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dronniou</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicolas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1169</fpage>
         <lpage>1189</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278213"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study investigates the potential of partial fuel stratification for reducing the knocking propensity of intake-boosted HCCI engines operating on conventional gasoline. Although intake boosting can substantially increase the high-load capability of HCCI, these engines would be more production-viable if the knock/stability load limit could be extended to allow higher loads at a given boost and/or to provide even higher thermal efficiencies. A technique termed partial fuel stratification (PFS) has recently been shown to greatly reduce the combustion-induced pressure-rise rate (PRR), and therefore the knocking propensity of naturally aspirated HCCI, when the engine is fueled with a ϕ-sensitive, two-stage-ignition fuel. The current work explores the potential of applying PFS to boosted HCCI operation using conventional gasoline, which does not typically show two-stage ignition. Experiments were conducted in a single-cylinder HCCI research engine (0.98 liters) at 1200 rpm. The engine was equipped with a compression-ratio 14 piston, and combustion phasing was controlled by EGR addition.</p>
            <p>PFS is produced by premixing the majority of the fuel and then directly injecting the remainder (up to about 20%) in the latter part of the compression stroke. For PFS to be effective, the fuel’s autoignition chemistry must vary with the local equivalence ratio (ϕ) to produce a staged combustion event. Accordingly, tests were conducted to determine the ϕ-sensitivity of gasoline. They show that at naturally aspirated conditions (P<sub>in</sub>= 1 bar), gasoline is not ϕ-sensitive, and PFS is not effective for reducing the PRR. However, with sufficient intake boost (<italic>e.g.</italic>P<sub>in</sub>= 2 bar), gasoline is found to become highly ϕ-sensitive, and PFS very effectively reduces the PRR. Varying the amount of PFS, by adjusting either the timing or amount of DI fuel, allows control of the PRR reduction. Applying PFS to high loads at P<sub>in</sub>= 2 bar substantially shifts the knock/stability limit and increases the maximum IMEP<sub>g</sub>from 11.7 (premixed) to 13.0 bar (PFS). Maximum load improvements with PFS are also seen for other intake pressures ranging from 1.6 to 2.4 bar. Finally, because it allows more advanced combustion phasing without knock, PFS is also effective for increasing the thermal efficiency of boosted HCCI over a range of loads for each P<sub>in</sub>, yielding typical fuel economy improvements of 2 - 2.5%. Overall, PFS has a strong potential for improving gasoline-fueled boosted HCCI operation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J-O., Tunestål, P., Johansson, B., Fiveland, S., Agama, J. R., and Assanis, D. N., “Compression Ratio Influence on Maximum Load of a Natural Gas-Fueled HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0111, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-0111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J.E., Babajimopoulos, A., and Assanis, D., “Comparing Enhanced Natural Thermal Stratification against Retarded Combustion Phasing for Smoothing of HCCI Heat-Release Rates,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2994, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J.E., “Influence of Fuel Autoignition Reactivity on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines, 1(1):39-58, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Comparing Late-cycle Autoignition Stability for Single- and Two-Stage Ignition Fuels in HCCI Engines,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 31: 2895-2902, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Amnéus, P., and Mauss, F., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 980787, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980787.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M. and Johansson, B., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) with Exhaust Gas Recirculation and Pilot Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1835, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1835.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J-O., Tunestål, P., Haroldsson, G., and Johansson, B., “A Turbo-Charged Dual Fuel HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1896, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-1896.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P. W., Schleyer, C. H., Duffy, K. P., Hardy, W. L., and Liechty, M. P., “Effects of Fuel Property Changes on Heavy-Duty HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0191, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines, 3(1): 750-767, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Smoothing HCCI Heat- Release Rates using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two- Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Sjöberg, M., “Isolating the Effects of Fuel Chemistry on Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine and the Potential of Fuel Stratification for Ignition Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0557, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0557.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J. E., Dronniou, N., and Sjöberg, M., “Tailoring HCCI Heat Release Rates with Partial Fuel Stratification: Comparison of Two-Stage and Single-Stage Ignition Fuels,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 33: 3047-3055, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J. E., Dronniou, N., Sjöberg, M., and Cannella, W. J., “Partial Fuel Stratification to Control HCCI Heat Release Rates: Fuel Composition and Other Factors Affecting Pre-Ignition Reaction of Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1917-1934, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahl, D., Andersson, M., Berntsson, A., Denbratt, I., and Koopmans, L., “Reducing Pressure Fluctuations at High Loads by Means of Charge Stratification in HCCI Combustion with Negative Valve Overlap,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1785, 2009, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wada, Y. and Senda, J., “Demonstrating the Potential of Mixture Distribution Control for Controlled Combustion and Emissions Reduction in Premixed Charge Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0498, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J. E., Dronniou, N., and Simmons, B., “Characteristics of Isopentanol as a Fuel for HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr., 3(2):725-741, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., and Hwang, W., “Thermodynamic and Chemical Effects of EGR and Its Constituents on HCCI Autoignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0207, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J. A., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2859.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snyder, J. A., Dronniou, N., Dec, J. E., and Hanson, R. K., “PLIF Measurements of Thermal Stratification in an HCCI Engine under Fired Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1683-1702, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1291.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Combined Effects of Fuel- Type and Engine Speed on Intake Temperature Requirements and Completeness of Bulk-Gas Reactions for HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3173, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E., Sjöberg, M., and Hwang, W., “Isolating the Effects of EGR on HCCI Heat-Release Rates and NOx Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines, 2(2):58-70, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2665.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., and Cernansky, N. P., “The Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, based on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0113, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Hwang, W., “Characterizing the Development of Thermal Stratification in an HCCI Engine Using Planar-Imaging Thermometry,” SAE Int. J. Engines, 2(1):421-438, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0650.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Influence of Fuel Autoignition Reactivity on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):39-58, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Risberg, P., Johansson, D., Andrae, J., Kalghatgi, G., Björnbom, P., and Ångström, H.-E., “The Influence of NO on the Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0416, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0416.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Influence of EGR Quality and Unmixedness on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines, 2(1):492-510, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0666.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
