<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26169325</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Crush Energy and Stiffness in Side Impacts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Struble</surname>
                  <given-names>John D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Exponent, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Struble</surname>
                  <given-names>Donald E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>5</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26169316</issue-id>
         <fpage>88</fpage>
         <lpage>106</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169325"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Crash tests of vehicles by striking deformable barriers are specified by Government programs such as FMVSS 214, FMVSS 301 and the Side Impact New Car Assessment Program (SINCAP). Such tests result in both crash partners absorbing crush energy and moving after separation. Compared with studying fixed rigid barrier crash tests, the analysis of the energy-absorbing behavior of the vehicle side (or rear) structure is much more involved. Described in this paper is a methodology by which analysts can use such crash tests to determine the side structure stiffness characteristics for the specific struck vehicle. Such vehicle-specific information allows the calculation of the crush energy for the particular side-struck vehicle during an actual collision – a key step in the reconstruction of that crash.</p>
            <p>Based on fundamental principles of physics and engineering, this methodology provides transparency in the calculation of side structure stiffness parameters for the particular vehicle of interest. Additionally, sample calculations are presented. Utilizing widely available computational tools and publicly available test data, the method was applied to a representative sample of recent-model vehicles.</p>
            <p>The results of this study show that variability in side structure stiffness from vehicle to vehicle appears to be real – not an artifact of computational method or data uncertainty – and not necessarily related to vehicle size or weight, for example. Independent tests of comparable vehicles, while few in number, produce remarkably similar stiffness results.</p>
            <p>Supported by sensitivity analyses, various simplifications are presented that in most cases will allow a good approximation to more rigorously-derived results.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Struble, D., Welsh, K. and Struble, J., “Side Impact Structural Characterization from FMVSS 214D Test Data,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0122, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell, K., “Energy Basis for Collision Severity,” SAE Technical Paper 740565, 1974, doi:10.4271/740565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Struble, D., "Automotive Accident Reconstruction: Practices and Principles," (Boca Raton, CRC Press, 2014), ISBN 978-1-4665-8837-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strother, C., Woolley, R., James, M. and Warner, C., “Crush Energy in Accident Reconstruction,” SAE Technical Paper 860371, 1986, doi:10.4271/860371.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolley, R., "Non-Linear Damage Analysis in Accident Reconstruction," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0504, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0504.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warner, C., Allsop, D. and Germane, G., “A Repeated Crash-Test Technique for Quantifying Vehicle Crush Coefficients,” SAE Technical Paper 860208, 1986, doi:10.4271/860208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prasad, A., “Energy Dissipated in Vehicle Crush – A Study Using the Repeated Test Technique,” SAE Technical Paper 900412, 1990, doi:10.4271/900412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noga, T. and Oppenheim, T., “CRASH3 User’s Guide and Technical Manual,” US Department of Transportation Report HS 805 732, (Washington, US Government Printing Office, 1981).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sharma, D., Stern, S., Brophy, J. and Choi, E.-H., “An Overview of NHTSA’s Crash Reconstruction Software WinSMASH,” Proceedings of the 20th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tumbas, N. and Smith, R., “Measurement Protocol for Quantifying Vehicle Damage from an Energy Point of View,” SAE Technical Paper 880072, 1988, doi:10.4271/880072.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Struble, D., “Generalizing CRASH3 for Reconstructing Specific Accidents,” SAE Technical Paper 870041, 1987, doi:10.4271/870041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willke, D. and Monk, M., “Crash III Model Improvements: Derivation of New Side Stiffness Parameters from Crash Tests, Vol. 2,” US Department of Transportation Report HS 807 353, (Washington, US Government Printing Office, 1987).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siddall, D. and Day, T., “Updating the Vehicle Class Categories,” SAE Technical Paper 960697, 1996, doi:10.4271/960697.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Osterholt, G., Cummings, J., Biller, B. and Calhoun, V., "Updating Generic Crush Stiffness Coefficients for Accident Reconstruction," SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1581, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1581.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, E., Lee, P., Erickson, M. and Hayes, W., "Increase in Vehicle Front, Rear and Side Stiffness Coefficients in the Past Twenty Years Necessitates New Representative Database," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-0351, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0351.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prasad, A., “Energy Absorbed by Vehicle Structures in Side-Impacts,” SAE Technical Paper 910599, 1991, doi:10.4271/910599.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, “Laboratory Test Procedure for FMVSS 214 ‘Dynamic’ Side Impact Protection,” US Department of Transportation Report TP-214D-05, (Washington, US Government Printing Office, 1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hackney, J., Monk, M., Holliwell, W. and Willke, D., “Results of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration’s Thoracic Side impact Protection Research Program,” SAE Technical Paper 840886, 1984, doi:10.4271/840886.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neptune, J. and Flynn, J., “A Method for Determining Crush Stiffness Coefficients from Offset Frontal and Side Crash Tests,” SAE Technical Paper 980024, 1998, doi:10.4271/980024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strother, C., Kent, R. and Warner, C., “Estimating Vehicle Deformation Energy for Vehicles Struck in the Side,” SAE Technical Paper 980215, 1998, doi:10.4271/980215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trella, T., Samaha, R., Fleck, J. and Strassburg, G., “Moving Deformable Barrier with Dynamic Force and Deflection Measurement Capabilities for Full Scale Tests,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0637, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0637.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swanson, J., Rockwell, T., Beuse, N., Summers, L.et al., “Evaluation of Stiffness Measures from the U.S. New Car Assessment Program,” Proceedings of the 18th Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marine, M. and Werner, S., “Delta-V Analysis from Crash Test Data for Vehicles with Post-Impact Yaw Motion,” SAE Technical Paper 980219, 1998, doi:10.4271/980219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Top 20 U.S. Vehicle Sales: 2015, from www.motorintelligence.com,” Wall Street Journal Online, wsj.com, 5 January 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, G., “Vehicle Year &amp; Model Interchange List (Sisters &amp; Clones List),” (Madison, Scalia Safety Engineering, 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
