<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">107</volume>
         <issue-id>i40195325</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44668163</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of a High Oleic Soybean Oil-Based Hydraulic Fluid</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>J. L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Glancey</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>S.</given-names>
                  <surname>Knowlton</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>E. R.</given-names>
                  <surname>Benson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>266</fpage>
         <lpage>269</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1999 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44668163"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The genetic modification of oilseeds has been a critical step in the evolution of biodegradable, non-toxic vegetable oil-based industrial fluids. Oils that are high in oleic acid possess the required properties for many industrial applications and have been successfully used as hydraulic fluids and numerous lubricants. Recently, the DuPont Co. has developed high oleic soybean varieties that produce oil with greatly improved oxidative stability. This oil provides the opportunity to make environmentally acceptable industrial fluids that may be lower in cost and/or functionally superior to vegetable oil-based fluids currently on the market. Research and testing over the last year has focused on utilizing genetically modified soyoil for industrial applications. Using standard bench tests and low volume fluid power pump tests, experiments were conducted to develop a soybean oil-based hydraulic fluid in cooperation with Lubrizol Corporation. Rotating Bomb (RBOT) tests, as well as pump wear, oil viscosity change and TAN change were each used to assess oil performance. Results indicate the high oleic soyoil, combined with antiwear and anti-oxidation additives, perform as well or better than commercially available vegetable based hydraulic fluids currently marketed as biodegradable, environmentally acceptable oils. Tests show the high oleic soybean hydraulic fluid is comparable in performance to the high oleic sunflower-based hydraulic fluid developed by Lubrizol and superior in performance to canola-based fluids currently on the market.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d407e202a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e209" publication-type="other">
Honary, L. 1995. Performance of selected vegetable oils in
ASTM hydraulic tests. SAE Technical Paper 952075. SAE,
Warrendale, PA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e222a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e229" publication-type="other">
Lawate, S. and C. Huang. 1996. Oilseed modification -
realizing value through lubricant development. The Lubri-
zol Corporation, 29400 Lakeland Blvd., Wickliffe, OH
44092-2298.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e245a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e252" publication-type="other">
Cheng, V.M., A.A. Wessol, P. Baudouin, M.T. BenKinny and
N.J. Novic. 1991. Biodegradable and nontoxic hydraulic
fluids. SAE Technical Paper 910964. SAE, Warrendale,
PA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e268a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e275" publication-type="other">
Glancey, J.L., E.R. Benson and S. Knowlton. 1996. A low
volume fluid power system for the evaluation of genetically
modified vegetables as industrial fluids. SAE Technical
Paper 961725. SAE, Warrendale, PA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d407e292a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d407e299" publication-type="other">
Benson, E.R. 1996. An antiwear evaluation procedure for
small volumes of genetically enhanced vegetable oils.
Degree with Distinction Thesis (unpublished). University of
Delaware, Newark, DE 19717.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


