<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308453</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Investigation of Intake Condition and Group-Hole Nozzle Effects on Fuel Economy and Combustion Noise for Stoichiometric Diesel Combustion in an HSDI Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Junghwan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Park</surname>
                  <given-names>Sung Wook</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andrie</surname>
                  <given-names>Mike</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sung</surname>
                  <given-names>Kian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Gangwon Provincial College</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1054</fpage>
         <lpage>1067</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308453"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The goal of this research is to investigate the physical parameters of stoichiometric operation of a diesel engine under a light load operating condition (6∼7 bar IMEP). This paper focuses on improving the fuel efficiency of stoichiometric operation, for which a fuel consumption penalty relative to standard diesel combustion was found to be 7% from a previous study. The objective is to keep NOx and soot emissions at reasonable levels such that a 3-way catalyst and DPF can be used in an aftertreatment combination to meet 2010 emissions regulation.</p>
            <p>The effects of intake conditions and the use of group-hole injector nozzles (GHN) on fuel consumption of stoichiometric diesel operation were investigated. Throttled intake conditions exhibited about a 30% fuel penalty compared to the best fuel economy case of high boost/EGR intake conditions. The higher CO emissions of throttled intake cases lead to the poor fuel economy. In comparison with the use of single-hole nozzles (SHN) GHN lowered the fuel consumption by 3% under throttled intake conditions, whereas it exhibited no significant improvement in ISFC in the high boost/EGR cases. In addition, while investigating the best fuel economy location from SOI sweeps, a sweet spot [1] was observed in exhaust CO and O₂ measurements.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Ra, Y., Gonzalez, D., M. A., Krieger, R., Reitz, R. D., Foster, D. E., Durrett, R. P., Siewert, R. M., “Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2007-01- 0193, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engines Fundamentals”, p529-239, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, S., Gonzalez D., M. A., Reitz, R. D., “Effects of Engine Operating Parameters on near Stoichiometric Diesel Combustion Characteristics”, SAE Paper 2007-01-0121, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee. S., Gonzalez D., M. A., Reitz, R. D., “Stoichiometric Combustion in a HSDI Diesel Engine to Allow Use of a Three-way Exhaust Catalyst”, SAE Paper 2006-01-1148, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, S., Reitz, R. D., “Spray Targeting to Minimize Soot and CO Formation in Premixed Charge Compression Ignition (PCCI) Combustion with a HSDI Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2006-01-0918, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chase, S., Nevin, R., Winsor, R., Baumgard, K., “Stoichiometric Compression Ignition (SCI) Engine”, SAE Paper 2007-01-4224, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, T. J., Bohac, S. V., Assanis, D. N., Szymkowicz, P. G., “Lean and Rich Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion in a Light- Duty Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2005-01-0166, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, J., Matsumoto, Y., Namba, M., Nishida, K., “Group-Hole Nozzle Effects on Mixture Formation and In-cylinder Combustion Processes in Direct-Injection Diesel Engines”, SAE Paper 2007-01-4050, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gao, J., Matsumoto, Y., Nishida, K., “Effects of Group-hole Nozzle Specifications on Fuel Atomization and Evaporation of Direct Injection Diesel Sprays”, SAE Paper 2007-01-1889, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dohle, U., Naber, D., Kruger, M., Stein, J.O., Gauthier, Y., “Results of Combustion Optimization by Use of Multihole Nozzles in Modern Passenger Car Diesel Engines”, 27th International Vienna Motor Symposium, April, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S. W., Reitz, R. D., “Modeling the Effect of Injector Nozzle-Hole Layout on Diesel Engine Fuel Consumption and Emissions”, Transactions of the ASME, Vol. 130, May 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S. W., Reitz, R. D., “Optimization of Fuel/air Mixture Formation for Stoichiometric Diesel Combustion Using a 2-spray-angle Group-hole Nozzle”, submitted to Combustion Theory and Modeling, May 1, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wickman, D. D., “HSDI Diesel Engine Combustion Chamber Geometry Optimization”, Ph.D. Thesis, University of Wisconsin, Madison, August 14, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pearsall, H. W., “Measuring the Total Hydrocarbons in Diesel Exhaust”, SAE Paper 670089, 1967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Labcaster, D. R., Krieger, R. B., Lienesch, J. H., “Measurement and Analysis of Engine Pressure Data” SAE Paper 750026, 1975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gatowski, J. A., Balles, E. N., Chun, K. M., Nelson, F. E., Ekchian, J. A., Heywood, J. B., “Heat Release Analysis of Engine Pressure Data”, SAE Paper 841359, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MATLAB R2007a, Help manual</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J. A., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion”, SAE Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A., “KIVA-3V, Release 2, Improvements to KIVA-3V”, LA Report, Los Alamos National Laboratory, May, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hessel, R. P., “KIVA-3V Lite Complete Manual”, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, S. W., Reitz, R. D., “Numerical Study on the Low Emission Window of Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Diesel Combustion”, Combustion Science and Technology, 179: 2279-2307, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, J., Park, S. W., Sung, K., Reitz, R. D., “Reduction of NOx and CO emissions in stoichiometric diesel combustion using a 3-way catalyst”, submitted to ASME ICE conference, May. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Master of Science Thesis, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C., Master of Science Thesis, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Bae, C, Miles, P. C., Choi, D., Bergin, M., Reitz, R. D., “The Effect of Swirl Ratio and Fuel Injection Parameters on CO Emission and Fuel Conversion Efficiency for High-Dilution, Low-Temperature Combustion in an Automotive Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2006-01-0197, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
