<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014676</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effects of Captions on EFL Learners’ Comprehension of English-Language Television Programs</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rodgers</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael P. H.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Michael P. H. Rodgers is an Assistant Professor at Carleton University. His research interests include vocabulary acquisition, language learning through viewing videos, and extensive viewing and listening. He has published in journals such as Applied Linguistics, Language Learning, and TESOL Quarterly.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Webb</surname>
                  <given-names>Stuart</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Stuart Webb is a Professor at the University of Western Ontario. His research interests include vocabulary, second language acquisition, and extensive reading and listening. His articles have been published in journals such as Studies in Second Language Acquisition, Applied Linguistics, and Language Learning.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>University of Nottingham.</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>University of Western Ontario.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014673</issue-id>
         <fpage>20</fpage>
         <lpage>38</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014676"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>The Multimedia Principle (Fletcher &amp; Tobias, 2005) states that people learn better and comprehend more when words and pictures are presented together. The potential for English language learners to increase their comprehension of video through the use of captions, which graphically display the same language as the spoken dialogue, has been documented in previous research. However, studies have generally used short videos (Markham &amp; Peter, 2003; Montero Perez, Peters, &amp; Desmet, 2014) or videos designed for language learning (Chung, 1999) rather than episodes of L2 television programs that students are most likely to watch on their own outside of the classroom. The present study aimed to fill this gap by investigating the comprehension of 372 Japanese university students who watched ten 42-minute episodes of an American television program with and without captions. While viewing the episodes, the participants completed comprehension tests. Analysis indicated that although the participants who viewed the episodes with captions had comprehension scores that were slightly higher across all episodes, their scores were only significantly different for three of the ten episodes. The results revealed that captions are likely to aid comprehension when episodes are most difficult. Explanations for the findings and pedagogical applications are offered.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>comprehension</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>captions</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>television</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>language learning</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brett, P. (1995). Multimedia for listening comprehension: The design of a multimedia-based resource for developing listening skills. System, 23(1), 77–85. https://doi.org/10.1016/0346-251X(94)00054-A</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buck, G. (2001). Assessing listening. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511732959</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chung, J. M. (1999). The effects of using video texts supported with advance organizers and captions on Chinese college students’ listening comprehension: An empirical study. Foreign Language Annals, 32(3), 295–308. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.1999.tb01342.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cohen, J. (1977). Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. New York, NY: Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Danan, M. (2004). Captioning and subtitling: Undervalued language learning strategies. Meta: Translators’ Journal, 49(1), 67–77. https://doi.org/10.7202/009021ar</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellis, N. C. (2005). At the interface: Dynamic interactions of explicit and implicit language knowledge. Studies in Second Language Acquisition, 27(2), 305–352. https://doi.org/10.1017/S027226310505014X</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fletcher, J. D., &amp; Tobias, S. (2005). The multimedia principle. In R. Mayer (Ed.), The Cambridge handbook of multimedia learning (pp. 117–133). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511816819.008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garza, T. J. (1991). Evaluating the use of captioned video materials in advanced foreign language learning. Foreign Language Annals, 24(3), 239–258. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.1991.tb00469.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gruba, P. (2004). Understanding digitized second language videotext. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 17(1), 51–82. https://doi.org/10.1076/call.17.1.51.29710</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guillory, H. G. (1998). The effects of keyword captions to authentic French video on learner comprehension. CALICO Journal, 15(1–3), 89–108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirai, A. (1999). The relationship between listening and reading rates of Japanese EFL learners. The Modern Language Journal, 83(3), 367–384. https://doi.org/10.1111/0026-7902.00028</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, H. C., &amp; Eskey, D. E. (1999). The effects of closed-captioned television on the listening comprehension of intermediate English as a Second Language (ESL) students. Journal of Educational Technology Systems, 28(1), 75–96. https://doi.org/10.2190/RG06-LYWB-216Y-R27G</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markham, P., &amp; Peter, L. A. (2003). The influence of English language and Spanish language captions on foreign language listening/reading comprehension. Journal of Educational Technology Systems, 31(3), 331–341. https://doi.org/10.2190/BHUH-420B-FE23-ALA0</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markham, P., Peter, L. A., &amp; McCarthy, T. J. (2001). The effects of native language vs. target language captions on foreign language students’ DVD video comprehension. Foreign Language Annals, 34(5), 439–445. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2001.tb02083.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montero Perez, M., Peters, E., &amp; Desmet, P. (2014). Is less more? Effectiveness and perceived usefulness of keyword and full captioned video for L2 listening comprehension. ReCALL, 26(01), 21–43. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344013000256</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richards, J. C. (1983). Listening comprehension: Approach, design, procedure. TESOL Quarterly, 17(2), 219–240. https://doi.org/10.2307/3586651</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodgers, M. P. H., &amp; Webb, S. (2011). Narrow viewing: The vocabulary in related television programs. TESOL Quarterly, 45(4), 689–717.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitt, N., Schmitt, D., &amp; Clapham, C. (2001). Developing and exploring the behaviour of two new versions of the Vocabulary Levels Test. Language Testing, 18(1), 55–88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwartz, J., Fedak, C., &amp; McG. (2007). Chuck [Television series]. Los Angeles, CA: NBC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shohamy, E. (1984). Does the testing method make a difference? The case of reading comprehension. Language Testing, 1(2), 147–170. https://doi.org/10.1177/026553228400100203</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shohamy, E., &amp; Inbar, O. (1991). Validation of listening comprehension tests: The effect of text and question type. Language Testing, 8(1), 23–40. https://doi.org/10.1177/026553229100800103</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spaan, M. (2007). Evolution of a test item. Language Assessment Quarterly, 4(3), 279–293. https://doi.org/10.1080/15434300701462937</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, E. (2002). Video listening tests: A pilot study. Columbia University Working Papers in TESOL &amp; Applied Linguistics, 2(1), 1–39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Webb, S. (2014). Extensive viewing: Language learning through watching television. In D. Nunan &amp; J. C. Richards (Eds.), Language learning beyond the classroom (pp. 159–168). London: Routledge. https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315883472</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Webb, S., &amp; Rodgers, M. P. H. (2009). Vocabulary demands of television programs. Language Learning, 59(2), 335–366. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2009.00509.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
