<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308261</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of a Synthetic Diesel Exhaust</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fanick</surname>
                  <given-names>E. Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Southwest Research Institute</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Merritt</surname>
                  <given-names>Patrick M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Southwest Research Institute</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Eng</surname>
                  <given-names>King D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Shell Global Solutions Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>65</fpage>
         <lpage>70</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308261"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A two-phase study was performed to establish a standard diesel exhaust composition which could be used in the future development of light-duty diesel exhaust aftertreatment. In the first phase, a literature review created a database of diesel engine-out emissions. The database consisted chiefly of data from heavy-duty diesel engines; therefore, the need for an emission testing program for light- and medium-duty engines was identified. A second phase was conducted to provide additional light-duty vehicle emissions data from current technology vehicles. Engine-out diesel exhaust from four 2004 model light-duty vehicles with a variety of engine displacements was collected and analyzed. Each vehicle was evaluated using five steady-state engine operating conditions and two transient test cycles (the Federal Test Procedure and the US06). Regulated emissions were measured along with speciation of both volatile and semi-volatile components of the hydrocarbons. The results from the literature search and the engine-out emissions data were used to suggest a possible synthetic diesel exhaust formulation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merritt, P.M., “Diesel Exhaust Standard Phase I: RC Project No. AVFL-10a,” prepared for the oordinating Research Council, Inc., August 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fanick, E.R., “Diesel Exhaust Standard Phase II: RC Project No. AVFL-10b,” prepared for the oordinating Research Council, Inc., August 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Code of Federal Regulations, Title 40 Protection of nvironment, Chapter I-Environmental Protection gency, Subchapter C-Air Programs, Part 86- ontrol of Emissions from New and In-Use Highway ehicles and Engines, Subpart D-Emission egulations New Light-Duty Vehicles and New ight-Duty Trucks and New Otto-Cycle Complete eavy-duty Vehicles; Test Procedures, Published by ffice of Federal Register National Archives and ecords Administration, Revised as of July 1, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siegl, W.O., Richert, J.F.O., Jensen, T.E., chuetzle, D., Swarin, S.J., Loo, J.F., Prostak, A., agy, D., and Schlenker, A.M., “Improved missions Speciation Methodology for Phase II of he Auto/Oil Air Quality Improvement Research rogram-Hydrocarbons and Oxygenates,” SAE aper No. 930142, International Congress and xposition, Detroit, MI, March 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fanick, E.R., Smith, L.R., Ahuja, M.S., Albu, S., antoro, S.J., Leonard, J.H., McCormack, M.C., and iens, F.J., “Comparison of Exhaust Emissions rom a Vehicle Fueled with Methanol-Containing dditives for Flame Luminosity,” SAE Paper No. 930220, International Congress and Exposition, etroit, MI, March 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
