<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169283</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Comparison of the NHTSA Research Offset Oblique and Small Overlap Impact Tests and the IIHS Moderate and Small Overlap Tests</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lam</surname>
                  <given-names>Joyce</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nissan North America, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dennis</surname>
                  <given-names>Nate J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nissan North America, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dix</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeff</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nissan North America, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lambrecht</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nissan North America, Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ootani</surname>
                  <given-names>Ryuuji</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nissan Motor Co., Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169277</issue-id>
         <fpage>268</fpage>
         <lpage>278</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169283"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) and the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety (IIHS) have both developed crash test methodologies to address frontal collisions in which the vehicle's primary front structure is either partially engaged or not engaged at all. IIHS addresses Small Overlap crashes, cases in which the vehicle's primary front energy absorbing structure is not engaged, using a rigid static barrier with an overlap of 25% of the vehicle's width at an impact angle of 0°. The Institute's Moderate Overlap partially engages the vehicle's primary front energy absorbing structure using a deformable static barrier with 40% overlap at a 0° impact angle. The NHTSA has developed two research test methods which use a common moving deformable barrier impacting the vehicle with 20% overlap at a 7° impact angle and 35% overlap at a 15° impact angle respectively. In this paper, the authors present a case study in which an exemplar mid-size sedan was subjected to all four impact conditions. Following the NHTSA research procedures and IIHS protocols, the anthropomorphic test devices used in this study were THOR-NT (with LX instrumented lower legs) for the NHTSA research tests, and the Hybrid III AM50 for the IIHS tests. Differences with regards to resulting vehicle deformation, vehicle kinematics, and occupant kinematics were noted between the IIHS and NHTSA test methods and are discussed in this paper.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brumbelow, M.L., and Zuby, D.S., “Impact and Injury Patterns in Frontal Crashes of Vehicles with Good Ratings for Frontal Crash Protection”, Paper No. 09-0257, Proceedings of the 21st International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles, Washington, DC, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sherwood, C.P., Nolan, J.M., and Zuby, D.S., “Characteristics of Small Overlap Crashes”, Paper No. 09-0423, Proceedings of the 21st International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles, Washington, DC, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sherwood, C., “An Update on the IIHS Small Overlap Frontal Crash Research Program”, Presentation at 2011 Government / Industry Meeting, Washington, DC, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sherwood, C., “An Update on the IIHS Small Overlap Research Program”, Presentation at 2012 Government / Industry Meeting, Washington, DC, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“IIHS Small Overlap Program Protocol and Rating Guidelines”, Presentation, August 1, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IIHS Status Report, Vol. 47, No. 6, August 14, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bean J. D., Kahane, C. J., Mynatt, M., Rudd, R. W., Rush, C. J., Wiacek, C., 2009. Fatalities in frontal crashes despite seat belts and air bags. DOT HS 811 202, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rudd, R., Scarboro, M., and Saunders, J., “Injury Analysis of Real- World Small Overlap and Oblique Frontal Crashes,” Paper No. 11-0384, Proceedings of the 22nd International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles, National Harbor, MD, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saunders, J., Craig, M., and Parent, D., “Moving Deformable Barrier Test Procedure for Evaluating Small Overlap/Oblique Crashes,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 5(1):172-195, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0577.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saunders, J., “Performance of a Driver and Right Front Passenger THOR in a Left and Right Frontal Oblique Test Procedure,” Presentation at 2013 Government / Industry Meeting, Washington, DC, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saunders, J. and Parent, D., “Repeatability of a Small Overlap and an Oblique Moving Deformable Barrier Test Procedure,” SAE Int. J. Trans. Safety 1(2):309-327, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kikuchi, T., Nakao, T., Watanabe, T., Saeki, H. et al., “An Investigation of Injury Factors Concerning Drivers in Vehicles Involved in Small-Overlap Frontal Crashes,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 5(2):801-806, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0599.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okabe, T., et al., “An Investigation of Injury Factors Concerning Drivers in Vehicles Involved in Small-Overlap Frontal Crashes”, Presentation at 2012 Government / Industry Meeting, Washington, DC, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, “NHTSA/Honda Meeting on Small Overlap/Oblique,” Presentation at NHTSA/Honda Research Meeting, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Insurance Institute for Highway Safety Test Protocol, “Moderate Overlap Frontal Crashworthiness Evaluation Crash Test Protocol (Version XII),” Rev. Aug. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Insurance Institute for Highway Safety Test Protocol, “Small Overlap Frontal Crashworthiness Evaluation Crash Test Protocol (Version I),” Rev. Oct. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Longhitano, D.C. and Turley, J.E., “The Upper-Body Response of THOR in Frontal Barrier Tests,” ESV Technical Paper 125, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shaw, G., Crandall, J.R., and Butcher, J., “Biofidelity Evaluation of the THOR Advanced Frontal Crash Test Dummy,” presented at International IRCOBI Conference on the Biomechanics of Impact, France, September 20-22, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mueller, B.C., Sherwood, C.P., Arbelaez, R.A., Zuby, D.S., et al., “Comparison of Hybrid III and THOR Dummies in Paired Small Overlap Tests,” Stapp Car Crash J. 55:379-409, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
