<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023188</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Fiscal Federalism and Fiscal Competition</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Absorbing Shocks</article-title>
            <subtitle>The Role of Rainy Day Funds and Transfers in a Fiscal Union</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Goodspeed</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Hunter College and Graduate Center of CUNY</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Department of Economics</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>695 Park Avenue</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>New York, NY 10065</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>15</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023188"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In this paper we investigate the role of rainy-day funds and transfers in a fiscal union. We begin by examining a country in autarky and considering its savings and funding decision for a rainy day fund. We then introduce a fiscal union and examine how the introduction of the union affects the rainy day fund. We find that contributions to a rainy day fund will be lower in a fiscal union, and further that the higher the fiscal transfer, the lower will be the contributions to the rainy-day fund. Is there an optimal size of the fiscal union in the sense of the size of the transfers involved? We find that there is. The trade-off is that members of the union benefit from the insurance provided by the union, but suffer because it reduces their contributions to their own rainy-day funds. We find that the optimal size of transfers in the fiscal union depend on a number of factors. In particular, member countries should have lower transfers if (1) own-fiscal policy is more effective; (2) rainy-day fund savings are highly (negatively) influenced by the presence of the transfers; (3) recession is a relatively lower probability event; and (4) redistribution yields a lower utility gain in the union. We also find that commitment to a transfer policy is an issue. A union that is prone to break the rules on transfers negatively impacts the contribution of individual member country’s rainy day funds.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bargain, O., M. Dolls, C. Fuest, D. Neumann, A. Peichl, N. Pestel and S. Siegloch (2012), “Fiscal Union in Europe? Efficiency, Equity and Stabilizing Effects of an EU-Wide Income Tax” Discussion Paper 6585, IZA Bonn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bordo, M., Markiewicz, A., Jonung, L. (2011), “A fiscal union for the euro: Some lessons from history”, NBER Working Paper No. 17380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuest, C. and A. Peichl (2012). ‘European Fiscal Union: What is it? Does it work? And are there really 'no alternatives'?’ Policy Paper 39 IZA, Bonn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kletzer, Kenneth and Jürgen von Hagen, 2000. “Monetary Union and Fiscal Federalism,” ZEI Working paper B01/2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sala-i-Martin, Xavier, and Jeffrey Sachs (1991), “Fiscal Federalism and Optimum Currency Areas: Evidence for europe from the United States.” in: Matthew Canzoneri, Vittorio Grilli, and Paul Masson (eds.), Estabilishing a Central Bank: Issues in Europe and Lessons from the US, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
