<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167729</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Performance Plus Range</article-title>
            <subtitle>Combined Battery Concept for Plug-In Hybrid Vehicles</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bockstette</surname>
                  <given-names>Jens</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>VKA RWTH-Aachen</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Habermann</surname>
                  <given-names>Knut</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ogrzewalla</surname>
                  <given-names>Juergen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pischinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Seibert</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167713</issue-id>
         <fpage>156</fpage>
         <lpage>171</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167729"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>PlugIn Hybrid Electric Vehicles (PHEV) offer the opportunity to experience electric driving without the risk of vehicle break-down due to a low battery charge state. Thus, PHEV's represent an attractive means of meeting future CO2-legislation.</p>
            <p>PHEV batteries must fulfill a divergent list of requirements: on the one hand, the battery must supply sufficient energy to ensure it can be driven an appropriate distance in EV-mode. On the other hand, even with a low state-of-charge (SOC), the battery must supply sufficient power to assist the engine in vehicle acceleration or to recuperate on deceleration. This leads to a compromise in terms of cell selection. Fundamentally, high energy cells cannot provide high charge and discharge rates and high power cells cannot provide sufficient energy. Consequently, the battery can either be provided with the required energy content by switching many power cells in parallel, or it can meet the power requirements with the help of a very large energy battery with a low discharge rate. Neither solution is optimal in terms of the packaging, weight and cost aspects.</p>
            <p>This paper presents an innovative and cost-efficient battery concept including customized set-up of the battery through combination of the energy and power modules. The current flow from the battery's energy pack to the power pack and back is realized through a cost-efficient current controller. The combined battery utilizes a predefined current, offering advantages in terms of predicted service life in comparison with conventional batteries. The combined battery provides cost advantages of 12% and weight advantages of 18% compared with conventional battery technology. The current controller offers the flexibility of combining different energy sources which, in turn, permits modular systems to be generated for a wide range of applications with potential scaling effects.</p>
            <p>Within this paper, the requirements for PHEV batteries are described along with the concept of the combined battery, the mechanical and electrical layout, as well as the test results of the battery concept on basis of a specific application example.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AXSEN, Jonn: Batteries for Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles (PHEVs): Goals and the State of Technology circa 2008. In: Institute of Transportation Studies University of California (2008.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DIXON, J.; NAKASHIMA, I.; ARCOS, E.F; ORTUZAR, M.: Electric Vehicle Using a Combination of Ultracapacitors and ZEBRA Battery. In: IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics 57 (2010.), Nr. 3, S. 943-949. - ISSN 0278-0046</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FARZAD: Hybrid Lithium-ion/Ultracap Energy Storage Systems for Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FREEDOMCAR: Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle R&amp;D Plan. 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FULLER, Thomas F.; DOYLE, Marc; NEWMAN, John: Simulation and Optimization of the Dual Lithium Ion Insertion Cell. In: ELECTROCHEMICAL SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (1994.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">HOFMANN, Peter: Hybridfahrzeuge: Ein alternatives Antriebskonzept für die Zukunft.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">JARUSHI, A. M.; SCHOFIELD, N.: Battery and supercapacitor combination for a series hybrid electric vehicle. In: Power Electronics, Machines and Drives (PEMD 2010), 5th IET International Conference on, 2010, S. 1-6</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">KALHAMMER, Fritz R.: Status and Prospects for Zero Emissions Vehicle Technology: Report of the ARB Independent Expert Panel 2007. (2007.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">KOHLER, T.P; BUECHERL, D.; HERZOG, H. G.: Investigation of control strategies for hybrid energy storage systems in hybrid electric vehicles. In: Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, 2009. VPPC ′09. IEEE, 2009, S. 1687-1693. - ISBN 978-1-4244-2600-3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">KROMER, Matthew A.; HEYWOOD, John B.: Electric Powertrains: Opportunities and Challenges in the U.S. Light-Duty Vehicle Fleet. 2007. - URL http://wiki.greenneedham.org/gnc/images/b/b9/MIT_ElectricDrivetrains.pdf. - doi: 17.11.2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LONG LAM: A Practical CircuitÂbased Model for State of Health Estimation of Liion Battery Cells in Electric Vehicles. (2011.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PESARAN, A.A.: Battery Requirements for Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles - Analysis and Rationale. (2009.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ROMAUS, C.; BOCKER, J.; WITTING, K.; SEIFRIED, A.; ZNAMENSHCHYKOV, O.: Optimal energy management for a hybrid energy storage system combining batteries and double layer capacitors. In: Energy Conversion Congress and Exposition, 2009. ECCE 2009. IEEE, 2009, S. 1640-1647. - ISBN 978-1-4244-2893-9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ROSARIO, L.C; LUK, P.C.K: Implementation of a modular power and energy management structure for battery- ultracapacitor powered electric vehicles. In: Hybrid Vehicle Conference (Conf. Pub. CP526), IET, URL http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp? arnumber=4077068, 2006, S. 141-156. - ISBN 978-0-86341-748-1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SINHUBER, Philipp: Conceptional Considerations for Electrification of Public City Buses: Energy Storage System and Charging Stations. In: IEEE Transaction on Power Electronics (2011.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VERKEHR, Bau und für S. Bundesministerium: Mobilität in Deutschland 2008: Ergebnisbericht Struktur - Aufkommen - Emissionen - Trends. (2008.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
