<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939448</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Financial Reporting and Auditing</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Auditor Tax Advisory Services and Clients’ Tax Avoidance</article-title>
            <subtitle>Do Auditors Draw a Line in the Sand for Tax Advisory Services?</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nesbitt</surname>
                  <given-names>Wayne L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Persson</surname>
                  <given-names>Anh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shaw</surname>
                  <given-names>Joanna</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>50</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939448"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We investigate whether current PCAOB regulations on the prohibition of the provision of aggressive tax strategies to publicly-listed clients, limits the association between auditor-provided tax services (APTS) and clients’ level of tax avoidance. A resurgence of consultancy services as well as incidents of audit firms’ involvement in clients’ tax aggressive activities have reignited concerns about the provision of non-audit services. Using non-linear and quartile regressions, we document a negative but declining association between tax fees paid and clients’ effective tax rates (ETR). Further, we find evidence that the association becomes positive for the most tax aggressive clients. This positive association is consistent with audit firms either foregoing or reducing the level of tax service engagement when clients become more tax aggressive, possibly due to regulatory, reputational, or litigation concerns. In cross-sectional analyses, we find some evidence that larger clients influence audit firms to be more tax aggressive, consistent with economic bonding. These results should be informative to policymakers and regulators on audit firms’ compliance with current regulations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abernathy, J., M. Barnes and C. Stefaniak. 2013. A Summary of 10 Years of PCAOB Research: What have We Learned? Journal of Accounting Literature, 32 (1): 30-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Abernathy, J., E. Rapley and J. Stekelberg. 2016. Do External Auditors Respond to Tax Risk? Evidence from Audit Fees and Auditor-Provided Tax Services. Working Paper. Kennesaw State University, Colorado State University and University of Arizona.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Abbott, L., S. Parker, G. Peters, and D. Rama .2003. Audit, Non-audit, and Information Technology Fees: Some Empirical Evidence. Accounting and the Public Interest, Vol. 3, (1): 1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">AICPA - American Institute of Certified Public Accountants Code of Professional Conduct (August 2016) https://www.aicpa.org/research/standards/codeofconduct.html (last accessed 02/01/2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Armstrong, C. S., Blouin, J. L., Jagolinzer, A. D., &amp; Larcker, D. F. (2015). Corporate governance, incentives and tax Avoidance. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 60, 1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Balakrishnan, K., J. Blouin, and W. Guay. 2012. Does Tax Aggressiveness Reduce Corporate Transparency? Working Paper. London School of Business and University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Ball, R. 2001. Infrastructure requirements for an economically efficient system of public financial reporting and disclosure. Brookings-Wharton Papers on Financial Services, 170-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Beardsley, E., A. Imdieke, and T. Omer. 2018. Evidence of a Nonlinear Association between Auditor-Provided Non-Audit Services and Audit Quality. Working Paper. University of Notre Dame, University of Notre Dame and University of Nebraska at Lincoln.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Beck, P., T. Frecka and I. Solomon .1988. A model of the market for MAS and audit services: knowledge spillovers and auditor-auditee bonding Journal of Accounting Literature, 7 (1988), pp. 50-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Blouin, J. 2014. Defining and Measuring Corporate Tax Avoidance. National Tax Journal, Vol. 67(4): 875-899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Byrnes, N., M. McNamee, D. Brady, and L. Lavelle. 2002. Accounting in crisis. BusinessWeek (January 28): 44-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Carson, E., Fargher, N. L., Geiger, M. A., Lennox, C. S., Raghunandan, K., &amp; Willekens, M. (2013). Audit reporting for going-concern uncertainty: A research synthesis. Auditing, 32(SUPPL.1), 353-384.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Ciconte, W.A., W.R. Knechel, M.A. Mayberry. 2017. Investments in Auditor-Provided Non-Audit Services and Future Operating Performance. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Cook, K., G. Huston and T. Omer. 2008. Earnings Management through Effective Tax Rates: The Effects of Tax-Planning Investment and the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002*. Contemporary Accounting Research, Vol. 25 (2): 447-471.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Cook, K. and T. Omer. (2013) The Cost of Independence: Evidence from Firms’ Decisions to Dismiss Auditors as Tax-Service Providers. Working Paper. Texas Tech University, University of Nebraska-Lincoln.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Deloitte Touché Tohmatsu Limited. Non-audit Services: Restrictions and Fee Cap. December 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Defond, M. L., &amp; Zhang, J. (2014). A Review of Archival Auditing Research. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 58(2-3), 275-326.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">De Simone, L., M. Ege and B. Stomberg. 2015. Internal Control Quality: The Role of Auditor-Provided Tax Services. The Accounting Review, Vol. 90: 1469-1496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Dickins, D. and J. Higgs. 2005. Interpretation and Use of Auditors Fee Disclosures. Financial Analysts Journal, Vol. 61, No. 3: 96-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Dyreng, S. D., M. Hanlon, and E. Maydew. 2008. Long-run corporate tax avoidance. The Accounting Review, Vol.831: 61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">EUR-Lex Access to European Union law. (2014, May 27). Retrieved March 23, 2018, from http://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/dir/2014/56/oj</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">EY Insights. EU Audit Legislation: Understanding the legislation and how it will affect you. October 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Francis, J. R. 2006. Are auditors compromised by non-audit services? Assessing the evidence. Contemporary Accounting Research, Vol.23 (3): 747-760.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Gleason, C. and L. Mills. 2011. Do auditor-provided tax services improve the estimate of tax reserves? Contemporary Accounting Research, Vol. 28(5): 1484-1509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Glezen, G., and J. Millar. 1985. An Empirical Investigation of Stockholder Reaction to Disclosures Required by ASR No. 250. Journal of Accounting Research, Vol. 23(2):859-870.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Graham, J., Raedy, J., &amp; Shackelford, D. (2010). Research in Accounting for Income Taxes. Journal of Accounting and Economics, 53(1-2), 412-434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Gul, F. A., J. Tsui, and D. S. Dhaliwal. 2006. Non-audit services, auditor quality, and the value relevance of earnings. Accounting and Finance, Vol.465: 797-817.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Hanlon, M., S. Heitzman. 2010. A review of tax research. Journal of Accounting and Economics, Vol. 50: 127-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Harris, S. B. (2014, November 24). The Rise of Advisory Services in Audit Firms. Retrieved March 23, 2018, from https://pcaobus.org/News/Speech/Pages/11242014_</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Harris.aspx Hogan, B., and T. Noga. 2015. Auditor-Provided Tax Services and Long-Term Tax Avoidance. Review of Accounting &amp; Finance, Vol. 14.3: 285-305</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Johnstone, K. M., &amp; Bedard, J. C. (2003). Risk Management in Client Acceptance Decisions. The Accounting Review, 78(4), 1003-1025.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Kinney, W., Z. Palmrose, and S. Scholz. 2004. Auditor independence, non-audit services, and restatements: Was the U.S. government right? Journal of Accounting Research, Vol. 42 (3): 561-588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Klassen, K., P. Lisowsky and D. Mescall. 2016. The Role of Auditors, Non-Auditors, and Internal Tax Departments in Corporate Tax Aggressive. The Accounting Review, Vol. 91: 179-205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Krishnan, J., H. Sami, and Y. Zhang. 2005. Does the provision of non-audit services affect investor perceptions of auditor independence? Auditing: A Journal of Practice &amp; Theory, Vol. 242: 111-135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Lassila, D., T. Omer, M. Shelley, and L. Smith. 2010. Do complexity, governance, and auditor independence influence whether firms retain their auditors for tax services? Journal of the American Taxation Association, Vol. 32 (1): 1-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Lennox, C. 2016. Did the PCAOB’s Restrictions on Auditors’ Tax Services Improve Audit Quality? The Accounting Review, Vol.91: 1493-1512.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Maydew, E. and D. Shackelford. 2007. The changing role of auditors in corporate tax planning, in Auerbach, Hines, and Slemrod. Taxing Corporate Income in the 21st Century, Cambridge University Press. 307-337.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">McGuire S., T. Omer and D. Wang. 2012. Tax Avoidance: Does Tax-Specific Industry Expertise Make a Difference. The Accounting Review, Vol. 87: 975-1003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Mills, L., Erickson, M. M., &amp; Maydew, E. L. (1998). Investments in Tax Planning. The Journal of the American Taxation Association, 20(1), 1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Omer, T., J. Bedard, and D. Falsetta. 2006. Auditor-Provided Tax Services: The Effects of a Changing Regulatory Environment. The Accounting Review. Vol. 81(5): 1095-117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">PCAOB - Public Accounting Oversight Board. (n.d.) https://pcaobus.org/About/Pages/default.aspx</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">PCAOB -.2005. Adopting Brief: Board Considers Ethics and Independence Rules Concerning Independence, Tax Services, and Contingent Fees. Washington, D.C.: PCAOB.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">SEC - Securities and Exchange Commission. (n.d.) https://www.sec.gov/ansIrs/about-lawsshtml.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">SEC -.2000. Revision of the Commission’s Auditor Independence Requirements. SEC Final Rule S7-13-00. Washington, D.C.: Securities and Exchange Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">SEC -. 2003. Strengthening the Commission’s Requirements Regarding Auditor Independence. SEC Final Rule S7-49-02. Washington, D.C.: Securities and Exchange Commission.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Sample Selection</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Spearman/Pearson Correlation Matrix</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4 - Panel A</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Regression Results Using One-Year GAAPETR and CASHETR Under Different Functional Forms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4 - Panel B</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Regression Results Using Three-Year GAAPETR and CASHETR Under Different Functional Forms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Regression Results Using One-Year GAAPETR and CASHETR Under Different Functional Forms at each Quartile</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Regression Results From Cross-sectional Tests of GAAPETR and CASHETR</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
