<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285043</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fatigue Analysis of Continuously Carbon Fiber Reinforced Laminates</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Gaier</surname>
                  <given-names>Christian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magna Engineering Center Steyr GmbH&amp;CoKG</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fischmeister</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Magna Engineering Center Steyr GmbH&amp;CoKG</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Maier</surname>
                  <given-names>Julia</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University Leoben</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pinter</surname>
                  <given-names>Gerald</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University Leoben</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>305</fpage>
         <lpage>315</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285043"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Lightweight constructions and the reduction of production time and costs is of increasingly importance. Therefore, engineers make a lot of effort to replace metallic parts by other materials. Carbon fiber reinforced laminates are suitable in many cases because of their high specific strength and the low specific weight. The available material-data of this material group from datasheets are mostly static values like tensile strength and fracture elongation. For the fatigue assessment of parts regarding geometry, loading conditions and material behavior, static material data are not sufficient, but also the knowledge of the local S-N curve is necessary. Component specific effects, such as fiber orientation, type of loading, mean stress, temperature, production process and many more, essentially influence these local S-N curves, determined by the material. For fatigue life prediction an assessment method was established, which takes into account the fiber orientation and considers different types of failure mechanisms like fiber fracture, inter fiber fracture and delamination. As input data, structural stresses are needed analyzed by the Finite Element Method, where the local orthotropic material behavior for each ply has been considered. A hypothesis for fatigue life prediction of orthotropic carbon fiber reinforced materials has been derived based on the well-known static failure criterion of Puck, implemented into a standard fatigue software tool and verified so far with component tests. The hypothesis is applicable even for general random-like and multi-axial loads.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puck A. Festigkeitsanalyse von Faser-Matrix-Laminaten: Modelle für die Praxis. München, Wien: Hanser; 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puck A, Schürmann H. Failure analysis of FRP laminates by means of physically based phenomenological models. Composites Science and Technology 1998(58):1045-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puck A, Schürmann H. Failure analysis of FRP laminates by means of physically based phenomenological models. Composite Science and Technology 2002(62):1633-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hashin Z. Finite thermoelastic fracture criterion with application to laminate cracking analysis. J. Mech.Phys.Solids 1996(Vol.44 No.7):1129-45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsai S, Wu E. A General Theory of Strength for Anisotropic Materials. Journal of Composite Materials 1971(Vol. 5):58-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deuschle H. 3D failure analysis of UD fibre reinforced composites: Puck's theory within FEA. Dissertation. Stuttgart; 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Talreja R. Fatigue of Composite Materials. Pennsylvania, U.S.A: Technomic Publishing Inc; 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Talreja R, Singh CV. Damage and failure of composite materials. Cambridge, New York: Cambridge University Press; 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reifsnider KL (ed.). Fatigue of composite materials. Amsterdam, New York: Elsevier; 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eftekhari M. and Fatemi A., “On the Strengthening Effect of Increasing Cycling Frequency on Fatigue Behavior of Some Polymers and Their Composites: Experiments and Modeling”, Int. J. of Fatigue, 2016;87:153-166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawai M. A phenomenological model for off-axis fatigue behavior of unidirectional polymer matrix composites under different stress ratios. Composites Part A: Applied Science and Manufacturing 2004;35(7- 8):955-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ladevèze P, Lubineau G. A computational mesodamage model for life prediction for laminates. In: Harris B, editor. Fatigue in composites: Science and technology of the fatigue response of fibre-reinforced plastics. Cambridge: Woodhead; CRC Press; 2003, p. 432-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lubineau G, Ladevèze P, Violeau D. Durability of CFRP laminates under thermomechanical loading: A micro-meso damage model. Composites Science and Technology 2006;66(7-8):983-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Philippidis TP, Vassilopoulos AP. Life prediction methodology for GFRP laminates under spectrum loading. Composites Part A: Applied Science and Manufacturing 2004;35(6):657-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Magna Engineering Center Steyr. FEMFAT software: advanced engineering services by Magna Powertrain; Available from: http://www.femfat.com/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichlseder W. Fatigue analysis by local stress concept. Computers &amp; Structures 2002(80):2109-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Unger B, Dannbauer H, Eichlseder W. Virtual Fatigue Optimisation of Automotive Structures. Engineering Integrity 2004;15(1):6-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaier C, Dannbauer H. A Multiaxial Fatigue Analysis Method for Ductile, Semi-Ductile, and Brittle Materials: Arabian Journal for Science &amp; Engineering, Volume 33, Number 1B, April 2008, pp. 223-235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaier C, Pramhas G, Steiner W. An Extended Critical Plane Criterion for General Load Situations. In: Blom AF, editor. Proceedings of the 8th International Fatigue Conference June 3-7 2002 Stockholm Sweden//Heath, West Midlands, UK: Engineering Materials Advisory Services; 2002, pp. 259-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaier C, Hofwimmer K, Dannbauer H. Accurate and Efficient Methods for Multiaxial Fatigue Analysis, Proceedings NAFEMS World Congress, 9th-12th June 2013, Salzburg.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaier C, Unger B, Dannbauer H. Multiaxial fatigue analysis of orthotropic materials. Rev. Metall. 2010;107(9):369-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guster C, Pinter G, Mösenbacher A, Eichlseder W. Evaluation of a Simulation Process for Fatigue Life Calculation of Short Fibre Reinforced Plastic Components. Procedia Engineering 2011;10:2104-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mösenbacher A, Brunbauer J, Pichler PF, Guster C, Pinter G. Modelling and validation of fatigue life calculation for short fibre reinforced injection moulded parts. In: ECCM16, editor. 16th European Conference on Composite Materials; 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaier C. Investigations on a statistical measure of the nonproportionality of stresses. International Journal of Fatigue 2004;26(4):331-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaier C, Fleischer H, Guster C, Pinter G. Influence of Fiber Orientation, Temperature and Moisture on the Fatigue Behavior of Injection Molded Fiber Reinforced Thermoplastics//Einfluss von Faserorientierung, Temperatur und Feuchtigkeit auf das Ermüdungsverhalten von kurzfaserverstärkten Thermoplasten. MP 2010;52(7-8):534-42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Radaj D. Ermüdungsfestigkeit: Grundlagen für Leichtbau, Maschinenund Stahlbau. 3rd ed. Berlin [u.a.]: Springer; 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haibach E. Betriebsfestigkeit: Verfahren und Daten zur Bauteilberechnung. Berlin: Springer; 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Orth M, Butz M, Gaier C. Entwicklung einer Methode zur Betriebsfestigkeitsanalyse von Strukturbauteilen aus CFK unter Zuhilfenahme verschiedener statischer Versagenskriterien//Development of a method for the durability assessment of structural parts made from carbon fiber reinforced plastics (CFRP) based on various static failure criteria. In: DVM, editor. 40. Tagung DVM Arbeitskreis Betriebsfestigkeit; 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brunbauer J, Stadler H, Pinter G. Mechanical properties, fatigue damage and microstructure of carbon/epoxy laminates depending on fibre volume content. International Journal of Fatigue 2015;70:85-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM International. Standard Test Method for Tensile Properties of Polymer Matrix Composite Materials (ASTM D3039/D3039M-00). West Conshohocken, PA, United States: ASTM International; 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM International. Standard Test Method for Compressive Properties of Polymer Matrix Composite Materials with Unsupported Gage Section by Shear Loading (ASTM D3410/D3410M-03). West Conshohocken, PA, United States: ASTM International; 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM International. Standard Test Method for In-Plane Shear Response of Polymer Matrix Composite Materials by Tensile Test of a ±45° Laminate (ASTM D3518/D3518M-94). West Conshohocken, PA, United States: ASTM International; 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brunbauer J, Pinter G. Effects of mean stress and fibre volume content on the fatigue-induced damage mechanisms in CFRP. International Journal of Fatigue 2015;75:28-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brunbauer J, Pinter G. On the strain measurement and stiffness calculation of carbon fibre reinforced composites under quasi-static tensile and tension-tension fatigue loads. Polymer Testing 2014;40:256- 64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM International. Standard Practice for Statistical Analysis of Linear or Linearized Stress -Life (S-N) and Strain-Life (e-N) Fatigue Data (ASTM E739-91). West Conshohocken, PA, United States: ASTM International; 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schürmann H. Konstruieren mit Faser-Kunststoff-Verbunden: Mit 39 Tabellen. 2nd ed. Berlin, Heidelberg, New York, NY: Springer; 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuchs PF, Pinter G, Tonjec M. Determination of the orthotropic material properties of individual layers of printed circuit boards. Microelectronics Reliability 2012;52(11):2723-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brunbauer J, Pinter G. Fatigue life prediction of carbon fibre reinforced laminates by using cycle-dependent classical laminate theory. Composites Part B: Engineering 2015;70:167-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reifsnider KL, Talug A. Analysis of fatigue damage in composite laminates. International Journal of Fatigue 1980;2(1):3-11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Talreja R. Damage Characterization. In: Reifsnider KL, editor. Fatigue of composite materials. Amsterdam, New York: Elsevier; 1991, p. 79- 103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kirchberger H., Fischmeister S., Dannbauer H., Puchner K., Development of a multifunctional truck cross member made of continuous fiber reinforced plastics, SIMULIA Community Conference, Berlin, Germany, May 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guideline VDI 2014 Part 3, Development of FRP components (fibrereinforced plastics) - Analysis, Düsseldorf, Germany September 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
