<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169042</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optimizing Lithium-Ion Batteries - Tailoring Electrodes for Microhybrid Vehicle Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sisk</surname>
                  <given-names>Brian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhenli</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Johnson Controls Power Solutions</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169031</issue-id>
         <fpage>86</fpage>
         <lpage>97</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169042"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Design of batteries for automotive applications requires a careful balance between vehicle requirements - as driven by automakers - and cost. Typically, for batteries, the goal is to meet the most stringent requirement at a competitive cost. The real challenge in doing so is understanding how the battery-level requirements vary with changes in the vehicle, powertrain, and drive cycle.</p>
            <p>In this work, we consider the relationship between vehicle-level and battery-level requirements of microhybrid vehicles and their linkage with battery design. These vehicle platforms demand high-power pulses for impractical durations - over 60 seconds on some drive cycles.</p>
            <p>We demonstrate a method for optimizing the battery design for fuel economy against any specific drive cycle, whether regulatory, consumer, or otherwise. This method allows for a high degree of customization against manufacturer or consumer value. Electrochemical modeling and vehicle modeling, coupled with experimental validation, is used to investigate the effects of key battery design parameters - such as particle size and coating thickness - on the energy and power capability of lithium ion batteries.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crowe, P., HybridCARS, September 19, 2013. Accessed October 15, 2013, http://www.hybridcars.com/48-volt-micro-hybrid-systemunveiled/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, U., “Meet the Microhybrid: A new Class of Green Cars.” Forbes, January 17, 2012. Accessed October 15, 2013, http://www.forbes.com/sites/uciliawang/2012/01/17/a-new-class-of-hybridelectric- car-emerges-to-woo-consumers/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burke, A. “Ultracapacitor technologies and application in hybrid and electric vehicles.” International Journal of Energy Research 34.2 (2010): 133-151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, Y., Zhao, F., Luo, Y., and Li K. “Energy Optimization for the Mild Hybrid Electric Vehicle with CVT Under Driving Conditions.” In Proceedings of the FISITA 2012 World Automotive Congress, pp. 375-386. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Obama Administration Finalizes Historic 54.5 mpg Fuel Efficiency Standards” National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, August 28, 2012. Accessed October 15, 2013, http://www.nhtsa.gov/About+NHTSA/Press+Releases/2012/Obama+Administration+Fina lizes+Historic+54.5+mpg+Fuel+Efficiency+Standards</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, S., Changqing, D., Fuwu, Y., et al. “A Rule-Based Energy Management Strategy for a New BSG Hybrid Electric Vehicle.” In Intelligent Systems (GCIS), 2012 Third Global Congress on, pp. 209-212. IEEE, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moawad, A., Kim, N., and Rousseau, A., “Impact of Technology on Electric Drive Fuel Consumption and Cost,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1011, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Halbach, S., Sharer, P., Pagerit, S., Rousseau, A. et al., “Model Architecture, Methods, and Interfaces for Efficient Math-Based Design and Simulation of Automotive Control Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0241, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Doyle, M., Fuller T., and Newman, J. Journal of the Electrochemical Society 140 (1993): 1526-1533.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, S-L., et al. “High Rate Capability of Li(Ni1/3Mn1/3Co1/3)O2 Electrode for Li-ion Batteries.” Journal of the Electrochemistry Society 159, no. 4 (2012): A438-A444.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Subramanian, V.R. “Mathematical Model Reformulation for Lithium- Ion Battery Simulations: Galvanostatic Boundary Conditions”, J. Electrochem. Soc. 156(2009): A260-A271</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guo, M., Sikha, G., and White, R.E, Journal of the Electrochemical Society 158 (2011): A122-A132</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, K. and Wang, C-Y. “Solid-state diffusion limitations on pulse operation of a lithium on cell for hybrid electric vehicles.” Journal of Power Sources 161 (2006): 628-639.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tarascon, J.-M. and Armand, M. “Issues and Challenges Facing Rechargeable Lithium Batteries”, Nature 414(2001): 359-367.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Braithwaite, J.W., Gonzales, A., Nagasubramanian, G., et al. “Corrosion of Lithium-ion Battery Current Collectors”, J. Electrochem. Soc. 146(1999), 448-456.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ceraolo, M., Huria, T., et al. “Lithium-ion starting-lighting-ignition batteries: Examining the feasibility.” In Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference (VPPC), 2011 IEEE, pp. 1-6. IEEE, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andre, D., Meiler, M., Steiner, K., et al. “Characterization of High-Power Lithium-ion batteries by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. I. Experimental Investigation”, J. Electrochem. Soc. 196(2011) 5334-5341.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nelson, P.A., Santini, D.J., and Barnes, J. “Factors Determining the Manufacturing Costs of Lithium-Ion Batteries for PHEVs.” EVS24 International Battery, Hybrid and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicle Symposium, Stavanger, Norway, May 13-16, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barré, A., Deguilhem, B., Grolleau, S., et al., “A review on lithiumion battery ageing mechanisms and estimations for automotive applications.” Journal of Power Sources 241 (2013): 680-689.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, K., Markel, T., and Pesaran, A. “PHEV battery trade-off study and standby thermal control.” In 26th Int. Battery Seminar &amp; Exhibit, Fort Lauderdale, FL. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wood, E., Alexander, M., and Bradley, T.H. “Investigation of Battery End-of-Life Conditions for Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles”, J. Power Sources 196(2011): 5147-5154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
