<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">finabull</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002263</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Finafrica Bulletin</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Cassa Di Risparmio Delle Provincie Lombarde</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0393456X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">25829504</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CONFERENCE SUR LE CREDIT AGRICOLE EN AFRIQUE SUB-SAHARIENNE ORGANISEE A ACCRA PAR LA F.A.O. / A CONFERENCE ON AGRICULTURAL CREDIT IN AFRICA SOUTH OF SAHARA, ORGANIZED IN ACCRA BY F.A.O.</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Roberto</given-names>
                  <surname>Ruozl</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1974</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i25829502</issue-id>
         <fpage>3</fpage>
         <lpage>10</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25829504"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>A Conference on agricultural credit in Africa south of Sahara, organized by F.A.O. and jointly financed by F.A.O. and the Cassa di Risparmio delle Provincie Lombarde, has been recently held in Accra (Ghana). The Conference was attended by the representatives of many institutions from more than 20 African countries, among whom Mr. A. M. SHERIF the representative for Liberia and a former scholarship holder at FINAFRICA training course. Many problems related to agricultural credit were dealt with. As far as securities are concerned, it has been said that credit institutions should require personal securities above all when granting credit to small farmers since in most cases there is no possibility to get real securities. Collective loans granted to formal and informal organizations were also mentioned and it was noted with satisfaction that the latter involve quite low percentages of insolvency as compared to ordinary African banking practice thus determining lower administrative costs for both parties. On the subject of loan evaluation, the stress was laid on the technical capacity of the borrower rather than on the securities he can supply. Credit institutions must be able to evaluate whether the loan will actually improve production either qualitatively or quantitatively. The report on Ghana underlined the good results obtained with collective loans, the success of agricultural credit schemes and the favourable perspectives for agriculture and financial intermediation in Ghana.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>fre</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e117a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e124" publication-type="other">
R.M. STURGEON, Group loans td small farmers, Ed. F.A.O., Accra, 1973.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e131a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e138" publication-type="other">
R.A.J. ROBERTS, Choosing suitable borrowers from the small-farm sector, Ed.
F.A.O., Accra, 1973.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e148a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e155" publication-type="other">
AGRICULTURAL DEVELOPMENT BANK, Agricultural credit programmes in Ghana,
Accra, 1973.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e165a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e172" publication-type="other">
KIDD DARKO, Help finance agriculture, In « Dally Graflc », Accra, 11/12/1973.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
