<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26789716</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Cellular Helmet Liner Design through Bio-inspired Structures and Topology Optimization of Compliant Mechanism Lattices</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Najmon</surname>
                  <given-names>Joel C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jacob</surname>
                  <given-names>DeHart J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wood</surname>
                  <given-names>Zebulun M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tovar</surname>
                  <given-names>Andres</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">WCX18 Best Papers Special Issue</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26789713</issue-id>
         <fpage>217</fpage>
         <lpage>236</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26789716"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The continuous development of sport technologies constantly demands advancements in protective headgear to reduce the risk of head injuries. This article introduces new cellular helmet liner designs through two approaches. The first approach is the study of energy-absorbing biological materials. The second approach is the study of lattices comprised of force-diverting compliant mechanisms. On the one hand, bio-inspired liners are generated through the study of biological, hierarchical materials. An emphasis is given on structures in nature that serve similar concussion-reducing functions as a helmet liner. Inspiration is drawn from organic and skeletal structures. On the other hand, compliant mechanism lattice (CML)-based liners use topology optimization to synthesize rubber cellular unit cells with effective positive and negative Poisson’s ratios. Three lattices are designed using different cellular unit cell arrangements, namely, all positive, all negative, and alternating effective Poisson’s ratios. The proposed cellular (bio-inspired and CML-based) liners are embedded between two polycarbonate shells, thereby, replacing the traditional expanded polypropylene foam liner used in standard sport helmets. The cellular liners are analyzed through a series of 2D extruded ballistic impact simulations to determine the best performing liner topology and its corresponding rubber hardness. The cellular design with the best performance is compared against an expanded polypropylene foam liner in a 3D simulation to appraise its protection capabilities and verify that the 2D extruded design simulations scale to an effective 3D design.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Mez, J. et al., “Clinicopathological Evaluation of Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy in Players of American Football,” JAMA 318(4):360-370, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Collins, M.W. et al., “Cumulative Effects of Concussion in High School Athletes,” Neurosurgery 51(5):1175-1179, 2002; discussion 1180-1181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">B.H.S.I., “Bicycle Helmet Liners: Foam and Other Materials,” 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Luo, Y. and Liang, Z., “Understanding how a Sport-Helmet Protects the Head from Closed Injury by Virtual Impact Tests,” Bio-Medical Materials and Engineering 28(3):279-291, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Schwizer, P., Demierre, M., and Smith, L.V., “An Experimental and Numerical Study of Softball to Facemask Impacts,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part P: Journal of Sports Engineering and Technology 231(4):336-343, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Teng, T.-L., Liang, C.-C., and Nguyen, V.-H., “Innovative Design of Bicycle Helmet Liners,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part L: Journal of Materials: Design and Applications 228(4):341-351, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Soe, S.P. et al., “Mechanical Characterisation of Duraform Flex for FEA Hyperelastic Material Modelling,” Polymer Testing 34:103-112, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Zhang, Y. and Kwok, T.H., “An Interactive Product Customization Framework for Freeform Shapes,” Rapid Prototyping Journal 23(6):1136-1145, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Moss, W.C., King, M.J., and Blackman, E.G., “Towards Reducing Impact-Induced Brain Injury: Lessons from a Computational Study of Army and Football Helmet Pads,” Computer Methods in Biomechanics and Biomedical Engineering 17(11):1173-1184, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Johnson, K.L. et al., “Constrained Topological Optimization of a Football Helmet Facemask Based on Brain Response,” Materials and Design 111:108-118, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Smith, T.A. et al., “Angular Head Motion with and without Head Contact: Implications for Brain Injury,” Sports Engineering 18(3):165-175, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Shuaeib, F.M. et al., “A New Motorcycle Helmet Liner Material: The Finite Element Simulation and Design of Experiment Optimization,” Materials and Design 28(1):182-195, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Halimi, M.T., Hassen, M.B., and Sakli, F., “Design of a Novel Comfort Liner for a Motorcycle Helmet,” International Journal of Sustainable Engineering 5(2):128-134, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Blanco, D.H., Cernicchi, A., and Galvanetto, U., “Design of an Innovative Optimized Motorcycle Helmet,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part P: Journal of Sports Engineering and Technology 228(2):95-110, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Mills, N.J. and Gilchrist, A., “Bicycle Helmet Design,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part L: Journal of Materials: Design and Applications 220(4):167-180, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Soe, S.P. et al., “Feasibility of Optimising Bicycle Helmet Design Safety through the Use of Additive Manufactured TPE Cellular Structures,” International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology 79(9-12):1975-1982, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Johnson, K., “Princeton Schools to Become the First in State to Require Headgear for Soccer, Lacrosse and Field Hockey Players,” 2013, http://www.nj.com/mercer/index. ssf/2013/08/princeton_schools_become_the_first_in_the_state_to_require_headgear_for_soccer_lacrosse_and_field_ho.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Helmets.org., “Helmets for Many Activities,” 2016, http://www.bhsi.org/other.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Neurology, A.A.o., “Helmet Add-Ons May Not Lower Concussion Risk in Athletes,” 2015, https://www.aan.com/PressRoom/Home/PressRelease/1347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Fu, K. et al., “Bio-Inspired Design: An Overview Investigating Open Questions from the Broader Field of Design-by-Analogy,” Journal of Mechanical Design, Transactions of the ASME 136(11), 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Gibson, L.J. and Ashby, M.F., “Energy Absorption in Cellular Materials,” Cellular Solids: Structure and Properties, Second Edition (Cambridge, Cambridge University Press, 1997), 309-344.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Wang, J. and Rai, R., “Classification of Bio-Inspired Periodic Cubic Cellular Materials Based on Compressive Deformation Behaviors of 3D Printed Parts and FE Simulations,” in 28th International Conference on Design Theory and Methodology, Charlotte, NC, 2016, V007T06A003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Vincent, J.F. and Mann, D.L., “Systematic Technology Transfer from Biology to Engineering,” Philos Trans A Math Phys Eng Sci 360(1791):159-173, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Tinsley, A. et al., “Exploring the Use of Functional Models as a Foundation for Biomimetic Conceptual Design,” in 19th International Conference Design Theory and Methodology and 1st International Conference Micro and Nano Systems, Presented at the 2007 ASME International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference, IDETC/CIE2007, Sept. 4-7, 2007 (Las Vegas, NV: American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME), 2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Nagel, J.K.S., Nagel, R.L., and Eggermont, M., “Teaching Biomimicry with an Engineering-to-Biology Thesaurus,” in ASME 2013 International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference, IDETC/CIE 2013, American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Portland, OR, Aug. 4, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Chakrabarti, A. et al., “A Functional Representation for Aiding Biomimetic and Artificial Inspiration of New Ideas,” Artificial Intelligence for Engineering Design, Analysis and Manufacturing: AIEDAM 19(2):113-132, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Vattam, S. et al., DANE: Fostering Creativity in and through Biologically Inspired Design (London: Springer, 2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Srinivasan, V. and Chakrabarti, A., “An Empirical Evaluation of Novelty-Sapphire Relationship,” in 2009 ASME International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference, DETC2009, Aug. 30-Sept. 2, 2009 (San Diego, CA, American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME), 2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Buhrig-Polaczek, A. et al., “Biomimetic Cellular Metals - Using Hierarchical Structuring for Energy Absorption,” Bioinspiration and Biomimetics 11(4), 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Looyrach, J. et al., “Pomelo (Citrus Maxima) Peel-Inspired Property for Development of Eco-Friendly Loose-Fill Foam. in 8th International Conference on Materials Science and Technology, MSAT 2014, Dec. 15-16, 2014 (Bangkok, Thailand, Trans Tech Publications Ltd., 2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Wang, B., Pan, B., and Lubineau, G., “Morphological Evolution and Internal Strain Mapping of Pomelo Peel Using X-Ray Computed Tomography and Digital Volume Correlation,” Materials and Design 137:305-315, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Mehta, P.S. et al., “Bio-Inspired Design of Lightweight and Protective Structures,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0396, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Naleway, S.E. et al., “Structural Design Elements in Biological Materials: Application to Bioinspiration,” Advanced Materials 27(37):5455-5476, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Wang, B. et al., “Keratin: Structure, Mechanical Properties, Occurrence in Biological Organisms, and Efforts at Bioinspiration,” Progress in Materials Science 76:229-318, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Gibson, L.J., Ashby, M.F., and Harley, B.A., Cellular Materials in Nature and Medicine (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Chintapalli, R.K. et al., “Fabrication, Testing and Modeling of a New Flexible Armor Inspired from Natural Fish Scales and Osteoderms,” Bioinspiration and Biomimetics 9(3):036005, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Wang, L. et al., “Why Do Woodpeckers Resist Head Impact Injury: A Biomechanical Investigation,” PLoS ONE 6(10):e26490, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Oda, J., Sakamoto, J., and Sakano, K., “Mechanical Evaluation of the Skeletal Structure and Tissue of the Woodpecker and Its Shock Absorbing System,” JSME International Journal, Series A: Solid Mechanics and Material Engineering 49(3):390-396, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Yoon, S.-H., Roh, J.-E., and Kim, K.L., “Woodpecker-Inspired Shock Isolation by Microgranular Bed,” Journal of Physics D: Applied Physics 42(3):035501, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Wu, Y. et al., “Dynamic Crash Responses of Bio-Inspired Aluminum Honeycomb Sandwich Structures with CFRP Panels,” Composites Part B: Engineering 121:122-133, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Jiang, C. et al., “Freeform Honeycomb Structures,” Comput. Graph. Forum 33(5):185-194, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Schaedler, T.A. et al., “Designing Metallic Microlattices for Energy Absorber Applications,” Advanced Engineering Materials 16(3):276-283, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Stephani, G. et al., “Iron Based Cellular Structures - Status and Prospects,” Advanced Engineering Materials 8(9):847-852, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Goehler, H. et al., “Functionalized Metallic Hollow Sphere Structures,” Advanced Engineering Materials 16(3):335-339, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Li, M.-Z., Stephani, G., and Kang, K.-J., “New Cellular Metals with Enhanced Energy Absorption: Wire-Woven Bulk Kagome (WBK)-Metal Hollow Sphere (MHS) Hybrids,” Advanced Engineering Materials 13(1-2):33-37, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Tay, Y.Y., Lim, C.S., and Lankarani, H.M., “A Finite Element Analysis of High- Energy Absorption Cellular Materials in Enhancing Passive Safety of Road Vehicles in Side-Impact Accidents,” International Journal of Crashworthiness 19(3):288-300, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Pinto, P. et al., “Compressive Properties and Energy Absorption of Aluminum Foams with Modified Cellular Geometry,” Journal of Materials Processing Technology 214(3):571-577, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Schaedler, T.A. and Carter, W.B., “Architected Cellular Materials,” Annual Review of Materials Research 46:187-210, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Gokhale, V.V. et al., “Design of an Advanced Layered Composite for Energy Dissipation using a 3D-Lattice of Micro Compliant Mechanism,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-1538, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-1538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Gokhale, V., Tapkir, and Tovar, A., “Force Diverting Helmet Liner Achieved through a Lattice of Multi-Material Compliant Mechanisms,” in ASME 2017 International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference, IDETC/CIE 2017, Aug. 6-9, 2017 (Cleveland, OH: American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME)).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Najmon, J.C., “Design of Compliant Mechanism Lattice Structures for Impact Energy Absorption,” Mechanical Engineering, Purdue University, Indianapolis, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Lu, G. and Yu, T., “Chapter 2: Methodology of Analysing Energy-Absorption Capacities,” in Energy Absorption of Structures and Materials, Lu, G. and Yu, T., Editors (Woodhead Publishing, 2003), 25-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Thielen, M., Speck, T., and Seidel, R., “Impact Behaviour of Freeze-Dried and Fresh Pomelo (Citrus Maxima) Peel: Influence of the Hydration State,” Royal Society Open Science 2(6):140322, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Thielen, M., Schuler, P., and Fischer S.F., “Biomimetic Engineering: Learning from Nature,” 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Fukuda, Y., “Histology of the Long Digital Tentacles,” in Nautilus: The Biology and Paleobiology of a Living Fossil, Reprint with Additions, Saunders, W.B. and Landman, N.H., Editors (Dordrecht, the Netherlands, Springer, 2010), 249-256.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Liu, K. and Tovar, A., “An Efficient 3D Topology Optimization Code Written in Matlab,” Structural and Multidisciplinary Optimization 50(6):1175-1196, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Svanberg, K., “The Method of Moving Asymptotes - A New Method for Structural Optimization,” International Journal for Numerical Methods in Engineering 24(2):359-373, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c58">NOCSAE, “Standard Test Method and Equipment Used in Evaluating the Performance Characteristics of Headgear/Equipment, in Certification of New Equipment,” National Operating Committee on Standards for Athletic Equipment, 2017, http://nocsae.org/standards/certification-of-new-equipment/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Hallquist, J.O., LS-DYNA Theory Manual (Livermore, CA: Livermore Software Technology Corporation, 2006).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Altidis, P., Warner B., and Adams V., “Analyzing Hyperelastic Materials with Some Practical Considerations,” IMPACT Engineering Solutions, Inc., 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Wohlers, T. and Gornet, T., “History of Additive Manufacturing,” 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Bouix, R., Viot, P., and Lataillade, J.-L., “Polypropylene Foam Behaviour under Dynamic Loadings: Strain Rate, Density and Microstructure Effects,” International Journal of Impact Engineering 36(2):329-342, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Gennarelli, T.A. et al., “Directional Dependence of Axonal Brain Injury due to Centroidal and Non-Centroidal Acceleration,” SAE Technical Paper 872197, 1987, doi:10.4271/872197.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Post, A. et al., “Peak Linear and Rotational Acceleration Magnitude and Duration Effects on Maximum Principal Strain in the Corpus Callosum for Sport Impacts,” Journal of Biomechanics 61:183-192, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c65">McHenry, B.G., “Head Injury Criterion and the ATB,” 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Mackay, M., “The Increasing Importance of the Biomechanics of Impact Trauma,” Sadhana 32(4):397-408, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Saaty, T., Thibault, L., Tomei, G., and Wiser, R., “Relative Measurement and Its Generalization in Decision Making Why Pairwise Comparisons Are Central in Mathematics for the Measurement of Intangible Factors the Analytic Hierarchy/Network Process,” RACSAM - Revista de la Real Academia de Ciencias Exactas, Fisicas y Naturales. Serie A. Matematicas 102(2):251-318, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Bio-inspired designs: (a) pumpkin, (b) stacked diatom skeletal, (c) internal Fibonacci spiral, (d) haystack, (e) wheel spoke, (f) external Fibonacci spiral, (g) spiral wave, (h) double helix, (i) hexagonal spring. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Flowchart of the bio-inspired design process. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Example of a bio-inspired design: biological form of a diatom skeletal remains under an electron microscope (left) and the corresponding engineering form (right) reproduced in Zbrush. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Section of 1 × 3 cellular unit cells of the peel design (bottom) inspired by the dense and porous layers (exocarp and mesocarp) of a pomelo peel (top) [54]. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Section of 1 × 3 cellular unit cells of the shell design (bottom) inspired by the cross-sectional topology of a nautilus shell (top). © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Section of 1 × 3 cellular unit cells of the bone design (bottom) inspired by the sandwich of (a) compact and (b) spongy bone found in a woodpecker’s skull (top) [37]. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Optimized topologies of the positive mechanism (left) and the negative mechanism (right) with corresponding section views of loads and boundary conditions of a quarter design domain. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Three-dimensional optimized topologies of positive (top) and negative (bottom) mechanisms. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Simulation of NOCSAE Drop Test Method ND 001 on a basic foam-based helmet to determine width of (top side) impact area. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Bio-inspired liner assemblies: peel liner (top), shell liner (middle), and bone liner (bottom). © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>CML-based liner assemblies: positive liner PL (top), negative liner NL (middle), and zero liner ZL (bottom). © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>2D ballistic simulation setup for the positive liner (PL) design. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Pairwise comparison table for weight calculation. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Deformation at peak displacement of the inner shell for (a) peel liner (d<sub>max</sub> = 1.6 mm), (b) shell liner (d<sub>max</sub> = 2.8 mm), (c) bone liner (d<sub>max</sub> = 1.9 mm), (d) positive liner PL (d<sub>max</sub> = 1.9 mm), (e) negative liner NL (d<sub>max</sub> = 1.4 mm), and (f) zero liner ZL (d<sub>max</sub> = 2.8 mm) (MEP test pad hidden for clarity). © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Displacement-acceleration and time-acceleration profiles of the six (basic) liners using Shore 60A rubber. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>PIE as a function of the horizontal position of the unit cells for the bio-inspired and CML-based (basic) liners using Shore 60A rubber. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Performance [normalized] values for the analysis of basic liners. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Displacement-acceleration and time-acceleration profiles for the parametric study of the peel (40A-70A), PL (50A-80A), and foam liners. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>PIE as a function of the horizontal position of the unit cells for the parametric study of the peel, PL, and foam liners. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Performance [normalized] values for the parametric study of rubber hardness. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>3D ballistic simulation setup for the PL design. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Deformation of the 3D PL with 70A rubber at peak displacement of the impactor. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Performance values of the 2D and 3D liners. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Displacement-acceleration and time-acceleration profiles for the EPP foam liner and CML-based PL design with 70A rubber: comparison of 2D and 3D models. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Polycarbonate shell material keycard. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Impactor material keycard. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Natural rubber material keycard. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.4</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>MEP polyurethane test pad material keycard. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.5</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Expanded polypropylene foam material keycard. © Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
