<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169212</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Dynamics and Simulation of RWD Vehicles Drifting at Steady State using BNP-MNC Tire Model</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chaichaowarat</surname>
                  <given-names>Ronnapee</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wannasuphoprasit</surname>
                  <given-names>Witaya</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Chulalongkorn University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169200</issue-id>
         <fpage>134</fpage>
         <lpage>144</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International and Copyright © 2013 TSAE</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169212"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Drifting, a very popular challenge in the recent motorsport, is a cornering technique with large angle of sideslip when rear tires encounter with combined slip over the linear region of the slip-tire friction characteristic. Besides, this technique is frequently used by expert rally drivers in order to ensure that the vehicle will not understeer. In this work, steady state cornering of a RWD vehicle on plane, with constant speed, sideslip and radius of curvature, was simplified via the single track vehicle model. In addition, BNP magic formula, along with MNC model, was used to estimate tire frictions. The computer program was developed, based on EOMs derived via body fixed coordinate, in order to calculate a suitable cornering speed and corresponding open-loop driving control inputs, steering angle and rear slip ratio, for a given radius of curvature and vehicle sideslip. By comparing the obtainable cornering speeds relating to different sideslips at various radii of curvature, the low-sideslip driving provides maximum speed for almost all radii; however, drifting is faster in some special radius. Due to this advantageous, the development of automatic drifting assistant may be feasible.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS:</label>
            <kwd>Drifting</kwd>
            <kwd>Vehicle dynamics</kwd>
            <kwd>Automotive control</kwd>
            <kwd>Single track vehicle model</kwd>
            <kwd>Dynamics simulation</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Zanten, A. T., Erhardt, R., Landesfeind, G., and Pfaff, K., “Vehicle stabilization by the vehicle dynamics control system ESP,” IFAC Mechatronic Systems, pp. 95-102, Darmstadt, Germany, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshimoto, K., Tanaka, H., and Kawakami, S., “Proposal of driver assistance system for recovering vehicle stability from unstable states by automatic steering,” IEEE International Vehicle Electronics, Changchun, China, Sep. 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tahami, F., Kazemi, R., and Farhanghi, S., “A novel driver assist stability system for all-wheel-drive electric vehicles,” IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, vol. 52, no. 3, pp. 683-692, May. 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gillespie, T. D., “Fundamentals of Vehicle Dynamics,” Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc., Warrendale, PA, ISBN 978-1-56091-199-9, 1992, doi: 10.4271/R-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Velenis, E., Tsiotras, P., and Lu, J., “Modeling aggressive maneuvers on loose surfaces: Data analysis and input parameterization,” Mediterranean Conference on Control and Automation, Athens, Greece, June. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Velenis, E., Tsiotras, P., and Lu, J., “Modeling aggressive maneuvers on loose surfaces: The cases of trail-braking and pendulum-turn,” European Control Conference, Kos, Greece, July. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdulrahim, M., “On the Dynamics of Automobile Drifting,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1019, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Velenis, E., Frazzoli, E., and Tsiotras, P., “On steady-state cornering equilibria for wheeled vehicles with drift,” Decision and Control, 2009, the 28th Chinese Control Conference, CDC/CCC., 2009, the 48th IEEE Conference, 2009. 3545-3550.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bakker, E., Nyborg, L., and Pacejka, H., “Tyre Modeling for Use in Vehicle Dynamics Studies,” SAE Technical Paper 870421, 1987, doi: 10.4271/870421.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Velenis, E., Katzourakis, D., Frazolli, E., Tsiotras, P. and Happee, R., “Steady-State Drifting Stabilization of RWD Vehicles,” Control Engineering Practice, Vol. 19, No. 11, Nov. 2011, pp. 1363-1376, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Velenis, E., Katzourakis, D., Frazolli, E., Tsiotras, P. and Happee, R., “Stabilization of Steady-State Drifting for a RWD Vehicle,” 10th International Symposium on Advanced Vehicle Control (AVEC), Loughborough, UK, August 22-26, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chaichaowarat, R., Wannasuphoprasit, W., “Two Dimensional Dynamic Model of Drifting Vehicle,” the 7th International Conference on Automotive Engineering, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Tire Model in Driving Simulator” http://code.eng.buffalo.edu/dat/sites/tire/tire.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Branch, R., and Branch, M., “The Tire-Force Ellipse (Friction Ellipse) and Tire Characteristics,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0094, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0094.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nicolas, V. T., Comstock, T. R., “Predicting Directional Behavior of Tractor Semitrailers When Wheel Anti-Skid Brake Systems Are Used”, Paper No. 72 - WA/Aut-16, ASME Winter Annual Meeting, November 26-30, 1972</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
