<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26649126</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of Chemistry-Based Laminar Flame Speed Correlation for Part-Load SI Conditions and Validation in a GDI Research Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Del Pecchia</surname>
                  <given-names>Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Breda</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastiano</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>d’Adamo</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fontanesi</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefano</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Irimescu</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Merola</surname>
                  <given-names>Simona</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>6</issue>
         <issue-id>e26649117</issue-id>
         <fpage>715</fpage>
         <lpage>742</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26649126"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>The detailed study of part-load conditions is essential to characterize engine-out emissions in key operating conditions. The relevance of part-load operations is further emphasized by the recent regulations such as the new WLTP standard.</p> 
            <p>Combustion development at part-load operations depends on a complex interplay between moderate turbulence levels (low engine speed and tumble ratio), low in-cylinder pressure and temperature, and stoichiometric-to-lean mixture quality (to maximize fuel efficiency). From a modelling standpoint, the reduced turbulence intensity compared to full-load operations complicates the interaction between different sub-models (e.g., reconsideration of the flamelet hypothesis adopted by common combustion models).</p> 
            <p>In this article, the authors focus on chemistry-based simulations for laminar flame speed of gasoline surrogates at conditions typical of part-load operations. The analysis is an extension of a previous study focused on full-load operations. The methodology is based on detailed chemistry 1D simulations of the flame structure. The comparison with the previous research reveals that flames at partial loads experience analogous temperature levels, despite the generally lower pressure. Therefore, particular attention will be devoted to the temperature scaling of flame speed, as well as to the extension to lean mixtures.</p> 
            <p>A correlation is proposed for laminar flame speed, and it is applied to simulate the combustion development on a single-cylinder research engine operated at 0.7 bar absolute pressure part-load condition. The engine is provided with an optical access to the combustion chamber, allowing a detailed comparison of the flame development since early flame kernel growth. The relevance of an accurate laminar flame speed modelling is then discussed in details.</p> 
            <p>The correlation for laminar flame speed proposed by the authors constitutes a useful reference for similar studies, and it can be used in conjunction with the most common CFD combustion models.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Tutuianu, M., Bonnel, P., Ciuffo, B., Haniu, T. et al., “Development of the World-Wide Harmonized Light Duty Test Cycle (WLTC) and a Possible Pathway for Its Introduction in the European Legislation,” Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment 40:61-75, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.trd.2015.07.011, ISSN: 1361-9209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Marotta, A., Pavlovic, J., Ciuffo, B., Serra, S. et al., “Gaseous Emissions from Light-Duty Vehicles: Moving from NEDC to the New WLTP Test Procedure,” Environmental Science &amp; Technology 49, 2015, doi:10.1021/acs.est.5b01364.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Colin, O. and Benkenida, A., “The 3-Zone Extended Coherent Flame Model (ECFM3Z) for Computing Premixed/Diffusion Combustion,” Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology 59(6):593-609, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Peters, N., Turbulent Combustion (Cambridge University Press, 2000).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Veynante, D. and Vervisch, L., “Turbulent Combustion Modeling,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 28:193-266, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Metghalchi, M. and Keck, J.C., “Burning Velocities of Mixtures of Air with Methanol, Isooctane, and Indolene at High Pressure and Temperature,” Combustion and Flame 48:191-210, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Gulder, O., Laminar Burning Velocities of Methanol, Ethanol, and Isooctane-Air Mixtures (Combustion Institute, 1982), 275-281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Zhao, Z., Conley, J., Kazakov, A., and Dryer, F., “Burning Velocities of Real Gasoline Fuel at 353 K and 500 K,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3265, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 3265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c9">D’Adamo, A., Del Pecchia, M., Breda, S., Berni, F. et al., “Chemistry-Based Laminar Flame Speed Correlations for a Wide Range of Engine Conditions for Iso-Octane, N-Heptane, Toluene and Gasoline Surrogate Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-2190, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01- 2190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bradley, D., Sheppart, C.G.W., Woolley, R., Greenhalgh, D.A. et al., “The Development and Structure of Flame Instabilities and Cellularity at Low Markstein Numbers in Explosions,” Combustion and Flame 122(1-2):195-209, 2000, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(00)00113-9, ISSN: 0010-2180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Bradley, D., Hicks, R.A., Lawes, M., Sheppard, C.G.W. et al., “The Measurement of Laminar Burning Velocities and Markstein Numbers for Iso-Octane-Air and Iso-Octane-NHeptane- Air Mixtures at Elevated Temperatures and Pressures in an Explosion Bomb,” Combustion and Flame- Combust Flame 115:126-144, 1998, doi:10.1016/S0010- 2180(97)00349-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Knop, V., Benkenida, A., Jay, S., and Colin, O., “Modelling of Combustion and Nitrogen Oxide Formation in Hydrogen- Fuelled Internal Combustion Engines within a 3D CFD Code,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy 33:5083- 5097, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2008.06.027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Jerzembeck, S., Peters, N., Pepiot-Desjardins, P., and Pitsch, H., “Laminar Burning Velocities at High Pressure for Primary Reference Fuels and Gasoline: Experimental and Numerical Investigation,” Combust and Flame 156:292- 301, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Rakopoulos, C.D., Kosmadakis, G., and Pariotis, E., “Evaluation of a Combustion Model for the Simulation of Hydrogen Spark-Ignition Engines Using a CFD Code,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy 35:12545-12560, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2010.09.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Verhelst, S., “A Study of the Combustion in Hydrogen- Fuelled Internal Combustion Engines,” Ph.D. thesis, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Gerke, U., Steurs, K., Rebecchi, P., and Boulouchos, K., “Derivation of Burning Velocities of Premixed Hydrogen/Air Flames at Engine Relevant Conditions Using a Single- Cylinder Compression Machine with Optical Access,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy 35:2566-2577, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Verhelst, S., Vancoillie, J., and Demuynck, J., “A Correlation for the Laminar Burning Velocity for Use in Hydrogen Spark Ignition Engine Simulation,” Fuel and Energy Abstracts 36, 2011, doi:957-974. 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2010.10.020.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Ji, C., Liu, X., Wang, S., Gao, B. et al., “Development and Validation of a Laminar Flame Speed Correlation for the CFD Simulation of Hydrogen-Enriched Gasoline Engines,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy 38:1997-2006, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2012.11.139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Di Sarli, V. and Di Benedetto, A., “Laminar Burning Velocity of Hydrogen-Methane/Air Premixed Flames,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy 32:367-346, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Liu, X., Ji, C., Gao, B., Wang, S. et al., “A Laminar Flame Speed Correlation of Hydrogen-Methanol Blends Valid at Engine-Like Conditions,” International Journal of Hydrogen Energy 38:15500-15509, 2013, doi:10.1016/j. ijhydene.2013.09.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c21">D'Adamo, A., Berni, F., Breda, S., Lugli, M. et al., “A Numerical Investigation on the Potentials of Water Injection as a Fuel Efficiency Enhancer in Highly Downsized GDI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0393, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0393.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Sileghem, L., Alekseev, V., Vancoillie, J., Van Geem, K. et al., “Laminar Burning Velocity of Gasoline and the Gasoline Surrogate Components Iso-Octane, N-Heptane and Toluene,” Fuel 112:355-365, 2013, doi:10.1016/j. fuel.2013.05.049.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Szybist, J.P. and Splitter, D.A., “Pressure and Temperature Effects on Fuels with Varying Octane Sensitivity at High Load in SI Engines,” Combustion and Flame 177:49-66, , 2017, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame. 2016.12.002, ISSN: 0010-2180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Ranzi, E., Frassoldati, A., Stagni, A., Pelucchi, M. et al., “Reduced Kinetic Schemes of Complex Reaction Systems: Fossil and Biomass-Derived Transportation Fuels,” International Journal of Chemical Kinetics, doi:10.1002/kin.20867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Cai, L. and Pitsch, H., “Optimized Chemical Mechanism for Combustion of Gasoline Surrogate Fuels,” Combustion and Flame 162:1623-1637, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Andrae, J.C.G., “Comprehensive Chemical Kinetic Modeling of Toluene Reference Fuels Oxidation,” Fuel 107:740-748, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.01.070, ISSN:0016-2361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Gauthier, B.M., Davidson, D.F., and Hanson, R.K., Combust Flame 139:300-311, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Andrae, J.C.G., “Development of a Detailed Kinetic Model for Gasoline Surrogate Fuels,” Fuel 87:2013-2022, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Andrae, J.C.G. and Head, R.A., “HCCI Experiments with Gasoline Surrogate Fuels Modeled by a Semidetailed Chemical Kinetic Model,” Combustion and Flame 156:842-851, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Dirrenberger, P., Glaude, P.A., Bonaceur, R., Le Gall, H. et al., “Laminar Burning Velocity of Gasolines with Addition of Ethanol,” Fuel 115:162-169, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Stagni, A., Cuoci, A., Frassoldati, A., Faravelli, T. et al., “Skeletal Mechanism Reduction through Species- Targeted Sensitivity Analysis,” Combustion and Flame, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Stagni, A., Cuoci, A., Frassoldati, A., Faravelli, T. et al., “Lumping and Reduction of Detailed Kinetic Schemes: An Effective Coupling,” Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Research 53(22):9004-9016, 2014, doi:10.1021/ie403272f.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Kukkadapu, G., Kumar, K., Sung, C.J., Mehl, M. et al., “Experimental and Surrogate Modeling Study of Gasoline Ignition in a Rapid Compression Machine,” Combustion and Flame 159:3066-3078, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2012.05.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Giovannoni, N., Breda, S., Paltrinieri, S., D'Adamo, A. et al., “CFD Analysis of the Effects of Fuel Composition and Injection Strategy on Mixture Preparation and Fuel Deposit Formation in a GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-24- 2408, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Malaguti, S., Fontanesi, S., and Severi, E., “Numerical Analysis of GDI Engine Cold-Start at Low Ambient Temperatures,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Bowditch, F., “A New Tool for Combustion Research a Quartz Piston Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 610002, 1961, doi:10.4271/610002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Irimescu, A., Merola, S.S., Tornatore, C., and Valentino, G., “Development of a Semi-Empirical Convective Heat Transfer Correlation Based on Thermodynamic and Optical Measurements in a Spark Ignition Engine,” Applied Energy 157:777-788, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2015.02.050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Rakopoulos, C.D., Kosmadakis, G.M., Dimaratos, A.M., and Pariotis, E.G., “Investigating the Effect of Crevice Flow on Internal Combustion Engines Using a New Simple Crevice Model Implemented in a CFD Code,” Applied Energy 88:111-126, 2011, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2010.07.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Irimescu, A., Tornatore, C., Merola, S., and Valentino, G., “Combustion Process Investigation in a DISI Engine Fuelled with N-Butanol through Digital Imaging and Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1887, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Breda, S., D’Adamo, A., Fontanesi, S., D'Orrico, F. et al., “Numerical Simulation of Gasoline and N-Butanol Combustion in an Optically Accessible Research Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 10(1):32-55, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01- 0546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <label>41.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Breda, S., D'Adamo, A., Fontanesi, S., Giovannoni, N. et al., “CFD Analysis of Combustion and Knock in an Optically Accessible GDI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(1):641-656, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <label>42.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Han, Z., Parrish, S., Farrell, P.V., and Reitz, R.D., “Modeling Atomization Processes of Pressure-Swirl Hollow-Cone Fuel Sprays,” Atomization and Sprays 7(6):663-684.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <label>43.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Cavicchi, A., Postrioti, L., Giovannoni, N., Fontanesi, S. et al., “Numerical and Experimental Analysis of the Spray Momentum Flux Measuring on a GDI Injector,” Fuel 206:614-627, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2017.06.054, ISSN: 0016- 2361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <label>44.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c44">von Kuensberg Sarre, C., Kong, S., and Reitz, R., “Modeling the Effects of Injector Nozzle Geometry on Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0912, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999- 01-0912.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <label>45.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Boudier, P., Henriot, S., Poinsot, T., and Baritaud, T., “A Model for Turbulent Flame Ignition and Propagation in Spark Ignition Engines,” Symposium (International) on Combustion 24(1):503-510, 1992, doi:10.1016/S0082- 0784(06)80064-0, ISSN: 0082-0784.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <label>46.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Berni, F., Fontanesi, S., Cicalese, G., and D'Adamo, A., “Critical Aspects on the Use of Thermal Wall Functions in CFD In-Cylinder Simulations of Spark-Ignition Engines,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 10(2):547-561, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0569.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <label>47.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Cicalese, G., Berni, F., Fontanesi, S., D'Adamo, A. et al., “A Comprehensive CFD-CHT Methodology for the Characterization of a Diesel Engine: From the Heat Transfer Prediction to the Thermal Field Evaluation,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-2196, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-2196.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <label>48.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Berni, F., Cicalese, G. and Fontanesi, S., “A Modified Thermal Wall Function for the Estimation of Gas-to-Wall Heat Fluxes in CFD in-Cylinder Simulations of High Performance Spark-Ignition Engines,” Applied Thermal Engineering 115:1045-1062, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. applthermaleng.2017.01.055, SSN 1359-311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>p,T<sub>u</sub> traces for all the operating conditions considered from spark time to peak pressure. Red dots: engine conditions (ECs) used for s<sub>L</sub> calculations. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Commercial gasolines and surrogates’ compositions: RD387 [33], Exxon 708629 [22], Total TAE 7000 [30], Gasoline EU5 E95 (present study), Dirrenberger’s surrogate [30] and Gauthier’s Surrogate A [27]. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Research octane number for the gasoline fuels and surrogates considered in the present study. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Calculated s<sub>L</sub> for four different fuel models (mechanism/blend) against experimental data from [13], T<sub>u</sub>=373 K and the following four pressure levels: 10 bar, 15 bar, 20 bar, and 25 bar. Green solid line represents Metghalchi and Keck’s correlation [6] prediction, while orange solid line represents the target for the polynomial fit. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Calculated s<sub>L</sub> for two different fuel models (mechanism/blend) and Metghalchi and Keck’s correlation [6] against experimental data from [22] at 1 bar and three temperature levels: 298 K, 328 K, and 358 K. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Calculated power exponent α for the chosen fuel models against the experimental one for a commercial gasoline [22] and the one predicted by Metghalchi and Keck’s correlation [6]. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Simulated dataset of s<sub>L</sub> for 15 bar and 670 K for gasoline surrogate over the range of equivalence ratio Φ = 0.4 – 2.0 and EGR = 0 % – 10 %. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Relative fitting error of polynomials of Equation 4 against calculated s<sub>L</sub> data for gasoline. The target value for the fitting procedure is the averaged value of the results obtained with the two fuel models previously chosen for a given (p, T<sub>u</sub>, Φ, EGR) condition. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Normalized s<sub>L</sub> values for Φ &lt; 0.7 obtained from the chemical kinetics simulations for three selected ECs considered. Dot colors represent the pressure level, while dot shapes represent the three temperature levels considered (low, medium, and high). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Dependence of normalized s<sub>L</sub> values on equivalence ratio and normalized temperature (T<sub>ref</sub> = 550 K) for Φ &lt; 0.7. Dot shapes represent the equivalence ratios while colors represent the three temperature levels considered (low, medium, and high). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Lean mixtures’ slope coefficient m (above) and y-axis intercept coefficient q (below) dependence on equivalence ratio for the three temperature levels. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Correlation between s<sub>L</sub> values obtained using pressure scaling (PS) and combined temperature-pressure scaling (TPS) for Φ&lt;0.7. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Normalized s<sub>L</sub> values predicted by pressure scaling (PS) and temperature-pressure scaling approach (TPS) for Φ &lt; 0.7 for 35 bar. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Normalized s<sub>L</sub> values predicted by pressure scaling (PS) and temperature-pressure scaling approach (TPS) for Φ &lt; 0.7 for 30 bar. Black-dashed data represent the calculated values, while blue and red lines represent calculated <inline-formula> 
                  <mml:math display="inline">
                     <mml:mrow>
                        <mml:msubsup>
                           <mml:mi>S</mml:mi>
                           <mml:mi>L</mml:mi>
                           <mml:mrow>
                              <mml:mi>n</mml:mi>
                              <mml:mo>,</mml:mo>
                              <mml:mi>l</mml:mi>
                              <mml:mi>e</mml:mi>
                              <mml:mi>a</mml:mi>
                              <mml:mi>n</mml:mi>
                           </mml:mrow>
                        </mml:msubsup>
                     </mml:mrow>
                  </mml:math>
               </inline-formula> with PS and TPS methodologies, respectively. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Normalized s<sub>L</sub> values for Φ &gt; 1.4 obtained from the chemical kinetics simulations for three selected ECs considered. Normalized s<sub>L</sub> values for Φ &gt; 1.4. Colors represent the pressure level while dot shapes represent the temperature level (low, medium, and high). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Dependence of normalized s<sub>L</sub> values on Φ and normalized temperature (T<sub>ref</sub> = 550 K) for Φ &gt; 1.4. Dot shapes represent the Φ value while colors represent the temperature level considered (low, medium, and high). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Rich mixtures’ slope coefficient m (above) and y-axis intercept coefficient q (below) dependence on Φ for the three temperature levels (low, medium, and high). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Correlation between s<sub>L</sub> values obtained using pressure scaling and combined pressure-temperature scaling for Φ &gt; 1.4. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Normalized s<sub>L</sub> values predicted by pressure scaling (PS) and temperature-pressure scaling approach (TPS) for Φ &gt; 1.4 and 5 bar pressure condition. Black-dashed data represent the calculated values while blue and red lines are calculated with PS and TPS methodologies, respectively. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Calculated s<sub>L</sub> data and polynomial fitting form from Equation 10 (for Φ &lt; 0.7), Equation 4 (for 0.7 &lt; Φ &lt; 1.4), and Equation 17 (for Φ &gt; 1.4) for gasoline at four selected ECs. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Schematic representation of the experimental setup and illustration of the optical access. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Engine specifications © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Fuel properties and PIONA characterization © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Flame front evolution detected via UV-visible imaging (top), flame outline (middle), and binary images (bottom) obtained through image processing. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>3D CFD computational grid. The model includes the combustion chamber, intake and exhaust ports, and the crevice between piston and liner. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 23</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>3D CFD mean in-cylinder pressure (top), cumulative apparent heat release rate (center), and apparent heat release rate (bottom) curves against experimental data during the combustion process. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 24</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Main combustion indicators based on the effective mass fraction burnt for the experimental and the 3D CFD cases. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 25</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Comparison between the experimental and calculated flame area as function of the crank angle degree after spark onset. Experimental optical limit is highlighted by the dashed black line. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 26</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Ratio between simulated and experimental (averaged over 100 consecutive cycles) flame area at 15 and 30 CAD ASOS. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 27</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Calculated equivalence ratio and laminar flame speed fields for the considered s<sub>L</sub> correlations at spark onset (690 CA). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 28</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>Modified Metghalchi and Keck’s correlation relative error map against calculated s<sub>L</sub> data for gasoline over the considered EC. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 29</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>Experimental flame centroid relative occurrence in terms of displacement along the y-axis. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>Calculated s<sub>L</sub> data and polynomial fitting form from Equation 10 (for Φ &lt; 0.7), Equation 4 (for 0.7 ≤ Φ ≤1.4), and Equation 17 (for Φ &gt; 1.4) for gasoline at 19 ECs covering from 5 to 35 bar. Also reported are s<sub>L</sub> correlations for RMFD-303 gasoline and for RMFD-303 gasoline modified version with lean and rich mixtures’ extensions, limited to their specific validation range. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE B.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>Fitting coefficients for gasoline s<sub>L</sub>, respectively, valid in the range: 0.7 ≤ Φ ≤ 1.4, Φ &gt; 1.4, and Φ &lt; 0.7 with pressure scaling coefficients. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE B.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-35">
            <p>Temperature scaling coefficients for gasoline s<sub>L</sub> valid for the rich-side extension (Φ &gt; 1.4). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE B.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-36">
            <p>Temperature scaling coefficients for gasoline s<sub>L</sub> valid for the lean-side extension (Φ &lt; 0.7). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
