<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3/4</issue>
         <issue-id>i24440119</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24440126</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental Tests of Survey Responses to Expenditure Questions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
                  <surname>Comerford</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Liam</given-names>
                  <surname>Delaney</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Colm</given-names>
                  <surname>Harmon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>419</fpage>
         <lpage>433</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2009</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440126"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper tests for a number of survey effects in the elicitation of expenditure items. In particular, we examine the extent to which individuals use features of the expenditure question to construct their answers. We test whether respondents interpret question wording as researchers intend and examine the extent to which prompts, clarifications and seemingly arbitrary features of survey design influence expenditure reports. We find that over one-quarter of respondents have difficulty distinguishing between 'you' and 'your household' when making expenditure reports; that respondents report higher pro-rata expenditure when asked to give responses on a weekly as opposed to annual timescale; that respondents give higher estimates when using a scale with a higher midpoint; and that respondents report higher aggregated expenditure when categories are presented in a disaggregated form. In summary, expenditure reports are constructed using convenient rules of thumb and available information, which will depend on the characteristics of the respondent, the expenditure domain and features of the survey question. It is crucial to further account for these features in ongoing surveys.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d113e186a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d113e193" publication-type="other">
Submitted February 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d113e200a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d113e207" publication-type="other">
Menon, 1993; Menon, Raghubir and Schwarz, 1995; Menon and Yorkston, 2000; Raghubir and
Menon, 2005.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d113e217a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d113e224" publication-type="other">
See also Hurd and Rohwedder (this issue).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d113e231a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d113e238" publication-type="other">
A11 of the results reported in Table 2 are robust to including a dummy for sampling location.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d113e246a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d113e253" publication-type="other">
Controlling for total expenditure in the food regression completely removes the effect of the scale but
has little effect on the coefficient in the alcohol regression. The use of the six-point (high-midpoint) scale
is orthogonal to the other survey conditions. It is possible that being randomly assigned the high-midpoint
scale in the closed-ended alcohol question is having a knock-on effect on answers to the open-ended
expenditure questions in the domains that immediately follow the alcohol question. When we examine the
effect of reporting on the high-midpoint scale on reported car expenditure (which is also an open-ended
question but asked prior to the presentation of the alcohol question), we find no effect. This is consistent
with respondents, having been conditioned to report higher alcohol expenditure by the high-midpoint
scale, then reporting higher food and total expenditure due to an anchoring effect. It is also possible that,
by chance, people asked the six-point scale have higher incomes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d113e297a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e301" publication-type="other">
Ariely, D., Loewenstein, G. and Prelec, D. (2003), 'Coherent arbitrariness: stable demand
curves without stable preferences', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 118, pp. 73-105.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e315" publication-type="other">
Browning, M., Crossley, T. F. and Weber, G. (2003), 'Asking consumption questions in
general purpose surveys', Economic Journal, vol. 113, pp. F540-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e325a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e329" publication-type="other">
Conrad, F. G., Schober, M. F. and Coiner, T. (2007), 'Bringing features of human dialogue to
web surveys', Applied Cognitive Psychology, vol. 21, pp. 165-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e339a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e343" publication-type="other">
Dawes, J., Riebe, E. and Giannopoulos, A. (2000), 'The impact of different scale anchors on
responses to the verbal probability scale', in Proceedings of ANZMAC 2000: Visionary
Marketing for the 21s' Century: Facing the Challenge, Australian and New Zealand
Marketing Academy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e360a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e364" publication-type="other">
Delaney, L. and O'Toole, F. (2006), 'Willingness to pay: individual or household?', Journal
of Cultural Economics, vol. 30, pp. 305-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e374a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e378" publication-type="other">
— and — (2008), 'Individual, household and gender preferences for social transfers', Journal
of Economic Psychology, vol. 29, pp. 348-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e388a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e392" publication-type="other">
Diamond, P. A. and Hausman, J. A. (1994), 'Contingent valuation: is some number better
than no number?', Journal of Economic Perspectives, vol. 8, no. 4, pp. 45-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e402a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e406" publication-type="other">
Garland, R. (1991), 'The mid-point on a rating scale: is it desirable?', Marketing Bulletin, vol.
2, pp. 66-70, Research Note 3.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e416a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e420" publication-type="other">
Haisley, E., Mostafa, R. and Lowenstein, G. (2008), 'Myopic risk-seeking: the impact of
narrow decision bracketing on lottery play', Journal of Risk and Uncertainty, vol. 37, pp.
57-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e433a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e437" publication-type="other">
Holm, S. (1979), 'A simple sequentially rejective multiple test procedure', Scandinavian
Journal of Statistics, vol. 6, pp. 65-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e448a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e452" publication-type="other">
Hurd, M. (1999), 'Anchoring and acquiescence bias in measuring assets in household
surveys', Journal of Risk and Uncertainty, vol. 19, pp. i 11-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e462a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e466" publication-type="other">
— and Rohwedder, S. (2009), 'Methodological innovations in collecting spending data: the
HRS Consumption and Activities Mail Survey', Fiscal Studies, vol. 30, pp. 435-59 (this
issue).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e479a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e483" publication-type="other">
Kahneman, D., Ritov, I., Jacowitz, K. and Grant, P. (1993), 'Stated willingness to pay for
public goods: a psychological perspective', Psychological Science, vol. 4, pp. 310-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e493a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e497" publication-type="other">
—, — and Schkade, D. (1999), 'Economic preferences or attitude expressions? An analysis of
dollar responses to public issues', Journal of Risk and Uncertainty, vol. 19, pp. 203-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e507a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e511" publication-type="other">
Lindhjem, H. and Navrud, S. (2008), 'Asking for individual or household willingness to pay
for environmental goods? Implication for aggregate welfare measures',
http://mpra.ub.uni-muenchen.de/l 1469/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e524a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e528" publication-type="other">
Loomis, J., Lockwood, M. and DeLacy, T. (1993), 'Some empirical evidence on embedding
effects in contingent valuation of forest protection', Journal of Environmental Economics
and Management, vol. 25, pp. 45-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e542a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e546" publication-type="other">
Menon, G. (1993), 'The effects of accessibility of information in memory on judgments of
behavioral frequencies', Journal of Consumer Research, vol. 20, pp. 431-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e556a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e560" publication-type="other">
—, Raghubir, P. and Schwarz, N. (1995), 'Behavioral frequency judgments: an accessibility-
diagnosticity framework', Journal of Consumer Research, vol. 22, pp. 212-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e570a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e574" publication-type="other">
— and Yorkston, E. A. (2000), 'The use of memory and contextual cues in the formation of
behavioral frequency judgments', in A. A. Stone, J. S. Turkkan, C. A. Bachrach, J. B.
Jobe, H. S. Kurtzman and V. S. Cain (eds), The Science of Self-Report: Implications for
Research and Practice, Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e590a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e594" publication-type="other">
Morewedge, C. K., Gilbert, D. T., Keysar, B., Berkovits, M. J. and Wilson, T. D. (2007),
'Mispredicting the hedonic benefits of segregated gains', Journal of Experimental
Psychology General, vol. 136, pp. 700-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e611" publication-type="other">
Oswald, A. J. (2008), 'On the curvature of the reporting function from objective reality to
subjective feelings', Economics Letters, vol. 100, pp. 369-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e625" publication-type="other">
Pradhan, M. (2009), 'Welfare analysis with a proxy consumption measure: evidence from a
repeated experiment in Indonesia', Fiscal Studies, vol. 30, pp. 391^117 (this issue).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e636a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e640" publication-type="other">
Prelec, D. and Loewenstein, G. (1991), 'Decision making over time and under uncertainty: a
common approach', Management Science, vol. 37, pp. 770-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e654" publication-type="other">
Raghubir, P. and Menon, G. (2005), 'When and why is ease of retrieval informative?',
Memory and Cognition, vol. 33, pp. 821—32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e668" publication-type="other">
Schkade, D. A. and Payne, J. W. (1994), 'How people respond to contingent valuation
questions: a verbal protocol analysis of willingness to pay for an environmental
regulation', Journal of Environmental Economics and Management, vol. 26, pp. 88-109.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e681a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e685" publication-type="other">
Schober, M. F., Conrad, F. G. and Fricker, S. (1999), 'When and how should survey
interviewers clarify question meaning?', Proceedings of the American Statistical
Association, Section on Survey Methods Research, pp. 985-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e698a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e702" publication-type="other">
Schuman, H. and Presser, S. (1996), Questions and Answers in Attitude Surveys: Experiments
on Question Form, Wording, and Context, London: Sage.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e712a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e716" publication-type="other">
Weber, B. J. and Chapman, G. B (2005), 'Playing for peanuts: why is risk seeking more
common for low-stakes gambles?', Organizational Behavior and Human Decision
Processes, vol. 97, pp. 31-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e730a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e734" publication-type="other">
Winter, J. (2002), 'Bracketing effects in categorized survey questions and the measurement of
economic quantities', Universität Mannheim, Sonderforschungsbereich 504, Discussion
Paper no. 02-35 (http://www.sfb504.uni-mannheim.de/publications/dp02-35.pdf).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e747a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e751" publication-type="other">
— (2004), 'Response bias in survey-based measures of household consumption', Economic
Bulletin, vol. 3, pp. 1-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e761a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e765" publication-type="other">
Wirtz, D., Rruger, J., Scollon, C. and Diener, E. (2003), 'What to do on spring break? The
role of predicted, on-line, and remembered experience in future choice', Psychological
Science, vol. 14, pp. 520-4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e778a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e782" publication-type="other">
Zaller, J. (1992), The Nature and Origins of Mass Opinion, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d113e792a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d113e796" publication-type="other">
— and Feldman, S. (1992), 'A simple theory of the survey response: answering questions
versus revealing preferences', American Journal of Political Science, vol. 36, pp. 579-
616.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


