<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939385</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Policy Innovations in Developing Countries</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Place-Based Policies and the Transition from Informal to Formal Employment. Evidence from Vietnam</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pham</surname>
                  <given-names>Anh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nguyen</surname>
                  <given-names>Hung</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939385"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper examines how industrial and economic zones affect labor market allocation from informal to formal employment in Vietnam. We use difference-in-differences approach with household and individual fixed effects to ensure that control and treatment groups were not different before the policies were implemented. We find that households in the zones had 40% more members working for more than one job. In addition, the hours and number of workers working in the informal sector increased by 40%. We do not find evidence for changes in total working hours, suggesting a reserve transition from formal to informal employment. This paper extends the literature on place-based policies, which mostly focuses on firms and formal employment, and the literature on informality whose main sources of identification are trade-shocks.</p> 
            <p>As for next steps, we will examine whether the industrial and economic zones in Vietnam led to regional economic growth. If so, this paper provides evidence for alternative (minority) views on how economic growth affects multiple-job holding and informal employment in developing countries. Alternatively, it could be that the industrial and economic zones in Vietnam deteriorated the regional economic development. If so, our empirical results are consistent with the traditional (majority) views. Industrial and economic zones could deteriorate regional economic development is itself an important result, since they are one of the main policies that many developing countries use to promote economic growth.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Blakeslee, David, Ritam Chaurey, Ram Fishman, and Samreen Malik (2017). “Structural Transformation and Spillovers from Industrial Areas” https://www.dropbox.com/s/kjb0cs51fmpaxbk/BlakesleeChaureyFishmanMalik.pdf?dl=0</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bennett, J., &amp; Estrin, S. (2007). Informality as a stepping stone: entrepreneurial entry in a developing economy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bondonio, Daniele, and Robert T. Greenbaum. 2007. “Do Local Tax Incentives Affect Economic Growth? What Mean Impacts Miss in the Analysis of Enterprise Zone Policies.” Regional Science and Urban Economics 37 (1): 121-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bosch, M., Goni, E., &amp; Maloney, W. F. (2007). The determinants of rising informality in Brazil: Evidence from gross worker flows. World Bank Policy Research Working Paper Series.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chandra, V., &amp; Khan, M. A. (1993). Foreign investment in the presence of an informal sector. Economica, 79-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Busso, Matias, Jesse Gregory, and Patrick Kline. “Assessing the Incidence and Efficiency of a Prominent Place Based Policy.” American Economic Review 103, no. 2 (April 2013): 897-947. https://doi.org/10.1257/aer.103.2.897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Elvery, Joel A. 2009. “The Impact of Enterprise Zones on Resident Employment: An Evaluation of the Enterprise Zone Programs of California and Florida.” Economic Development Quarterly 23 (1): 44-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Fajnzylber, P., Maloney, W., &amp; Rojas, G. M. (2006). Microenterprise dynamics in developing countries: How similar are they to those in the industrialized world? Evidence from Mexico. The World Bank Economic Review, 20(3), 389-419.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Fajnzylber, Pablo, William F. Maloney, and Gabriel V. Montes-Rojas. “Does Formality Improve Micro-Firm Performance? Evidence from the Brazilian SIMPLES Program.” Journal of Development Economics 94, no. 2 (March 2011): 262-76. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdeveco.2010.01.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Fields, G. S. (1975). Rural-urban migration, urban unemployment and underemployment, and job-search activity in LDCs. Journal of Development Economics, 2(2), 165-187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Ham, John C., Charles Swenson, Ayse Imrohoroglu, and Heonjae Song. 2011. “Government Programs Can Improve Local Labor Markets: Evidence from State Enterprise Zones, Federal Empowerment Zones and Federal Enterprise Community.” Journal of Public Economics 95 (7-8): 779-97. Harris, J. R., &amp; Todaro, M. P. (1970). Migration, unemployment and development: a two-sector analysis. American Economic Review, 126-142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Kline, Patrick. “Place Based Policies, Heterogeneity, and Agglomeration.” American Economic Review 100, no. 2 (May 2010): 383-87. https://doi.org/10.1257/aer.100.2.383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">La Porta, Rafael, and Andrei Shleifer. “Informality and Development.” Journal of Economic Perspectives 28, no. 3 (August 2014): 109-26. https://doi.org/10.1257/jep.28.3.109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Lu, Yi, Jin Wang, and Lianming Zhu (2015). “Place-Based Policies, Creation, and Displacement: Evidence from China.s Economic Zone Program” http://ylu6.weebly.com/uploads/8/6/4/2/8642496/lwz_sez_17nov2015.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Neumark, David, and Jed Kolko. 2010. “Do Enterprise Zones Create Jobs? Evidence from California’s Enterprise Zone Program.” Journal of Urban Economics 68 (1): 1-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Rothenberg, Alexander D., Samuel Bazzi, Shanthi Nataraj, and Amalavoyal V. Chari. “When Regional Policies Fail.” Product Page, 2017. https://www.rand.org/pubs/working_papers/WR1183.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Wang, Jin. “The Economic Impact of Special Economic Zones: Evidence from Chinese Municipalities.” Journal of Development Economics 101 (March 2013): 133-47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdeveco.2012.10.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Number of industrial and economic zones in operation</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Summary of households in the commune where industrial and economic zones located</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Summary of individuals in the commune where industrial and economic zones located</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Industrialization and structural change in a transition economy</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Summary and definition of variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Descriptive statistics for individuals from 2002 to 2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Summary of descriptive Statistics for overall sample at the individual’s level</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Marginal effects of industrial and economic zone establishment on household employment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Marginal effects of industrial and economic zone establishment on individual employment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>TRIPLE HOUSEHOLD PANELS (three-wave panels: VHLSS 2002-04-06 &amp; 2004-06-08 &amp; 2010-12-14): sampling individuals in the age of 20-4</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>TRIPLE PANELS (three-wave panels: VHLSS 2002-04-06 &amp; 2004-06-08 &amp; 2010-12-14): sampling individuals in the age of 20-64</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
