<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26142289</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Design of Financial Securities: Empirical Evidence from Private-Label RMBS Deals</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Taylor A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Begley</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Amiyatosh</given-names>
                  <surname>Purnanandam</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26142283</issue-id>
         <fpage>120</fpage>
         <lpage>161</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/26142289"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>We study the key drivers of security design in the residential mortgage-backed security (RMBS) market during the run-up to the subprime mortgage crisis. We show that deals with a higher level of equity tranche have a significantly lower delinquency rate conditional on observable loan characteristics. The effect is concentrated within pools with a higher likelihood of asymmetric information between deal sponsors and potential buyers of the securities. Further, securities sold from high-equity-tranche deals command higher prices conditional on their credit ratings. Overall, our results show that the goal of security design in this market was not only to exploit regulatory arbitrage, but also to mitigate information frictions that were pervasive in this market.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1261e281a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e288" publication-type="other">
For example, issues surrounding the equity tranche of securitization deals form an important part of the Dodd-
Frank Reform Act. In discussing the effects of risk retention requirements pursuant to the Section 946 of the
Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, the Treasury secretary stressed the importance
of this tool in mitigating some contracting frictions and notes that: "... the academic literature on risk retention
with respect to asset-backed securitization is limited." Scharfstein and Sunderam (2011) examine some other
recent policy proposals and provide suggestions for the more broad reform of the housing finance system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e311a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e318" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Keys et al. (2012), Gorton and Metrick (2012) for recent surveys, Keys et al. (2010), Mian and
Sufi (2009), Purnanandam (2011), Demy any k and Van Hemert (2011), He, Qian, and Strahan (2012), Loutskina
and Strahan (2011), and Acharya and Richardson (2009) for work related to the subprime mortgage crisis, and
Ashcraft and Schuermann (2008) for a detailed analysis of the securitization process.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e334a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e341" publication-type="other">
See Gorton and Pennacchi (1990), Boot and Thakor (1993), Riddiough (1997), DeMarzo and Duffie (1999),
DeMarzo (2005), Hartman-Glaser, Piskorski, and Tchistyi (2011), and Chemla and Hennessy (2014) for a rigorous
theoretical treatment of this issue.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e354a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e361" publication-type="other">
We present a detailed discussion of the construction of the equity tranche and sponsors' economic exposure to it
in Section 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e372a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e379" publication-type="other">
Pooling equilibrium is also a possibility within the information-based view. Under pooling equilibrium, we
should again not find any association between the level of the equity tranche and pool quality since sponsors
with low pool quality mimic the ones with high pool quality in such equilibrium. We focus on the predictions
from a separating equilibrium.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e395a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e402" publication-type="other">
See Benmelech, Dlugosz, and Ivashina (2012) on securitization in the case of collateralized loan obligations and
Nadauld and Weisbach (2012) for the effect of securitization on the cost of debt.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e412a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e419" publication-type="other">
An originate-to-hold model of lending can be viewed as a limiting case of an RMBS deal for which the entire
stake is kept by the originating bank. From that perspective, our empirical findings are consistent with the basic
idea of this literature: as the seller's stake in the deal increases, the underlying loans perform better in the future.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e432a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e439" publication-type="other">
A recent paper by Friewald, Hennessy, and Jankowitsch (2016) develops a theoretical model of security design
in which secondary market liquidity plays a key role in obtaining an equilibrium with multiple tranching of the
cash flows backed by a security.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e452a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e459" publication-type="other">
In the limiting case of full transparency (symmetric information), signaling is meaningless.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e466a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e473" publication-type="other">
These CoreLogic-specific data items are available for 162 deals in our sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e481a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e488" publication-type="other">
Our results are robust to using alternative measures of geographical diversification, such as a Herfindahl index
across states and concentration in the top-three states (GeoHerfindahl), and this is presented in later tests.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e498a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e505" publication-type="other">
The default data are available for a slightly lower number of deals because they are based on the sample formed
by the intersection of our hand-collected data with CoreLogic default data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e515a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e522" publication-type="other">
We provide an example of the classification of NoDoc loans in Appendix C.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e529a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e536" publication-type="other">
Finally, we check the annual reports of major sponsors in our sample and find significant retention on their
balance sheets. For example, Lehman Brothers had approximately $2 billion of non-investment-grade retained
interests in residential mortgaged-backed securitization as of November 30, 2006. We obtain similar evidence
from the annual reports of Goldman Sachs and Merrill Lynch during this period. For example, Goldman Sachs'
2005 annual report states, "During the years ended November 2005 and November 2004, the firm securitized
$92.00 billion and $62.93 billion, respectively, of financial assets, including $65.18 billion and $47.46 billion,
respectively, of residential mortgage-backed securities." The report also shows the value of their retained interests
in mortgage-backed securities as $2,928 and $1,798 billion, respectively, for those time periods. A back of the
envelope calculation suggests that (2.928-1.798)/62.93 = 1.73% was retained during this time period. This is
only a rough approximation, but it clearly shows that deal sponsors did retain at least a piece of these securities.
A similar computation using information from Merrill Lynch's annual reports gives an estimate of 2.84%.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e574a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e581" publication-type="other">
Our results are not sensitive to using even finer time periods, such as the month or quarter of the deal.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e588a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e597" publication-type="other">
Our inference is also robust to computing standard errors clustered at the sponsor level, and we present this in
robustness tests later. We recognize, however, that it is important to have a sufficiently large number of clusters to
obtain consistent standard errors using this method, and our sample has only twenty-six clusters. As an alternative
estimation technique, we estimate a seemingly unrelated regression model for the proportion of AAA, mezzanine,
and equity tranche in a deal (not tabulated). Our results are stronger for this specification.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e617a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e624" publication-type="other">
Our results remain similar if we use a linear probability model, or if we estimate the default models using the
full sample rather than separately estimating the model for each cohort. Our main tests using these alternative
models are presented in the Appendix in Table A.3.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e637a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e644" publication-type="other">
Alternatively, we compute our measure of abnormal default based on the ratio of actual and predicted default
rate and find similar results for our tests. Our measure is dollar weighted to best capture the economic losses
borne by the security holders.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e657a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e664" publication-type="other">
Defining variables by cohort is not only economically sensible, but it also ensures that we have a good balance in
the number of observations that fall in each of the four buckets based on these two dimensions (i.e., our estimates
are not driven by small subset of observations in any one of these four groups).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e677a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e684" publication-type="other">
Note that these pool-level variables have been used to measure the expected default rate in the first stage. Their
inclusion in the model is to ensure that our results are not driven by any residual explanatory power left in these
variables due to imperfect model fit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e697a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e704" publication-type="other">
A very small number of sold tranches are below the BBB rating. We include them in the BBB category.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e711a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e718" publication-type="other">
We also run the same test using a linear probability model and find similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1261e726a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1261e733" publication-type="other">
We perform the same tests using a dummy variable that indicates if the servicer is any of the top four originators
and get similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1261e752a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e756" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V., and M. Richardson. 2009. Restoring financial stability: How to repair a failed system, volume 542.
Hoboken: Wiley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e766a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e770" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V., P. Schnabl, and G. Suarez. 2013. Securitization without risk transfer. Journal of Financial Economics
107:515-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e780a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e784" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, S., G Amromin, I. Ben-David, S. Chomsisengphet, and D. D. Evanoff. 2014. Predatory lending and
the subprime crisis. Journal of Financial Economics 113:29-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e794a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e798" publication-type="other">
An, X., Y. Deng, and S. A. Gabriel. 2011. Asymmetric information, adverse selection, and the pricing of CMBS.
Journal of Financial Economics 100:304-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e809a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e813" publication-type="other">
Ashcraft, A., P. Goldsmith-Pinkham, and J. Vickery. 2010. MBS ratings and the mortgage credit boom.
Collingdale, PA: DIANE Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e823a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e827" publication-type="other">
Ashcraft, A. B., andT. Schuermann. 2008. Understanding the securitization of subprime mortgage credit, (no.318)
Now Publishers Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e837a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e841" publication-type="other">
Benmelech, E., and J. Dlugosz. 2009. The alchemy of CDO credit ratings. Journal of Monetary Economics
56:617-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e851a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e855" publication-type="other">
Benmelech, E., J. Dlugosz, and V. Ivashina. 2012. Securitization without adverse selection: The case of CLOs.
Journal of Financial Economics 106:91-113.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e865a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e869" publication-type="other">
Bernardo, A.E. and B. Cornell. 1997. The valuation of complex derivatives by major investment firms: Empirical
evidence. Journal of Finance 52: 785-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e879a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e883" publication-type="other">
Boot, A. W. A., and A. V. Thakor. 1993. Security design. Journal of Finance 48:1349-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e891a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e895" publication-type="other">
Chemla, G, and C. A. Hennessy. 2014. Skin in the game and moral hazard. Journal of Finance 69:1597-641.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e902a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e906" publication-type="other">
DeMarzo, P., and D. Duffie. 1999. A liquidity-based model of security design. Econometrica 67:65-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e913a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e917" publication-type="other">
DeMarzo, P. M. 2005. The pooling and tranching of securities: A model of informed intermediation. Review of
Financial Studies 18:1-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e927a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e931" publication-type="other">
Demiroglu, C., and C. James. 2012. How important is having skin in the game? Originator-sponsor affiliation
and losses on mortgage-backed securities. Review of Financial Studies 25:3217-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e941a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e945" publication-type="other">
Demyanyk, Y., and O. Van Hemert. 2011. Understanding the subprime mortgage crisis. Review of Financial
Studies 24:1848-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e955a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e959" publication-type="other">
Friewald, N., C. A. Hennessy, and R. Jankowitsch. 2016. Secondary market liquidity and security design: Theory
and evidence from ABS markets. Review of Financial Studies 29:1254-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e970a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e974" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G., and A. Metrick. 2012. Securitization. Working Paper 18611, National Bureau of Economic Research,
December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e984a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e988" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and G. Pennacchi. 1990. Financial intermediaries and liquidity creation. Journal of Finance
45:49-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e998a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1002" publication-type="other">
Griffin, J. M., and D. Y. Tang. 2012. Did subjectivity play a role in CDO credit ratings? Journal of Finance
67:1293-328.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1012a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1016" publication-type="other">
Hartman-Glaser, B. 2013. Reputation and signaling. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1023a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1027" publication-type="other">
Hartman-Glaser, B., T. Piskorski, and A. Tchistyi. 2011. Optimal securitization with moral hazard. Journal of
Financial Economics 104:186-202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1037a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1041" publication-type="other">
He, J., Qian, J., and Strahan, P. 2012. Are all ratings created equal? The impact of issuer size on the pricing of
mortgage-backed-securities. Journal of Finance 67:2097-137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1052a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1056" publication-type="other">
Hébert, B. 2015. Moral hazard and the optimality of debt. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1063a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1067" publication-type="other">
Ho, G., and A. Pennington-Cross. 2006. The impact of local predatory lending laws on the flow of subprime
credit. Journal of Urban Economics 60:210-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1077a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1081" publication-type="other">
Keys, B., T. Piskorski, A. Seru, and V. Vig. 2012. Mortgage financing in the housing boom and bust. In Housing
and the financial crisis. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1091a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1095" publication-type="other">
Keys, B. J., T. Mukherjee, A. Seru, and V. Vig. 2010. Did securitization lead to lax screening? Evidence from
subprime loans. Quarterly Journal of Economics 125:307-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1105a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1109" publication-type="other">
Lekkas, V., J. M. Quigley, and R. Van Order. 1993. Loan loss severity and optimal mortgage default. Real Estate
Economics 21:353-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1119a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1123" publication-type="other">
Leland, H. E., and D. H. Pyle. 1977. Informational asymmetries, financial structure, and financial intermediation.
Journal of Finance 32:371-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1134a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1138" publication-type="other">
Loutskina, E., and P. E. Strahan. 2011. Informed and uninformed investment in housing: The downside of
diversification. Review of Financial Studies 24:1447-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1148a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1152" publication-type="other">
Mason, J. R. 2007. Mortgage loan modification: Promises and pitfalls. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1159a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1163" publication-type="other">
Mian, A., and A. Sufi. 2009. The consequences of mortgage credit expansion: Evidence from the US mortgage
default crisis. Quarterly Journal of Economics 124:1449-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1173a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1177" publication-type="other">
Nadauld, T. D., and M. S. Weisbach. 2012. Did securitization affect the cost of corporate debt? Journal of
Financial Economics, 105:332-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1187a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1191" publication-type="other">
Piskorski, T., A. Seru, and V. Vig. 2010. Securitization and distressed loan renegotiation: Evidence from the
subprime mortgage crisis. Journal of Financial Economics 97:369-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1201a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1205" publication-type="other">
Purnanandam, A. 2011. Originate-to-distribute model and the subprime mortgage crisis. Review of Financial
Studies 24:1881-915.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1216a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1220" publication-type="other">
Qi, M., and X. Yang. 2009. Loss given default of high loan-to-value residential mortgages. Journal of Banking
&amp; Finance 33:788-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1230a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1234" publication-type="other">
Riddiough, T. J. 1997. Optimal design and governance of asset-backed securities. Journal of Financial
Intermediation 6:121-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1244a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1248" publication-type="other">
Scharfstein, D., and A. Sunderam. 2011. The economics of housing finance reform. In The future of housing
finance, 146-98. Ed. M. N. Baily. Washington, DC: Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1258a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1262" publication-type="other">
Stanton, R., and N. Wallace. 2012. CMBS subordination, ratings inflation, and regulatory-capital arbitrage.
Working Paper, UC Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1261e1272a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1261e1276" publication-type="other">
Williams, B. 2015. Search, liquidity, and retention: Signaling multidimensional private information. Working
Paper, NYU.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
