<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23024767</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE ZIMBABWE STOCK EXCHANGE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Jonathan Tsamwisi</given-names>
                  <surname>Muzamani</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23024723</issue-id>
         <fpage>75</fpage>
         <lpage>85</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23024767"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The current literature on the necessity and role of stock exchanges in developing countries is not very conclusive. This article looks at the necessity of stock exchanges in developing countries by using data on a stock exchange that had not been used by other authors, the Zimbabwe Stock Exchange. We measure role and necessity of the Zimbabwe Stock Exchange by looking how it has performed as a market where firms can raise new funds for their operations. Previous research in this area had shown limited use of the developing country stock exchanges as a source of long term capital for firms in the respective studies. We found that on the Zimbabwe Stock Exchange, between the years 1980 to 1992 there was varying use of the stock exchange as a source of capital. We find significant use of the stock exchange to raise capital during the early part of the period and the last part of the period under study. We also found that the extent of use of the stock exchange as an avenue for raising funds was largely determined by the performance of the stock exchange. The higher the performance, as measured by the stock market index, the greater the amount of funds raised by firms on the stock exchange. Given that most of the downward movements on the stock exchange have been caused by government policy we conclude that, within the Zimbabwean market, whether or not the stock exchange fulfils its role as provider of capital largely depends on government policies.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d8e162a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e166" publication-type="other">
Calamanti, A., The securities markets and underdevelopment, (Finafrica Giuffre, Milan) (1983).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e173a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e177" publication-type="other">
Calamanti, A., The Tunis Stock Exchange, Savings and Development, Vol. Ill, no. 3 (1979).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e184a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e188" publication-type="other">
Calamanti, A., The Abidjan Stock Exchange: An instrument for savings mobilization and the indegenization of
economic activity, Savings and Development, Vol. IX, no. 2, (1980a).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e198a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e202" publication-type="other">
Calamanti, A., The stock exchange and securities market in Morocco, Savings and Development, Vol. IV, no.
4, (1980b).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e213a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e217" publication-type="other">
Dickie, R.B., Development of third world securities markets: an analysis of general principles and a case study
of the Indonesian market, Law and Policy in International Business, Vol. 13, (1981), pp. 177-222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e227a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e231" publication-type="other">
Drake, P.J., Securities markets in less developed countries, Journal of Development Studies, Vol. 13, no. 2, (1977).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e238a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e242" publication-type="other">
Drake, P.J., Money, finance and development, Martin Robertson, Oxford., (1980).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e249a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e253" publication-type="other">
Drake, P.J., Some reflections on problems affecting securities markets in less developed countries, Savings
and Development, vol. IX, no. 1, (1985).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e263a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e267" publication-type="other">
Lloyd, B., The role of capital markets in developing countries, Moorgate and Wall Street, (Spring), (1976), pp. 45-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e274a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e278" publication-type="other">
Lloyd, B., The efficiency of financial institutions and markets, Investment Analyst, no. 47, May, (1977).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e286a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e290" publication-type="other">
Kitchen, R., The role of the Jamaica Stock Exchange in the capital market: An Historical Analysis, Savings and
Development, Vol. XI, No. 3, (1987).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e300a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e304" publication-type="other">
Mauri, A. and A. Calamanti, A Note on the role of LDCs securities markets in savings mobilization, The Journal
of Development Studies, (Peshawar) V. (1983).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e314a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e318" publication-type="other">
Parkinson, J.M. The Nairobi Stock Exchange in the context of development in Kenya, Savings and Develop-
ment, Vol. VIII, no. 4 (1984).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e328a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e332" publication-type="other">
Samuels, J.M., Inefficient capital markets and their implications, in Derkinderen, F.G.J, and R.L. Crum (eds)
Risk, Capital Costs and Project Financing Decisions, Martinus Nijhoff, Boston/The Hague/London, (1981),
pp. 129-148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e345a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e349" publication-type="other">
Samuels, J.M. and N. Yacout., Stock exchanges in developing countries, Savings and Development, Vol. V,
No. 4, (1981).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
