<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464752</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464755</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investor Heterogeneity, Investor-Management Disagreement and Share Repurchases</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Sheng</given-names>
                  <surname>Huang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Anjan V.</given-names>
                  <surname>Thakor</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2453</fpage>
         <lpage>2491</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464755"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper develops and tests a new theoretical explanation for stock repurchases. Investors may disagree with the manager about the firm's investment projects. A repurchase causes a change in the investor base as investors who are most likely to disagree with the manager tender their shares. Therefore, a firm is more likely to buy back shares when the level of investor-management agreement is lower, and agreement improves as a consequence. Moreover, dispersion of opinion among investors cannot explain repurchase activity once the stock price and investor-management agreement are controlled for. Overall, the evidence is consistent with firms strategically using repurchases to improve alignment between management and shareholders.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e199a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e206" publication-type="other">
The 2003 dividend tax cut caused an increase in dividends, but there was also a simultaneous spike in repurchases
after the tax cut (Chetty and Saez 2005, 2006). Chetty and Saez (2006) suggest that repurchases may have
increased even more, absent the tax change. Dividend payments may also be affected by CEO overconfidence;
see Deshmukh, Goel, and Howe (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e222a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e229" publication-type="other">
For examples, see Asquith and Mullins (1986), Comment and Jarrell (1991), Dann (1981), D'Mello and Shroff
(2000), Lie and McConnell (1998), Louis and White (2007), and Vermaelen (1981).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e239a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e246" publication-type="other">
Comment and Jarrell ( 1991 ) state that "the bulk of buy back activity is conducted through open-market repurchase
programs and dutch-auction self-tender offers, methods which have less signaling effectiveness than the
conventional fixed-price offer. This suggests that most stock buyback activity may be principally motivated by
objectives other than (or in addition to) signaling stock undervaluation." Accelerated share repurchase programs,
adopted in the last few years, may help get around some of these issues. See Bargeron, Kulchania, and Thomas
(2011) and Chemmanur, Cheng, and Zhang (2010) for a discussion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e269a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e276" publication-type="other">
The literature similarly argues that a problem with considering open-market repurchase programs as costly signals
is that the programs are not firm commitments, and thus the completion rate of these programs varies substantially
across companies. See, for example, Stephens and Weisbach (1998) and Rau and Vermaelen (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e290a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e297" publication-type="other">
Oded (2005) presents an asymmetric information-based signaling model to explain the positive announcement
returns of open-market repurchase programs. Yet the literature also documents several sources of announcement
returns that are unrelated to signaling. See Babenko (2009), Dittmar (2000), Grullon and Michaely (2004), and
Maxwell and Stephens (2003), among others. Further, Babenko, Tserlukevich, and Vedrashko (2012) suggest that
although managers may buy stock prior to a repurchase program announcement, such purchases are likely to be
motivated by personal wealth maximization rather than an intention to convey information. For an asymmetric
information justification for open-market repurchases that does not involve signaling, see Brennan and Thakor
(1990), who show that large shareholders will have an incentive to acquire costly information about the firm to
enable them to decide whether to tender their shares when the firm repurchases shares, whereas small shareholders
will prefer to avoid the information acquisition cost and remain uninformed. Thus, a repurchase creates a relative
advantage for large shareholders that dividends do not, and firms will repurchase shares when the preferences
of large shareholders dominate the firm's decision. Also, Constantinides and Grundy (1989) develop a model in
which firms simultaneously issue securities and repurchase stock and derive a separating equilibrium in which
insiders and outside investors end up with the same valuation of the firm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e345a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e354" publication-type="other">
Lie (2005) shows that firms with actual repurchases after open-market repurchase program announce-
ments experience improvements in operating performance relative to their control firms. However,
Gong, Louis, and Sun (2008) suggest that the reported improvement in operating performance is likely to be
driven by prerepurchase downward earnings management rather than genuine growth in profitability.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e370a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e377" publication-type="other">
Cook, Krigman, and Leach (2004) document that open-market repurchases by firms in the U.S. increase the
market liquidity of repurchasing firms' stock. Brockman and Chung (2001) present evidence from Hong Kong
that open-market repurchases reduce liquidity on the day of actual repurchases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e390a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e397" publication-type="other">
Cross-sectional heterogeneity among investors in their extent of agreement with the managers leads to an
imperfectly elastic demand curve for shares.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e407a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e414" publication-type="other">
Oded (2013) formally models the value of flexibility in open-market repurchases and its trade-off with the agency
cost of free cash flow.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e424a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e431" publication-type="other">
This assumption is reasonable if investors are risk neutral and wealth constrained with equal wealth endowments.
More generally, we would expect investors with higher pt- 's to invest more. However, the results are even stronger
under the latter specification.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e445a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e452" publication-type="other">
We thank Stuart Gillan for sharing the shareholder proxy proposal data from 1987 to 1995.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e459a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e466" publication-type="other">
We thank Diane Del Guercio for the helpful discussion on "just vote no" campaigns and the data on this for 2003.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e473a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e480" publication-type="other">
Skinner (2008) suggests that the overall level of repurchases is determined by earnings, while other factors help
explain the timing of repurchases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e490a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e497" publication-type="other">
The associated odds ratios from the logistic regressions are 1.263 and 11.773, respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e504a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e511" publication-type="other">
One concern arises that improvement in agreement might be negatively related to the prerepurchase agreement
mechanically in our empirical study due to the limitation in using proxies for agreement. For instance, in the
case of shareholder proxy proposal as an agreement proxy, the marginal effect of the incidence of receiving a
proxy proposal in one year on the incidence of receiving a proposal again in the following years might be well
less than one, because shareholders do not submit proposals frequently. As such, we focus on the analysis based
on the specification (13).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e534a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e541" publication-type="other">
Gay, Kale, and Noe (1991) analyze three repurchase mechanisms under shareholder heterogeneity that include
fixed-price tender offer, Dutch auction, and transferable put rights. Gay, Kale, and Noe (1996) derive and test an
optimal shareholder bidding strategy under shareholder heterogeneity in a Dutch auction share repurchase.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e555a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e562" publication-type="other">
Recent papers, for instance, Dittmar and Thakor (2007) and Moeller, Schlingemann, and Stulz (2007), also use
this proxy for dispersion of opinion among investors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e572a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e579" publication-type="other">
It is negative but insignificant in the sample of firms when dual-class control premium is used as an agreement
proxy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e589a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e596" publication-type="other">
The idea behind this variable is that informed trading induces volatility (e.g., Glosten and Milgrom 1985; French
and Roll 1986) and idiosyncratic price changes mainly reflect private information being incorporated into stock
prices by informed trading (Roll 1988). See Ferreira and Laux (2007) for a reference of empirical evidence in
support of this informational interpretation of idiosyncratic volatility.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e612a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e619" publication-type="other">
Intuitively, strong positive or negative reactions by the market around information-revealing events, such as
earning announcements, suggest a high information asymmetry between management and investors. So, as in
Dierkens ( 1991 ), the dispersion in the market reactions over a period is used as a proxy for information asymmetry.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e632a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e639" publication-type="other">
We also conduct a robustness check using the samples of the other two main agreement proxies. Our conclusion
is not qualitatively affected.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e649a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e656" publication-type="other">
We impose this more stringent criterion—0.5% of the market capitalization—following the literature (e.g., Lie
2005; Gong, Louis, and Sun 2008) to rule out the potential cases in which firms have repurchased preferred stock
and nonstock securities. Our results, however, are not affected by whether or not this criterion is imposed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e670a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e677" publication-type="other">
By using net repurchases instead of raw repurchases, we focus on repurchases that are less likely to be motivated
by undoing the EPS dilution associated with stock options (e.g., Kahle 2002; Weisbenner 2004) or by funding
firms' acquisitions or pension plans.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e690a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e697" publication-type="other">
Identifying an accurate measure of repurchases is empirically difficult. Banyi, Dyl, and Kahle (2008) find
higher error rates in commonly used estimators of share repurchases. Our measure here is an approximation
of open-market and privately-negotiated repurchases, as it may also include repurchases of securities other
than common stock. Despite being rare, we may have also omitted those open-market or privately negotiated
repurchases made in the same year of self-tender offer or Dutch auction repurchases. However, the prior literature
(e.g., Stephens and Weisbach 1998; Jagannathan, Stephens, and Weisbach 2000; Grullon and Michaely 2002)
suggests that transactions other than open-market repurchases represent only a small fraction of firms' repurchase
activity.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e726a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e733" publication-type="other">
Proxy proposals can be broadly classified into two types: governance-related vs. social responsibility-related
(typically submitted by religious/socially responsible investors). In this study, we focus on the former type only.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e743a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e750" publication-type="other">
Del Guercio, Seery, and Woidtke (2008) identify 112 "just vote no" campaigns from 1990 to 2003, while we find
186 such campaigns from 2004 to 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e760a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e767" publication-type="other">
This sample size is smaller than that of the vote recommendation sample due to the missing information in actual
votes for many firm-years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e777a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e784" publication-type="other">
Recall that the stock price in our model depends on both manager-investor agreement and the noise term e.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e800a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e804" publication-type="other">
Allen, F., and D. M. Gale. 1999. Diversity of opinions and financing of new technologies. Journal of Financial
Intermediation 8:68-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e818" publication-type="other">
Allen, F., and R. Michaely. 2003. Payout policy. In Handbook of the economics of finance. Eds. G Constandinides,
M. Harris, and R. Stulz. North-Holland: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e828a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e832" publication-type="other">
Asquith, P., and D. Mullins. 1986. Signaling with dividends, stock repurchases and equity issues. Financial
Management 15:27—44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e842a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e846" publication-type="other">
Babenko, I. 2009. Share repurchases and pay-performance sensitivity of employee compensation contracts.
Journal of Finance 64:117-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e857a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e861" publication-type="other">
Babenko, I., Y. Tserlukevich, and A. Vedrashko. 2012. The credibility of open market share repurchase signaling.
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 47:1059-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e871a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e875" publication-type="other">
Bagwell, L. S. 1991a. Share repurchase and takeover deterrence. Rand Journal of Economics 22:72-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e882a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e886" publication-type="other">
. 1991b. Shareholder heterogeneity: Evidence and implications. American Economic Review 81:218-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e893a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e897" publication-type="other">
. 1992. Dutch auction repurchases: An analysis of shareholder heterogeneity. Journal of Finance
47:71-105.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e907a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e911" publication-type="other">
Banyi, M. L., E. A. Dyl, and K. M. Kahle. 2008. Errors in estimating share repurchases. Journal of Corporate
Finance 14:460-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e921a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e925" publication-type="other">
Barber, B., J. Lyon, and C. Tsai. 1999. Improved methods for tests of long-run abnormal stock returns. Journal
of Finance 54:165-201.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e936a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e940" publication-type="other">
Bargeron, L., M. Kulchania, and S. Thomas. 2011. Accelerated share repurchases. Journal of Financial Economics
101:69-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e950a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e954" publication-type="other">
Boehme, R., B. Danielsen, and S. Sorescu. 2006. Short sale constraints, difference of opinion, and overvaluation.
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 41:455-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e964a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e968" publication-type="other">
Boot, A., R. Gopalan, and A. Thakor. 2006. The entrepreneur's choice between private and public ownership.
Journal of Finance 61:803-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e978a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e982" publication-type="other">
. 2008. Market liquidity, investor participation and managerial autonomy: Why do firms go private?
Journal of Finance 63:2013-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e992a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e996" publication-type="other">
Boot, A., and A. Thakor. 2011. Managerial autonomy, allocation of control rights, and optimal capital structure.
Review of Financial Studies 24:3434-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1006a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1010" publication-type="other">
Brav, A., J. R. Graham, C. R. Harvey, and R. Michaely. 2005. Payout policy in the 21st century. Journal of
Financial Economics 77:483-527.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1025" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M., and A. Thakor. 1990. Shareholder preferences and dividend policy. Journal of Finance 45:993-1018.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1032a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1036" publication-type="other">
Brockman, P., and D. Y. Chung. 2001. Managerial timing and corporate liquidity: Evidence from actual share
repurchases. Journal of Financial Economics 61:417-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1046a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1050" publication-type="other">
Cai, J., J. Garner, and R. Walkling. 2009. Electing directors. Journal of Finance 64:2389-421.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1057a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1061" publication-type="other">
Chemmanur, T., Y. Cheng, and T. Zhang. 2010. Why do firms undertake accelerated share repurchase programs?
Working Paper, Boston College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1071a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1075" publication-type="other">
Chen, J., H. Hong, and J. Stein. 2002. Breadth of ownership and stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics
66:171-205.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1085a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1089" publication-type="other">
Chetty, R., and E. Saez. 2005. Dividend taxes and corporate behavior: Evidence from the 2003 dividend tax cut.
Quarterly Journal of Economics 120:791-833.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1100a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1104" publication-type="other">
. 2006. The effects of the 2003 dividend tax cut on corporate behavior: Interpreting the evidence. American
Economic Review Papers and Proceedings 96:124-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1114a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1118" publication-type="other">
Comment, R., and G Jarrell. 1991. The relative signaling power of Dutch-auction and fixed-price self-tender
offers and open market share repurchases. Journal of Finance 46:1243-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1128a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1132" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, G, and B. Grundy. 1989. Optimal investment with stock repurchase and financing as signals.
Review of Financial Studies 2:445-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1142a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1146" publication-type="other">
Cook, D., L. Krigman, and J. C. Leach. 2004. On the timing and execution of open market repurchases. Review
of Financial Studies 17:463-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1156a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1160" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and A. Thakor. 2005. Financial intermediation as a belief-bridge between optimists and pessimists.
Journal of Financial Economics 75:535-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1170a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1174" publication-type="other">
Dann, L. 1981. The effects of common stock repurchase on security holder's returns. Journal of Financial
Economics 9:101-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1189" publication-type="other">
Datta, S., M. Iskandar-Datta, and K. Raman. 2001. Executive compensation and corporate acquisition decisions.
Journal of Finance 56:2299-336.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1203" publication-type="other">
D'Avolio, G 2002. The market for borrowing stock. Journal of Financial Economics 66:271-306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1210a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1214" publication-type="other">
DeAngelo, H., L. DeAngelo, and D. J. Skinner. 2004. Are dividends disappearing? Dividend concentration and
the consolidation of earnings. Journal of Financial Economics 72:425-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1224a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1228" publication-type="other">
. 2008. Corporate payout policy. Foundations and trends in finance, vol. 3, nos. 2-3, 95-287.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1235a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1239" publication-type="other">
Del Guercio, D., L. Seery, and T. Woidtke. 2008. Do boards pay attention when institutional investor activists
'just vote no ' I Journal of Financial Economics 90:84—103.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1249a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1253" publication-type="other">
Deshmukh, S., A. Goel, and K.M. Howe. 2013. CEO overconfidence and dividend policy. Journal of Financial
Intermediation 22:440-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1264a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1268" publication-type="other">
Dierkens, N. 1991. Information asymmetry and equity issues. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis
26:181-200.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1278a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1282" publication-type="other">
Dittmar, A. 2000. Why do firms repurchase stock? Journal of Business 73:331-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1289a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1293" publication-type="other">
Dittmar, A., and R. Dittmar. 2008. The timing of financing decisions: An examination of the correlation in
financing waves. Journal of Financial Economics 90:59-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1303a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1307" publication-type="other">
Dittmar, A., and A. Thakor. 2007. Why do firms issue equity? Journal of Finance 62:1-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1318" publication-type="other">
D'Mello, R., and R Shroff. 2000. Equity undervaluation and decisions related to repurchase tender offers: An
empirical investigation. Journal of Finance 55:2399-424.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1332" publication-type="other">
Diether, K. 2004. Long-run event performance and opinion divergence. Working Paper, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1340a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1344" publication-type="other">
Diether, K., C. Malloy, and A. Scherbina. 2002. Differences of opinion and the cross-section of stock returns.
Journal of Finance 57:2113-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1354a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1358" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 2001. Disappearing dividends: Changing firm characteristics or lower propensity to
pay? Journal of Financial Economics 60:3-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1372" publication-type="other">
Fenn, G W, and N. Liang. 2001. Corporate payout policy and managerial stock incentives. Journal of Financial
Economics 60:45-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1386" publication-type="other">
Ferreira, M., and P. Laux. 2007. Corporate governance, idiosyncratic risk, and information flow. Journal of
Finance 62:951-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1400" publication-type="other">
Figlewski, S. 1981. The informational effect of restrictions on short sales: Some empirical evidence. Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis 16:463-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1410a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1414" publication-type="other">
French, K., and R. Roll. 1986. Stock return variance: The arrival of information and the reaction of traders.
Journal of Financial Economics 17:5-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1429" publication-type="other">
Gao, X., and J. Ritter. 2010. The marketing of seasoned equity offerings. Journal of Financial Economics
97:33-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1443" publication-type="other">
Garmaise, M. 2001. Rational beliefs and security design. Review of Financial Studies 14:1183-213.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1454" publication-type="other">
Gaspar, J., M. Massa, R Matos, R. Patgiri, and Z. Rehman. 2013. Payout policy choices and shareholder
investment horizons. Review of Finance 17:261-320.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1464a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1468" publication-type="other">
Gay, G, J. Kale, andT. Noe. 1991. Share repurchase mechanisms: A comparative analysis of efficacy, shareholder
wealth, and corporate control effects. Financial Management 20:44-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1478a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1482" publication-type="other">
. 1996. Dutch auction share repurchases. Economica 63:57-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1493" publication-type="other">
Gillan, S. L., and L. T. Starks. 2000. Corporate governance proposals and shareholder activism: The role of
institutional investors. Journal of Financial Economics 57:275-305.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1504a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1508" publication-type="other">
Glosten, L., and P. Milgrom. 1985. Bid, ask, and transaction prices in a specialist market with heterogeneously
informed traders. Journal of Financial Economics 14:71-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1518a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1522" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P. A., J. L. Ishii, and A. Metrick. 2003. Corporate governance and equity prices. Quarterly Journal of
Economics 118:107-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1532a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1536" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Extreme governance: An analysis of dual-class firms in the United States. Review of Financial
Studies 23:1051-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1546a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1550" publication-type="other">
Gong, G, H. Louis, and X. Sun. 2008. Earnings management and firm performance following open-market
repurchases. Journal of Finance 63:947-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1560a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1564" publication-type="other">
Grullon, G, and R. Michaely. 2002. Dividends, share repurchases, and the substitution hypothesis. Journal of
Finance 57:1649-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1574a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1578" publication-type="other">
. 2004. The information content of share repurchase programs. Journal of Finance 59:651-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1590" publication-type="other">
Guay, W., and J. Harford. 2000. The cash flow permanence and information content of dividend increases vs.
repurchases. Journal of Financial Economics 57:385-415.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1604" publication-type="other">
Jagannathan, M., C. P. Stephens, and M. S. Weisbach. 2000. Financial flexibility and the choice between dividends
and stock repurchases. Journal of Financial Economics 57:355-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1618" publication-type="other">
Kahle, K. M. 2002. When a buyback isn't a buyback: Open market repurchases and employee options. Journal
of Financial Economics 63:235-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1628a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1632" publication-type="other">
Kandel, E., and N. D. Pearson. 1995. Differential interpretation of public signals and trade in speculative markets.
Journal of Political Economy 103:831-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1642a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1646" publication-type="other">
Krishnaswami, S., and V. Subramaniam. 1999. Information asymmetry, valuation, and the corporate spin-off
decision. Journal of Financial Economics 53:73-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1656a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1660" publication-type="other">
Lie, E. 2005. Operating performance following open market share repurchase announcements. Journal of
Accounting and Economics 39:411-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1671a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1675" publication-type="other">
Lie, E., and J. J. McConnell. 1998. Earnings signals in fixed-price and Dutch auction self-tender offers. Journal
of Financial Economics 49:161-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1685a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1689" publication-type="other">
Louis, H., and H. White. 2007. Do managers intentionally use repurchase tender offers to signal private
information? Evidence from firm financial reporting behavior. Journal of Financial Economics 85 :205-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1699a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1703" publication-type="other">
Masulis, R., C. Wang, and F. Xie. 2009. Agency problems in dual-class companies. Journal of Finance
64:1697-727.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1713a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1717" publication-type="other">
Maxwell, W., and C. Stephens. 2003. The wealth effects of repurchases on bondholders. Journal of Finance
58:895-919.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1727a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1731" publication-type="other">
Miller, E. 1977. Risk, uncertainty and divergence of opinion. Journal of Finance 32:1151-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1738a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1742" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F., and M. H. Miller. 1958. The cost of capital, corporate investment and the theory of investment.
American Economic Review 48:261-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1753a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1757" publication-type="other">
Moeller, S., F. Schlingemann, and R. Stulz. 2007. How do diversity of opinion and information asymmetry affect
acquirer returns? Review of Financial Studies 20:2047-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1767a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1771" publication-type="other">
Oded, J. 2005. Why do firms announce open market repurchase programs? Review of Financial Studies
18:271-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1781a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1785" publication-type="other">
. 2013. Payout policy, financial flexibility, and agency costs of free cash flow. Working Paper, Tel Aviv
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1795a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1799" publication-type="other">
Ofer, A., and A. Thakor. 1987. A theory of stock price responses to alternative corporate cash disbursement
methods: Stock repurchases and dividends. Journal of Finance 42:365-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1809a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1813" publication-type="other">
Peyer, U., andT. Vermaelen. 2005. The many facets of privately negotiated stock repurchases. Journal of Financial
Economics 75:361-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1823a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1827" publication-type="other">
Ramakrishnan, R. T. S., and A. Thakor. 1984. Information reliability and a theory of financial intermediation.
Review of Economic Studies 51:415-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1838a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1842" publication-type="other">
Rau, P. R., and T. Vermaelen. 2002. Regulation, taxes, and share repurchases in the United Kingdom. Journal of
Business 75:245-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1852a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1856" publication-type="other">
Renneboog, L., and P. G Szilagyi. 2011. The role of shareholder proposals in corporate governance. Journal of
Corporate Finance 17:167-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1866a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1870" publication-type="other">
Roll, R. 1988. R2. Journal of Finance 43:541-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1877a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1881" publication-type="other">
Skinner, D. J. 2008. The evolving relation between earnings, dividends, and stock repurchases. Journal of
Financial Economics 87:582-609.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1891a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1895" publication-type="other">
Song, F., and A. Thakor. 2007. Relationship banking, fragility and the asset-liability matching problem. Review
of Financial Studies 20:2129-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1905a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1909" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Financial system architecture and the co-evolution of banks and markets. Economic Journal
120:1021-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1924" publication-type="other">
Stephens, C. P., and M. S. Weisbach. 1998. Actual share reacquisition in open-market repurchase programs.
Journal of Finance 53:313-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1934a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1938" publication-type="other">
Stulz, R. 1988. Managerial control of voting rights: Financing policies and the market for corporate control.
Journal of Financial Economics 20:25-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1948a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1952" publication-type="other">
Thakor, A. 2012. Incentives to innovate and financial crises. Journal of Financial Economics 103:130-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1959a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1963" publication-type="other">
Thakor, A., and T. Whited. 2011. Shareholder-manager disagreement, animal spirits, and corporate investment.
Review of Finance 15:277-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1973a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1977" publication-type="other">
Thomas, R. S., and J. F. Cotter. 2007. Shareholder proposals in the new millenium: Shareholder support, board
response, and market reaction. Journal of Corporate Finance 13:368-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1987a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1991" publication-type="other">
Van den Steen, E. 2004. Rational overoptimism (and other biases). American Economic Review 94:1141-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1999a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e2003" publication-type="other">
. 2010a. Disagreement and the allocation of control. Journal of Law, Economics and Organization
26:385-426.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e2013a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e2017" publication-type="other">
. 2010b. Interpersonal authority in a theory of the firm. American Economic Review 100:466-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e2024a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e2028" publication-type="other">
Vermaelen, T. 1981. Common stock repurchases and market signaling. Journal of Financial Economics 9:139-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e2035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e2039" publication-type="other">
Weisbenner, S. J. 2004 Corporate share repurchases: What role do stock options play? Working Paper, University
of Illinois.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


