<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285015</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optimization of Exhaust After-Treatment System (EATS) to BS 6 Emission Level for a Light Commercial Vehicle (LCV) Using Existing BS 4 Engine Results and 1-D Simulation Approach</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rajan</surname>
                  <given-names>Ragupathi Soundara</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV India Pvt. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sharma</surname>
                  <given-names>Vijay</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV India Pvt. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Emran</surname>
                  <given-names>Ashraf</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV India Pvt. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rathod</surname>
                  <given-names>Devising</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV India Pvt. Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kwee</surname>
                  <given-names>John Henry</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Michaelis-Hauswaldt</surname>
                  <given-names>Thorsten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Körfer</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV Group Holding GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>February 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285006</issue-id>
         <fpage>72</fpage>
         <lpage>80</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285015"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The emission legislations are becoming increasingly strict all over the world and India too has taken a big leap in this direction by signaling the migration from Bharat Stage 4 (BS 4) to BS 6 in the year 2020. This decision by the Indian government has provided the Indian automotive industry a new challenge to find the most optimal solution for this migration, with the existing BS 4 engines available in their portfolio. Indian market for the LCV segment is highly competitive and cost sensitive where the overall vehicle operation cost (vehicle cost + fluid consumption cost) is the most critical factor. The engine and after-treatment technology for BS 6 emission levels should consider the factors of minimizing the additional hardware cost as well as improving the fuel efficiency. Often both of which are inversely proportional.</p>
            <p>The presented study involves the optimization of after treatment component size, layout and various systems for NOₓ and PM reduction. The study aims to analyze hardware changes required on the selected BS 4 engine to achieve improved engine out emission levels so as to minimize the Exhaust gas After-Treatment System (EATS) size using 1-D simulations approach.</p>
            <p>Normally the after treatment calibration and the engine thermodynamic calibration are performed separately which leads to complexity achieving the optimum fuel consumption and tail pipe emissions at vehicle level. FEV has developed a new strategy in which simultaneous optimization of involved systems like engine level thermodynamics, controls, transmission system and the EATS can be performed, thus arriving at the best engine and EATS configuration.</p>
            <p>In this study, the approaches to migrate from BS 4 to BS 6 for a Light Commercial Vehicle (LCV) application have been detailed. For an existing BS 4 diesel engine there can be two different approaches possible to meet the BS 6 emission targets. The first approach involves keeping the existing engine hardware unchanged and arriving at the required EATS, layout and sizing. The second approach involves implementation of engine level internal measures for improving engine-out emission levels and then arriving at a more optimized EATS. The engine level changes considered for this approach does not include any major architectural changes in the hardware. Both the approaches are evaluated on these two factors: a) cost of hardware addition to the existing engine and after-treatment system b) operational fluid cost. No changes into the transmission layout have been considered in this study. Although it was established that increase in the number of gears in the transmission will help reducing the engine out emissions [1].</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhardwaj, O., Blanco, D., Krishnamurthy, K., and Holderbaum, B., "Optimization of Engine Efficiency and Diesel Aftertreatment System Architecture Using an Integrated System Simulation Approach," SAE Technical Paper 2016-28-0227, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-28-0227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosefort, Y., Wiartalla, A., Kwee, H., and Pischinger, S., "Exhaust- Aftertreatment Integrated, DoE-based Calibration," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1303, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger, S., “Lecture notes - Internal Combustion Engines Volume II” 6th edition August 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Körfer, T., "Potential of Advanced, Combined Aftertreatment Systems for Light-Duty Diesel Engines to Meet Upcoming EU and US Emission Regulation," SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0163, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fillippo, D., Chianale, A., Menghini D., and Sacco N., "Untersuchung zur NOx-Reduktionaleistung verschiedener NOx Speicherkatalysatoren für die Abgasnachbehandlung bei Dieselmotoren", Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug - und Motorentechnik 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boger, T., Jamison, J., Warkins, J., Golomb, N., Warren, C., and Heibel, A., "Eine neue Generation von Aluminium-Titanat Dieselpartikelfiltern für die Anwendung in Fahrzeugapplikationen mit EU6 Gesetzgebung”, Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bar, F., and Cooper, B., "Die Herausforderung CO2 und Emissionen für zukünftige Dieselmotoren gleichzeitig zu reduzieren : Zielfuhrende Ansätze?", Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Göbel, U., Muller, W., Grisstede, I., and Rohr, F., "Diesel NOx- Aftertreatment Systems for North America", Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger, S., Körfer, T., Wiartalla, A., Schnitzler, J. et al., "Combined Particulate Matter and NOx Aftertreatment Systems for Stringent Emission Standards," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1128, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Kurozumi, N., Kawamoto, K., and Nakamura, K., "Der Neue Nissan 2,5L Dieselmotor mit Abgasnachbehandlungssystem : NOx- Speicherkatalysator und Cordierit-DPF-System", Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug und Motorentechnik 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
