<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">51</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186601</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44440311</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The POSSIBILITIES of SHAVED GEARS for AIRCRAFT ENGINES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>A. W.</given-names>
                  <surname>HARRIS</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1943</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>329</fpage>
         <lpage>344</lpage>
         <page-range>329-333, 344</page-range>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44440311"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>ALTHOUGH shaving had already become a common method of finishing spur and helical gears in the automotive industry before the war, there were many problems that had to be solved before this method could be applied to aircraft-engine gears. The major objection of the aircraft industry to shaving has been the probability of distortion during heat-treatment subsequent to finishing the tooth form. Mr. Harris suggests that the heattreatment procedure be changed to make expansion more uniform, and then an allowance be introduced in cutting the gear originally to compensate for this uniform expansion. Another objection to shaving has been the probability of highly concentrated stresses due to cutter marks and the line of demarcation between the hobbed and shaved contour in the tooth fillet. Mr. Harris proposes a form of hob for giving smooth fillet contours that will blend with the shaved active profile of the gear. The author also discusses the types of errors that might occur in the gear before shaving and be only partially corrected.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


