<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278032</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Emissions Characterization from Different Technology Heavy-Duty Engines Retrofitted for CNG/Diesel Dual-Fuel Operation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Besch</surname>
                  <given-names>Marc C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Israel</surname>
                  <given-names>Joshua</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Thiruvengadam</surname>
                  <given-names>Arvind</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kappanna</surname>
                  <given-names>Hemanth</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Carder</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>West Virginia University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1342</fpage>
         <lpage>1358</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278032"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study was aimed at experimentally investigating the impact of diesel/natural gas (NG) dual-fuel retrofitting onto gaseous emissions emitted by i) legacy, model year (MY) 2005 heavy-duty engines with cooled EGR and no after-treatment system, and ii) a latest technology engine equipped with DPF and urea-SCR after-treatment systems that is compliant with 2010 US-EPA emissions standards. In particular, two different dual-fuel conversion kits were evaluated in this study with pure methane (CH₄) being used as surrogate for natural gas. Experiments were conducted on an engine dynamometer over a 13-mode steady-state test cycle as well as the transient FTP required for engine certification while gaseous emissions were sampled through a CVS system.</p>
            <p>Tailpipe NOₓ emissions were observed at a comparable level for diesel and diesel/CH₄ dual-fuel operation for the 2010 compliant engine downstream the SCR. However, a reduction of ∼26% in diesel exhaust fluid (DEF) consumption was measured for dual-fuel operation, corroborating with engine-out NOₓ concentrations that were observed to be ∼32% lower as compared to diesel-only operation, indicating that the addition of natural gas significantly decreased NOₓ emissions formed during the combustion process. On the other hand, dual-fuel operation of the non after-treatment equipped, legacy engines showed conflicting NOₓ emissions results. While NOₓ emissions were observed to reduce for one of the legacy engines by ∼25%, dual-fuel operation of the second legacy engine resulted in a 6.6% increase in brake-specific NOₓ.</p>
            <p>Carbon dioxide emissions (CO₂) were observed to decrease across all steady-state engine load modes and by 3 to 8% over the transient FTP cycle with no specific trend towards an engine technology. Methane addition to the post-2010 engine, however, resulted in the highest overall CO₂ reduction for the given amount of CH₄ injected. Additionally, this study was focusing on evaluating possible greenhouse gas benefits (i.e. tank to exhaust) from diesel/NG retrofitting as a function of engine technology. It was observed that despite the reduction in CO₂ emissions the global warming potential (GWP) benefits of dual-fuel operation were outweighed by a significant increase in methane-hydrocarbon (MHC) emissions, specifically by factors of 1.6 and 2.3-4.8 for the post-2010 and legacy engines, respectively.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Z., Karim, G.A., “Simulation of combustion processes in gasfuelled diesel engines,” Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. (Part A), J. Power Energy, (211), 159-169, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Papagiannakis, R.G., Rakopoulos, C.D., Hountalas, D.T., Rakopoulos, D.C., “Emission characteristics of high speed, dual fuel, compression ignition engine operating in a wide range of natural gas/diesel fuel proportions,” Fuel (89), 1397-1406, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagemakers, A. and Leermakers, C., “Review on the Effects of Dual-Fuel Operation, Using Diesel and Gaseous Fuels, on Emissions and Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0869, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0869.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hesterberg, T. W., Lapin, C. A., Bunn, W. B., “A comparison of emissions from vehicles fueled with diesel or compressed natural gas,” Environmental Science and Technology, (42), 6437-6445, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, A., Thipse, S., Tyagi, A., Rairikar, S. et al., “Literature Review and Simulation of Dual Fuel Diesel-CNG Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-26-0001, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-26-0001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stalhammer, P., Erlandsson, L., Willner, K., and Johannesson, S., “Assessment of Dual-Fuel Technology,” Report SGC 233, June, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cozzolini, A., Littera, D., Ryskamp, R., Smallwood, J. et al., “Characteristics of Exhaust Emissions from a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Retrofitted to Operate in Methane/Diesel Dual-Fuel Mode,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0181, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harrington, J., Munshi, S., Nedelcu, C., Ouellette, P. et al., “Direct Injection of Natural Gas in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1630, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McTaggart-Cowan, G.P., Bushe, W.K., Hill, P.G., Munshi, S.R., “A supercharged heavy-duty diesel single cylinder research engine for highpressure direct injection of natural gas,” Int. J. Engine Res., (4), 315-30, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Littera, D., Besch, M., Cozzolini, A., Carder, D. et al., “Fresh and Aged SCRT Systems Retrofitted on a MY 1998 Class-8 Tractor: Investigation on In-use Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0175, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sahoo, B.B., Sahoo, N., Saha, U.K., “Effect of Engine Parameters and Type of Gaseous Fuel on the Performance of Dual-Fuel Gas diesel Engines - A Critical Review”, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 13(6), 1151-1184, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.bbr.2011.03.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “Characterization and Potential of Dual Fuel Combustion in a Modern Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2223, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dronniou, N., Kashdan, J., Lecointe, B., Sauve, K. et al., “Optical Investigation of Dual-fuel CNG/Diesel Combustion Strategies to Reduce CO2 Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):873-887, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1313.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Papagiannakis, R., Hountalas, D., Rakopoulos, C., and Rakopoulos, D., “Combustion and Performance Characteristics of a DI Diesel Engine Operating from Low to High Natural Gas Supplement Ratios at Various Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1392, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1392.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Papagiannavkis, R., and Hountalas, D., “Experimental investigation concerning the effect of natural gas percentage on performance and emissions of a DI dual fuel diesel engine,” Applied Thermal Engineering, 23, 353-365, 2003, doi:10.1016/S1359-4311(02)00187-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maji, S., Pal, A., and Arora, B., “Use of CNG and Diesel in CI Engines in Dual Fuel Mode,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-28-0072, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-28-0072.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guo, J., Ge, Y., Hao, L., Tan, J., Li, J., and Feng, X., “On-road measurement of regulated pollutants from diesel and CNG buses with urea selective catalytic reduction systems,” Atmospheric Environment, (99), 1-9, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grossale, A., Nova, I., and Tronconi, E., “Study of a Fezeolite-based system as NH3-SCR catalyst for diesel exhaust aftertreatment,” Catalysis Today, 136, 18-27, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lyons, J., Heiken, J., and Crawford, R., “Effects of Gas Composition on Emissions of Heavy-Duty Natural Gas Engines,” Sierra Research Inc., Report, SR2010-02-01, February, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karavalakis, G., Gysel, N., Hajbabaei, M., Durbin, T. et al., “Influence of Different Natural Gas Compositions on the Regulated Emissions, Aldehydes, and Particle Emissions from a Transit Bus,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1137, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Feist, M., Landau, M., and Harte, E., “The Effect of Fuel Composition on Performance and Emissions of a Variety of Natural Gas Engines,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(2):100-117, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United States Environmental Protection Agency, Department of Transportation, and National Highway Transportation Safety Agency, “Green-house Gas Emissions Standards and Fuel Efficiency Standards for Medium - and Heavy-Duty Engines and Vehicles; Final Rule,” September, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United States Environmental Protection Agency, “Code of Federal Regulations, Title 40, Part 1036, §108, Greenhouse gas emissions standards,” accessed Jan. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kappanna, H., Besch, M., Thiruvengadam, A., Delgado, O. et al., “Greenhouse Gas Emissions of MY 2010 Advanced Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Measured Over a Cross-Continental Trip of USA,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0170, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Covington, A., and Johnson, D., “Methane Leak and Loss Audits of Natural Gas fueled Compressor,” Proc. of ASME 2014 ICEF Technical Conference, ICEF2014-5626, October, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arteconi, C., Brandoni, D., Evangelista, F., and Polonara, F., “Lifecycle greenhouse gas analysis of LNG as a heavy-duty fuel in Europe,” Applied Energy, (87)6, 2055-2013, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, “Direct Global Warming Potentials,” IPCC Fourth Assessment Report, Climate Change 2007, Working Group I: The Physical Science Basis, Chapter 2.10, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United States Environmental Protection Agency, “Code of Federal Regulations, Title 40, Part 1065, Engine-Testing Procedures,” accessed Jan. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R.L Polk &amp; Co., 2012 US new commercial Class 3-8 heavy-duty vehicle registrations, Southfield, MI, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abd, A.G.H., Soliman, H.A., Badr, O.A., and Abd, R.M.F., “Effect of injection timing on the performance of a dual fuel engine,” Energy Conversion and Management, Vol. 43, pp. 269-277, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Selim, M.Y.E., “Sensitivity of dual fuel engine combustion and knocking limits to gaseous fuel composition,” Energy Conversion and Management, Vol. 45, pp. 411-425, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United States Environmental Protection Agency, “Code of Federal Regulations, Title 40, Part 86, Subpart N, Exhaust Test Procedures for Heavy-Duty Engines,” accessed Jan. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pilger, C., Szpindor, A., Trebing, J., Dahodwala, M., Uras, H., et al., “Dual Fuel Retrofit - HD OBD,” Panel presentation at SAE International 2014 On-Board Diagnostics Symposium, Sep. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smeets, M., “OBD Considerations for Dual- and Bi-Fuel Heavy-Duty Engines,” Abstract, SAE 2015 On-Board Diagnostics Symposium - Europe, Stuttgart, Germany, March 2nd-4th, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mustafi, N. and Raine, R., “A Study of the Emissions of a Dual Fuel Engine Operating with Alternative Gaseous Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1394, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1394.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lim, O., Iida, N., Cho, G., and Narankhuu, J., “The Research about Engine Optimization and Emission Characteristic of Dual Fuel Engine Fueled with Natural Gas and Diesel,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-32- 0008, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-32-0008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Papagianakkis, R., and Hountalas, D., “Combustion and exhaust emission characteristics of a dual fuel compression ignition engine operated with pilot diesel fuel and natural gas,” Energy Conversion and Management, 45, 2971-2987, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, J., Qin, J., and Yao, M., “Turbocharged diesel/CNG Dual-fuel Engines with Intercooler: Combustion, Emissions and Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3082, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3082.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, Z. and Su, W., “A Study On the Determination of the Amount of Pilot Injection and Rich and Lean Boundaries of the Pre-Mixed CNG/Air Mixture for a CNG/Diesel Dual-Fuel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0765, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0765.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, John B. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. McGraw- Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishiyama, T., Kang, J., Ozawa, Y., and Sako, T., “Improvement of Performance and Reduction of Exhaust Emissions by Pilot-Fuel- Injection Control in a Lean-Burning Natural-Gas Dual-Fuel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):243-253, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United States Environmental Protection Agency, “Code of Federal Regulations, Title 40, Part 1036, §705, Generating and calculating emissions credits,” accessed Jan. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
