<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023221</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Policymaking in the Face of Uncertainty</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fiscal Uncertainty and How to Deal With It</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Auerbach</surname>
                  <given-names>Alan J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>
                  <addr-line>Robert D. Burch Professor of Economics and Law</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>Director, Robert D. Burch Center for Tax Policy and Public Finance</addr-line>
                  <addr-line>University of California, Berkeley</addr-line>
               </aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>29</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023221"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Long-term projections of the federal budget show significant future imbalances, but these projections are enormously uncertain. Some argue that this uncertainty means we should pay less attention to the long-term budget projections, so as to avoid taking painful measures that may prove to be unnecessary. But in general, the appropriate response to uncertainty is instead to take more action now, as a precautionary measure against the possibility of worse-than-expected outcomes. “What is clear is that hoping for a better future does not constitute an appropriate policy response to uncertainty, and waiting until the size of the problem is known is waiting too long.”</p>
            <p>Much of the uncertainty in the short and medium run deficit is related to the business cycle. For the long run, the main sources of budget uncertainty over the next 25 years are the rate of productivity growth, the interest rate on the federal debt, and the rate of excess health cost growth. Whether these factors move in a favorable or unfavorable direction will determine the nature and extent of the fiscal response needed for stabilizing the national debt as a share of GDP. A possibly unfavorable outcome should weigh more heavily in future planning than should the opportunity cost of saving now if outcomes turn out to be better than expected. The United States should actively respond to this uncertainty by increasing its rate of saving, either through a reduction in spending, an increase in taxes, a reduction in the size of implicit government liabilities, or some combination of these actions. A precautionary savings buffer would allow for longer-term planning, more flexibility to meet economic shocks, and would reduce the need to increase marginal tax rates in the face of budget pressures.</p>
            <p>More effectively conveying uncertainty, perhaps by requiring the Congressional Budget Office to include a quantitative assessment of the degree of uncertainty present in its forecasts, would be a step in the right direction towards addressing the uncertainty involved with fiscal policymaking. Another policy option would be to subject the government budget to some sort of a “stress test,” in order to determine the government’s ability to meet its needs if unfavorable conditions arise. Finally, if automatic adjustments were used to provide budget stability and ensure appropriate risk-sharing across generations, it would reduce the need for Congress to continually make changes to legislation in response to changes in circumstances.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alesina, Alberto F., and Silvia Ardagna. 2013. “The Design of Fiscal Adjustments,” in J. Brown, ed., Tax Policy and the Economy 27, pp. 19–68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J. 1999. “On the Performance and Use of Government Revenue Forecasts,” National Tax Journal 52, December, pp. 767–782.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J. 2003. “Fiscal Policy, Past and Present,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 2003, Spring, pp. 75–122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J. 2006. “Budget Windows, Sunsets, and Fiscal Control,” Journal of Public Economics 90, January, pp. 87–100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J. 2009. “Long-Term Objectives for Government Debt,” FinanzArchiv 65, December, pp. 472–501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and William G. Gale. 2009. “The Economic Crisis and the Fiscal Crisis: 2009 and Beyond,” Tax Notes 125, October 5, pp. 101–130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and William G. Gale.2014. “Forgotten But Not Gone: The Long-Term Fiscal Imbalance,” Tax Notes 144, September 29, pp. 1555–1570.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and Kevin Hassett. 2007. “Optimal Long-Run Fiscal Policy: Constraints, Preferences and the Resolution of Uncertainty,” Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 31, May, pp. 1451–1472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and Laurence J. Kotlikoff. 1987. Dynamic Fiscal Policy, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Auerbach, Alan J., and Joel Slemrod. 1997. “The Economic Effects of the Tax Reform Act of 1986,” Journal of Economic Literature 35, June, pp. 589–632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barro, Robert J. 1974. “Are Government Bonds Net Wealth?” Journal of Political Economy 82, November-December, pp. 1095–1117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barro, Robert J. 1979. “On the Determination of the Public Debt,” Journal of Political Economy 87, October, pp. 940–971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berger, Loïc. 2014. “Precautionary Saving and the Notion of Ambiguity Prudence,” Economics Letters 123, May, pp. 248–251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blanchard, Olivier, and Daniel Leigh. 2013. “Growth Forecast Errors and Fiscal Multipliers,” IMF Working Paper 13/1, January.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Börsch-Supan, Axel, Anette Reil-Held, and Christina Benita Wilke. 2003. “How to Make a Defined Benefit System Sustainable: The ‘Sustainability Factor’ in the German Benefit Indexation Formula,” MEA Arbeitspapier 37-2003, Universität Mannheim.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO). 2005. “Quantifying Uncertainty in the Analysis of Long-Term Social Security Projections,” November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2007. “The Uncertainty of Budget Projections: A Discussion of Data and Methods,” March 5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2008. Data Used to Construct CBO's Measures of Uncertainty in Budget Projections, March 25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2014a. Estimates of Potential GDP and the Related Unemployment Rate, February 4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office (CBO) 2014b. “The 2014 Long-Term Budget Outlook,” July 25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellsberg, Daniel. 1961. “Risk, Ambiguity, and the Savage Axioms,” Quarterly Journal of Economics 75(4), November, pp. 643–669.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubbard, R. Glenn, Jonathan Skinner, and Stephen P. Zeldes. 1995. “Precautionary Saving and Social Insurance,” Journal of Political Economy 103(2), April, pp. 360–399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamin, David. 2014. “In Good Times and Bad: Designing Legislation that Responds to Fiscal Uncertainty,” Hutchins Center on Fiscal and Monetary Policy, Brookings Institution, November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knight, Frank H. 1921. Risk, Uncertainty and Profit. Boston: Houghton-Mifflin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, Ronald, and Shripad Tuljapurkar. 1998. “Uncertain Demographic Futures and Social Security Finances,” The American Economic Review 88(2), May, pp. 237–241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manski, Charles F. 2013. Public Policy in an Uncertain World, Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manski, Charles F. 2014. “Communicating Uncertainty in Official Economic Statistics,” NBER Working Paper 20098, May.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miao, Jianjun. 2004. “A Note on Consumption and Savings under Knightian Uncertainty,” Annals of Economics and Finance 5, November, 299–311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OASDI Board of Trustees. 1997–2014. Annual Report of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance and Federal Disability Insurance Trust Funds, Social Security Administration.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Office of Management and Budget (OMB). 2014. Fiscal Year 2015 Budget of the U.S. Government: Analytical Perspectives.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rueben, Kim, and Carol Rosenberg. 2009. “What Are Rainy Day Funds and How Do They Work?” Tax Policy Center, August 12.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skinner, Jonathan. 1988. “Risky Income, Life Cycle Consumption, and Precautionary Savings,” Journal of Monetary Economics 22, September, pp. 237–255.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Social Security Advisory Board (SSAB). 2011. Technical Panel on Assumptions and Methods, September.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Viceira, Luis M. 2001. “Optimal Portfolio Choice for Long-Horizon Investors with Nontradable Labor Income,” Journal of Finance 56(2), April, pp. 433–470.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
