<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">finaanalj</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">finaanalj</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j101316</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Financial Analysts Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The Financial Analysts Federation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">0015198X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i403123</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">4470306</article-id>
         
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Industry Reviews</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Copper Industry</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
              <string-name>John A. Olsen</string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
              <string-name>Terry A. Blaney</string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>1968</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>1968</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>36</fpage>
         <lpage>40</lpage>
         <page-range>36-40</page-range>
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1968 The Financial Analysts Federation</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/4470306"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>The use of probability or decision tree analysis has been applied to a study of the copper industry, focusing on copper prices, the principal determinant of individual company earnings. Computer models were designed to incorporate probabilities assigned to a range of estimates for several factors bearing on copper supply and demand. The result of combining these variables into a decision tree is a distribution of several thousand individual forecasts of primary copper needs, representing the analysts' best judgment of the future. There appeared to be a strong likelihood of a copper shortage in 1968 accompanied by higher prices that year and perhaps 1969, with a gradual easing by 1970-71, the remainder of the forecast period. Probability techniques were also applied to an analysis of the major copper companies utilizing the conclusions of the price forecast. The result is a distribution of earning power for each company with an indication of the analysts' confidence limits for that earning power in each year. Several limitations inherent in more traditional analysis are avoided through the use of the probabilistic model approach. It encourages self discipline by the analyst as he identifies and quantifies those factors which have the most important effect on the companies being studied. Second, the analyst's customers can readily see the assumptions he used and the degree of confidence he has in his forecasts. Third, areas of weakness can be identified for future improvement. Finally, the forecast can be easily updated or modified as conditions change by merely changing the weights used. The analyst should be no longer afraid to read the earnings reports in the paper.</p>
          </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
