<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939369</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Charity and Public Goods 2</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Charity, Status, and Optimal Taxation</article-title>
            <subtitle>Welfarist and Paternalist Approaches</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aronsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson-Stenman</surname>
                  <given-names>Olof</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wendner</surname>
                  <given-names>Ronald</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>63</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939369"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper deals with tax policy responses to charitable giving. Charitable donations are described in terms of voluntary contributions to a public good, to which the government also contributes through public revenue, and the set of tax instruments contains general, nonlinear taxes on income and charitable giving. Individuals are concerned with their warm-glow of giving as well as status determined by their relative contributions to charity and relative consumption compared to others, in addition to own absolute consumption, leisure and the public good. We analyze the conditions under which it is optimal to tax or subsidize charitable giving and derive corresponding optimal policy rules. Another purpose is to compare the optimal tax policy and public good provision by a conventional welfarist government with those by two kinds of paternalist governments, where the government does not share (i) the consumer preferences for status in terms of relative giving and relative consumption, and (ii) in addition does not share the consumer preference for warm-glow. The optimal policy rules for marginal taxation and public good provision are similar across governments, except for the stronger incentive to tax charitable giving at the margin under paternalism (ii). Numerical simulations supplement the theoretical results.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abel, A.B., (2005) Optimal Taxation When Consumers Have Endogenous Benchmark Levels of Consumption. Review of Economic Studies 72, 1-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Akerlof, G.A., (1997) Social Distance and Social Decisions. Econometrica 65, 1005-1028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Alpízar, F., F. Carlsson, and O. Johansson-Stenman (2005) How Much Do We Care about Absolute versus Relative Income and Consumption? Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization 56, 405-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Alpizar, F., F. Carlsson, and O. Johansson-Stenman, (2008) Anonymity, Reciprocity and Conformity: Evidence from Voluntary Contributions to a National Park in Costa Rica. Journal of Public Economics 92, 1047-1060.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Andreoni, J., (1989) Giving with Impure Altruism: Applications to Charity and Ricardian Equivalence. Journal of Political Economy 97, 1447-1458.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Andreoni, J., (1990) Impure Altruism and Donations to Public Goods: A Theory of Warm- Glow Giving. Economic Journal 100, 464-77.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Andreoni, J. and R. Petrie, (2004). Public Goods Experiments without Confidentiality: a Glimpse into Fund-raising. Journal of Public Economics 88, 1605-1623.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Aronsson, T., O. Johansson-Stenman, (2008) When the Joneses' Consumption Hurts: Optimal Public Good Provision and Nonlinear Income Taxation. Journal of Public Economics 92, 986-997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Aronsson, T., O, Johansson-Stenman, (2010) Positional Concerns in an OLG Model: Optimal Labor and Capital Income Taxation. International Economic Review 51, 1071-1095.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Aronsson, T., O, Johansson-Stenman, (2014) When Samuelson met Veblen Abroad: National and Global Public Good Provision When Social Comparisons Matter. Economica 81, 224-243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Aronsson, T., O. Johansson-Stenman (2018) Paternalism Against Veblen: Optimal Taxation and Non-Respected Preferences for Social Comparisons. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 10, 39-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Aronsson, T., O. Johansson-Stenman, and R. Wendner (2018) Redistribution through Charity and Optimal Taxation when People are Concerned with Social Status. Unpublished Manuscript.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Atkinson, A.B., (1976) The Income Tax Treatment of Charitable Contributions. In: Grieson, R. (Ed.), Public and Urban Economics: Essays in the Honor of William S. Vickrey. D.C. Heath, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Auten, G., H. Sieg, C.T. Clotfelter, (2002) Charitable Giving, Income and Taxes: An Analysis of Panel Data. American Economic Review 92, 371-382.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Besley, T., S. Coate, (1992) Understanding welfare stigma: Taxpayer resentment and statistical discrimination, Journal of Public Economics 48, 165-184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Blackorby, C., W. Bossert, D. Donaldson, (2005) Population Issues in Social Choice Theory, Welfare Economics and Ethics. New York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Blanchflower, D.G., A.J. Oswald, (2004) Well-Being Over Time in Britain and the USA. Journal of Public Economics 88, 1359-1386.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Bergstrom, T., L. Blume, and H. Varian (1985) On the Private Provision of Public Goods. Journal of Public Economics 29, 25-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Blomquist S., L. Micheletto, (2006) Optimal Redistributive Taxation when Government’s and Agents’ Preferences Differ. Journal of Public Economics 90, 1215-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Blumkin, T., E. Sadka, (2007) A case for taxing charitable donations. Journal of Public Economics 91 (7-8), 1555-1564.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Boskin, M.J., E. Sheshinski, (1978) Individual Welfare Depends Upon Relative Income. Quarterly Journal of Economics 92, 589-601.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Bowles, S., Y. Park, (2005) Emulation, Inequality, and Work Hours: Was Thorsten Veblen Right? Economic Journal 115, F397-F412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Carlsson, F., O. Johansson-Stenman, P. Martinsson, (2007) Do You Enjoy Having More Than Others? Survey Evidence of Positional Goods. Economica 74, 586-598.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Cartwright, E., A. Patel, (2013) How Category Reporting can Improve Fundraising. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization 87, 73-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Clark, A.E., A.J. Oswald, (1994) Unhappiness and Unemployment, Economic Journal 104, 648-659.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Clark, A., C. Senik, (2010) Who Compares to Whom? The Anatomy of Income Comparisons in Europe. Economic Journal 120, 573-594.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Clotfelter, C.T. (Ed.), (1992) Who Benefits from the Nonprofit Sector. The University of Chicago Press, Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Clotfelter, C.T., (2014) Charitable Giving and Tax Policy in the U.S. In: Fack, G., C. Landais (Eds.), Charitable Giving and Tax Policy: A Historical and Comparative Perspective. Oxford, Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">DellaVigna, S., J. List, U. Malmendier, (2012) Testing for Altruism and Social Pressure in Charitable Giving. Quarterly Journal of Economics 127, 1-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Diamond, P., (1980) Income Taxation with Fixed Hours of Work. Journal of Public Economics 13(1): 101-110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Diamond, P., (2006) Optimal Tax Treatment of Private Contributions for Public Goods with and Without Warm-Glow Preferences. Journal of Public Economics 90, 897-919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Dodds, S. (2012) Redistributive Taxation and Heterogeneous Relative Consumption Concerns. Canadian Journal of Economics 45, 220-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Duesenberry, J.S. (1949) Income, Saving and the Theory of Consumer Behavior. Harvard University Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Dupor, B., W.F. Liu, (2003) Jealousy and Overconsumption. American Economic Review 93, 423-428.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Easterlin, R.A., (2001) Income and Happiness: Towards a Unified Theory. Economic Journal 111, 465-484.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Eckerstorfer, P., R. Wendner (2013) Asymmetric and Non-atmospheric Consumption Externalities, and Efficient Consumption Taxation, Journal of Public Economics 106, 42-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Fack, G. and C. Laindais, eds., (2012) Charitable Giving and Tax Policy: A Historical and Comparative Perspective. Conference Volume, CEPR/CEPREMAP Conference on Altruism and Charitable Giving held in May 2012, Paris School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Feldstein, M., (1980) A Contribution to the Theory of Tax Expenditures: The Case of Charitable Giving. In: Aaron, H. J., and M. J. Boskin (Eds.), The Economics of Taxation, Essays in Honor of Joseph Peckman, 99-122. Brookings Institution, Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Ferrer-i-Carbonell, A., (2005) Income and Well-being: An Empirical Analysis of the Comparison Income Effect. Journal Public Economics 89, 997-1019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Galí, J., (1994) Keeping Up with the Joneses: Consumption Externalities, Portfolio Choice and Asset Prices. Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 26, 1-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Glazer, A., K. Konrad, (1996) A Signaling Explanation for Charity. American Economic Review 86, 1019-1028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Goodin, R. E. (1986) Laundering Preferences. In Foundations of Social Choice Theory, edited by J. Elster and A. Hylland. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Harbaugh, W., (1998a) What do Donations Buy? A Model of Philanthropy Based on Prestige and Warm Glow. Journal of Public Economics 67, 269-284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Harbaugh, W., (1998b) The Prestige Motive for Making Charitable Transfers. American Economic Review 88, 277-282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Harsanyi, J. (1982) Morality and the Theory of Rational Behavior. In Utilitarianism and Beyond, edited by Sen, A. and Williams, B. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Johansson-Stenman, O., F. Carlsson, D. Daruvala, (2002) Measuring Future Grandparents' Preferences for Equality and Relative Standing. Economic Journal 112, 362-383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Kanbur, R., M. Tuomala. (2013) Relativity, Inequality and Optimal Nonlinear Income Taxation. International Economic Review 54, 1199-1217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Kaplow, L., (1995) A note on subsidizing gifts. Journal of Public Economics 58, 469-477.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Kaplow, L., (1998) Tax policy and gifts. American Economic Review: Papers and Proceedings 88, 283-288.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Kleven, H., W. Kopczuk, (2011) Transfer program complexity and the takeup of social benefits. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy 3, 54-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Layard, R., (1980) Human Satisfaction and Public Policy. Economic Journal 90, 737-750.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Ljungqvist, L., Uhlig, H., (2000) Tax Policy and Aggregate Demand Management Under Catching Up with the Joneses. American Economic Review 90, 356-366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Micheletto, L. (2011) Optimal Nonlinear Redistributive Taxation and Public Good Provision in an Economy with Veblen Effects. Journal of Public Economic Theory 13, 71-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Moffit, R., (1983) An economic model of welfare stigma, American Economic Review 75, 1023-1035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Oswald, A., (1983) Altruism, Jealousy and the Theory of Optimal Non-Linear Taxation. Journal of Public Economics 20, 77-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Reinstein, D., G. Riener, (2012) Decomposing Desert and Tangibility Effects in a Charitable Giving Experiment. Experimental Economics 15, 229-240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Roberts, R.D., (1987) Financing Public Goods. Journal of Political Economy 95, 420-437.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Sen, A.K., (1983) Development: Which Way Now? The Economic Journal 93, 745-762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Sen, A.K., (1999) Development as Freedom (ed. A. Knopf), New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Saez, E., (2004) The Optimal Treatment of Tax Expenditures. Journal of Public Economics 88, 2657-2684.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Sen, A. K. (1979) Personal Utilities and Public Judgments: or What’s Wrong with Welfare Economics. Economic Journal 89, 537-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Solnick, S., D. Hemenway, (2005) Are Positional Concerns Stronger in Some Domains than in Others? American Economic Review, papers and proceedings 45, 147-151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Stiglitz, J.E., (1982) Self-Selection and Pareto Efficient Taxation. Journal of Public Economics 17, 213-240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Warr, P., (1982). Pareto optimal redistribution and private charity. Journal of Public Economics 19, 131-138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Veblen, T. (1899) The Theory of the Leisure Class. New York: Macmillan.Wendner, R., L.H. Goulder, (2008) Status Effects, Public Goods Provision, and the Excess Burden. Journal of Public Economics 92, 1968-1985</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Marginal Taxation or Subsidization of Charitable Giving</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Simulation results: variation in the preferences for charitable giving, σ.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Simulation results: variation in the degree of consumption positionality, α .</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Simulation results: variation in the degree of charitable positionality, β .</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Simulation results: variation in the preference for charitable giving, σ , based on the alternative utility function.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
