<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007074</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Influence of the DVR on the Transient Response of Wind Farms Against Voltage Sags</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ríos</surname>
                  <given-names>Alberto</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Guevara</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Universidad Técnica de Ambato, Tungurahua, Ecuador.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007065</issue-id>
         <fpage>335</fpage>
         <lpage>347</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007074"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In this paper has been evaluated the transient response of Dynamic Voltage Restorer (DVR) against voltage sags and the impact of these electronic devices to maintain the continuity of supply of wind farms against a three-phase voltage sag. The aim of these studies is to verify the influence of the DVR on the ability of wind turbines and wind farms to fulfill the more demanding grid connection requirements of power systems operators. Moreover, the simulations are performed in order to:
<list list-type="bullet">
                  <list-item>
                     <p>Analyse the impact of DVR device on the transient response of wind farm.</p>
                  </list-item>
                  <list-item>
                     <p>Evaluate the capacity of fixed speed wind farms to maintain the continuity of supply during three-phase voltage sags.</p>
                  </list-item>
               </list>
            </p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>Wind turbines</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>transient stability</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>grid integration</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>FACTS devices</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T.J.E. Miller, “Reactive Power Control in Power Systems”. John Wiley &amp;Sons, New York, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L.A. Erinmez, “Static Var Compensators”. Report prepared by Working Group 38-01, Task Force Nº2 on SVC, CIGRE, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Bernet, “Recent Development of High Power Converters for Industry and Traction Applications”, IEEE Transaction on Power Electronics, Vol. 15, No. 6, November 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CIGRE Working Group 14.19, “Static Synchronous Compensator (STATCOM)”, Technical Report, CIGRE 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Mohan Mathur and R.K. Varma, “Thyristor-Based FACTS Controllers for Electrical Transmission System”, Springer, Berlin, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C.A. Cañizares, “STATCOM Modelling for Voltage and Angle Stability Studies”, Electrical Power &amp; Energy Systems 25, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. Freitas, M.B.C. Salles, J.C.M. Vieira, A. Morelato, L.C. Pereira da Silva and V.F. Da Costa, “Impacts on Dynamic Reactive Power Compensation on the Performance of Wind Power Generators”, International Journal of Energy Technology and Policy, Special Issue on Reactive Compensation for Wind Farms, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ríos Villacorta, S. Arnaltes Gómez and J.L. Rodríguez Amenedo, “Improving Voltage Stability in a Wind Farm using SVC”, EWEC, London, United Kingdom. 22–25 November, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Gaztañaga, I. Etxebarria-Otadui, D. Ocnasu ans S. Bacha, “Real-Time Analysis of Transient Response Improvement of Fixed-Speed Wind Farms by Using a Reduced-Scale STATCOM Prototype”, IEEE Transaction on Power Systems, Vol. 22, May 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Grunbaum, T. Gustafsson and U. Olsson, “SVC Light: Evaluation of First Installation at Hagfors, sweden”, CIGRE Conference, Paris, France, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Grunbaum, P. Halvarsson, D. Larsson and P. Jones, “Conditioning of Power Grids serving Offshore Wind Farms based on Asynchonous Generators”, IEE PEMD 2004, 2nd International Conference on Power Electronics, Machines and Drives, Edinburgh, UK, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z. Saad-Saoud, M. Lisboa, J. Ekanayake, N. Jenkins and G. Strbac, ”The application of STATCOMs to Wind Farms”, IEE Proceedings Generation, Transmission and Distribution, Vol. 145, Nº5, September 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Aten, J. Martínez and P.J. Cartwrigth, “Fault Recovery of a Wind Farm with Fixed-Speed Induction Generators using a STATCOM”, Wind Engineering, Vol. 29, Nº4, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Noroozian and C. W. Taylor, “Benefits of SVC and STATCOM for Electric Utility Application”, Technical Report, October 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Acha, C.R. Fuente-Esquivel, H. Aabriz and C. Angeles, “FACTS: Modelling and Simulation in Power Networks”, John Wiley and Sons, England, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X.P. Zhang, C. Rehtanz and B. Pal, “Flexible AC Transmission Systems: Modelling and Control”, Springer, Berlin, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N.G. Hingorani and L. Gyugyi, “Understanding FACTS: Concepts and Technology of Flexible AC Transmission Systems”, IEEE Press, New York, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Boonchiam and N. Mithulananthan, “Understanding of Dynamic Voltage Restorers through MATLAB Simulation”, Thammasat Int. J. Sc., Vol. 11, Nº3, July-September 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ghosh and G. Ledwich, “Power Quality Enhacement using Custom Power Devices”, Kluwer Academic Publishers, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CIGRE Working Group 14.31, “Custom Power: State of the Art”, Technical Report, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O. Anaya-Lara and E. Acha, “Modelling and Analysis of Custom Power Systems by PSCAD/EMTDC”. IEEE Transactions on Power Delivery, Vol. 17, Nº1, January 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S.S. Choi, J. Li and D.M. Vilathgamuwa, “A Generalized Voltage Compensation for Mitigating the Impacts of Voltage Sags/Swells”, IEEE Transactions on Power Delivery, Vol. 20, Nº3, July 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.G. Nielsen and F. Blaabjerg, “A Detailed Comparison of System Topologies for Dynamic voltage Restorers”, IEEE Transactions on Industry Application, Vol. 41, Nº5, September/October 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Fitzer, M. Barnes and P. Green, “Voltage Sag Detection Technique for a Dynamic Voltage Restorer”, IEEE Transactions on Industry Application, Vol. 40, Nº1, January/February 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">V.K. Ramachandaramurthy, A. Arulampalam, C. Fitzer, C. Zhan, M. Barnes and N. Jerkings, “Supervisor Control of Dynamic Voltage Restorers”, IEE Proceedings Generation, Transmission and Distribution, Vol. 151, Nº4, July 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.G. Nielsen, M. Newman, H. Nielsen and F. Blaablerg, “Control and Testing of Dynamic Voltage Restorer at Medium Voltage Level“, IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, Vol. 19, Nº3, May 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Sannino and J. Svensson, “A Series-Connected Voltage Source Converter for Voltage Sag Mitigation using a Vector Control and Filter Compensation Algorithm”, Industry Application Conference 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N.H. Woodley, “Field Experience with Dynamic Voltage Restorer Systems”, IEEE Power Engineering Society Winter Meeting, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CH. Kavitha Busi and M.E. Murali, “Fault Ride-Through of a DFIG Wind urbine Using a Dynamic Voltage Restorer during Symmetrical and Asymmetrical Grid Faults”, International Journal of Advanced Trends in Computer Science and Engineering, Special Issue of ICETEM 2013 – Held on 29–30 November, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>[30]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Gómez-Pérez, E. Jiménez-Macías, E. Martínez-Cámara and J. Ramos-Hernanz, “DGFACTS comparative in wind power to solve LVRT requirements”, International Conference on Renewable Energies and Power Quality (ICRERQ’13).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>[31]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mustafa Jawad Kadhim and D.S. Chavan, “Improvement Fault-Ride Through of DFIG Based Wind Turbines by Using a Series Compensation Technology with Emphasis Put on the Mitigation of Voltage Dips”, International Journal of Recent Technology and Engineering (IJRTE).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>[32]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M.N. Hinaja, S. Premalatha, S.S. Dash and P.C. Babu, “A Novel Control Strategy for DVR to Improve Voltage Profile in Wind Farm”, Advance Material Research, Vol. 768, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>[33]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Lakshmi, “Modelling of Dynamic Voltage Restorer against Balanced and Unbalanced Voltage Sags in Distribution Systems”, IOSR Journal of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Vol. 4, Issue 6, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>[34]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ríos, M. Gascó, S. Arnaltes and J.L. Rodríguez-Amenedo, “Implementation of the Wind Park PQ Curve in the dimensioning of the reactive compensation system”, Nordic Wind Power Conference, Gotebörg, Sweden, March 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>[35]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ríos, S. Arnaltes and J.L. Rodríguez-Amenedo, “Reactive Capability Limits of Wind Farms”, International Journal of Energy Technology and Policy, Special issue on Reactive Compensation for Wind Farms, March 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>[36]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ríos and M. Gascó, “Control, Regulation and Storage Systems to Optimize the Integration of Wind Power”, 11th International Workshop on Large-Scale Integration of Wind Power into Power Systems as well as on Transmission Networks for Offshore Wind Power Plants, Lisbon, Portugal, November 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>[37]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ríos and M. Gascó, “Transient Stability of Variable Speed Wind Farms during Grid Faults”, Journal of Wind Engineering. Journal of Renewable Energy and Wind Power, Issue Nº2, April 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>[38]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Operational Procedure P.O. 12.3: “Requirements for Response in the Event of Voltage Dips in Wind Farm”, Red Eléctrica de España, REE, Octuber 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
