<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909501</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Examining Sensitivities in the Cost of Base Realignment Actions (COBRA) Program</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Smith</surname>
                  <given-names>David A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ David Smith is the Operations Research Analyst for the Army Basing Study (TABS). TABS determined the Army recommendations for the 2005 BRAC round. Before this assignment he was an Assistant Professor in the Department of Mathematical Sciences at the United States Military Academy.</p>
                  <p>MAJ Smith is a 1990 graduate of USMA and a received a Masters Degree in Applied Math from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in 2000. He was commissioned an Armor officer and served in positions from platoon leader to battalion operations officer before transferring to the ORSA branch.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2005</year>
            <string-date>December 2005</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>38</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909482</issue-id>
         <fpage>21</fpage>
         <lpage>23</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2005, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909501"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>Notes</title>
         <fn id="fn1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <p>The end-of-year formula is calculated on the implicit assumption that the costs and benefits occur in lump sums at year-end. When costs and benefits occur in a steady stream, applying mid-year discount factors is more appropriate. The first cost year is estimated to occur after six months, rather than at the end of one year to approximate better a steady stream of costs and benefits occurring in the first year.</p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
