<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830737</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830739</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>IMPROVING BANKABILITY OF SMALL FARMERS IN NORTHERN VIETNAM / COMMENT AMÉLIORER LA "BANCABILITÉ" DES PETITS EXPLOITANTS AGRICOLES DU VIETNAM DU NORD</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gertrud Buchenrieder</given-names>
                  <surname>Schrieder</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Insa</given-names>
                  <surname>Theesfeld</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>385</fpage>
         <lpage>403</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830739"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Access to financial services has proven to be important for poverty reduction in developing countries. Clearly, it is the poor who face considerable rationing with respect to the financial market. The reasons are manifold and can be associated with the demand and supply side of financial intermediation. They all result in higher transaction costs (TCs) or a reduced risk-bearing capacity. TCs include the noninterest expenses incurred by both lenders and borrowers in making (obtaining), servicing (implementing), and collecting (repaying) loans. The term 'risk-bearing capacity' describes the borrowers' capacity in terms of income, wealth and skill to cope with the risk of loosing the transaction costs if the credit application is refused or in case of a failing of the debt-financed investment. The term 'bankability' has entered the arena of development economics. Advocators of the notion that access to financial services reduces poverty claim that improving bankability supports credit access. From the perspective of the potential client, the term bankability comprises all aspects that increase the risk-bearing capacity and/or reduce the costs of acquiring a financial service, particularly credit. One finding in this paper is that a large proportion of the population in rural Vietnam refrains from becoming indebted not because of the TCs but because of their low risk-bearing capacity. Employing participatory research tools, one solution developed by small-holders in rural northern Vietnam was to set up an insurance fund to increase the risk-bearing capacity while being indebted and thus become bankable. L'accès aux services financiers s'est avéré être un facteur important dans la lutte contre la pauvreté dans les pays sous-développés. Il a été clairement mis en évidence que c'est le pauvre qui fait face au rationnement le plus important au niveau du marché financier. Les raisons sont d'ordre multiple et peuvent être associées aussi bien à l'ordre qu'à la demande de l'intermédiation financière. Elles résultent en coûts de transaction (CT) élevés et une capacité limitée à prendre de risque. Les CT incluent les dépenses (hors intérêts) auxquelles font face les prêteurs et les emprunteurs lors de la délivrance (l'obtention), la révision (mise en œuvre) et la collecte (payement) des emprunts. Le terme "capacité à prendre le risque" décrit la capacité de l'emprunteur en termes de revenu et d'aptitude à gérer le risque (de perdre les coûts de transaction) en cas de refus de la demande de crédit. Le terme "bancabilité" est entré dans l'arène de l'économie du développement. Les partisans de l'idée que l'accès aux services financiers réduirait la pauvreté prétendent que l'amélioration de la bancabilité supporte l'accès au crédit. Du point de vue du client potentiel, le terme "bancabilité" inclut tous les aspects qui augmentent la capacité à prendre le risque et/ou réduisent le coût d'acquisition d'un service financier, particulièrement le crédit. Un des résultats de cet article est qu'une large proportion de la population du Viêt-nam rural s'abstient à s'endetter non pas en raison des CT, mais en raison de leur capacité à prendre le risque. L'étude basée sur des outils de recherche participative révèle que l'une des solutions développées par les petits producteurs du nord du Viêt-nam rural était de mettre au plan une forme d'assurance pour accroître leur capacité à prendre du risque et à devenir ainsi bancable.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d43e184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e188" publication-type="other">
Alderman, H. and C. Paxon. 1992. "Do the poor insure? A synthesis of literature on risk and consumption in
developing countries". Working paper 1008. Washington D.C., USA: World Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e202" publication-type="other">
CGAP and UNDP. 1996. "Microfinance in Viet Nam", a collaborative study based upon the experiences of NGOs,
UN agencies and bilateral donors. CGAP and UNDP. Mai 1996. Hanoi, page 5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e212a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e216" publication-type="other">
CGAP. 1995. "Policy Document. A policy framework for the Consultative Group to Assist the Poorest (CGAP)" - A
micro-finance program. Washington D.C., USA: World Bank, CGAP. page 1.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e230" publication-type="other">
General Statistical Office. 1995. Statistical Data on basis situation and infrastructure of rural regions in Vietnam.
Hanoi: Statistical Publishing House.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e241a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e245" publication-type="other">
Hanh. 1999. Presentation from the director of the VBP, Mrs. Ha Thi Hanh. Workshop at Hanoi Agriculture University
(HAU). Hanoi. 13/03/1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e255a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e259" publication-type="other">
Ladman, J.R. 1984. "Loan-Transactions Costs, Credit Rationing, and Market Structure: The Case of Bolivia". In:
Undermining Rural Development with Cheap Credit. Westview Press, Boulder and London, page 104-119.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e269a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e273" publication-type="other">
Microenterprise Best Practice Newsletter. June 1999. Volume 1. No. 4, page 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e280a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e284" publication-type="other">
Nadler, Paul Dr. 1999. "Snapshots of Diversity: The Changing World of Finance". The Secured Lender, page 23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e291a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e295" publication-type="other">
Schenk, R. 1998. Die Auswirkung der Landreform in Nordvietnam auf die Zuganglichkeit zu mittel- und
langfristigen Krediten fur Kleinbauern. Diplomarbeit. Stuttgart, D: Universitat Hohenheim, Lehrstuhl fur
landwirtschaftliche Entwicklungstheorie und -politik.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e312" publication-type="other">
Schenk, R., Neef, A., and F. Heidhues. 1999. "Factors influencing smallholders' access to credit in Northern
Vietnam". Vietnam Socio-Economic Development Review (14).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e323a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e327" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G. 1999. "Rural finance and its relevance for stabilization of natural resources and rural development
in northern Vietnam". University of Hohenheim, Germany, mimeo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e341" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G., and M. Sharma. 1999. "Impact of finance on poverty reduction and social capital formation - A
review and synthesis of empirical evidence". Savings and Developmenf\3 (1): 67-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e355" publication-type="other">
Statistical District Office, Ba Be district, Mai 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e366" publication-type="other">
Theesfeld, I.J. 1999. Vietnam's rural credit market - Determinants of farmers'bankability. Master Thesis. Stuttgart,
D: University of Hohenheim, Department of Development Theory and Agricultural Development Policy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e376a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e380" publication-type="other">
The World Bank Group. 1998. Vietnam - Country Assistance Strategy of the World Bank Group 1999-2000.
Report No: 18375. August 20, 1998, page 1-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e390a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e394" publication-type="other">
VBA, Ba Be district. 1999. Interview with director of the VBA in Ba Be district, April 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e402a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e406" publication-type="other">
VBP. 1995. Information booklet. Hanoi, page 11.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


