<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830787</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830791</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MEASURING INTERNATIONAL FINANCIAL LIBERALISATION IN CARICOM</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Carlene</given-names>
                  <surname>Belford</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Kevin</given-names>
                  <surname>Greenidge</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2002</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>151</fpage>
         <lpage>164</lpage>
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830791"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Over the last two decades, the Caribbean countries have adopted policies aimed at liberalising their financial systems, mostly as part of their economic stabilisation and structural adjustment programmes. More recently, efforts at creating a Caribbean Community (CARICOM) Single Market and Economy have led the governments of the member countries to step-up their liberalisation process. This increased trend towards financial liberalisation has made it extremely important to be able to quantify these efforts in assessing the degree of liberalisation achieved thus far. Based on Quinn (1997), this paper produces an index to capture the extent of international financial liberalisation for each CARICOM country from 1979 to 1999. This measure assesses the many government policies regulating inward and outward financial transactions and allows comparison of the types and intensity of regulation across time and space. It is based upon a coding of the domestic and international laws of the individual CARICOM states, most of whose legislation is available from 1979 to 1999. The resulting indices appear to be consistent with the observed changes in financial liberalisation in the individual territories. Durant les deux dernières décennies, les pays des Caraïbes ont adopté des politiques visant à libéraliser leurs systèmes financiers, utilisé pour la plupart comme une partie du programme de stabilisation et d'adaptation structurelle de leur économie. Plus récemment, les efforts pour créer un marché et une économie unique dans la CARICOM, ont incité les gouvernements des pays membres à accorître le processus de libéralisation. Cette tendance accrue vers la libéralisation financière a accentué la volonté de mesurer ces efforts en évaluant le degré de libéralisation réalisé jusqu'ici. Basé sur Quinn (1997), cet article offre un index permettant de se rendre compte de l'importance de la libéralisation financière pour chaque pays de la CARICOM, de 1979 à 1999. Cet index évalue les nombreuses politiques gouvernementales régularisant les transactions financières intérieures et extérieures et permet de comparer les types et l'intensité des règlements à travers le temps et l'espace. Il est basé sur un codage des lois locales et internationales des différents états de la CARICOM dont la plupart est disponible de 1979 à 1999. Les indices résultants semblent, en effet correspondre aux changements observés par la libéralisation financière dans les différents territoires.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e147a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e151" publication-type="other">
Alesina Alberto, Vittorio Grilli and Gian Maria Milesi, "The Political Economy on Capital Controls"; in L. Leiderman and A. Razin
(eds.), Capital Mobility: The Impact on Consumption, Investment and Growth. Cambridge University Press, 1994, pp 289 - 321.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e165" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, Geert, Campbell R. Harvey and Christian Lundblad, "Emerging Equity Markets and Economic
Development", NBER Working Paper #7363, 2000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e175a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e179" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, Geert, Campbell R. Harvey and Christian Lundblad, "Does Financial Liberalisation Spur Growth?", NBER
Working Paper #8245, 2001.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e189a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e193" publication-type="other">
Bynoe - Mayers, Nola and Roland Craigwell, "Measuring Financial Development in Barbados: 1978-1998", Central
Bank of Barbados Working Papers, 2000, pp 105- 114.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e204a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e208" publication-type="other">
Doyle, Michelle A., "Capital Mobility: Estimate &amp; Implications, The Case of Barbados", Central Bank of Barbados
Working Papers, Vol. II, 1997, pp 55 - 74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e218a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e222" publication-type="other">
Edwards, Sebastian, "Capital Mobility and Economic Performance: Are Emerging Economies Different?", NBER
Working Paper #8076, 2001.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e232a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e236" publication-type="other">
El Hadj, Sidya Ould, "Financial Liberalisation: Its Relevance and Experience in the Caribbean", Social and
Economic Studies, Vol.46, Nos. 2 &amp; 3, 1997, pp 1- 30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e250" publication-type="other">
Feldstein Martin and Charles Horioka, "Domestic Saving and International Capital Flows", Economic Journal 90,
June 1980, pp 314 - 329.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e260a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e264" publication-type="other">
Garrett Geoffrey, "Capital Mobility, Trade and the Domestic Politics of Economic Policy", International Organisation,
49, 1995, pp 657-687.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e278" publication-type="other">
Klein, Michael and Giovanni Olivei, "Capital Account Liberalisation, Financial Depth and Economic Growth", NBER
Working Paper #7384, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e289a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e293" publication-type="other">
McKinnon Ronald I., Money and Capital in Economic Development. Brookings Institution, Washington DC, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e304" publication-type="other">
McKinnon Ronald I. The Order of Economic Liberalisation: Financial Control in the Transition to a Market Economy.
The Johns Hopkins University Press, USA, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e318" publication-type="other">
Pill, Huw and Mahmood Pradhan, "Financial Liberalisation in Africa and Asia", Paper presented at the 1997
Annual Meetings Program of Seminar, World Bank Group IMF, Washington, DC 20431,USA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e332" publication-type="other">
Quinn Dennis, "The Correlates of Change in International Financial Regulation", American Political Science
Review, Vol.91, September, No.3, 1997, pp 531- 551.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e346" publication-type="other">
Shaw Edward S., Financing Deepening in Economic Development. Oxford University Press, New York, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e353a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e357" publication-type="other">
1980 - 2000 issues of the Annual Report of Exchange Arrangement and Exchange Restrictions, IMF publication.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e365a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e369" publication-type="other">
CARICOM Protocols - Amending the Treaty of Chaguaramas, Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Foreign Trade, Barbados.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


