<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007063</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Wind Resource Assessment in Complex Urban Environment</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Romanić</surname>
                  <given-names>Djordje</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rasouli</surname>
                  <given-names>Ashkan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hangan</surname>
                  <given-names>Horia</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>WindEEE Research Institute, Western University, 2535 Advanced Avenue, N6M 0E2, London, ON, Canada</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007056</issue-id>
         <fpage>193</fpage>
         <lpage>212</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007063"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A wind energy assessment methodology is proposed for urban environments and applied for a specific urban development. Micro-scale wind energy maps are created using computational fluid dynamics simulations. The wind maps are used to calculate the available wind energy for the 2015 Pan American Games Athletes’ Village, in Toronto, Canada. The structure of the urban boundary layer has also been analyzed. It is shown that the maximum available energy can cover an important ratio of typical power requirements for the buildings. However, it is found that existing wind turbines have power curves that are de-coupled from the probability density functions of the wind availability. Therefore, the need for designing new urban wind turbines is discussed and required specifications are highlighted.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Key words:</label>
            <kwd>Urban wind energy</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Sustainable design</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Computational fluid mechanics</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Urban boundary layer</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Wind resource assessment</kwd>
            <x>; </x>
            <kwd>Horizontal axis wind turbines (HAWT)</kwd>
            <x>.</x>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munich Reinsurance Company (Munich Re), “Megacities - Megarisks: trends and challenges for insurance and risk management,” Munich Reinsurance Company (Munich Re), Munich, Germany, Disaster management professionals DRR10363, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Index Mundi, “World Demographics Profile 2013,” 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. R. Raupach, A. S. Thom, and I. Edwards, “A wind-tunnel study of turbulent flow close to regularly arrayed rough surfaces,” Boundary-Layer Meteorol, vol. 18, no. 4, pp. 373–397, Jun. 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Cheng and I. P. Castro, “Near Wall Flow over Urban-like Roughness,” Boundary-Layer Meteorology, vol. 104, no. 2, pp. 229–259, Aug. 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Kanda, R. Moriwaki, and F. Kasamatsu, “Large-Eddy Simulation of Turbulent Organized Structures within and above Explicitly Resolved Cube Arrays,” Boundary-Layer Meteorology, vol. 112, no. 2, pp. 343–368, Aug. 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Z.-T. Xie, O. Coceal, and I. P. Castro, “Large-Eddy Simulation of Flows over Random Urbanlike Obstacles,” Boundary-Layer Meteorol, vol. 129, no. 1, pp. 1–23, Oct. 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. W. Rotach, R. Vogt, C. Bernhofer, E. Batchvarova, A. Christen, A. Clappier, B. Feddersen, S.-E. Gryning, G. Martucci, H. Mayer, V. Mitev, T. R. Oke, E. Parlow, H. Richner, M. Roth, Y.-A. Roulet, D. Ruffieux, J. A. Salmond, M. Schatzmann, and J. A. Voogt, “BUBBLE – an Urban Boundary Layer Meteorology Project,” Theor. Appl. Climatol., vol. 81, no. 3–4, pp. 231–261, Jul. 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. J. Allwine, M. J. Leach, L. W. Stockham, J. S. Shinn, R. P. Hosker, J. F. Bowers, and J. C. Pace, “Joint urban 2003: study overview and instrument locations,” presented at the Symposium on Planning, Nowcasting, and Forecasting in the Urban Zone, Seattle, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. R. Oke, “The urban energy balance,” Progress in Physical geography, vol. 12, no. 4, pp. 471–508, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. W. Rotach, “Turbulence close to a rough urban surface part I: Reynolds stress,” Boundary-Layer Meteorol, vol. 65, no. 1–2, pp. 1–28, Jul. 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. W. Macdonald, R. F. Griffiths, and D. J. Hall, “An improved method for the estimation of surface roughness of obstacle arrays,” Atmospheric Environment, vol. 32, no. 11, pp. 1857–1864, Jun. 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Tennekes, “The Logarithmic Wind Profile,” Journal of the Atmospheric Sciences, vol. 30, no. 2, pp. 234–238, Mar. 1973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. R. Garratt, “Flux profile relations above tall vegetation,” Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society, vol. 104, no. 439, pp. 199–211, 1978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. R. Garratt, “Surface influence upon vertical profiles in the atmospheric near-surface layer,” Quarterly Journal of the Royal Meteorological Society, vol. 106, no. 450, pp. 803–819, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Christen, E. van Gorsel, and R. Vogt, “Coherent structures in urban roughness sublayer turbulence,” International Journal of Climatology, vol. 27, no. 14, pp. 1955–1968, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. P. Schmid, H. A. Cleugh, C. S. B. Grimmond, and T. R. Oke, “Spatial variability of energy fluxes in suburban terrain,” Boundary-Layer Meteorol, vol. 54, no. 3, pp. 249–276, Feb. 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. t. Millward-Hopkins, A. s. Tomlin, L. Ma, D. Ingham, and M. Pourkashanian, “The predictability of above roof wind resource in the urban roughness sublayer,” Wind Energy, vol. 15, no. 2, pp. 225–243, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. M. Cionco, “A Mathematical Model for Air Flow in a Vegetative Canopy,” J. Appl. Meteor., vol. 4, no. 4, pp. 517–522, Aug. 1965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. M. Cionco, “A wind-profile index for canopy flow,” Boundary-Layer Meteorol, vol. 3, no. 2, pp. 255–263, Dec. 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. W. Macdonald, “Modelling The Mean Velocity Profile In The Urban Canopy Layer,” Boundary-Layer Meteorology, vol. 97, no. 1, pp. 25–45, Oct. 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. S. Bahaj, L. Myers, and P. A. B. James, “Urban energy generation: Influence of microwind turbine output on electricity consumption in buildings,” Energy and Buildings, vol. 39, no. 2, pp. 154–165, Feb. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Mertens, “The energy yield of roof mounted wind turbines,” Wind Engineering, vol. 27, no. 6, pp. 507–518, Dec. 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. A. Heath, J. D. Walshe, and S. J. Watson, “Estimating the potential yield of small building-mounted wind turbines,” Wind Energy, vol. 10, no. 3, pp. 271–287, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. M. Sunderland, G. Mills, and M. F. Conlon, “Estimating the wind resource in an urban area: A case study of micro-wind generation potential in Dublin, Ireland,” Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics, vol. 118, pp. 44–53, Jul. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gatineau, QC: Environment Canada, “Canadian Wind Energy Atlas [computer file].” 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urban Design Associates, “West Don Lands Block Plan and Design Guidelines.” Jan-2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Frey-Buness, D. Heimann, and R. Sausen, “A statistical-dynamical downscaling procedure for global climate simulations,” Theor Appl Climatol, vol. 50, no. 3–4, pp. 117–131, Sep. 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Kaltschmitt, W. Streicher, and A. Wiese, Renewable Energy - Technology, Economics and Environment, XXXII. Berlin Heidelberg New York: Springer, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. P. Elliott, “The growth of the atmospheric internal boundary layer,” Transactions, American Geophysical Union, vol. 39, pp. 1048–1054, 1958.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>[30]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ESDU, “Strong winds in the atmospheric boundary layer. Part 1: Hourly mean wind speeds,” Engineering Science Data Unit ESDU Data Item 82026, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>[31]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. S. B. Grimmond and T. R. Oke, “Heat Storage in Urban Areas: Local-Scale Observations and Evaluation of a Simple Model,” J. Appl. Meteor., vol. 38, no. 7, pp. 922–940, Jul. 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>[32]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strong Winds in the Atmospheric Boundary Layer: Pt. 2: Discrete Gust Speeds. 83045. London: ESDU International PLC, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>[33]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">STAR-CCM+ User Guide 9.02. CD-Adapco.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>[34]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. H. Pletcher, J. C. Tannehill, and D. Anderson, Computational Fluid Mechanics and Heat Transfer, Second Edition. CRC Press, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>[35]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. R. Menter, “Two-equation eddy-viscosity turbulence models for engineering applications,” AIAA Journal, vol. 32, no. 8, pp. 1598–1605, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>[36]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. R. Menter, M. Kuntz, and R. Langtry, “Ten Years of Industrial Experience with the SST Turbulence Model,” in The fourth international symposium on turbulence, heat and mass transfer, turbulence heat and mass transfer series, Begell House, Antalya, 2003, vol. Turbulence, heat and mass transfer 4:, pp. 625–632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>[37]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Versteeg and W. Malalasekera, An Introduction to Computational Fluid Dynamics: The Finite Volume Method, 2 edition. Harlow, England; New York: Prentice Hall, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>[38]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. M. Jubayer and H. Hangan, “Numerical simulation of wind effects on a stand-alone ground mounted photovoltaic (PV) system,” Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics, vol. 134, pp. 56–64, Nov. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>[39]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. A. C. Rocha, H. H. B. Rocha, F. O. M. Carneiro, M. E. Vieira da Silva, and A. V. Bueno, “k–ω SST (shear stress transport) turbulence model calibration: A case study on a small scale horizontal axis wind turbine,” Energy, vol. 65, pp. 412–418, Feb. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>[40]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R.-J. Yang and W.-J. Luo, “Turbine blade heat transfer prediction in flow transition using k-omega two-equation model,” Journal of Thermophysics and Heat Transfer, vol. 10, no. 4, pp. 613–620, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>[41]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Franke, A. Hellsten, K. H. Schlunzen, and B. Carissimo, “The COST 732 Best Practice Guideline for CFD simulation of flows in the urban environment: a summary,” International Journal of Environment and Pollution, vol. 44, no. 1/2/3/4, p. 419, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>[42]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I. P. Castro and A. G. Robins, “The flow around a surface-mounted cube in uniform and turbulent streams,” Journal of Fluid Mechanics, vol. 79, no. 02, pp. 307–335, 1977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>[43]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. Rodi, “Comparison of LES and RANS calculations of the flow around bluff bodies,” Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics, vol. 69–71, pp. 55–75, Jul. 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>[44]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Parsons, T. H. Kuehn, R. J. Couvillion, J. W. Coleman, N. Suryanarayana, and Z. Ayub, 2005 ASHRAE HANDBOOK: Fundamentals: Inch-Pound Edition. Atlanta, GA.: Amer Society of Heating, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>[45]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Mertens, G. van Kuik, and G. van Bussel, “Performance of an H-Darrieus in the skewed flow on a roof,” J. Sol. Energy Eng. Trans.-ASME, vol. 125, no. 4, pp. 433–440, Nov. 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>[46]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Romanić, M. Ćurić, I. Jovičić, and M. Lompar, “Long-term trends of the ‘Koshava’ wind during the period 1949–2010,” Int. J. Climatol., p. n/a–n/a, Mar. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>[47]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA).” [Online]. Available: http://www.eia.gov/. [Accessed: 17-Dec-2013].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>[48]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wineur, “Urban wind turbines technology review,” European Commission under the Intelligent Energy - Europe Programme, A comparison text to the Catalouge of European Urban Wind Turbine Manufacture.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>[49]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. K. Sharma, A. Biswas, and R. Gupta, “Performance Measurement of a Three-Bladed Combined Darrieus-Savonius Rotor,” International Journal of Renewable Energy Research (IJRER), vol. 3, no. 4, pp. 885–891, Dec. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>[50]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Gavaldà, J. Massons, and F. Díaz, “Experimental study on a self-adapting Darrieus— Savonius wind machine,” Solar &amp; Wind Technology, vol. 7, no. 4, pp. 457–461, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
