<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26296408</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Wargame Rules as Intellectual Catalysts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rubel</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert C. (Barney)</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Captain Robert C. “Barney” Rubel USN, is retired and living in Monticello, Illinois. From May 2006 to August 2014 he was Dean of the Center for Naval Warfare Studies (CNWS) at the US Naval War College. Prior to assuming this position, he was Chairman of the Wargaming Department. A 30-year Navy veteran, he was a light attack naval aviator, flying the A-7 Corsair II and later the F/A-18 Hornet. He commanded Strike Fighter Squadron 131 and served as the Inspector General at US Southern Command.</p> 
                  <p>Captain Rubel’s shore assignments were principally involved with professional military education. He is a graduate of the Spanish Naval War College in Madrid and the US Naval War College in Newport, RI. He completed three separate faculty tours at the US Naval War College as a joint military operations instructor and ultimately as the Deputy Dean of the Center for Naval Warfare Studies. During these tours, he served as the William F. Halsey Chair of Air Strike Warfare and later the Colin Powell Chair of Joint Warfare.</p> 
                  <p>As Dean of CNWS, Professor Rubel designed and directed an eight-month effort that provided the logic and concepts that underpinned the 2007 US national maritime strategy “A Cooperative Strategy for 21st Century Seapower.” Professor Rubel increased student advanced research and developed new lines of inquiry including strategic cyberspace, unmanned systems, naval logistics, and command via challenged networks. He also redirected the vector of the International Law Department from teaching maritime law to research on cutting edge law of war issues. He has published more than 30 articles and book chapters on a number of subjects related to naval operational warfighting and strategy.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>September 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>50</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26296396</issue-id>
         <fpage>24</fpage>
         <lpage>29</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26296408"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Downes-Martin, Stephen. 2013. “Adjudication, ‘The Diabolus in Machina of Wargaming,’” Naval War College Review, Summer, pp. 71-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanley, John T. 1991. On Wargaming (dissertation, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Mich.; University Microfilms International, 1991).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuehn, John T. 2007. The Influence of Naval Arms Limitation on U.S. Naval Innovation During the Interwar Period, 1921–1937. Dissertation, Kansas State University, Manhattan, KS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Middlebrook, Martin. 1989. The Fight for the Malvinas. Viking Press, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, Edwin. 1991. War Plan Orange: The U.S. Strategy to Defeat Japan 1897–1945. Naval Institute Press, Annapolis, MD. p. 168.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parshall, Johnathan, and Tully, Anthony. 2005. Shattered Sword. Potomac Books, Inc., Dulles, VA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perla, Peter. 1990. The Art of Wargaming. US Naval Institute Press, Annapolis, MD.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rubel, Robert. 2006. “The Epistemology of Wargaming,” Naval War College Review, Spring, pp 124–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US Navy. 2013. Naval Warfare Publication 5-01 Navy Planning, December, pp. 3–4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Woodward, Admiral Sandy. 1992.One Hundred Days, with Patrick Robinson. Naval Institute Press, Annapolis, MD.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Work, Robert. 2015. “Wargaming and Innovation,” Deputy Secretary of Defense Memorandum, 9 February; https://news.usni.org/2015/03/18/document-memo- to-pentagon-leadership-onwargaming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
