<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909702</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Pythagoras User’s Group Update</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Alt</surname>
                  <given-names>Jon</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ Jonathan Alt is an Operations Analyst assigned to TRADOC Analysis Center – Monterey who received a BS in Engineering Management from the United States Military Academy in 1993 and an MS in Operations Analysis from the Naval Post Graduate School in 2006. Prior to becoming an operations analyst he served as an infantry officer in both the 3rd Infantry Division and the 101st Airborne Division.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Marling</surname>
                  <given-names>Robin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>LT Robin Marling received a BS in Mathematics from the United States Naval Academy in 2001. She received her MS in Information Systems and Operations from the Naval Postgraduate School in 2002. She has served aboard the USS Harpers Ferry and USS Enterprise and is currently stationed at the Operations Analysis Division of the Marine Corps Combat Development Command.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bitinas</surname>
                  <given-names>Edd</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Edmund Bitinas has been building and applying computer simulations in support of the Department of Defense for nearly thirty years. For the last six years he has been a Study Leader for the Marine Corps Studies Program. He is currently supporting the Marine Personnel Carrier Analysis of Alternatives, the Agent-Based Simulation Validation and Verification Framework Development Study, and an application of Pythagoras to Counter Insurgency Operations. Mr Bitinas is a Chief Scientist for Northrop Grumman Mission Systems.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2008</year>
            <string-date>March 2008</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909694</issue-id>
         <fpage>6</fpage>
         <lpage>8</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909702"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
