<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275472</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Ethanol Autoignition Characteristics and HCCI Performance for Wide Ranges of Engine Speed, Load and Boost</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sjoberg</surname>
                  <given-names>Magnus</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dec</surname>
                  <given-names>John E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>84</fpage>
         <lpage>106</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275472"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The characteristics of ethanol autoignition and the associated HCCI performance are examined in this work. The experiments were conducted over wide ranges of engine speed, load and intake boost pressure (P<sub>in</sub>) in a single-cylinder HCCI research engine (0.98 liters) with a CR = 14 piston.</p>
            <p>The data show that pure ethanol is a true single-stage ignition fuel. It does not exhibit low-temperature heat release (LTHR), not even for boosted operation. This makes ethanol uniquely different from conventional distillate fuels and offers several benefits: a) The intake temperature (T<sub>in</sub>) does not have to be adjusted much with changes of engine speed, load and intake boost pressure. b) High P<sub>in</sub>can be tolerated without running out of control authority because of an excessively low T<sub>in</sub>requirement.</p>
            <p>However, by maintaining true single-stage ignition characteristics, ethanol also shows a relatively low temperature-rise rate just prior to its hot ignition point. Therefore, ethanol does not tolerate as much combustion-phasing retard as fuels that exhibit LTHR and/or pronounced intermediate-temperature heat release. Since combustion retard is important for avoiding excessive pressure-rise rates, the distinct single-stage ignition characteristic of ethanol can be considered a drawback when reaching for higher loads. Nonetheless, an IMEP<sub>g</sub>of 11.3 bar was demonstrated for P<sub>in</sub>= 247 kPa.</p>
            <p>Finally, the latest ethanol chemical-kinetics mechanism from the National University of Ireland - Galway was evaluated against the experimental engine data using a multi-zone model. Overall, the mechanism performs very well over wide ranges of operating conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maly R. R., Degen, W., “Impact of Future Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-21-0073, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Wermuth, N. and Najt, P., “Development of Robust Gasoline HCCI Idle Operation Using Multiple Injection and Multiple Ignition (MIMI) Strategy,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0499, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Influence of Fuel Autoignition Reactivity on the High-Load Limits of HCCI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):39-58, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J.E., “Comparing Late-cycle Autoignition Stability for Single- and Two-Stage Ignition Fuels in HCCI Engines,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 31: 2895-2902, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christie, M. J., Fortino, N., and Yilmaz H., “Parameter Optimization of a Turbo Charged Direct Injection Flex Fuel SI Engine,” SAE Int. J. of Engines 2(1):123-133, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Amnéus, P., and Mauss, F., “Supercharged Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 980787, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gnanam, G., Sobiesiak A., Reader, G., and Zhang C., “An HCCI Engine Fuelled with Iso-octane and Ethanol,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3246, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, Y., He, B.-Q., Xie, H., and Zhao H., “The Combustion and Emission Characteristics of Ethanol on a Port Fuel Injection HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0631, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw-Hill, New York, ISBN 0-07-100499-8, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E, Davisson, M. L., Sjöberg, M., Leif, R. N., and Hwang, W., “Detailed HCCI Exhaust Speciation and the Sources of Hydrocarbon and Oxygenated Hydrocarbon Emissions,” SAE Int. J. of Fuels and Lubricants 1(1):50-67, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., and Cernansky, N. P., “Potential of Thermal Stratification and Combustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, based on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0113, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lutz, A. E., Kee, R. J. and Miller, J. A., “Senkin: A FORTRAN Program for Predicting Homogeneous Gas Phase Chemical Kinetics with Sensitivity Analysis,” Sandia National Laboratories Report No. SAND87-8248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lutz, A.E., “Multi-zone Model for Homogeneous Ignition,” Sandia National Laboratories, Internal Report, July 8, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Curran H., Serinyel, Z., and Metcalfe, W., Combustion Chemistry Centre at NUI Galway, Ireland, personal communication, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl, M., Pitz, W.J., Sjöberg, M., and Dec, J. E., “Detailed Kinetic Modeling of Low-Temperature Heat Release for PRF Fuels in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1806, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Hultqvist, A. and Johansson, B., “Demonstrating the Multi Fuel Capability of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine with Variable Compression Ratio,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3679, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A. and Itoh, T., “Parametric Study of Gasoline HCCI with Various Compression Ratios, Intake Pressures and Temperatures,” presented at A New Generation of Engine Combustion Processes for the Future ?:77-84, France, Nov. 26-27, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J. E., Babajimopoulos, A., and Assanis, D., “Comparing Enhanced Natural Thermal Stratification against Retarded Combustion Phasing for Smoothing of HCCI Heat-Release Rates,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2994, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Hwang, W., “Characterizing the Development of Thermal Stratification in an HCCI Engine Using Planar-Imaging Thermometry,” SAE Int. J. of Engines 2(1):421-438, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “An investigation into lowest acceptable combustion temperatures for hydrocarbon fuels in HCCI engines,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 30:2719-2726, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jun, D. and Iida, N., “A Study of High Combustion Efficiency and Low CO Emission in a Natural Gas HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1974, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves S.M., Flowers, D.L., Espinosa-Loza, F., Martinez-Frias, J., Dec, J.E., Sjöberg, M., Dibble R.W., and Hessel, R.P., “Spatial Analysis of Emissions Sources for HCCI Combustion at Low Loads Using a Multi-Zone Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1910, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christensen, M., Hultqvist, A. and Johansson, B., “The Effect of Top-land Geometry on Emissions of Unburned Hydrocarbons from a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1893, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S. M., Flowers, D. L., Espinosa-Loza, F., Martinez-Frias, J., Dibble, R. W., Christensen, M., Johansson, B., and Hessel, R. P., “Piston-Liner Crevice Geometry Effect on HCCI Combustion by Multi-Zone Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-0-2869, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Lavoie, G.A. and Assanis, D.N., “Modeling HCCI Combustion with High Levels of Residual Gas Fraction - A Comparison of Two VVA Strategies,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3220, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J.E., “An Investigation of the Relationship between Measured Intake Temperature, BDC Temperature, and Combustion Phasing for Premixed and DI HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1900, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E. and Sjöberg, M., “Isolating the Effects of Fuel Chemistry on Combustion Phasing in an HCCI Engine and the Potential of Fuel Stratification for Ignition Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0557, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grandin, B., Denbratt, I., Bood, J., Brackmann, C., Bengtsson, P.-E., “A Study of the influence of exhaust gas recirculation and stoichiometry on the heat release in the endgas prior to knock using rotational coherent anti-Stokes Raman spectroscopy thermometry,” Int. J. of Engine Research 3(4):209-221, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NIST Chemistry WebBook, “Standard Reference Database Number 69,” March 2009, http://webbook.nist.gov/chemistry/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olsson, J.-O., Tunestål, P., Johansson, B., Fiveland, S., Agama, J.R., and Assanis, D.N., “Compression Ratio Influence on Maximum Load of a Natural Gas-Fueled HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0111, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., and Yang, Yi, “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine Knock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1): 750-767, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J.A., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2859, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsurushima, T., Kunishima, E., Asaumi Y., Aoyagi, Y., and Enomoto, Y., “The Effect of Knock on Heat Loss in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0108, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
