<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663747</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/367754</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB760207</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Notes</article-title>
            <subtitle>University Schools of Business</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>04</month>
            <year>2003</year>
            <string-date>April 2003</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>76</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2003.76.issue-2</issue-id>
         <fpage>365</fpage>
         <lpage>370</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/367754"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Appointments</title>
         <p>Gordon J. Alexander, visiting prof., UCLA, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kurt M. Anstreicher, Henry B. Tippie Research Professor of Management Sciences, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Michel Avitar, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Stacey Baker, asst. prof., marketing, Wyoming, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Charles Bame‐Aldred, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ann Bastianelli, lecturer, marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>James Beach, visiting lecturer, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Jeffrey Bevelander, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Shannon Bradshaw, asst. prof., management sciences, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Pedro Carrillo, instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>John Cartwell, prof., Rutgers, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>N. K. Chidabaran, asst. prof., Rutgers, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Kris Clark, instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Matthew Clayton, asst. prof., Rutgers, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Gregory Crawford, asst. prof., economics, Univ. Arizona, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Russell Cropanzano, prof., management and policy, Univ. Arizona, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mourad Dakhli, asst. prof., Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Shawn D. Davis, visiting asst. prof., Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Cheryl Druehl, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Kent Drummond, assoc. prof., marketing, Wyoming, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Lance‐Michael Erickson, asst. prof., marketing, Univ. Arizona, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Chitru S. Fernando, assoc. prof., finance, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Linda Ferrell, asst. prof., marketing, Wyoming, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Lynn M. Fisher, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Craig R. Fox, assoc. prof., UCLA, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Louis Gattis, Jr., teaching prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>R. Matthew Germonprez, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Angelisa Gillyard, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Brent Goldfarb, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Anandasivam Gopal, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Peter H. Gray, asst. prof., business administration, Pittsburgh, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Deborah Gregory, lecturer, finance, Univ. Arizona, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Federico Guerrero, asst. prof., Nevada—Reno, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Traci J. Hess, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Steven L. Heston, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Craig Hill, asst. prof., Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Walter C. Hutchens, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Sanjay Jain, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Steve Johnson, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Itir Z. Karaesmen, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Sandy Klasa, asst. prof., finance, Univ. Arizona, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Canan Kocabasoglu, asst. prof., Univ. Kansas, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jeffrey D. Kudisch, teaching prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Terri Kurtzberg, asst. prof., Rutgers, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Timothy D. Landry, assoc. prof., marketing, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Peter S. H. Leeflang, visiting prof., UCLA, Apr. 2003.</p>
         <p>Vedran Lelas, visiting asst. prof., Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Kenneth Levine, instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Haidan Li, asst. prof., accounting, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Carlos Mello‐e‐Souza, asst. prof., Seattle, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Shaila Miranda, assoc. prof., management information systems, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Abhay N. Mishra, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Charles A. Nichols, visiting instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Erin Outz, visiting instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert B. Oxnam, visiting prof., Georgia State, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Chrisoula Papadopoulou, visiting asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Dilip K. Patro, visiting asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Craig Pirrong, prof., finance, and energy markets director, Global Energy Management Institute, Houston, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Timothy G. Pollock, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Evgenia Portniaguina, asst. prof., finance, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Yiming Qian, asst. prof., finance, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mari Rege, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Joel D. Rubin, clinical assoc. prof., business law, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Louis St. Peter, visiting lecturer, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Saras Sarasvathy, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Saonee Sarkar, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Skip Schutz, instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>William Schwartz, asst. prof., accounting, Univ. Arizona, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Rajeev Sharma, asst. prof., management information systems, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Galit Shmueli, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Loree Silloway, instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>K. (Shiva) Sivaramakrishnan, prof., accounting and taxation, and Bauer Chair; Houston, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Jerel Slaughter, asst. prof., management and policy, Univ. Arizona, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Melvin Smith, instructor, Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Joydeep Srivastava, asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Claire Stammerjohan, asst. prof., Washington State, Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>William W. Stammerjohan, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Greg L. Stewart, assoc. prof., management and organization, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Neal M. Stoughton, visiting prof., UCLA, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Vanitha Swaminathan, asst. prof., business administration, Pittsburgh, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mohan Tanniru, prof., and head, management information systems, Univ. Arizona, Dec. 2002.</p>
         <p>Marcia H. Taylor, visiting lecturer, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Barrett W. Thomas, asst. prof., management sciences, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Rajkumar Venkatesan, asst. prof., Connecticut, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Gilbert F. Viets, clinical assoc. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark Votruba, instructor, Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Walter Wallace, instructor, Georgia State, Spring 2002.</p>
         <p>Joel Watson, asst. prof., Washington State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Charles H. Whiteman, C. Woody Thompson Professor, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Angela F. Wofford, visiting instructor, Georgia State, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Yao Zhao, asst. prof., Rutgers, Sept. 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Grants</title>
         <p>David S. Bates, assoc. prof., finance, Iowa; Aug. 2002; John Hawkinson Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Warren J. Boe, prof., management sciences, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Charles A. Taff Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Terry L. Boles, assoc. prof., management and organization, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Henry B. Tippie Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Kenneth G. Brown, asst. prof., management and organization, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Huneke Faculty Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Renato E. deMatta, assoc. prof., management sciences, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Martin and Barbara Johnson Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Puneet Handa, assoc. prof., finance, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Martha and Dennis Hesse Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Edwin M. Hartman, prof., Rutgers; Jan. 2002; $600,000; Prudential Financial; to support the Prudential Business Ethics Center at Rutgers.</p>
         <p>Raj Jagannathan, prof., management science, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Huneke Faculty Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Irwin P. Levin, prof., marketing, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Ray William Shearman Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Harry J. Paarsh, prof., economics, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Robert Jensen Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Thomas A. Rietz, assoc. prof., finance, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Hershberger Faculty Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Raymond G. Riezman, prof., economics, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Lloyd J. and Thelma W. Palmer Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>John L. Solow, assoc. prof., economics, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Pioneer Hi‐Bred Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>Greg Stewart, assoc. prof., management and organizations, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Henry B. Tippie Research Fellow.</p>
         <p>W. Nick Street, assoc. prof., management sciences, Iowa; Aug. 2002; Henry B. Tippie Research Fellow.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Leaves</title>
         <p>Chris Earley, prof., organizational behavior, Indiana; Oct. 2002–Dec. 2002, leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Donald Erlenkotter, prof., UCLA; Oct. 2002–Dec. 2002; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Jeff Green, prof., business economics and public policy, Indiana; Spring 2002 and Spring 2003; administrative leave; Spring 2004; banked hours.</p>
         <p>Patrick Hopkins, assoc. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana; 2002–3; leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Jing Liu, asst. prof., UCLA; Jan. 2003–Mar. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Linda Pastor, lecturer, business communications, Indiana; 2002–3; leave without pay.</p>
         <p>Jim Patterson, prof., operations and systems management, Indiana; Spring 2003; to be Maastricht resident faculty advisor.</p>
         <p>Sandeep Purao, assoc. prof., Georgia State; 2002–3; in residence at the School of Information Systems, Pennsylvania State University.</p>
         <p>Lynn M. Shore, prof., Georgia State; 2002–3; visiting at the University of California, Irvine.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Promotions</title>
         <p>Ritu Agarwal, prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Brian Arthaud‐Day, lecturer, accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Bart J. Bronnenberg, assoc. prof., UCLA, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Paul R. Brown, prof., accounting, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jennifer N. Carpenter, assoc. prof., finance, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Laku Chidambaram, W. P. Wood Professor of Management Information Systems, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>David L. Cooperrider, prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Terry L. Crain, Dale Looper Chair in Accounting, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Kurt T. Dirks, assoc. prof., organizational behavior, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Deborah Dougherty, prof., Rutgers, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Vanessa Druskat, assoc. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Amy Dunbar, assoc. prof., Connecticut, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Gary W. Emery, Michael F. Price Professor of Finance, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Rodney S. Evans, Ruby K. Powell Professor of Marketing, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert S. Goldstein, assoc. prof., finance, Washington Univ., July 2002.</p>
         <p>Susan Helper, prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>David Hummels, assoc. prof., Purdue, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ananth Iyer, prof., Purdue, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Shane A. Johnson, prof., Louisiana State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>G. Logan Jordan, assoc. dean, administration, Purdue, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Steven Karau, assoc. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Vijay Khatri, asst. prof., accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Carol A. Knapp, Visiting Glen McLaughlin Chair in Business Ethics, Univ. Oklahoma, Fall 2002.</p>
         <p>Dong Gil Ko, asst. prof., information systems, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Greg Magnan, assoc. prof., Seattle, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Prakash Mirchandani, prof., business administration, Pittsburgh, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Donald V. Moser, prof., business administration, Pittsburgh, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Carl Obermiller, prof., Seattle, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Marcus Odom, assoc. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Dar Palmon, prof., Rutgers, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Sam Park, prof., Rutgers, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Morton P. K. Pincus, prof., accounting, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Nagpurnanand Prabhala, assoc. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Luiqa Raschid, prof. Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Patricia D. Setser, lecturer, accounting and information systems, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Baba Shiv, assoc. prof., marketing, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>V. Carlos Slawson, Jr., assoc. prof., Louisiana State, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Daniel C. Smith, chair, marketing, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>W. Nick Street, assoc. prof., management sciences, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Jon A. Turner, prof., information systems, NYU, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Haluk Unal, prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>R. Venkatesh, assoc. prof. (tenured), Pittsburgh, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Viswanath Venkatesh, assoc. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Russell Wermers, assoc. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Batia Mishan Wiesenfeld, assoc. prof., management, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Zhijie Xiao, assoc. prof., Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign, Aug. 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Resignations</title>
         <p>Stephen Baginski, chair, doctoral programs, Indiana, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Bernie Brown, visiting lecturer, Georgia State, Spring 2002.</p>
         <p>Roger Griffeth, prof., Georgia State, Summer 2002.</p>
         <p>Bud Hamilton, asst. prof., Georgia State, May 2002.</p>
         <p>Mark T. Kirby, visiting instructor, Georgia State, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Michael Newman, visiting prof., Georgia State, Spring 2002.</p>
         <p>Kathy S. Schwaig, asst. prof., Georgia State, Summer 2002.</p>
         <p>Michael Way, senior lecturer, operations and decisions technology, Indiana, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Shaker Zahra, prof., Georgia State, Summer 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Retirements</title>
         <p>Jack Bailes, prof., Oregon State, July 2002.</p>
         <p>David A. Bowers, prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2002.</p>
         <p>James F. Cox III, prof., Univ. Georgia, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kenneth O. Kortanek, prof., management sciences, Iowa, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>W. Giles Mellon, prof., Rutgers, June 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Deaths</title>
         <p>Chalmers A. Monteith, professor emeritus, Kent State; March 25, 2002; Myrtle Beach, South Carolina.</p>
         <p>Howard R. (Ted) Smith, professor emeritus, Univ. Georgia; July 30, 2002; Athens, Georgia.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc8">
         <title>Correction</title>
         <p>Yehuda Bassok is an associate professor at the University of Southern California. He has not resigned.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
