<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169293</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Target Population for Intersection Advanced Driver Assistance Systems in the U.S.</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kusano</surname>
                  <given-names>Kristofer D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gabler</surname>
                  <given-names>Hampton C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Virginia Tech</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169292</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>16</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169293"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Intersection crashes are a frequent and dangerous crash mode in the U.S. Emerging Intersection Advanced Driver Assistance Systems (I-ADAS) aim to assist the driver to mitigate the consequences of vehicle-to-vehicle crashes at intersections. In support of the design and evaluation of such intersection assistance systems, characterization of the road, environment, and drivers associated with intersection crashes is necessary. The objective of this study was to characterize intersection crashes using nationally representative crash databases that contained all severity, serious injury, and fatal crashes. This study utilized four national crash databases: the National Automotive Sampling System, General Estimates System (NASS/GES); the NASS Crashworthiness Data System (CDS); and the Fatality Analysis Reporting System (EARS) and the National Motor Vehicle Crash Causation Survey (NMVCCS).</p>
            <p>Straight Crossing Path (SCP), Left Turn Across Path Opposite Direction (LTAP/OD), and Left Turn Across Path Lateral Direction (LTAP/LD) made up 78% to 98% of all crossing path crashes. Furthermore, between 73% and 95% of these top three crossing path scenarios occurred at intersections. The analysis in this paper, therefore, focused on SCP, LTAP/OD, and LTAP/LD crashes at intersections, referred to as simply intersection crashes for the remainder of this summary.</p>
            <p>This paper quantified traffic control devices, speed limits, environmental conditions, alcohol involvement, and driver age in intersection crashes. Using the additional driver and crash contributing data included in the NMVCCS data, this paper also quantified critical reason for crashes, maneuvers approaching the intersection and avoidance maneuvers in intersection crashes. The results of this study are crucial for the design and evaluation of I-ADAS.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kusano, K. D., and Gabler H. C.. 2014. “Comprehensive Target Populations for Current Active Safety Systems Using National Crash Databases.” Traffic Injury Prevention 15 (7): 753-61. doi:10.1080/15389 588.2013.871003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gennareli, T. A., and Wodzin E.. 2005. AIS 2005. Barrington. IL: Association for the Advancement of Automotive Medicine.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Compton, C. P. 2005. “Injury Severity Codes: A Comparison of Police Injury Codes and Medical Outcomes as Determined by NASS CDS Investigators.” J Safety Res 35 (5): 483-84.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najm. W G, Smith J D, and Smith D L. 2001. Analysis of Crossing Path Crashes. National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Report DOT HS 809423. Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragland, D R and Zabyshny A A. 2003. Intersection Decision Support Project: Taxonomy of Crossing-Path Crashes at Intersections Using GES 2000 Data. Safe Transportation Research &amp; Education Center. Berkeley, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Preston H., Storm R, Donath M, and Shankwitz C. 2004. Review of Minnesota's Rural Intersection Crashes: Methodology for Identifying Intersections for Intersection Decision Support (IDS). Minnesota Department of Transportation, Report Number MN/RC-2004-31, St. Paul, MN.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eigen, A. M. and Najm W. G.. 2009. Problem Definition for Pre- Crash Sensing Advanced Restraints. National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Report DOT HS 811 114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langford, J., and Koppel S.. 2006. “Epidemiology of Older Driver Crashes - Identifying Older Driver Risk Factors and Exposure Patterns.” Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour 9(5): 309-21. doi:10.1016/i.trf.2006.03.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Preusser, D. F., Williams A. F., Ferguson S. A., Ulmer R. G., and Weinstein H. B.. 1998. “Fatal Crash Risk for Older Drivers at Intersections.” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 30 (2): 151-59. doi:10.1016/S0001-4575(97)00090-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
