<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169091</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Novel ZSB-PAM Power Regulation Method Applied in Wireless Charging System for Vehicular Power Batteries</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhenshi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wei</surname>
                  <given-names>Xuezhe</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dai</surname>
                  <given-names>Haifeng</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Tongji University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>July 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169081</issue-id>
         <fpage>326</fpage>
         <lpage>335</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169091"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Wireless charging system for vehicular power batteries is becoming more and more popular. As one of important issues, charging power regulation is indispensable for online control, especially when the distance or angle between chassis and ground changes. This paper proposes a novel power regulation method named Z-Source-Based Pulse-Amplitude-Modulation (ZSB-PAM), which has not been mentioned in the literatures yet. The ZSB-PAM employs a unique impedance network (two pairs of inductors and capacitors connected in X shape) to couple the cascaded H Bridge to the power source. By controlling the shoot-through state of H bridge, the input voltage to H bridge can be boosted, thus the transmitter current can be adjusted, and hence, charging current and power for batteries. A LCL-LCL resonant topology is adopted as the main transfer energy carrier, for it can work with a unity power factor and have the current source characteristic which is suitable for battery charging. And finite element models (FEMs) of transmitter and receiver coils in the LCL-LCL topology are built in COMSOL. From those, corresponding parameters, like self-inductance, mutual inductance and parasitic resistances caused by skin and proximity effect, can be extracted. Additionally, apart from power regulation, employing ZSB-PAM can realize the optimal efficiency in either LCL-LCL topology or the whole charging system. At last, the conclusions are verified by simulations and experiments.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kurs A., Karalis A., Moffatt R., Joannopoulos J. D., Fisher P., and Soljacic M., “Wireless power transfer via strongly coupled magnetic resonances,” Science, vol. 317, pp. 83-86, Jul 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Covic G. A. and Boys J. T., “Modern Trends in Inductive Power Transfer for Transportation Applications,” Emerging and Selected Topics in Power Electronics, IEEE Journal of, vol. 1, pp.28-41, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keeling N. A., Covic G. A., and Boys J. T., “A Unity-Power-Factor IPT Pickup for High-Power Applications,” Industrial Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 57, pp. 744-751, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zaheer A., Covic G. A., and Kacprzak D., “A Bipolar Pad in a 10-kHz 300-W Distributed IPT System for AGV Applications,” Industrial Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 61, pp. 3288-3301, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang C. Y., Boys J. T., and Covic G. A., “LCL Pickup Circulating Current Controller for Inductive Power Transfer Systems,” Power Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 28, pp.2081-2093, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chwei-Sen W., Covic G. A., and Stielau O. H., “Power transfer capability and bifurcation phenomena of loosely coupled inductive power transfer systems,” Industrial Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 51, pp. 148-157, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turki, F., Körner, A., Tlatlik, J., and Brown, A., “Compact, Safe and Efficient Wireless and Inductive Charging for Plug-In Hybrids and Electric Vehicles,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 3(1):139-151, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1892.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scudiere, M. and McKeever, J., “Wireless Power Transfer for Electric Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0354, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huh, J. and Rim, C., “KAIST Wireless Electric Vehicles - OLEV,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-39-7263, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlson R. W. and Normann B., “Test Results of the PLUGLESS™ Inductive Charging System from Evatran Group, Inc,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power., vol. 3, pp. 64-71, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi W. P., Ho W. C., Liu X., and Hui S. Y. R., “Comparative study on power conversion methods for wireless battery charging platform,” in Power Electronics and Motion Control Conference(EPE/PEMC), 2010 14th International, 2010, pp. S15-9-S15-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Madawala U. K. and Thrimawithana D. J., “New technique for inductive power transfer using a single controller,” Power Electronics, IET, vol. 5, pp. 248-256, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fang Zheng P., “Z-source inverter,” Industry Applications, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 39, pp. 504-510, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qin L., Dong C., and Fang Zheng P., “Novel Loss and Harmonic Minimized Vector Modulation for a Current-Fed Quasi-Z-Source Inverter in HEV Motor Drive Application,” Power Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 29, pp. 1344-1357, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bin G., Jih-Sheng L., Kees N., and Cong Z., “Hybrid-Switching Full-Bridge DC/DC Converter With Minimal Voltage Stress of Bridge Rectifier, Reduced Circulating Losses, and Filter Requirement for Electric Vehicle Battery Chargers,” Power Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 28, pp. 1132-1144, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cannon B. L., Hoburg J. F., Stancil D. D., and Goldstein S. C., “Magnetic Resonant Coupling As a Potential Means for Wireless Power Transfer to Multiple Small Receivers,” Power Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 24, pp. 1819-1825, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raju S., Rongxiang W., Mansun C., and Yue C. P., “Modeling of Mutual Coupling Between Planar Inductors in Wireless Power Applications,” Power Electronics, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 29, pp. 481-490, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xi N. and Sullivan C. R., “An Equivalent Complex Permeability Model for Litz-Wire Windings,” Industry Applications, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 45, pp. 854-860, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei X. Z., Wang Z. S., and Dai H. F., “A Critical Review of Wireless Power Transfer via Strongly Coupled Magnetic Resonances,” Energies, vol. 7, pp. 4316-4341, Jul 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
