<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007470</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">jinsuissu</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Insurance Issues</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15316076</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23324244</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Western Risk and Insurance Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26931209</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Enterprise Risk Management Adoption and Managerial Incentives</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Altuntas</surname>
                  <given-names>Muhammed</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Berry-Stölzle</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hoyt</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2020</year>
            <string-date>FALL 2020</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">43</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26931206</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>42</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2020 by the Western Risk and Insurance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26931209"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Enterprise Risk Management (ERM) is the approach of managing all risks faced by a firm in an integrated, holistic fashion. This research analyzes factors that influence a firm’s decision to start an ERM program. Our comprehensive survey data of German property-liability insurance companies allows us to construct direct measures of ERM program adoption and ERM quality. We find that negative changes in past firm performance increase a firm’s probability to adopt ERM and are accompanied by significant improvements in the quality of a firm’s risk management process. Furthermore, these effects are stronger for firms that would be expected to have relatively high forced CEO turnover rates after periods of bad performance, supporting the prediction of the career concerns view and consistent with managerial incentives generally. Skilled managers concerned about keeping their jobs should reduce the volatility of a firm’s earnings after a period of poor performance, and ERM adoption can help achieve that goal.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Aabo, T., J. R. S. Fraser, and B. J. Simkins (2005) “The Risk and Evolution of the Chief Risk Officer: Enterprise Risk Management at Hydro One,” Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 17: 62–75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Ai, J., V. Bajtelsmit, and T. Wang (2018) “The Combined Effect of Enterprise Risk Management and Diversification on Property and Casualty Insurers Performance,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 85(2): 513–543.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Altuntas, M., T. R. Berry-Stölzle, and J. D. Cummins (2019) “Enterprise Risk Management and Economies of Scale and Scope: Evidence from the German Insurance Industry,” Annals of Operations Research, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Altuntas, M., T. R. Berry-Stölzle, and R. E. Hoyt (2011) “Implementation of Enterprise Risk Management: Evidence from the German Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” The Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance—Issues and Practice 36: 414–439.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Altuntas, M., A. P. Liebenberg, E. D. Watson, and S. Yildiz (2017) “Hedging, Cash Flows, and Firm Value: Evidence of an Indirect Effect,” Journal of Insurance Issues 40(1): 1–22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Beasley, M. S., R. Clune, and D. R. Hermanson (2005) “Enterprise Risk Management: An Empirical Analysis of Factors Associated with the Extent of Implementation,”Journal of Accounting and Public Policy 24: 521–531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Berry-Stölzle, T. R., G. C. Lai, and S. Wende (2010) “The Effect of Regulation on Comparative Advantages of Different Organizational Forms: Evidence from the German Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Berry-Stölzle, T. R. and J. Xu (2018) “Enterprise Risk Management and the Cost of Capital,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 85(1): 159–201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bittlingmayer, G. (1998) “Output, Stock Volatility, and Political Uncertainty in a Natural Experiment: Germany, 1880–1940,” Journal of Finance 53(6): 2243–2257.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Breeden, D. T. and S. Viswanathan (2016) “Why Do Firms Hedge? An Asymmetric Information Model,” The Journal of Fixed Income 25(3): 1–19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Brown, S. J., W. N. Goetzmann, and J. Park (2001) “Careers and Survival: Competition and Risk in the Hedge Fund and CTA Industry,” Journal of Finance 56: 1869–1886.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Chen, R. and K. A. Wong (2004) “The Determinants of Financial Health of Asian Insurance Companies,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 71: 469–499.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Cheng, J., E. Elyasiani, and J. Jia (2011) “Institutional Ownership Stability and Risk Taking: Evidence from the Life-Health Insurance Industry,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 78(3): 609–641.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Chung, J.-W., B. A. Sensoy, L. Stern, and M. S. Weisbach (2012) “Pay for Performance from Future Fund Flows: The Case of Private Equity,” Review of Financial Studies 25(11): 3259–3304.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Cole, C. R. and K. A. McCullough (2006) “A Reexamination of the Corporate Demand for Reinsurance,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 73: 169–192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Colquitt, L. L., R. E. Hoyt, and R. B. Lee (1999) “Integrated Risk Management and the Role of the Risk Manager,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 2: 43–61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">COSO (Committee of Sponsoring Organizations of the Treadway Commission) (2004) Enterprise Risk Management—Integrated Framework.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Cummins, J. D., M. A. Weiss, and H. Zi (1999) “Organizational Form and Efficiency: The Coexistence of Stock and Mutual Property-Liability Insurers,” Management Science 45(9): 1254–1269.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Dahya J., J. J. McConnell, and N. G. Travlos (2002) “The Cadbury Committee, Corporate Performance and Top Management Turnover,” Journal of Finance 57: 461–483.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">DeMarzo, P. and D. Duffie (1995) “Corporate Incentives for Hedging and Hedge Accounting,” Review of Financial Studies 8: 743–771.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Denis, D. J., D. K. Denis, and A. Sarin (1997) “Agency Problems, Equity Ownership, and Corporate Diversification,” Journal of Finance 52: 135–160.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Eckles, D. L., R. E. Hoyt, and S. M. Miller (2014) “The Impact of Enterprise Risk Management on the Marginal Cost of Reducing Risk: Evidence from the Insurance Industry,” Journal of Banking &amp; Finance 49: 409–423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Fama, E. F. (1980) “Agency Problems and the Theory of the Firm,” Journal of Political Economy 88: 288–307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Fama, E. F. and M. C. Jensen (1983) “Separation of Ownership and Control,” Journal of Law and Economics 26(2): 301–325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Farrell, K. and D. Whidbee (2002) “Monitoring by the Financial Press and Forced CEO Turnover,” Journal of Banking and Finance 26: 2249–2276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Farrell, M. and R. Gallagher (2015) “The Valuation Implications of Enterprise Risk Management Maturity,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 82: 625–657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Gibbons, R. and K. J. Murphy (1992) “Optimal Incentive Contracts in the Presence of Career Concerns: Theory and Evidence,” Journal of Political Economy 100: 468– 505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Grace, M. F., J. T. Leverty, R. D. Phillips, and P. Shimpi (2015) “The Value of Investing in Enterprise Risk Management,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 82(2): 289–316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Harrington, S. E., G. Niehaus, and K. J. Risko (2002) “Enterprise Risk Management: The Case of United Grain Growers,” Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 14: 71– 81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">He, E. and D. W. Sommer (2010) “Separation of Ownership and Control: Implications for Board Composition,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 77: 265–295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">He, E. and D. W. Sommer (2011) “CEO Turnover and Ownership Structure: Evidence from the U.S. Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 78: 673–701.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Holmström, B. (1982) “Managerial Incentive Schemes—A Dynamic Perspective,” in Essays in Economics and Management in Honour of Lars Wahlbeck, Helsinki.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Hoyt, R. E. and A. P. Liebenberg (2011) “The Value of Enterprise Risk Management,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 78: 795–822.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Huson, M. R., R. Parrino, and L. T. Starks (2001) “Internal Monitoring Mechanisms and CEO Turnover: A Long-Term Perspective,” Journal of Finance 56: 2265–2297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Kim, J. M. (2016) “Failure Risk and the Cross-Section of Hedge Fund Returns,” Financial Management 45(4): 845–876.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Kleffner, A. E., R. B. Lee, and B. McGannon (2003) “The Effect of Corporate Governance on the Use of Enterprise Risk Management: Evidence from Canada,”Risk Management and Insurance Review 6: 53–73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Knüpfer, S., E. Rantapuska, and M. Sarvimäki (2017) “Formative Experiences and Portfolio Choice: Evidence from the Finnish Great Depression,” Journal of Finance 72(1): 133–166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Lamm-Tennant, J. and L. T. Starks (1993) “Stock Versus Mutual Ownership Structures: The Risk Implications,” Journal of Business 66: 29–46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Lee, S.-J., D. Mayers, and C. W. Smith (1997) “Guaranty Funds and Risk-Taking: Evidence from the Insurance Industry,” Journal of Financial Economics 44: 3–24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Liebenberg, A. P. and R. E. Hoyt (2003) “The Determinants of Enterprise Risk Management: Evidence from the Appointment of Chief Risk Officers,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 6: 37–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Ma, Y. L. and P. Wang (2014) “Executive Compensation and Risk Taking in the Property and Liability Insurance Industry,” Journal of Insurance Issues 37(2): 187– 212.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Mayers, D. and C. W. Smith (1981) “Contractual Provisions, Organizational Structure, and Conflict Control in Insurance Markets,” Journal of Business 54: 407–434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">McShane, M. K., T. Zhang, and L. A. Cox (2012) “Risk Allocation across the Enterprise: Evidence from the Insurance Industry,” Journal of Insurance Issues 35(1): 73–99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Meulbroek, L. (2002) “A Senior Manager’s Guide to Integrated Risk Management,” Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 14: 56–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Miccolis, J. and S. Shah (2000) Enterprise Risk Management: An Analytic Approach, Tillinghast–Towers Perrin Monograph.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Nair, A., E. Rustambekov, M. McShane, and S. Fainshmidt (2014) “Enterprise Risk Management as a Dynamic Capability: A Test of Its Effectiveness During a Crisis,” Managerial and Decision Economics 35(8): 555–566.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Nam, J., J. Wang, and G. Zhang (2008) “Managerial Career Concerns and Risk Management,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 75: 785–809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Nance, D., C. W. Smith, and C. Smithson (1993) “On the Determinants of Corporate Hedging,” Journal of Finance 48: 267–284.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Nocco, B. and R. Stulz (2006) “Enterprise Risk Management: Theory and Practice,” Journal of Applied Corporate Finance 18: 8–20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Pagach, D. and R. Warr (2011) “The Characteristics of Firms That Hire Chief Risk Officers,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 78: 185–211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Pagano, M., F. Panetta, and L. Zingales (1998) “Why Do Companies Go Public? An Empirical Analysis,” Journal of Finance 53: 27–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Palepu, K. (1985) “Diversification Strategy, Profit Performance, and the Entropy Measure,” Strategic Management Journal 6: 239–255.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Pottier, S. W. and D. W. Sommer (2002) “The Effectiveness of Public and Private Sector Summary Risk Measures in Predicting Insurer Insolvencies,” Journal of Financial Services Research 21: 101–116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Scordis, N. A. (2018) “Influence of Board-Level Risk Committee on Value,” Journal of Insurance Issues 41(1): 111–134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Shumway, T. (2001) “Forecasting Bankruptcy More Accurately: A Simple Hazard Model,” Journal of Business 74: 101–124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Standard &amp; Poor’s (2005) Insurance Criteria: Evaluating the Enterprise Risk Management Practices of Insurance Companies, October 17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Tukey, J. W. (1977) Exploratory Data Analysis, Addison-Wesley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Cumulative number of survey respondents engaged in ERM by year.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Variable Definitions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics and Univariate Comparison</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Determinants of ERM Adoption</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>The Moderating Effects of Group Affiliation and Organizational Form</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>New CEOs and ERM Adoption</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Distribution of the Average Risk Management Quality and the Holistic Risk Management Index by year.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Changes in Risk Management Quality Relative to Firms’ Adoption of ERM, Pooled Across Nine Adoption Years</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Determinants of Changes in Firms’ Risk Management Quality</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8.</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>The Moderating Effects of Group Affiliation and Organizational Form</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9.</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>New CEOs and Changes in Firms’ Risk Management Quality</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
