<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277506</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Diesel Exhaust Aftertreatment with Scrubber Process</article-title>
            <subtitle>NOₓ Destruction</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
                  <given-names>Derek</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>West Virginia University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ayre</surname>
                  <given-names>Louise</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>West Virginia University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Clark</surname>
                  <given-names>Nigel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>West Virginia University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Balon</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>MJ Bradley &amp; Associates</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moynihan</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>MJ Bradley &amp; Associates</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>782</fpage>
         <lpage>789</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277506"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Oxides of nitrogen (NOₓ) emissions, produced by engines that burn fuels with atmospheric air, are known to cause negative health and environmental effects. Increasingly stringent emissions regulations for marine engines have caused newer engines to be developed with inherent NOₓ reduction technologies. Older marine engines typically have a useful life of over 20 years and produce a disproportionate amount of NOₓ emissions when compared with their newer counterparts. Wet scrubbing as an aftertreatment method for emissions reduction was applied to ocean-going marine vessels for the reduction of sulfur oxides (SOₓ) and particulate matter (PM) emissions. The gaseous absorption process was explored in the laboratory as an option for reducing NOₓ emissions from older diesel engines of harbor craft operating in ports of Houston and Galveston. A scrubber system was designed, constructed, and evaluated to provide the basis for a real-world design. The details of this research have been presented in previously reported work. The main byproduct of the scrubber process was a weak nitric acid solution (&lt;10 wt%). This paper presents an exploration of a method developed to destroy the NOₓ emissions captured and stored during the scrubbing process. This method utilized a stainless steel acid boiler vessel and catalyst for the NOₓ destruction process. The acid boiler vessel allowed for the injection of weak nitric acid (&lt;10 wt%) and diesel fuel into a chamber for evaporation. The thermal decomposition of the nitric acid produced a nitrogen dioxide rich stream that then reacted with metered diesel fuel over two automotive-style, platinum based, three way catalysts (TWCs). In the laboratory, heat energy for acid evaporation and reduction was provided by electric resistance heaters. Real world applications would use waste heat from the engine and scrubber process for acid evaporation and reduction. The system was evaluated with a fixed acid injection rate and various fuel flow rates to validate the thermal decomposition of nitric acid and overall NOₓ reductions. Exit stack emissions were measured on a ‘semi-raw’ and dilute basis. Acid to fuel ratios of 49.8:1 and 58.9:1 yielded NOₓ reductions of 99.7% and 98%, respectively. The fuel utilized for the destruction process added a 1% fuel penalty to the complete scrubber system. The scrubber component of the whole system was capable of reducing NOₓ emissions by 42% and 62% over a high flow and low flow cycle, respectively. The scrubber section of the overall system was therefore the primary limitation to the level of NOₓ reduction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pulkrabek, W.W.; “Engineering Fundamentals of the Internal Combustion Engine (Second Edition),” Pearson Prentice Hall, Upper Saddle River, NJ, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skalska, K., Miller, J., and Ledakowicz, S.; “Trends in NOx Abatement: A Review,” Science of the Total Environment, 2010, vol. 408, pp. 3976-3989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA; “Nitrogen Oxides, How and Why They Are Controlled?,” US EPA &lt;http://www.epa.gov/ttn/catc/dir1/fnoxdoc.pdf&gt;. Accessed February 3, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA, Air Emissions Sources, “Nitrogen Oxides,” US EPA, &lt;http://www.epa.gov/air/emissions/nox.htm#noxnat&gt;, Accessed August 8, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parker, L., Nopmongcol, U., Lindhjem, C., Wells, S., Jimenez, M., and Yarwood, G.; “Implement Port of Houston's Current Inventory and Harmonize the Remaining 8-county Shipping Inventory for TCEQ Modeling: Final Report,” ENVIRON International Corporation, 2010, &lt;http://www.tceq.texas.gov/assets/public/implementation/air/am/contracts/reports/ei/5820784006FY1005-20100818-environ- HGBShipsEI.pdf&gt;, Accessed August 8, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Revelt, J,; “Commercial Marine Emission Inventory,” Conference on Marine Vessels and Air Quality, EPA, San Francisco, CA. 1 Feb 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Charmley, W., “The Federal Government's Role in Reducing Heavy Duty Diesel Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2708, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakatsuji, T., Rouistenmäki, J., Nishiaki, N., Fukushima, G. et al., “A NOx Reduction System Using Highly Active Double- Layered NOx Trap Catalysts with Various Regeneration Properties,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1158, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tissera, C., Swartz, M., Tatli, E., Vellaisamy, R. et al., “NOX Decomposition in Natural Gas, Diesel and Gasoline Engines for Selective NOX Recirculation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2144, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2144.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nuszkowski, J., Clark, N., Spencer, T., Carder, D., Gautum, M., Balon, T., and Moynihan, P.; “Atmospheric Emissions from a Passenger Ferry with Selective Catalytic Reduction,” Journal of Air and Waste Management Association, 59: 18-30, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Viola, M., “HC-SCR Catalyst Performance in Reducing NOx Emissions from a Diesel Engine Running Transient Test Cycles,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2487, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2487.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayre, L., Johnson, D., Clark, N., England, J., Atkinson, R., McKain, D., Ralston, B., Balon, T. Jr., and Moynihan, P.; “Novel NOx Emission Reduction Technology for Diesel Marine Engines,” ASME 2011 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference ICEF2011 October 2-5, 2011, Morgantown, West Virginia, USA ICEF2011-60182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schifftner, K., and Hesketh, H.; “Wet Scrubbers (Second Edition),” Technomic Publishing Co., Inc., Pennsylvania, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joshi, J., Mahajani, V., and Juvekar, V.; “Invited Review, Absorption of NOx Gases,” Chemical Engineering Communications, 1985, Vol. 33, pp. 1-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">World Bank Group. “Pollution Prevention and Abatement Handbook.” International Finance Corporation, 1998, pp. 245. &lt;http://www1.ifc.org/wps/wcm/connect/60add78048855368aeecfe6a6515bb18/HandbookNitrogenOxidesPollutionPreventionAnd Control.pdf? MOD=AJPERES&amp;CACHEID=60add78048855368aeecfe6a6515bb18&gt;. Accessed February 24, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manelis, G., Nazin, G., Rubstov, I., and Strunin, V.; “Thermal Decomposition and Combustion of Explosives and Propellants.” Taylor &amp; Francis, New York, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urbanski, T.; “Chemistry and Technology of Explosives.” Permagon Press, New York, NY, 1964.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Model 951A NO/NOx Analyzer Instruction Manual.” Rosemount Analytical Inc. USA 2000. &lt;http://www2.emersonprocess.com/siteadmincenter/PM%20Rosemount%20Analytical%20Documents/PGA_Manual_951A_200007.pdf.&gt;, Accessed January 28, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
