<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">33</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40031014</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40704320</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Are America's Poorest Children Receiving Their Share of Federal Education Funds? School-Level Title I Funding in New York, Los Angeles, and Chicago</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Carolyn A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Brown</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>130</fpage>
         <lpage>146</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007 Board of Trustees of the University of Illinois</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40704320"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The No Child Left Behind (NCLB) Act is the largest incursion of the federal government into education in American history. More than $ 12 billion is attached to unprecedented requirements for all students, poor and nonpoor, to reach a level of academic proficiency. Title I and its NCLB reauthorization explicitly allot funds to individual schools for the needs of their poor students, but few studies have looked at school-level distributions of Title I funds. As schools, especially in urban areas, struggle to meet the standards set by NCLB, researchers need to examine how districts distribute these funds to schools and whether these funds are reaching the poorest children in an equitable manner. Are schools with the highest concentrations of poor children getting the most Title I assistance? This study examined school-level Title I funds distribution in the three largest U. S. districts—New York City Public Schools, Los Angeles Unified School District, and Chicago Public Schools—to determine the equitability of funding.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e150a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e154" publication-type="other">
Ascher, C. 1987. Chapter 1 Programs: New Guides from the Research. New York: ERIC Clearinghouse on Urban
Education, Institute of Urban and Minority Education, Teachers College, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e164a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e168" publication-type="other">
Berne, R., and L. Stiefel. 1984. The Measurement of Equity in School Finance: Conceptual Methodological,
and Empirical Dimensions. Baltimore, MD: Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e178a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e182" publication-type="other">
Carey, K. 2002. Overview of K-12 Education Finance. Washington, DC: Center on Budget and Policy
Priorities.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e192a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e196" publication-type="other">
Duncombe, W. 2002. Estimating the Cost of an Adequate Education in New York. Syracuse, NY: Center for
Policy Research Working Paper, Syracuse University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e207a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e211" publication-type="other">
Education Funding Research Council. 2003. Title I Handbook. Washington, DC: Author.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e218a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e222" publication-type="other">
General Accounting Office. 2002. Title I Funding: Poor Children Benefit Though Funding per Poor Child
Differs. GAO-02-242. Washington, DC: Author.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e232a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e236" publication-type="other">
Goettel, R. J. 1977. A Comparative Analysis ofESEA, Title I Administration in Eight States. Education Re-
source Information Center ED159283. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e250" publication-type="other">
Hennessy, M., G. Takata, and N. L. Ames. 1980. "Title I Selection Methods and the Coverage of Disad-
vantaged Students." Evaluation Review 4(1): 43-57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e260a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e264" publication-type="other">
Irwin, P. M. 1978. "An Analysis of "Title I Funds Allocation: The Current Formula." Education Resource
Information Center ED155281. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e278" publication-type="other">
Maryland Commission on Education Finance. 2002. Equity and Excellence Report. Annapolis: State of
Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e289a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e293" publication-type="other">
Milne, A. 1977. "Demonstration Studies of Funds Allocation Within Districts: A Report." ED145548.
Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e303a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e307" publication-type="other">
National Center for Education Statistics. 2002. School Enrollment Statistics. Retrieved April 16, 2002, from
http://www.nces.ed.gov.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e317a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e321" publication-type="other">
Odden, A. R., and L. O Picus. 1992. School Finance: A Policy Perspective. New York: McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e332" publication-type="other">
Puma, M. J. 1999. The "Prospects" Study of Educational Growth and Opportunity: Implications for Policy
and Practice. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e346" publication-type="other">
Reschovsky, A., and J. Imazeki. 1997. The Development of School Finance Formulas to Guarantee the Provision
of Adequate Education to Low-Income Students. Developments in School Finance Report. Washington,
DC: U.S. Department of Education, National Center for Education Statistics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e359a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e363" publication-type="other">
Stullich, S., B. Donly, and S. Stolzbert. 1999. Targeting Schools: Study of Title I Allocations Within School
Districts. ED432649. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e374a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e378" publication-type="other">
Taylor, W. L, and D. M. Piche. 1990. A Report on Shortchanging Children: The Impact of Fiscal Inequity
on the Education of Students at Risk. Washington, DC: Congress of the U.S., House Committee on
Education and Labor.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


