<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">17</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830353</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830359</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>TECHNOLOGICAL CHANGE, ENVIRONMENT AND POOR WOMEN, ESPECIALLY TRIBAL WOMEN, IN INDIA / CHANGEMENTS TECHNOLOGIQUES, ENVIRONNEMENT ET FEMMES DU NIVEAU SOCIO-ECONOMIQUE LE PLUS BAS EN INDE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Kartik C.</given-names>
                  <surname>Roy</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Clement A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Tisdell</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>423</fpage>
         <lpage>439</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830359"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In India, as in several other less developed countries, the poor and especially women within poor households are particularly dependent on common-property resources (CPRs) for their livelihood. The relative importance of common-property resources as a contributor to the overall income of the households of tribals and scheduled castes, the groups with the lowest socio-economic status in Indian society, is high and their womenfolk are especially reliant on such resources to enable them to contribute to the economic welfare of their households. However, due to economic growth and 'development', CPRs are being lost at a rapid rate in tribal and 'marginal' areas. This is strikingly so for forested and wooded areas which make a substantial contribution to the subsistence income of tribals. Partly these changes are a result of the environmental effects of new technologies such as Green Revolution technologies, but have also been accentuated by population growth putting greater pressures on CPRs, and the appropriation of many of these resources by lowlanders - (that is directly or indirectly in many cases to the benefit of the urban elite). This thesis is supported by the secondary data for India and by the results of fieldwork in the Belpahari tribal area in the Mindapur District of West Bengal. En Inde, comme dans plusieurs pays en voie de développement, les pauvres, et surtout les femmes dans les ménages pauvres, sont particulièrement dépendentes des ressources naturelles communes pour survivre. L'importance relative des ressources naturelles communes comme contribution au revenu global des ménages des tribus et des castes, qui forment les classes du rang social-économique le plus bas dans la société indienne, est grande. Ces femmes ont notamment besoin de telles ressources pour pouvoir contribuer à la prospérité économique. Cependant, à cause de la croissance économique et du développement, des ressources naturelles communes disparaissent rapidement dans les régions tribales et périphériques. C'est surtout le cas dans les régions boisées et les forêts qui contribuent considérablement au revenu minimal des tribus. Ces changements sont dûs en partie aux effets sur l'environnement des nouvelles technologies telles que les technologies de la 'Green Revolution', mais ils sont également renforcés par la croissance démographique qui exerce davantage des pressions sur les ressources naturelles communes, et par l'appropriation de ces ressources par les habitants — (c'est-à-dire directement ou indirectement dans beaucoup de cas en faveur de l'élite urbaine). Cette thèse est soutenue par des données secondaires sur l'Inde et par les résultats du travail sur le terrain dans la région de la tribu Belpahari dans le district Mindapur du West Bengal.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e119a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e123" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, B. (1989) "Rural Women, Poverty and Natural Resources", Economic and Political Weekly, 24(43).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e130a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e134" publication-type="other">
Agarwal, B. (1983) "Women, Poverty and Agricultural Growth in India", The Journal of Peasant Studies, 13(4).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e141a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e145" publication-type="other">
Bandopadhyay, J. and Moench, M. (1985) "Local Needs and Forest Resource Management" in Bandopadhyay,
J. (ed.) Himalayas in India's Environment: Crisis and Responses, Dehradun: Nataraj Publishers.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e155a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e159" publication-type="other">
Bhaduri, J. and Surin, V. (1980) "Community Forestry and Women Headloaders", Report of the Seminar on
Community Forestry and People's Participation, Ranchi: Consortium for Community Forestry, No. 20-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e170a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e174" publication-type="other">
Centre for Science and Environment [CSE] (1986) "Between Need and Greed: The Wasting of India, the Green-
ing of India", A Paper presented by CSE to the Union Council of Ministers, New Delhi, 12th May.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e188" publication-type="other">
Centre for Science and Environment (1985-86) The State of India's Environment: Citizens' Report, New Delhi.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e195a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e199" publication-type="other">
Chand, M. and Bezboruah, B. (1980) "Employment Opportunities for Women in Forestry", Report of the Seminar
on Community Forestry and Peoples' Participation, Ranchi: Consortium for the Community Forestry,
November 20-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e212a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e216" publication-type="other">
Chen, M. (1989) "Womens' Work in Indian Agriculture by Agro-Ecologic Zones; Meeting Basic Needs of Landless
and Land-poor Women", Economic and Political Weekly, 24(43).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e230" publication-type="other">
Choudhury, S. and Prakash, S. (1990) "Ecological Implications of Economic Development of Meghataya (India):
A Study of Levels and Patterns of Consumption and Production of Forest Based Economies", Journal
of Quantitative Economics, 6(1), pp. 162-180.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e243a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e247" publication-type="other">
Choudhury, S. and Prakash, S., ibid.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e255a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e259" publication-type="other">
CSE (1985) The State of India's Environment 1984-85: The Second Citizens' Report, New Delhi: CSE.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e266a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e270" publication-type="other">
D'Souza, V.S. (1990) Development Planning and Structural Inequalities: The Response of the Underprivileged,
New Delhi: Sage Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e280a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e284" publication-type="other">
Duwury, N. (1989) "Women in Agriculture: A Review of the Indian Agriculture", Economic and Political Weekly,
24(43).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e298" publication-type="other">
Fernandes, W. and Menon, G. (1987) "Tribal Women and Forest Economy: Deforestation, Exploitation and Status
Change", Delhi: Indian Statistical Institute.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e308a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e312" publication-type="other">
Government of India (1982) Report of the Committee on Forests and Tribals in India, New Delhi: Ministry of
Home Affairs.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e326" publication-type="other">
Hanger, J. and Moris, J. (1973) "Women and Household Economy in Mewa: An Irrigated Rice Settlement in
Kenya" in Chambers, R. and Moris, J. (eds) Africa Studies, No. 38, Stelle, Munchen.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e341" publication-type="other">
Ishikawa, S. (1978) Labour Absorption in Asian Agriculture: An Issues Paper, ILO, ARTEP, Bangkok.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e348a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e352" publication-type="other">
Jackson, M.G. (1985) "A Strategy for Improving the Productivity of Livestock in the Hills of Uttarpradesh" in
Singh, J.S. (ed.) Environmental Regeneration in Himalaya, Nainital: Gyanodaya Prakashan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e366" publication-type="other">
Jain, D. (1985) "The Household Traps: Report on a Field Survey of Female Activity Patterns" in Jain, D. and
Banerjee, N. (1985) (eds) Tyranny of the Household: Investigative Essays on Women's Work, New Delhi:
Shakti Books.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e379a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e383" publication-type="other">
Jain, D. and Malini, C. (1985) "Domestic Work — Its Implications for Enumeration of Workers" in Saradamoni,
K. (1985) (ed.) Womens' Work and Society, Calcutta: ISI.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e393a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e397" publication-type="other">
Jain, L.C. (1988) "Poverty, Environment and Development, A View from Gandhi's Window", Economic and
Political Weekly, 23(7).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e411" publication-type="other">
Jain, L.C, ibid.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e419a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e423" publication-type="other">
Jayasuriya, S. and Shand, RT. (1986) "Technical Change and Labour Absorption in Agriculture: Some Emerg-
ing Trends", World Development, Vol. 14, No. 3, pp. 415-428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e433a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e437" publication-type="other">
Jodha, N.S. (1986) "Common Property Resources and Rural Poor", Economic and Political Weekly, 21(27).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e444a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e448" publication-type="other">
Joshi, B.K. (1987) "Energy Use in Rural Areas in Uttarakhand", {Mimed), Delhi: Adikisory Board of Energy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e459" publication-type="other">
Kane, R. (1991) "Yet Another Review", Business India, October 28 - Nov. 10, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e466a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e470" publication-type="other">
Longmire, J. (1992) "The Impact on Wages and Employment of Technological Change in Wheat Production
in Pakistan, 1965-1990, Discussion Paper in Economics, Department of Economics, University of
Queensland, Australia, 4072 (forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e483a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e487" publication-type="other">
Moench, M. (1986) "Trust and Forest Management in a Garhwal Village", Working Paper, Honolulu: Environ-
ment and Policy Institute, East-West Center. }</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e502" publication-type="other">
Nagbrahman, D. and Sambrani, S. (1983) "Womens' Drudgery in Firewood Collection", Economic and Political
Weekly, January 1-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e516" publication-type="other">
Playfair, M. (1939) The Garos, Guwahati: United Publishers 1975 (Reprinted).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e523a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e527" publication-type="other">
Ramakrishnan, P.S. (1992) "Ecology, Environment and Sustainable Rural Development in India" in Roy, K.C,
Tisdell, C.A. and Sen, R.K. (eds) Economic Development and Environment: A Case Study of India, Calcutta:
Oxford University Press, pp. 42-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e540a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e544" publication-type="other">
Rao, C.H.H. (1991) "Rural Society and Agricultural Development in Course of Industrialization, Case of India",
Economic and Political Weekly, 24 (11, 12).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e558" publication-type="other">
Roy, K.C, Tisdell, C.A. and Alauddin, M. (1992) "Rural-Urban Migration and Poverty in South Asia", Journal
of Contemporary Asia, 22(1).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e568a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e572" publication-type="other">
Ryan, GJ. (1984) "The Determinants of Individual Diets and Nutritional Status in Six Villages in Southern In-
dia", Research Bulletin No. 7, Hyderabad: ICRISAT.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e587" publication-type="other">
Sen, G. (1987) "Women Agricultural Labourers — Regional Variations in Incidence and Employment", Paper
presented at the National Workshop on Women in Agriculture, New Delhi, September 23-24.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e601" publication-type="other">
Tisdell, C.A. (1988) "Technology: A Factor in Development and Socio-Economic and Environmental Change"
in Tisdell, C and Maitra, P. (eds) Technological Change, Development and the Environment: Socio-
Economic Perspectives, London: Routledge, pp. 1-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e618" publication-type="other">
Tisdell, C.A. and Alauddin, M. (1992) "The Ishikawa Curve and Agricultural Productivity in Bangladesh: Some
New Findings", Hitotsubashi Journal of Economics, Vol. 33, in press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


