<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277903</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Speciation of Nitrogen Compounds in the Tailpipe Emissions from a SI Car under Real World Driving Conditions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Khalfan</surname>
                  <given-names>Ahmad</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Hu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andrews</surname>
                  <given-names>Gordon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Leeds</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>October 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277873</issue-id>
         <fpage>1961</fpage>
         <lpage>1983</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277903"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The tailpipe exhaust emissions were measured using a EURO4 emissions compliant SI car equipped with on-board measurement systems such as a FTIR system for gaseous emission, a differential GPS for velocity, altitude and position, thermal couples for temperatures, and a MAX fuel meter for transient fuel consumption. Various nitrogen species emissions (NO, NO₂, NOx, NH₃, HCN and N₂O) were measured at 0.5 Hz. The tests were designed and employed using two real world driving cycles/routes representing a typical urban road network located in a densely populated area and main crowded road. Journeys at various times of the day were conducted to investigate traffic conditions impacts such as traffic and pedestrian lights, road congestion, grade and turning on emissions, engine thermal efficiency and fuel consumption. The time aligned vehicle moving parameters with Nitrogen pollutant emission data and fuel consumption enabled the micro-analysis of correlations between these parameters. The average data for journeys such as emissions, thermal efficiency and fuel consumption were presented, though this paper is focused on nitrogen compounds. Traffic events and vehicle transient movements’ impact on emissions were studied. Engine power output has been calculated by using vehicle specific power (VSP). The analysis result of tailpipe emissions and their relation to real world driving profile improved understanding of urban area nitrogen compound emissions, which will be useful for controlling of urban air quality.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hawirko, J. and Checkel, M., “Quantifying Vehicle Emission Factors for Various Ambient Conditions using an On-Road, Real- Time Emissions System,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0301, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Andrews, G., Savvidis, D., Daham, B. et al., “Impact of Driving Cycles on Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Fuel Economy for SI Car Real World Driving,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):1320- 1333, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Andrews, G., Savvidis, D., Daham, B. et al., “Characterization of Regulated and Unregulated Cold Start Emissions for Different Real World Urban Driving Cycles Using a SI Passenger Car,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1648, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Andrews, G., Khan, A., Savvidis, D. et al., “Analysis of Driving Parameters and Emissions for Real World Urban Driving Cycles using an on-board Measurement Method for a EURO 2 SI car,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-2066, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-2066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Andrews, G., Daham, B., Bell, M. et al., “Impact of Traffic Conditions and Road Geometry on Real World Urban Emissions Using a SI Car,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0308, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Andrews, G., Daham, B., Bell, M. et al., “Study of the Emissions Generated at Intersections for a SI Car under Real World Urban Driving Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01- 1080, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tziraks, E., Pitsas K., Zannikos F., and Stournas S., Vehicle Emissions and Drivng Cycles: Comparison of the Athens Driving Cycle (ADC) with ECE-15 and European Driving Cycle (EDC). Global Nest, 2006. 8(3): p. 282-290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, A., et al., On-road pollutant emission and fuel consumption characteristics of buses in Beijing. Journal of Environmental Sciences, 2011. 23(3): p. 419-426. DOI:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1001-0742(10)60426-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, X.M., Carmichael G., Chen D.L., Tang Y.H., and Wang T.J., Impacts of different emission sources on air quality during March 2001 in the Pearl River Delta (PRD) region. Atmospheric Environment, 2005. 39(29): p. 5227-5241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wyatt, D., Li, H., and Tate, J., “Examining the Influence of Road Grade on Vehicle Specific Power (VSP) and Carbon Dioxide (CO2) Emission over a Real-World Driving Cycle,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1518, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1518.11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finlayson-Pitts, B.J. and Pitts J.N., Jr., Tropospheric air pollution: ozone, airborne toxics, polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons, and particles. Science, 1997. 276(5315): p. 1045-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UN. Guidance documents and other methodological materials for the implementation of the 1999 Protocol to Abate Acidification, Eutrophication and Ground-level Ozone (Gothenburg Protocol) United Nations Economic Commission for Europe 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heeb, N.V., et al., Three-way catalyst-induced formation of ammonia-velocity- and acceleration- dependent emission factors. Atmospheric Environment, 2006. 40(31): p. 5986-5997.doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2005.12.035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heeb, N.V., Saxer C.J., Forss A.-M., and Brühlmann S., Correlation of hydrogen, ammonia and nitrogen monoxide (nitric oxide) emissions of gasoline- fueled Euro-3 passenger cars at transient driving. Atmospheric Environment, 2006. 40(20): p. 3750-3763. doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2006.03.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heeb, N.V., Saxer C.J., Forss A.-M., and Brühlmann S., Trends of NO-, NO2-, and NH3-emissions from gasoline-fueled Euro- 3- to Euro-4-passenger cars. Atmospheric Environment, 2008. 42(10): p. 2543-2554. doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2007.12.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, I.Y. and Cant N., The Formation and Reactions of Hydrogen Cyanide During Isobutane-SCR over Fe-MFI Catalysts. Catalysis Surveys from Asia, 2003. 7(4): p. 191-202. doi:10.1023/B:CATS.0000008160.18010.cb.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karlsson, H.L., Ammonia, nitrous oxide and hydrogen cyanide emissions from five passenger vehicles. Science of The Total Environment, 2004. 334-335(0): p. 125-132.doi:http://dx.doi. org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2004.04.061.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Ropkins, K., Andrews, G., Daham, B. et al., “Evaluation of a FTIR Emission Measurement System for Legislated Emissions Using a SI Car,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3368, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, Y., Yu L., and Song G., Improved Vehicle-Specific Power Bins for Light-Duty Vehicles in Estimation of Carbon Dioxide Emissions in Beijing. Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board, 2010. 2191(−1): p. 158-165. DOI:10.3141/2191-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bielaczyc, P., Szczotka, A., Swiatek, A., and Woodburn, J., “A Comparison of Ammonia Emission Factors from Light-Duty Vehicles Operating on Gasoline, Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG) and Compressed Natural Gas (CNG),” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):751-759, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1095.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
