<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277850</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>In-Use Fuel Economy and CO₂ Emissions Measurement using OBD Data on US Light-Duty Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>DeFries</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy H.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eastern Research Group Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sabisch</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eastern Research Group Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kishan</surname>
                  <given-names>Sandeep</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Eastern Research Group Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Posada</surname>
                  <given-names>Francisco</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ICCT</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>German</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ICCT</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bandivadekar</surname>
                  <given-names>Anup</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ICCT</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1382</fpage>
         <lpage>1396</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277850"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Fuel economy (FE) and greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions measured via chassis testing under laboratory conditions were never intended to represent the wide range of real-world driving conditions that are experienced during a vehicle's lifetime. Comprehensive real-world information is needed to better assess US FE label adjustments, determine off-cycle credits for FE standards, and forecast real-world driving behavior, fuel consumption, and CO2 emissions. This paper explores a cost effective method to collect in-use fuel consumption data using the on-board diagnostics (OBD) data stream in light-duty vehicles (LDVs). The accuracy of fuel consumption calculated from the OBD data was analyzed in two ways. First, fuel rates calculated from standard OBD Parameter IDs (PIDs) were compared with fuel rate estimates based on enhanced PID (OEM fuel injector fuel rate) data in two different vehicles. The cumulative fuel rate derived from standard PIDs was lower than the fuel rate values obtained from injector-based data (Enhanced PID) for the tested vehicles by approximately 3% and 13%. A second analysis compared fuel rates calculated from OBD inputs, including mass air flow (MAF) sensor and narrow-band O2 sensors, against fuel rates determined through carbon balance measurements from dynamometer chassis testing. The OBD MAF data were sufficient to closely match the fuel consumption measured by chassis testing during stoichiometric operation. Vehicle-specific algorithms were developed for cold start and deceleration fuel cut-off events, identified from the narrowband O2 sensor signal, resulting in cumulative fuel consumption within 3% of the dynamometer results.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davis, S.C., Diegel, S.W., Boundy, R.G.,, Transportation Energy Data Book: Edition 30, in Oak Ridge National Laboratory, ORNL- 6986, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobsen, M.R., Evaluating US Fuel Economy Standards in a Model with Producer and Household Heterogeneity. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2013. 5(2): p. 148-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Train, K.E. and Winston C., Vehicle Chioce Behavior and the Declining Market Share of U.S. Automakers International Economic Review, 2007. 48(4): p. 1469-1496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">European Commission (EC), Proposal for a regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council amending regulation(EC) no 443/2009 to define the modalities for reaching the 2020 target to reduce CO2 emissions from new passenger cars, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), Light- Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards; Final Rule in 40 CFR Parts 85, 86, and 600 2010: Federal Register/Vol. 75, No. 88. p. 25324-25728.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bleijenberg, A., et al., Pathways to Low Carbon Transport in the EU - From Possibility to Reality. Report of the CEPS Task Force on transport and climate change. CEPS Task Force Report, June 2013, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, J., Hardigan, P., Ginder, J., Wallington, T. et al., “Implications of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 for the US Light-Duty Vehicle Fleet,” SAE Technical Paper 2009- 01-2770, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2770.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Casadei, A., Huang, H., Brandao, F., Kasab, J. et al., “Complex Systems Method Applied to Identify Carbon Dioxide Emission Reductions for Light-Duty Vehicles for the 2020-2025 Timeframe,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0360, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01- 0360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Control of Air Pollution From Motor Vehicles and New Motor Vehicle Engines; Modification of Federal Onboard Diagnostic Regulations for Light- Duty Vehicles and Light-Duty Trucks; Extension of Acceptance of California OBD II Requirements, in Rules and Regulations 1998: Federal Register/Vol. 63, No. 245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Standard, “E/E Diagnostic Test Modes,” SAE Standard J1979, Rev. Feb. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huff, S., West, B., and Thomas, J., “Effects of Air Conditioner Use on Real-World Fuel Economy,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01- 0551, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0551.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
