<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277807</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optical Investigation of Dual-fuel CNG/Diesel Combustion Strategies to Reduce CO₂ Emissions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dronniou</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicolas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP Energies Nouvelles</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kashdan</surname>
                  <given-names>Julian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP Energies Nouvelles</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lecointe</surname>
                  <given-names>Bertrand</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP Energies Nouvelles</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sauve</surname>
                  <given-names>Kyle</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Westport Innovations Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Soleri</surname>
                  <given-names>Dominique</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Westport Innovations Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>873</fpage>
         <lpage>887</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277807"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Dual-fuel combustion strategies combining a premixed charge of natural gas and a pilot injection of diesel fuel offer the potential to reduce CO₂ emissions as a result of the high Hydrogen/Carbon (H/C) ratio of methane gas. Moreover, the high octane number of methane means that dual-fuel combustion strategies can be employed on compression ignition engines without the need to vary the engine compression ratio, thereby significantly reducing the cost of engine hardware modifications. The aim of this investigation is to explore the fundamental combustion phenomena occurring when methane is ignited with a pilot injection of diesel fuel. Experiments were performed on a single-cylinder optical research engine which is typical of modern, light-duty diesel engines. A high-speed digital camera recorded time-resolved combustion luminosity and an intensified CCD camera was used for single-cycle OH*chemiluminescence imaging. Experiments were performed for a wide range of equivalence ratios of the premixed charge. At low equivalence ratios, optical engine results revealed that combustion of the premixed charge of methane gas was dominated by spray entrainment and mixture stratification of diesel fuel. At higher equivalence ratios particularly close to stoichiometry, time-resolved natural luminosity images revealed significant modifications in combustion behavior indicating some evidence of flame propagation. Corresponding rates of heat release support the optical measurements in terms of revealing a significant impact on combustion following an increase of equivalence ratio. PLIF-tracer experiments were also performed in order to investigate the influence of in-cylinder fuel distribution on dual-fuel ignition.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">2005 US EPAct about Federal Incentive for Alternative Fuel Infrastructure, PL 109-58, § 1342, 26 USC 30C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sahoo, B.B., Sahoo, N., Saha, U.K., “Effect of Engine Parameters and Type of Gaseous Fuel on the Performance of Dual-Fuel Gas diesel Engines - A Critical Review”, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 13 (2009) 1151-1184, 2009, DOI:10.1016/j.bbr.2011.03.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrano, D., and Lecointe, B., “Exploring the Potential of Dual Fuel diesel-CNG Combustion for Passenger Car Engine,” Proceedings of the FISITA 2012 World Automotive Congress, 2012, DOI:10.1007/978-3-642-33777-2_11.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrano, D., Obiols, J., and Lecointe, B., “Optimization of Dual Fuel Diesel-Methane Operation on a Production Passenger Car Engine - Thermodynamic Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2505, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Reitz, R., Splitter, D., and Musculus, M., “Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Stratification for Controlling PCI Heat-Release Rates Using High-Speed Chemiluminescence Imaging and Fuel Tracer Fluorescence,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):248-269, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L., Hanson, R. M., Splitter, D. A., and Reitz, R. D., “Fuel reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI): a pathway to controlled high-efficiency clean combustion,” International Journal of Engine Research (12), 2011 12:209, DOI:10.1177/1468087411401548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “An Experimental Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):700-716, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., “Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Heavy-Duty Engine Operation at Mid-and High-Loads with Conventional and Alternative Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0363, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A., Walker, N., and Reitz, R., “Effect of Cetane Improvers on Gasoline, Ethanol, and Methanol Reactivity and the Implications for RCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):170-187, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishiyama, T., Kang, J., Ozawa, Y., and Sako, T., “Improvement of Performance and Reduction of Exhaust Emissions by Pilot-Fuel- Injection Control in a Lean-Burning Natural-Gas Dual-Fuel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):243-253, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01- 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “Characterization and Potential of Dual Fuel Combustion in a Modern Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2223, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01- 2223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dong, Y., Vagelopoulos, C. M., Spedding, G. R., and Egolfpoulos, F. N., “Measurement of Laminar Flame speeds through Digital Particle Velocimetry: Mixtures of Methane and Ethane with Hydrogen, Oxygen, Nitrogen and Helium,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute (29)1419:1426, 2002, DOI:10.1016/S1540- 7489(02)80174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01- 1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taschek, M., Koch, P., Egermann, J., and Leipertz, A., “Simultaneous Optical Diagnostics of HSDI Diesel Combustion Processes,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3845, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3845.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Colban, W., Miles, P., Park, S. et al., “Sources of UHC Emissions from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1265- 1289, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Espey, C. and Dec, J., “Diesel Engine Combustion Studies in a Newly Designed Optical-Access Engine Using High-Speed Visualization and 2-D Laser Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 930971, 1993, doi:10.4271/930971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Königsson, F., Stalhammar, P., and Angstrom, H., “Controlling the Injector Tip Temperature in a Diesel Dual Fuel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0826, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0826.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Birgel, A., Ladommatos, N., Aleiferis, P., Zülch, S. et al., “Deposit Formation in the Holes of Diesel Injector Nozzles: A Critical Review,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2383, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ikemoto, M., Omae, K., Nakai, K., Ueda, R. et al., “Injection Nozzle Coking Mechanism in Common-rail Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):78-87, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1818.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
