<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40002386</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40056836</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="pub-doi">10.1093/rfs/hhm082</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Identifying Term Structure Volatility from the LIBOR-Swap Curve</article-title>
          </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
              <string-name>
                  <given-names>Samuel</given-names>
                  <surname>Thompson</surname>
              </string-name>
            </contrib>
          </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>819</fpage>
         <lpage>854</lpage>
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2008 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40056836"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper proposes a new family of specification tests and applies them to affine term structure models of the London Interbank Offered Rate (LIBOR)-swap curve. Contrary to Dai and Singleton (2000), the tests show that when standard estimation techniques are used, affine models do a poor job of forecasting volatility at the short end of the term structure. Improving the volatility forecast does not require different models; rather, it requires a different estimation technique. The paper distinguishes between two econometric procedures for identifying volatility. The "cross-sectional" approach backs out volatility from a cross section of bond yields, and the "time-series" approach imputes volatility from time-series variation in yields. For an affine model, the volatility implied by the time-series procedure passes the specification tests, while the cross-sectionally identified volatility does not. This is surprising, since under correct specification, the "cross-sectional" approach is maximum likelihood. One explanation is that affine models are slightly misspecified; another is that bond yields do not span volatility, as in Collin-Dufresne and Goldstein (2002).</p>
          </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>C52</kwd>
            <kwd>G13</kwd>
          </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
              <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
              <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
          </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
        
         <fn-group>
            <title>[Footnotes]</title>
            <fn id="d28e159a1310">
               <label>7</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e166" publication-type="other">
Ahn, Dittmar, and Gallant (2002);</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e172" publication-type="other">
Duffee (2002);</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e178" publication-type="other">
Hong and Li (2005);</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e185" publication-type="other">
Brandt and Chapman (2003);</mixed-citation>
            </p>
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e191" publication-type="other">
Duarte (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="d28e198a1310">
               <label>10</label>
               
               <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d28e205" publication-type="other">
Hong and Li (2005)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      
        
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d28e221a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e225" publication-type="other">
Ahn, D.-H., R. Dittmar, and A. R. Gallant. 2002. Quadratic Term Structure Models: Theory and Evidence. The
Review of Financial Studies 15:243-88.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e235a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e239" publication-type="other">
Ait-Sahalia, Y. 1996. Testing Continuous-Time Models of the Spot Interest Rate. The Review of Financial Studies
9(2):385-426.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e249a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e253" publication-type="other">
Ait-Sahalia, Y. 2002. Maximum-Likelihood Estimation of Discretely Sampled Diffusions: A Closed-Form Ap-
proximation Approach. Econometrica 70(1):223-62.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e263a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e267" publication-type="other">
Ait-Sahalia, Y. 2007. Closed-Form Expansions for Multivariate Diffusions. Annals of Statistics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e275a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e279" publication-type="other">
Ait-Sahalia, Y, and R. Kimmel. 2002. Estimating Affine Multifactor Term Structure Models Using Closed-Form
Likelihood Expansions. Working Paper, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e289a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e293" publication-type="other">
Andrews, D. W. 1991 . Heteroskedasticity and Autocorrelation Consistent Covariance Matrix Estimation. Econo-
metrica 59(3):817-58.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e303a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e307" publication-type="other">
Bai, J. 2003. Testing Parametric Conditional Distributions of Dynamic Models. Review of Economics and
Statistics 85(3):531-49.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e317a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e321" publication-type="other">
Bates, D. 2006. Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Latent Affine Processes. Review of Financial Studies
19:909-65.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e331a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e335" publication-type="other">
Bikbov, R., and M. Chernov. 2005. Term Structure and Volatility: Lessons from the Eurodollar Markets. Working
Paper, London Business School.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e345a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e349" publication-type="other">
Bliss, R. 1997. Testing Term Structure Methods. Advances in Futures and Options Research 9:197-231.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e357a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e361" publication-type="other">
Brandt, M., and D. Chapman. 2003. Comparing Multifactor Models of the Term Structure. Working Paper, Duke
University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e371a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e375" publication-type="other">
Brandt, M. W., and P. Santa-Clara. 2002. Simulated Likelihood Estimation of Diffusions with an Application to
Exchange Rate Dynamics in Incomplete Markets. Journal of Financial Economics 63:161-210.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e385a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e389" publication-type="other">
Calvet, L., and A. Fisher. 2004. How to Forecast Long-Run Volatility: Regime-Switching and the Estimation of
Multifractal Processes. Journal of Financial Econometrics 2:49-83.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e399a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e403" publication-type="other">
Carrasco, M., and X. Chen. 2002. Mixing and Moment Properties of Various GARCH and Stochastic Volatility
Models. Econometric Theory 18:17-39.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e413a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e417" publication-type="other">
Chen, L. 1996. Stochastic Mean and Stochastic Volatility--A Three-Factor Model of the Term Structure of
Interest Rates and Its Applications in Derivatives Pricing and Risk Management. Financial Markets, Institutions
and Instruments 5:1-88.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e430a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e434" publication-type="other">
Chen, R. R., and L. Scott. 1993. Maximum Likelihood Estimation for a Multifactor Equilibrium Model of the
Term Structure of Interest Rates. Journal of Fixed Income 3(3):14-31 .</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e445a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e449" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H. 2001. Asset Pricing. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e456a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e460" publication-type="other">
Collin-Dufresne, P., and R. Goldstein. 2002. Do Bonds Span the Fixed Income Markets? Theory and Evidence
for Unspanned Stochastic Volatility. Journal of Finance 57(4):1685-730.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e470a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e474" publication-type="other">
Collin-Dufresne, P., R. Goldstein, and C. S. Jones. 2004. Can Interest Rate Volatility Be Extracted from the Cross
Section of Bond Yields? An Investigation of Unspanned Stochastic Volatility. NBER, Working Paper No. 10756.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e484a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e488" publication-type="other">
Corradi, V, and N. R. Swanson. 2001 . Bootstrap Specification Tests with Dependent Observations and Parameter
Estimation Error. Journal of Econometrics 124(1):117-48.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e498a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e502" publication-type="other">
Dai, Q., and K. J. Singleton. 2000. Specification Analysis of Affine Term Structure Models. Journal of Finance
(55): 1943-78.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e512a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e516" publication-type="other">
Davidson, J. 1994. Stochastic Limit Theory. New York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e524a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e528" publication-type="other">
Diebold, F. X., T. A. Gunther, and A. S. Tay. 1998. Evaluating Density Forecasts, with Applications to Financial
Risk Management. International Economic Review 39:863-83.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e538a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e542" publication-type="other">
Duan, J.-C. 2003. A Specification Test for Time Series Models by a Normality Transform. Working Paper,
University of Toronto.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e552a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e556" publication-type="other">
Duarte, J. 2004. Evaluating an Alternative Risk Preference in Affine Term Stucture Models. Review of Financial
Studies 17:379-404.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e566a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e570" publication-type="other">
Duffee, G. R. 2002. Term Premia and Interest Rate Forecasts in Affine Models. Journal of Finance 57:405-43.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e577a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e581" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and R. Kan. 1996. A Yield-Factor Model of Interest Rates. Mathematical Finance 6(4):379-406.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e588a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e592" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and K. J. Singleton. 1997. An Econometric Model of the Term Structure of Interest-Rate Swap Yields.
Journal of Finance 52(4):1287-321 .</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e603a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e607" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., and K. J. Singleton. 1999. Modeling Term Structures of Defaultable Bonds. Review of Financial
Studies 12(4):687-720.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e617a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e621" publication-type="other">
Durbin, J. 1969. Tests for Serial Correlation in Regression Analysis Based on the Periodogram of Least-Squares
Residuals. Biometrika 56(1):1-15.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e631a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e635" publication-type="other">
Durham, G. B., and A. R. Gallant. 2002. Numerical Techniques for Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Contin-
uous Time Diffusion Processes. Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 20:297-316.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e645a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e649" publication-type="other">
Durlauf, S. 1991. Spectral Based Testing of the Martingale Hypothesis. Journal of Econometrics 50:355-76.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e656a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e660" publication-type="other">
Elerian, O., S. Chib, and N. Shephard. 2001. Likelihood Inference for Discretely Observed Non-Linear Diffusions.
Econometrica 69:959-93.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e670a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e674" publication-type="other">
Eraker, B. 2001. MCMC Analysis of Diffusion Models with Application to Finance. Journal of Business and
Economic Statistics 1 9(2):177-91.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e685a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e689" publication-type="other">
Fournie, E. 1992. Un Test de Type Kolmogorov-Smirnov Pour Processus de Diffusion Ergodiques. Working
Paper, No. 1696, INRIA, 1-29.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e699a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e703" publication-type="other">
Gallant, A. R., and G. Tauchen. 1996. Which Moments to Match. Econometric Theory 12:657-81.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e710a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e714" publication-type="other">
Gourieroux, C, A. Monfort, and E. Renault. 1993. Indirect Inference. Journal of Applied Econometrics 20:S85-
S118.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e724a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e728" publication-type="other">
Hansen, B. E. 1991. GARCH(1,1) Processes are Near Epoch Dependent. Economics Letters 36:181-86.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e735a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e739" publication-type="other">
Hong, Y. 1999. Hypothesis Testing in Time Series via the Empirical Characteristic Function: A Generalized
Spectral Density Approach. Journal of the American Statistical Association 94:448.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e749a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e753" publication-type="other">
Hong, Y. 2000. Generalized Spectral Tests for Serial Dependence. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, Series
B 62:557-74.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e764a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e768" publication-type="other">
Hong, Y, and H. Li. 2005. Nonparametric Specification Testing for Continuous-Time Models with Application
to Spot Interest Rates. Review of Financial Studies 18:37-84.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e778a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e782" publication-type="other">
Inoue, A. 1999. A Conditional Goodness-of-Fit Test for Time Series. Working Paper, University of British
Columbia.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e792a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e796" publication-type="other">
Jaquier, E., N. Poison, and P. Rossi. 1994. Bayesian Analysis of Stochastic Volatility Models. Journal of Business
and Economic Statistics 1 2:371-417.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e806a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e810" publication-type="other">
Jones, C. S. 2003a. Estimating Yield Curves from Asynchronous LIBOR and Swap Quotes. Working Paper,
Marshall School of Business.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e820a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e824" publication-type="other">
Jones, C. S. 2003b. Nonlinear Mean Reversion in the Short-Term Interest Rate. Review of Financial Studies
16:793-843.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e834a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e838" publication-type="other">
Kim, S., N. Shephard, and S. Chib. 1998. Stochastic Volatility: Likelihood Inference and Comparison with ARCH
Models. Review of Economic Studies 65:361-93.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e849a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e853" publication-type="other">
Lo, A. W. 1988. Maximum Likelihood Estimation of Generalized Ito Processes with Discretely Sampled Data.
Econometric Theory 4:231-47.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e863a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e867" publication-type="other">
Newey, W. K., and K. D. West. 1987. A Simple, Positive Semi-Definite, Heteroskedasticity and Autocorrelation
Consistent Covariance Matrix. Econometrica 55:703-8.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e877a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e881" publication-type="other">
Pearson, N. D., and T.-S. Sun. 1994. Exploiting the Conditional Density in Estimating the Term Structure: An
Application to the Cox, Ingersoll, and Ross Model. Journal of Finance 49(4): 1279-304.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e891a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e895" publication-type="other">
Pedersen, A. R. 1995. A New Approach to Maximum Likelihood Estimation for Stochastic Differential Equations
Based on Discrete Observations. Scandinavian Journal of Statistics 22:55-71.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e905a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e909" publication-type="other">
Piazzesi, M. 2005. Bond Yields and the Federal Reserve. Journal of Political Economy 1 13:31 1-44.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e916a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e920" publication-type="other">
Pritsker, M. 1998. Nonparametric Density Estimation and Tests of Continuous Time Interest Rate Models. Review
of Financial Studies ll(3):449-87.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e931a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e935" publication-type="other">
Rosenblatt, M. 1 952. Remarks on a Multivariate Transformation. Annals of Mathematical Statistics 23(3):470-72.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e942a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e946" publication-type="other">
Segal, I. E. 1938. Fudicial Distribution of Several Parameters with Application to a Normal System. Cambridge
Philosophical Society Proceedings 33:41-47.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e956a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e960" publication-type="other">
Sin, C, and H. White. 1996. Information Criteria for Selecting Possibly Misspecified Parametric Models. Journal
of Econometrics 7 1 :207-25.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d28e970a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d28e974" publication-type="other">
Vasicek, O. 1977. An Equilibrium Characterization of the Term Structure. Journal of Financial Economics
5:177-88.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      </back>
</article>
