<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830710</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830716</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>POVERTY, RURAL FINANCIAL INSTITUTION BUILDING AND GENDER SENSITIVE DEMAND ANALYSIS IN THE NORTH-WEST AND WEST PROVINCE OF CAMEROON / PAUVRETÉ, DÉVELOPPEMENT DU SYSTÈME FINANCIER RURAL ET QUESTIONS DE GENRE DANS L'ANALYSE DE LA DEMANDE DANS LES PROVINCES NORDOUEST ET OUEST DU CAMEROUN</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gertrud</given-names>
                  <surname>Schrieder</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>95</fpage>
         <lpage>110</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830716"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Research on rural finance has devoted little attention to household's preferences regarding financial services. Yet, part of the success of financial institution building depends on the potential clients' acceptance of the services offered. Cameroon's financial market shows the dualistic structure of an informal and formal sector, typical for most developing countries. Research on informal financial markets revealed that particular traits exist that distinguish them from their formal counterparts. From the 1980s onwards, rural financial institution building started to adopt instruments of informal financial intermediaries to strengthen their performance. Despite this, many programs failed. This paper argues that the adoption of financial instruments in the informal market ought to be complemented by a forward analysis of households' requirement profiles for financial services. Conjoint analysis provides a powerful method to (1) predict client preferences and demand for financial service profiles; and to (2) involve the target group already in the pre-marketing phase of the financial institution building process. This paper concisely presents econometric results of an innovative Conjoint analysis application in the context of a preference analysis in a developing rural economy. The analysis is based on 356 interviews conducted in 1992 in seven villages of Cameroon. It quantitatively identifies the demand for specific financial service profiles and formulates policies oriented towards rural financial market development. Particular stress is laid on demand aspects in financial intermediation that relate to food security, thus, emphasizing rural women's demand structure. Also, concepts from the New Institution Economics are integrated in the discussion to interprete the findings of the empirical demand analysis. Les recherches dans le domaine du développement des marchés financiers ruraux ont accordé peu d'attention à l'identification et à l'analyse des besoins et préférences en services financiers de la clientèle rurale. Cette négligence est préjudiciable à la fois à la clientèle rurale et au développement des marchés financiers ruraux. Le marché financier camerounais présente une structure duale, constituée d'un secteur formel et d'un secteur informel. Cette structure est caractéristique de la plupart des pays en voie de développement. Les recherches sur le secteur informel ont révélé qu'il présente des caractéristiques qui le distinguent du secteur formel. Depuis les années 1980, la prise en compte des instruments financiers du secteur informel a contribué à améliorer la performance des intermédiaires financiers du secteur formel rural. Cependant, cette évolution n'a pas permis d'éliminer toutes les insuffisances liées à l'offre de service financière. Cette contribution propose et utilise la méthode d'Analyse Conjointe pour identifier et analyser avec plus d'efficacité les préférences de la clientèle rurale en services financiers. L'analyse conjointe est souvent utilisée pour estimer les préférences des consommateurs pour des produits et services. La méthode est ici utilisée pour évaluer les préférences d'une couche de population à faible revenus, qui auparavant n'avait pas accès aux services financiers du secteur formel. L'analyse est basée sur une enquête menée en 1992 sur un échantillon de 356 individus au Cameroun. Elle identifie quantitativement la demande de services financiers spécifiques et propose des politiques pour leur amélioration. L'accent est mis sur les aspects d'intermédiation financière liés à la sécurité alimentaire. Par conséquent, la structure de demande financière des femmes est analysée en détail. En outre, des éléments de la Nouvelle Théorie Economique des Institutions sont considérés dans l'interprétation de résultats empiriques.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e144a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e151" publication-type="other">
Burkett 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e158a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e165" publication-type="other">
North (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e171" publication-type="other">
Adams et al. 1987</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e177" publication-type="other">
Bechtel
and Zander 1994</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e187" publication-type="other">
Zeller et al. 1997</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e194a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e201" publication-type="other">
Engel et al. 1993</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e208a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e215" publication-type="other">
Schrieder (1996)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e223a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e230" publication-type="other">
Schrieder
and Heidhues 1995</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e249a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e253" publication-type="other">
Adams, D. W, Graham, D., and Von Pischke, J. D., eds., 1984. Undermining rural development with cheap
credit. Boulder: Westview Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e263a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e267" publication-type="other">
Addelman, S., 1962. Orthogonal main-effect plans for asymmetrical factorial experiments. Technometrics 4
(1): 21-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e277a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e281" publication-type="other">
Bechtel, H. Ph. K., and Zander, R., 1994. Providing financial services to the rural poor: IFAD's experience,
challenges and evolving approaches. Technical issues in rural poverty alleviation, Staff Working Paper
No. 16. Rome: International Fund for Agricultural Development (IFAD), Technical Advisory Division.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e294a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e298" publication-type="other">
Bouman, F. J. A., 1977. "Indigenous savings and credit societies in the Third World - Any message". Savings
and development 1 (4): 181-218.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e309a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e313" publication-type="other">
Bouman, F. J. A., 1990. "Informal rural finance. An Aladdin's lamp of information". Sociologia ruralis 30 (2):
155-173.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e323a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e327" publication-type="other">
Bundesministerium f4r wirtschaftliche Zusammenarbeit und Entwicklung (BMZ), 1994. Sektorkonzept Finanz-
systementwicklung. Forderung von Sparen und Kredit". Bonn: BMZ.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e341" publication-type="other">
Burkett, P., 1988. Informal finance in developing countries: Lessons for the development of formal financial in-
termediaries. Coral Gables: University of Miami.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e355" publication-type="other">
Desai, B. M., and Mellor, J. W., 1993. Institutional finance for agricultural development. An analytical survey of
critical issues. Food Policy Review 1. Washington, D.C: International Food Policy Research Institute
(IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e372" publication-type="other">
Engel, J. R, Blackwell, R. D., Miniard P. W., 1993. Consumer behavior. Seventh Edition. Fort Worth: The Dry-
den Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e386" publication-type="other">
Green, P. E., and Srinivasan, V., 1978. "Conjoint analysis in consumer research: Issues and outlook". Journal
of consumer research 5 (September): 103-123.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e397a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e401" publication-type="other">
Green, P. E., and Srinivasan, V., 1990. "Conjoint analysis in marketing: New developments with implications
for research and practice". Journal of marketing 54 (October): 3-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e411a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e415" publication-type="other">
Heidhues, R, and Weinschenck, G., 1990. Cameroon. In Rural finance profiles in African countries, Vol. 2, ed.
M. Masini, 65-206. Milano: Finafrica-Caprilo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e429" publication-type="other">
Hoff, K., Braverman, A., and Stiglitz, J. E., 1993. Introduction. In The economics of rural organization. Theory,
practice, and policy. 1-29, eds. Hoff, K., Braverman, A., and J. E. Stiglitz. New York, NY: Oxford Univer-
sity Press, A World Bank Book.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e442a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e446" publication-type="other">
Male, C, 1993. Women's issues related to microenterprises and the informal sector. In New directions in do-
nor assistance to microenterprises, 35-42. Paris: Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Develop-
ment (OECD).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e459a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e463" publication-type="other">
Moore, W. L., 1980. Levels of aggregation in conjoint analysis: An empirical comparison". Journal of marke-
ting research 17 (November): 516-523.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e473a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e477" publication-type="other">
North, D. C, 1990. Institutions, institutional change and performance: Cambridge: Cambridge University
Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e492" publication-type="other">
Richter, R., and Furubotn, E. G., 1996. Neue Institutionenokonomik. Tubingen: Mohr - Siebeck.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e499a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e503" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G., 1996. The role of rural finance for food security of the poor in Cameroon. Development econo-
mics and policy, vol. 6, ed. R Heidhues. Frankfurt: Peter Lang Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e513a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e517" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G., and Heidhues, R, 1995. Reaching the Poor through Financial Innovations. Quarterly Journal of
International Agriculture 34 (2): 132-148.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e527a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e531" publication-type="other">
World Bank, 1989. World development report 1989: Financial systems and development. New York, NY:
Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e541a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e545" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., 1995. The demand for financial services by rural household - Conceptual framework and empirical
findings. Quarterly Journal of International Agriculture 34 (2): 149-170.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e555a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e559" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M., Schrieder, G., Braun, J. von, and Heidhues, R, 1997. Rural finance for food security of the poor:
Concept, review, and implications for research and policy. Food Policy Review 4. Washington, D.C.: In-
ternational Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


