<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277793</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Role of Engine Speed and In-Cylinder Flow Field for Stratified and Well-Mixed DISI Engine Combustion Using E70</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sjöberg</surname>
                  <given-names>Magnus</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Labs.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zeng</surname>
                  <given-names>Wei</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Labs.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reuss</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Labs., Univ. of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>642</fpage>
         <lpage>655</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277793"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study compares the role of the in-cylinder flow field for spray-guided stratified-charge combustion and for traditional well-mixed stoichiometric operation, both using E70 fuel. The in-cylinder flow field is altered by changing the engine speed between 1000 and 2000 rpm. The stratified operation with the ethanol blend enabled “head ignition” of the fuel sprays, thus minimizing the available fuel/air-mixing time prior to combustion, creating a highly stratified combustion event.</p>
            <p>For well-mixed stoichiometric operation, the heat-release rate (HRR) scales proportionally with engine speed due to increased in-cylinder turbulence, as is well-known from literature. In contrast, increasing the engine speed influences the stratified combustion process very differently. Ensemble-averaged over 500 cycles, the time-based HRR in kW remains comparatively unchanged as the engine speed increases. However, cyclic variability of the stratified combustion increases substantially with engine speed.</p>
            <p>These observations lead to the development of two hypotheses; a) For highly stratified spray-guided combustion, the heat-release rate of the main combustion phase is primarily controlled by mixing rates and turbulence level associated with fuel-jet penetration. b) During the main combustion phase, the role of the in-cylinder flow field generated by the intake and compression strokes is primarily its stochastic disturbance of the mixing and flow associated with the fuel jets, thereby causing cycle-to-cycle variations of the spray-guided stratified combustion.</p>
            <p>These hypotheses are supported by cycle-resolved heat-release analysis, and also by PIV measurements in a companion paper [1], which show that the magnitude of the flow variations increases with engine speed. This increased variability may explain the occurrence of partial-burn cycles at high engine speed. In particular, the in-cylinder flow frequently becomes sufficiently strong to disturb both fuel/air-mixing and flame spread, both being critically important for the heat-release rate of the highly stratified charge.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, W., Sjöberg, M., and Reuss, D., “Using PIV Measurements to Determine the Role of the In-Cylinder Flow Field for Stratified DISI Engine Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):615-632, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1237.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Solomon, S., Qin, D., Manning, M., Chen, Z., et al. (eds.), “Contribution of Working Group I to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change”, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom and New York, NY, USA, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwarz, C., Schünemann, E., Durst, B., Fischer, J. et al., “Potentials of the Spray-Guided BMW DI Combustion System,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1265, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01- 1265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fansler, T.D., Drake, M.C., and Böhm, B., “High-Speed Mie- Scattering Diagnostics for Spray-Guided Gasoline Engine Development”, Proceedings of the 8th International Symposium on Internal Combustion Diagnostics, Baden-Baden, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Reuss, D.L., “High-speed imaging of spray-guided DISI engine combustion with near-TDC injection of E85 for ultra-low NO and soot”, Proceeding of the Combustion Institute, 34(2):2933-2940, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2012.05.033.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Reuss, D., “NOx-Reduction by Injection-Timing Retard in a Stratified-Charge DISI Engine using Gasoline and E85,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(3):1096-1113, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1643.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM Standard D5798-11, “Standard Specification for Ethanol Fuel Blends for Flexible-Fuel Automotive Spark-Ignition Engines”, June 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US Energy Policy Act of 1992 (Title III, Sec. 301).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Honda, T., Kawamoto, M., Katashiba, H., Sumida, M. et al., “A Study of Mixture Formation and Combustion for Spray Guided DISI,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0046, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwarz, C., Schünemann, E., Durst, B., Fischer, J. et al., “Potentials of the Spray-Guided BMW DI Combustion System,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1265, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01- 1265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drake, M.C., Fansler, T.D., and Lippert, A.M., “Stratified-charge combustion: modeling and imaging of a spray-guided directinjection spark-ignition engine”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 30(2):2683-2691, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2004.07.028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahms, R., Fansler, T.D., Drake, M.C., Kuo, T.W., Lippert, A.M., and Peters, N., “Modeling ignition phenomena in spray-guided spark-ignited engines”, Proceeding of the Combustion Institute 32(2):2743-2750, 2009., doi:10.1016/j.proci.2008.05.052.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahms, R.N., Drake, M.C., Fansler, T.D., Kuo, T.W., and Peters, N., “Understanding ignition processes in spray-guided gasoline engines using high-speed imaging and the extended spark-ignition model SparkCIMM. Part A: Spark channel processes and the turbulent flame front propagation”, Combustion and Flame 158, pp 2229-2244, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahms, R.N., Drake, M.C., Fansler, T.D., Kuo, T.W., and Peters, N., “Understanding ignition processes in spray-guided gasoline engines using high-speed imaging and the extended spark-ignition model SparkCIMM: Part B: Importance of molecular fuel properties in early flame front propagation”, Combustion and Flame 158, pp. 2245-2260, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahms, R., Drake, M., Grover, Jr., R., Solomon, A. et al., “Detailed Simulations of Stratified Ignition and Combustion Processes in a Spray-Guided Gasoline Engine using the SparkCIMM/G-Equation Modeling Framework,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):141-161, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0132.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - the Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serras-Pereira, J., Aleiferis, P., Richardson, D., and Wallace, S., “Characteristics of Ethanol, Butanol, Iso-Octane and Gasoline Sprays and Combustion from a Multi-Hole Injector in a DISI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):893-909, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1591.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuss, D., “Cyclic Variability of Large-Scale Turbulent Structures in Directed and Undirected IC Engine Flows,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0246, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “An Investigation of the Relationship Between Measured Intake Temperature, BDC Temperature, and Combustion Phasing for Premixed and DI HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1900, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fansler T.D., Drake M.C., Düwel I., and Zimmermann F.P., “Fuel- Spray and Spark-Plug Interactions in a Spray-Guided Direct- Injection Gasoline Engine,” Proceedings of the 7th International Symposium on Internal Combustion Diagnostics, Baden-Baden, Germany, pp. 81-97, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi:10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, B., Reuss, D.L. and Sick, V., “High-speed Imaging Analysis of Misfires in a Spray-guided Direct Injection Engine”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 33(2):3089-3096, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2010.07.079.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
