<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3/4</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000477</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40009040</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Acquisition of Lexical Translation Relations from MRDS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ann</given-names>
                  <surname>Gopestake</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ted</given-names>
                  <surname>Briscoe</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Piek</given-names>
                  <surname>Vossen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alicia</given-names>
                  <surname>Ageno</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Irene</given-names>
                  <surname>Castellon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Francesc</given-names>
                  <surname>Ribas</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>German</given-names>
                  <surname>Rigau</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Horacio</given-names>
                  <surname>Rodríguez</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Anna</given-names>
                  <surname>Samiotou</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>183</fpage>
         <lpage>219</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1994 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40009040"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>In this paper we present a methodology for extracting information about lexical translation equivalences from the machine readable versions of conventional dictionaries (MRDs), and describe a series of experiments on semi-automatic construction of a linked multilingual lexical knowledge base for English, Dutch, and Spanish. We discuss the advantages and limitations of using MRDs that this has revealed, and some strategies we have developed to cover gaps where no direct translation can be found.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>machine readable dictionaries</kwd>
            <kwd>lexical acquisition</kwd>
            <kwd>lexical knowledge bases</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d2796424e281a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e285" publication-type="other">
Ageno, A., I. Castellon, G. Rigau, H. Rodriguez, and M.F. Verdejo. 1992. SEISD:
An Environment for Extraction of Semantic Information from On-Line Dictionar-
ies. In Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing
(ANLP-92), pages 253-255, Trento, Italy.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e301a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e305" publication-type="other">
Ageno, A., F. Ribas, G. Rigau, H. Rodriguez, and F. Verdejo. 1993. TGE: Tlinks
Generation Environment. Technical Report ACQUILEX II Working paper 8,
Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e318a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e322" publication-type="other">
Ageno, A., F. Ribas, G. Rigau, H. Rodriguez, and A. Samiotou. 1994. TGE: Tlinks
Generation Environment. In Proceedings of the 15th International Congress on
Computational Linguistics (COLING-94), Kyoto, Japan.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e335a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e339" publication-type="other">
Alshawi, H., D. Carter, M. Rayner, and B. Gamback. 1991. Translation by Quasi
Logical Form Transfer. In Proceedings of the 29th Annual Meeting of the Associ-
ation for Computational Linguistics (ACL-91), pages 161-168, Berkeley, Califor-
nia.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e356a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e360" publication-type="other">
Boguraev, B. and E.J. Briscoe, editors. 1989. Computational Lexicography for
Natural Language Processing. Longman, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e370a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e374" publication-type="other">
Briscoe, E.J. 1991. Lexical Issues in Natural Language Processing. In E. Klein and
F. Veltman, editors, Natural language and speech. Springer- Verlag, pages 39-68.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e384a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e388" publication-type="other">
Calzolari, N. 1992. Acquiring and Representing Semantic Information in a Lexical
Knowledge Base. In J. Pustejovsky and S. Bergler, editors, Lexical Semantics
and Knowledge Representation. Springer- Verlag, Berlin, pages 235-244. Lecture
Notes in AI: 627.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e404a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e408" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, R. 1992. The Logic of Typed Feature Structures. Cambridge University
Press. Tracts in Theoretical Computer Science.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e418a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e422" publication-type="other">
Carroll, J. and C. Grover. 1989. The Derivation of a Large Computational Lexicon
for English from LDOCE. In B. Boguraev and E.J. Briscoe, editors, Compu-
tational lexicography for natural language processing. Longman, London, pages
117-134.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e438a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e442" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A. 1990. An Approach to Building the Hierarchical Element of a
Lexical Knowledge Base from a Machine Readable Dictionary. In Proceedings of
the First International Workshop on Inheritance in Natural Language Processing,
pages 19-29, Tilburg, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e459a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e463" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A. 1992. The ACQUILEX LKB: Representation Issues in Semi-
automatic Acquisition of Large Lexicons. In Proceedings of the 3rd Conference
on Applied Natural Language Processing (ANLP-92), pages 88-96, Trento, Italy.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e476a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e480" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A. 1993. The Compleat LKB. Technical Report 316, Computer Labo-
ratory, University of Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e490a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e494" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A. and E.J. Briscoe. 1995. Semi-Productive Polysemy and Sense Ex-
tension. Semantics, 12:15-67.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e504a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e508" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A., B. Jones, A. Sanfilippo, H. Rodriguez, P. Vossen, S. Montemagni,
and E. Marinai. 1992. Multilingual Lexical Representation. Technical Report
253, Computer Laboratory, University of Cambridge. The (other) Cambridge
ACQUILEX papers.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e524a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e528" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A. and A. Sanfilippo. 1993. Multilingual Lexical Representation. In
Proceedings of the AAAI Spring Symposium on Building Lexicons for Machine
Translation, Stanford, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e541a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e545" publication-type="other">
Dowty, D. 1991. Thematic Proto-Roles and Argument Selection . Language,
67:547-619.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e556a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e560" publication-type="other">
Estival, D., A. Ballim, G. Russell, and S. Warwick. 1990. A Syntax and Semantics
for Feature Structure Transfer. In Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference
on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in MT of NLs (TMI-90), pages 131-143,
Austin, Texas.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e576a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e580" publication-type="other">
Gaya, S. Gili. 1987. Diccionario General Ilustrado de la Lengua Española VOX.
Biblograf S.A., Barcelona.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e590a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e594" publication-type="other">
Gaya, S. Gili. 1992. VOX Harraps Diccionario Esencial: Ingles-Espanol Espaiiol-
Inglés. Biblograf S. A., Barcelona, second edition.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e604a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e608" publication-type="other">
Helmreich, S., L. Guthrie, and Y. Wilks. 1993. The Use of Machine Readable Dic-
tionaries in the Pangloss Project. In Proceedings of the AAAI Spring Symposium
on Building Lexicons for Machine Translation, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e621a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e625" publication-type="other">
Hutchins, W.J. and H.L. Somers, editors. 1992. An Introduction to Machine Trans-
lation. Academic Press, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e635a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e639" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, R., K. Netter, J. Wedekind, and A. Zaenen. 1989. Translation by Struc-
tural Correspondences. In Proceedings of the 4th Conference of the European
Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL-89), pages 272-
281, Manchester, UK.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e656a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e660" publication-type="other">
Kay, M., J-M. Gawron, and P. Norvig, editors. 1994. Verbmobil: A Transla-
tion System for Face-to-Face Dialog. CSLI Lecture Notes, No. 33. University of
Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e673a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e677" publication-type="other">
Klavans, J.L. 1988. COMPLEX: A Computational Lexicon for Natural Language
Systems. In Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Computational
Linguistics (Coling-88), Budapest, Hungary.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e690a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e694" publication-type="other">
Klavans, J.L., M.S. Chodorow, and N. Wacholder. 1990. From Dictionary to
Knowledge Base via Taxonomy. In Proceedings of the Sixth Conference of the
University of Waterloo Centre for the New Oxford English Dictionary and Text
Research: Electronic Text Research, University of Waterloo, Canada.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e710a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e714" publication-type="other">
Levin, B., editor. 1993. English Verb Classes and Alternations. Chicago University
Press, Chicago.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e724a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e728" publication-type="other">
Marti, M.A. and C. Soler. 1994. Dealing with Lexical Mismatches. In Proceedings
of EURALEX-94, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e738a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e742" publication-type="other">
Martin, W. and G. A. J. Tops, editors. 1984. Groot Woordenboek Engels-Nederlands.
Van Dale Lexicografie, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e753a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e757" publication-type="other">
Martin, W. and G.A.J. Tops, editors. 1986. Groot Woordenboek Nederlands-Engels.
Van Dale Lexicografie, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e767a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e771" publication-type="other">
Messinger, H. and G. Türck, editors. 1990. Deutsch-Englisch Lang ens cheidts
Taschenwörterbücher. Langenscheidt, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e781a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e785" publication-type="other">
Neff, M., B. Blaser, J-M Lange, H. Lehmann, and I. Dominguez. 1993. Get It
Where You Can: Acquiring and Maintaining Bilingual Lexicons for Machine
Translation. In Proceedings of the AAAI Spring Symposium on Building Lexi-
cons for Machine Translation, Stanford University, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e801a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e805" publication-type="other">
Neff, M. and M. McCord. 1990. Acquiring Lexical Data from Machine-Readable
Dictionary Resources for Machine Translation. In Third International Confer-
ence on Theoretical and Methodological Issues in Machine Translation of Natural
Languages (TMI-90), Austin, Texas.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e821a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e825" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S. and V. Raskin. 1988. The Subworld Concept Lexicon and the Lexicon
Management System. Computational Linguistics, 13(3- 4):276- 289.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e835a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e839" publication-type="other">
Nirenburg, S., V. Raskin, and A. B. Tucker. 1987. The Structure of Interlingua in
TRANSLATOR. In S. Nirenburg, editor, Machine Translation: Theoretical and
Methodological Issues. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, England, pages
90-113.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e856a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e860" publication-type="other">
Procter, P., editor. 1978. Longman Dictionary of Contemporary English. Longman,
London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e870a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e874" publication-type="other">
Pustejovsky, J. 1991. The Generative Lexicon. Computational Linguistics,
17(4):409-441.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e884a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e888" publication-type="other">
Samiotou, A. 1993. Performance of Cross-linguistic Equivalence Relations: A
Lexicon-based approach. Master's thesis, Centre for Computational Linguistics,
UMIST, England.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e901a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e905" publication-type="other">
Samiotou, A., I. Castellon, F. Ribas, and G. Rigau. 1994. Translation Equivalence
via Lexicon: A Study on Tlinks. Technical Report ACQUILEX II Working paper
25, Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e918a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e922" publication-type="other">
Sanfilippo, A. 1993. LKB Encoding of Lexical Knowledge from Machine-readable
Dictionaries. In E.J. Briscoe, A. Copestake, and V. de Paiva, editors, Inheri-
tance, Defaults and the Lexicon. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, Eng-
land, pages 190-222.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e938a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e942" publication-type="other">
Sanfilippo, A., E.J. Briscoe, A. Copestake, M. A. Marti, and A. Alonge. 1992.
Translation Equivalence and Lexicalization in the ACQUILEX LKB. In Proceed-
ings of the 4th International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological Issues
in Machine Translation (TMI-92), Montreal, Canada.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e959a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e963" publication-type="other">
Sanfilippo, A. and V. Poznanski. 1992. The Acquisition of Lexical Knowledge
from Combined Machine- Readable Dictionary Sources. In Proceedings of the 3rd
Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing (ANLP-92), pages 80-88,
Trento, Italy.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e979a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e983" publication-type="other">
Shieber, S.M., editor. 1986. An Introduction to Unification- Based Approaches to
Grammar. CSLI, Stanford University, Stanford CA. CSLI Lecture Notes 4.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e993a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e997" publication-type="other">
Sutcliffe, R. 1993. Using Distributed Patterns as Language Independent Lexical
Representations. In Proceedings of the AAAI Spring Symposium on Building
Lexicons for Machine Translation, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1010a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1014" publication-type="other">
Talmy, L. 1985. Lexicalization patterns. In T. Shopen, editor, Language Typology
and Syntactic Description. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1024a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1028" publication-type="other">
Trujillo, A. 1995. Towards a Cross-Linguistically Valid Classification of Spatial
Prepositions. Machine Translation, 10(1-2), forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1038a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1042" publication-type="other">
van Sterkenburg, P. and W.J.J. Pijnenburg, editors. 1984. Groot Woordenboek van
Hedendaags Nederlands. Van Dale Lexicografie, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1053a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1057" publication-type="other">
Vossen, P. 1990. A Parser-Grammar for the Meaning Descriptions of LDOCE.
Technical Report Links Project Technical Report 300-169-007, Amsterdam Uni-
versity.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1070a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1074" publication-type="other">
Vossen, P. 1991. Converting Data from a Lexical Database to a Knowledge Base.
Technical Report ACQUILEX Working paper 27, University of Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1084a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1088" publication-type="other">
Vossen, P. 1992. The Automatic Construction of a Knowledge Base from Dictio-
naries: A Combination of Techniques. In H. Tommola, K. Tarantola, T. Salmin
Tolonen, and J. Schop, editors, Proceedings of EURALEX-92 (Vol. 1-2), Tam-
pere, Finland.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1104a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1108" publication-type="other">
Vossen, P. 1993. Extracting Equivalence Relations for a Multilingual Lexical
Knowledge Base. Technical Report ACQUILEX 2 Working Paper No. 14, Uni-
versity of Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1121a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1125" publication-type="other">
Vossen, P. and A. Copestake. 1993. Untangling Definition Structure into Rep-
resentation. In E.J. Briscoe, A. Copestake, and V. de Paiva, editors, Defaults,
Inheritance and the Lexicon. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, England,
pages 246-274.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1141a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1145" publication-type="other">
Vossen, P., W. Meijs, and M. Broeder. 1989. Meaning and Structure in Dictionary
Definitions. In B. Boguraev and E.J. Briscoe, editors, Computational Lexicogra-
phy for Natural Language Processing. Longman, London, pages 171-192.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1159a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1163" publication-type="other">
Walker, D. and R. Amsler. 1986. The Use of Machine-readable Dictionaries in
Sublanguage Analysis. In R. Grishman and R. Kittredge, editors, Analyzing
Language in Restricted Domains. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Hillsdale, New
Jersey, pages 69-83.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1179a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1183" publication-type="other">
Whitelock, P. 1992. Shake-and-Bake Translation. In Proceedings of the 14th
International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING-92), Nantes,
France.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1196a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1200" publication-type="other">
Wilks, Y., D. Fass, C-M. Guo, J. McDonald, T. Plate, and B. Slator. 1989. A
Tractable Machine Dictionary as a Resource for Computational Semantics. In
B. Boguraev and E.J. Briscoe, editors, Computational Lexicography for Natural
Language Processing. Longman, London, pages 193-231.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1216a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1220" publication-type="other">
Zajac, R. 1989. A Transfer Model Using a Typed Feature Structure Rewriting
System with Inheritance. In Proceedings of the 27th Annual Meeting of the As-
sociation for Computational Linguistics (ACL-89), pages 1-7, Vancouver, BC.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1233a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1237" publication-type="other">
Zeevat, H., E. Klein, and J. Calder. 1987. An Introduction to Unification Categorial
Grammar. In N. Haddock, E. Klein, and G. Morrill, editors, Categorial Gram-
mar, Unification Grammar, and Parsing: Working Papers in Cognitive Science,
Volume 1. Centre for Cognitive Science, University of Edinburgh, pages 195-222.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d2796424e1262a1310">
               <label>1</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1269" publication-type="other">
(Ageno et al., 1994)</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1275" publication-type="other">
Vossen, 1993;</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1281" publication-type="other">
Ageno et al., 1993;</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1288" publication-type="other">
Samiotou et al., 1994;</mixed-citation>
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1294" publication-type="other">
Copestake et
al., 1992).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1304a1310">
               <label>3</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1311" publication-type="other">
Sutcliffe (1993)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1318a1310">
               <label>6</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1325" publication-type="other">
glass of beer (Vossen, 1991).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d2796424e1332a1310">
               <label>9</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d2796424e1339" publication-type="other">
Vossen and Copestake (1993)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
