<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i20869260</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">20869268</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Impact of a Strong Bank-Firm Relationship on the Borrowing Firm</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Nishant</given-names>
                  <surname>Dass</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Massimo</given-names>
                  <surname>Massa</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1204</fpage>
         <lpage>1260</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/20869268"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Commercial banks acquire inside information about the firms they lend to. We study the impact of this informationally privileged position on the borrowing firm using a broad panel of U.S. firms over the 1993—2004 period. We measure the strength of the bank-firm relationship by bank-firm proximity, size of the loan, and the lender's insider potential. We show that a stronger relationship, by inducing better monitoring, improves the borrower's corporate governance. Simultaneously, it makes the bank a potentially more informed agent in the equity market. This information asymmetry increases adverse selection for the other market participants and lowers the firm's stock liquidity. This trade-off between improved corporate governance and greater information asymmetry affects the firm's value. Our results have normative implications for the role of banks in the development of financial markets.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d10e293a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e300" publication-type="other">
Baker, Stein, and Wurgler (2003)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d10e307a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e314" publication-type="other">
http://www.smith.umd.edu/faculty/hvidkjaer/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d10e321a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e328" publication-type="other">
http://pages.stern.nyu.edu/~jhasbrou/Research/GibbsEstimates/
Liquidity%20estimates.htm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d10e338a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d10e345" publication-type="other">
FDIC's Summary of Deposits</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d10e361a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e365" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V., and T. C. Johnson. 2007. Insider Trading in Credit Derivatives. Journal of Financial Economics
84(1):110-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e375a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e379" publication-type="other">
Allen, F., and D. Gale. 2000. Comparing Financial Systems. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e386a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e390" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y. 2002. Illiquidity and Stock Returns: Cross-Section and Time-Series Effects. Journal of Financial
Markets 5:31-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e404" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y., and H. Mendelson. 1986. Asset Pricing and the Bid-Ask Spread. Journal of Financial Economics
17(2):223-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e415a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e419" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y., H. Mendelson, and B. Lauterbach. 1997. Market Microstructure and Securities Values: Evidence
from the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange. Journal of Financial Economics 45(3):365-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e429a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e433" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., J. C. Stein, and J. Wurgler. 2003. When Does the Market Matter? Stock Prices and the Investment of
Equity-Dependent Firms. Quarterly Journal of Economics 118(3):969-1005.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e443a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e447" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., N. Miller, M. Petersen, R. Rajan, and J. Stein. 2005. Does Function Follow Organizational Form?
Evidence from the Lending Practices of Large and Small Banks. Journal of Financial Economics 76(2):237-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e457a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e461" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., and G. F. Udell. 1995. Relationship Lending and Lines of Credit in Small Firm Finance. Journal
of Business 68:351-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e471a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e475" publication-type="other">
Berkman, H., and V. R. Eleswarapu. 1998. Short-Term Traders and Liquidity: A Test Using Bombay Stock
Exchange Data. Journal of Financial Economics 47(3):339-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e485a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e489" publication-type="other">
Berle, A., and G. Means. 1932. The Modern Corporation and Private Property. New York: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e497a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e501" publication-type="other">
Besanko, D., and G. Kanatas. 1993. Credit Market Equilibrium with Bank Monitoring and Moral Hazard. Review
of Financial Studies 6(1):213-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e511a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e515" publication-type="other">
Best, R. W., C. W. Hodges, and B. X. Lin. 2004. Does Information Asymmetry Explain the Diversification
Discount? Journal of Financial Research 27(2):235-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e525a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e529" publication-type="other">
Bhide, A. 1993. The Hidden Costs of Stock Market Liquidity. Journal of Financial Economics 34(1):31-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e536a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e540" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., and D. Scharfstein. 1996. Optimal Debt Structure and the Number of Creditors. Journal of Political
Economy 104(1):1-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e550a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e554" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., and E. L. von Thadden. 1998. Blocks, Liquidity, and Corporate Control. Journal of Finance 53(1): 1-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e561a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e565" publication-type="other">
Boot, A. 2000. Relationship Banking: What Do We Know? Journal of Financial Intermediation 9:7-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e573a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e577" publication-type="other">
Boot, A., and A. Thakor. 2000. Can Relationship Banking Survive Competition? Journal of Finance 55(2):679-
714.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e587a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e591" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M. J., T. Chordia, and A. Subrahmanyarn. 1998. Alternative Factor Specifications, Security Character-
istics, and the Cross-Section of Expected Stock Returns. Journal of Financial Economics 49(3):345-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e601a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e605" publication-type="other">
Chen, J., H. Harrison, and J. D. Kubik. 2005. Outsourcing Mutual Fund Management: Firm Boundaries, Incentives
and Performance. Working Paper, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e615a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e619" publication-type="other">
Clarke, J., and K. Shastri. 2001. On Information Asymmetry Metrics. Working Paper, Georgia Institute of
Technology.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e629a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e633" publication-type="other">
Coffee, J. C. 1991. Liquidity versus Control: The Institutional Investor as Corporate Monitor. Columbia Law
Review 91:1277-368.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e643a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e647" publication-type="other">
Cooper, S. K., J. C. Groth, and W. E. Avera. 1985. Liquidity, Exchange Listing and Common Stock Performance.
Journal of Economics and Business 37(1):35-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e658a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e662" publication-type="other">
Core, J. E., R. W. Holthausen, and D. F. Larcker. 1999. Corporate Governance, Chief Executive Officer Com-
pensation, and Firm Performance. Journal of Financial Economics 51:371-406.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e676" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and T. Moskowitz. 1999. Home Bias at Home: Local Equity Preference in Domestic Portfolios.
Journal of Finance 54(6):2045-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e686a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e690" publication-type="other">
Coval, J. D., and T. Moskowitz. 2001. The Geography of Investment: Informed Trading and Asset Prices. Journal
of Political Economy 109(4):811-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e700a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e704" publication-type="other">
Cremers, K. J. M., and V. B. Nair. 2005. Governance Mechanisms and Equity Prices. Journal of Finance
60(6):2859-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e714a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e718" publication-type="other">
Cremers, K. J. M., V. B. Nair, and C. Y. Wei. 2007. Governance Mechanisms and Bond Prices. Review of
Financial Studies 20(5): 1359-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e728a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e732" publication-type="other">
Davis, G. F. 1996. The Significance of Board Interlocks for Corporate Governance. Corporate Governance: An
International Review 4(3): 154-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e747" publication-type="other">
Denis, D. J., D. K. Denis, and A. Sarin. 1997. Ownership Structure and Top Executive Turnover. Journal of
Financial Economics 45(2): 193-221.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e761" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D. 1984. Financial Intermediation and Delegated Monitoring. Review of Economic Studies 51:393-414.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e772" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D. 1989. Reputation Acquisition in Debt Markets. Journal of Political Economy 97(4):828-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e779a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e783" publication-type="other">
Easley, D., and M. O'Hara. 1987. Price, Trade Size, and Information in Securities Markets. Journal of Financial
Economics 19:69-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e793a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e797" publication-type="other">
Easley, D., and M. O'Hara. 1992. Time and the Process of Security Price Adjustment. Journal of Finance
47(2):577-605.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e807a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e811" publication-type="other">
Easley, D., and M. O'Hara. 2004. Information and the Cost of Capital. Journal of Finance 59(4): 1553-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e819a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e823" publication-type="other">
Easley, D., N. Kiefer, M. O'Hara, and J. Paperman. 1996. Liquidity, Information, and Infrequently Traded Stocks.
Journal of Finance 51(4): 1405-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e833a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e837" publication-type="other">
Ellis, K., R. Michaely, and M. O'Hara. 2000. When the Underwriter Is the Market Maker: An Examination of
Trading in the IPO Aftermarket. Journal of Finance 55(3): 1039-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e847a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e851" publication-type="other">
Falkenstein, E. G. 1996. Preferences for Stock Characteristics as Revealed by Mutual Funds Portfolio Holdings.
Journal of Finance 51(1):111-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e861a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e865" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1997. Industry Costs of Equity. Journal of Financial Economics 43(2): 153-
93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e875a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e879" publication-type="other">
Faure-Grimaud, A., and D. Gromb. 2004. Public Trading and Private Incentives. Review of Financial Studies
17(4):985-1014.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e889a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e893" publication-type="other">
Fich, E. M., and A. Shivdasani. 2006. Are Busy Boards Effective Monitors? Journal of Finance 61(2):689-724.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e901a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e905" publication-type="other">
Financial Times. 2003. Banks Could Adopt Derivatives Code: Investors Fear that Knowledge of Lending Plans
Would Give Banks an Unfair Advantage. Financial limes May 30:45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e915a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e919" publication-type="other">
Foster, F. D., and S. Viswanathan. 1990. A Theory of Interday Variations in Volumes, Variances, and Trading
Costs in Securities Markets. Review of Financial Studies 3(4):593-624.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e929a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e933" publication-type="other">
Frank, M. Z., and V. K. Goyal. 2003. Testing the Pecking Order Theory of Capital Structure. Journal of Financial
Economics 67(2):217-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e947" publication-type="other">
Garmaise, M. and T. Moskowitz. 2004. Confronting Information Asymmetries: Evidence from Real Estate
Markets. Review of Financial Studies 17(2):405-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e957a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e961" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., J. Ishii, and A. Metrick. 2003. Corporate Governance and Equity Prices. Quarterly Journal of
Economics 118:107-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e971a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e975" publication-type="other">
Grinblatt, M., and M. Keloharju. 2001. How Distance, Language, and Culture Influence Stockholdings and
Trades. Journal of Finance 56(3): 1053-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e986a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e990" publication-type="other">
Hasbrouck, J. 2005. Trading Costs and Returns for US Equities: Estimating Effective Costs from Daily Data.
Working Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1000a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1004" publication-type="other">
Hauswald, R., and R. Marquez. 2006. Competition and Strategic Information Acquisition in Credit Markets.
Review of Financial Studies 19(3) :967-1000.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1014a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1018" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J. J. 1979. Sample Selection Bias as a Specification Error. Econometrica 47(1): 153-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1025a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1029" publication-type="other">
Hellwig, M. F. 2000. On the Economics and Politics of Corporate Finance and Corporate Control. Corporate
Governance (ed. X. Vives), 95-134. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1039a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1043" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E., and M. S. Weisbach. 1998. Endogenously Chosen Boards of Directors and Their Monitoring of
the CEO. American Economic Review 88(1):96-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1053a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1057" publication-type="other">
Holmstrom, B. and J. Tirole. 1997. Financial Intermediation, Loanable Funds, and the Real Sector. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 112(3):663-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1068a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1072" publication-type="other">
Ibbotson, R. G. 1975. Price Performance of Common Stock New Issues. Journal of Financial Economics
2(3):235-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1082a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1086" publication-type="other">
International Herald Tribune. 2007. Barclays Is Accused of Insider Trading. April 27:11.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1093a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1097" publication-type="other">
James, C. 1987. Some Evidence on the Uniqueness of Bank Loans. Journal of Financial Economics 19(2):217-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1104a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1108" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. 1986. Agency Costs of Free Cash Flow, Corporate Finance, and Takeovers. American Economic
Review 76(2):323-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1118a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1122" publication-type="other">
Kahn, C., and A. Winton. 1998. Ownership Structure, Speculation, and Shareholder Intervention. Journal of
Finance 53(1):99-129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1132a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1136" publication-type="other">
Khalil, F., and B. M. Parigi 1998. Loan Size as a Commitment Device. International Economic Review 39(1):
135-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1147a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1151" publication-type="other">
Klock, M. S., S. A. Mansi, and W. F. Maxwell. 2005. Does Corporate Governance Matter to Bondholders?
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 40(4):693-719.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1165" publication-type="other">
Kovenock, D., and G. Phillips. 1995. Capital Structure and Product Market Rivalry: How Do We Reconcile the
Theory and the Evidence? American Economic Review 85(2):403-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1175a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1179" publication-type="other">
Kyle, A. S. 1985. Continuous Trading and Insider Trading. Econometrica 53(6): 1315-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1186a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1190" publication-type="other">
Levine, R. 2002. Bank-Based or Market-Based Financial Systems: Which Is Better? Journal of Financial
Intermediation 11(4):398-428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1200a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1204" publication-type="other">
Llorente, G., R. Michaely, G. Saar, and J. Wang. 2002. Dynamic Volume-Return Relation of Individual Stocks.
Review of Financial Studies 15(4): 1005-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1218" publication-type="other">
Lowry, M. 2003. Why Does IPO Volume Fluctuate So Much? Journal of Financial Economics 67(1):3-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1226a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1230" publication-type="other">
Lummer, S. L., and J. J. McConnell. 1989. Further Evidence on the Bank Lending Process and the Capital Market
Response to Bank Loan Agreements. Journal of Financial Economics 25:99-102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1240a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1244" publication-type="other">
Malloy, C. J. 2005. The Geography of Equity Analysis. Journal of Finance 60(2):719-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1251a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1255" publication-type="other">
Massa, M., and Z. Rehman. 2008. Information Flows within Financial Conglomerates: Evidence from the
Banks-Mutual Funds Relationship. Journal of Financial Economics 89(2):288-306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1265a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1269" publication-type="other">
Maug, E. 1998. Large Shareholders as Monitors: Is There a Trade-Off Between Liquidity and Control. Journal
of Finance 53(1):99-129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1279a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1283" publication-type="other">
Mayer, C. 1988. New Issues in Corporate Finance. European Economic Review 32:1167-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1290a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1294" publication-type="other">
Milgrom, P., and N. Stokey. 1982. Information, Trade, and Common Knowledge. Journal of Economic Theory
26(1): 17-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1305a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1309" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M., and R. G. Rajan. 1994. The Benefits of Lending Relationships: Evidence from Small Business
Data. Journal of Finance 49(1):3-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1319a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1323" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M., and R. G. Rajan. 1995. The Effect of Credit Market Competition on Firm-Creditor Relationships.
Quarterly Journal of Economics 110(2):407-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1333a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1337" publication-type="other">
Puri, M. 1996. Commercial Banks in Investment Banking: Conflict of Interest or Certification Role? Journal of
Financial Economics 40(3):373-401.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1347a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1351" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R. G. 1992. Insiders and Outsiders: The Choice Between Informed and Arm's-Length Debt. Journal of
Finance 47(4): 1367-1400.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1361a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1365" publication-type="other">
Ritter, J., and D. Zhang. 2007. Affiliated Mutual Funds and the Allocation of Initial Public Offerings. Journal of
Financial Economics 86(2):337-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1375a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1379" publication-type="other">
Santos, J., and A. Rumble. 2006. The American Keiretsu and Universal Banks: Investing, Voting and Sitting on
Nonfinancials Corporate Boards. Journal of Financial Economics 80(2):419-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1390a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1394" publication-type="other">
Santos, J., and K. E. Wilson. 2005. Does Bank's Corporate Control Benefit Firms? Evidence from US Banks'
Control Over Firms' Voting Rights. Working Paper, New York Federal Reserve Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1404a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1408" publication-type="other">
Schenone, C. 2004. The Effect of Banking Relationships on the Firm's IPO Underpricing. Journal of Finance
59(6):2903-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1418a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1422" publication-type="other">
Seyhun, H. N. Forthcoming. Investment Bankers, Insiders, and Chinese Walls. Journal of Law, Economics, and
Policy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1436" publication-type="other">
Sharpe, S. 1990. Asymmetric Information, Bank Lending, and Implicit Contracts: A Stylized Model of Customer
Relationships. Journal of Finance 45(4): 1069-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1446a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1450" publication-type="other">
Slovin, M. B., S. A. Johnson, and J. L. Glascock. 1992. Firm Size and the Information Content of Bank Loan
Announcements. Journal of Banking and Finance 16(6): 1057-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1460a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1464" publication-type="other">
Slovin, M. B., M. E. Sushka, and C. D. Hudson. 1988. Corporate Commercial Paper, Note Issuance Facilities,
and Shareholder Wealth. Journal of International Money and Finance 7:289-302.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1475a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1479" publication-type="other">
Subramaniam, V., and S. Krishnaswami. 1999. Information Asymmetry, Valuation, and the Corporate Spin-Off
Decision. Journal of Financial Economics 53(1):73-112.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1493" publication-type="other">
Sufi, A. 2007. Information Asymmetry and Financing Arrangements: Evidence from Syndicated Loans. Journal
of Finance 62(2):629-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d10e1503a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d10e1507" publication-type="other">
Wooldridge, J. M. 2001. Econometric Analysis of Cross-Section and Panel Data. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


