<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">22</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830638</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830641</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>PRECISION IN LIQUIDITY RISK MANAGEMENT: A SEGMENTED APPROACH / LA PRÉCISION DANS LA GESTION DU RISQUE DE LIQUIDITÉ: UNE APPROCHE SEGMENTÉE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Biswa N.</given-names>
                  <surname>Bhattacharyay</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1998</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>27</fpage>
         <lpage>49</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830641"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Banking worlwide banking is becoming increasing complex day by day. The 1980s and 1990s witnessed severe financial crisis and even failure of several banks. In view of the above, urgent and up-to-date policy matters are required to manage risks and minimize their negative consequences in the banking and financial sector. The generalization of risks in the financial sectors are not limited to financial and political risk; they go beyond known boundaries of classical risks including liquidity, interest rate, market, foreign exchange, credit, payments and settlements etc. One of the important area of bank management is the liquidity risk management. Every bank needs to maintain an appropriate and adequate liquidity level as an inadequate liquidity may cause severe financial problems and even bank failures. This article attempts to present a general model liquidity risk measurement and management framework and related policy issues. This framework is followed by a new segmented approach for measuring the required amount of liquidity for a model bank. In this approach, a required percentage (weightage) of liquidity is assigned to each category of liabilities, on or off balance sheets, taking various economic, market related and country related factors into consideration. Various methods for estimation of liquidity weightage and measuring funding dependency are also discussed. An empirical estimation of liquidity weightage is presented as a case study for banks in Qatar. L'activité bancaire est en train de devenir de plus en plus complexe dans le monde entier. Au cours des années 1980 et 1990 on a assisté à une crise financière majeure et à la faillite de nombreuses banques ce qui indique le besoin urgent de mesures politiques modernes visant à supporter la gestion des risques et à en minimiser les conséquences négatives pour le système bancaire et financier. La généralisation des risques dans le secteur financiers ne se borne pas au risque financier et politique: elle dépasse les limites connues des risques classiques jusqu'à inclure la liquidité, le taux d'intérêt, le marché, les changes, le crédit, les paiements, etc. Un domaine important de la gestion bancaire est la gestion du risque de liquidité. La banque doit garder un niveau adéquat et approroprié de liquidité car une liquidité insuffisante peut causer de graves problèmes financiers et même la faillite de l'institution. Cet article se propose de présenter le cadre d'un modèle général de mesure et gestion du risque de liquidité et les problèmes de politique que ce modèle implique. L'auteur propose en suite une nouvelle approche segmentée conçue pour mesurer le niveau nécessaire de liquidité dans une banque modèle. Dans l'approche proposée on alloue un pourcentage requis (weightage) de liquidité à chaque catégorie de passivité dans et hors du bilan, tout en tenant comptes de plusieurs facteurs ayant trait à l'économie, au marché, au pays. L'auteur présente aussi plusieurs méthodes pour estimer le pourcentage de liquidité requis et pour mesurer la dépendence du financement. L'article comprend également un cas d'étude sur l'estimation du pourcentage de liquidité requis pour les banques du Qatar.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e144a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e151" publication-type="other">
Alattiya, K. Abdulla, (1992), "Toward more effective approach in Manageing Liquidity Risks in Banks", Al Masaref
Al Arabiya, Journal of Union of Arab Banks, Beirut, Lebanon.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e161a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e168" publication-type="other">
Basle Committee on Banking Supervison, (1992), "A Framework for Measuring and Managing Liquidity", Bank
For International Settlements, Basle.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e178a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e185" publication-type="other">
Financial and Payment System Department, (1992), "Functions of and Risks in Payment and Settlement System
in Japan, Payment System Division, Bank of Japan, Tokyo.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e195a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e202" publication-type="other">
Kallberg, G. J. and Parkinson, K. (1984) "Current Asset Management: Cash, Credit and Investory", John Wiley
&amp; Sons, New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e213a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e220" publication-type="other">
Qatar Central Bank, (1995) "Eighteenth Annual Report 1994", Department of Research and Statistics, Qatar
Central Bank, Doha, Qatar.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e230a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e237" publication-type="other">
Shanmugam Bala, et al., (1992), "Bank Management", John Wiley &amp; Sons, Birsbane.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


