<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277797</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of Mixture Stratification on Ignition and Combustion in a GCAI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brands</surname>
                  <given-names>Thorsten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hottenbach</surname>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Koss</surname>
                  <given-names>Hans-Jürgen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grunefeld</surname>
                  <given-names>Gerd</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brassat</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Adomeit</surname>
                  <given-names>Philipp</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pischinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Aachen Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277784</issue-id>
         <fpage>714</fpage>
         <lpage>729</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277797"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Fuel consumption and NOₓ emissions of gasoline engines at part load can be significantly reduced by Controlled Auto-Ignition combustion concepts. However, the range of Gasoline Controlled Auto-Ignition (GCAI) operation is still limited by lacking combustion stability at low load and by high pressure-rise rates toward higher loads. Previous investigations indicate that the auto-ignition process is particularly determined by the thermodynamic state of the charge and by stratification effects of residual gas, temperature, and air-fuel ratio. However, little experimental data exist on the direct influence of mixture stratification on local ignition and heat-release rate (HRR) in direct-injection (DI) GCAI engines, because it is challenging to measure all the relevant charge and combustion parameters quasi-simultaneously with sufficient spatial/temporal resolution and precision.</p>
            <p>In the present article, a newly designed laser-diagnostic approach is therefore presented, in which one-dimensional Spontaneous Raman Scattering (SRS) is combined with high-speed chemiluminescence imaging. SRS yields the composition of the charge along a line in terms of air-fuel ratio, exhaust-gas content, and temperature. Thereby, the mixture formation process is analyzed. Additionally, high-speed chemiluminescence imaging is conducted in the same experiment, in order to characterize the ignition and combustion process with relatively high temporal and spatial resolution. In particular, the influence of the three charge parameters, which are measured shortly before combustion, on the ignition process is investigated by exploiting the combined results of both optical techniques.</p>
            <p>The results show that first auto-ignition in each cycle is basically determined by the gas-phase temperature, which depends on both the residual-gas distribution and local vaporization cooling. Thus, large-scale thermal stratification of the charge leads to a staged combustion process, which progresses from high-temperature to low-temperature regions. However, the progress of combustion and the resulting maximum heat-release rate also depend on the small-scale inhomogeneity in the mixture, which can be controlled by the fuel-injection timing. Furthermore, it is demonstrated that the stability of combustion phasing is dependent on the cyclic variability in the gas-exchange process.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A., Fischer, W., Karrelmeyer, R., Sauer, C. et al., “Kontrollierte Selbstzündung beim Ottomotor - CO2 Einsparpotenziale,” MTZ 01:50-57, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thirouard, B., Cherel, J., and Knop, V., “Investigation of Mixture Quality Effect on CAI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01- 0141, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adomeit, P., Sehr, A., Weinowski, R., Stapf, K. et al., “Operation Strategies for Controlled Auto Ignition Gasoline Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):164-172, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urata, Y., Awasaka, M., Takanashi, J., Kakinuma, T. et al., “A Study of Gasoline-fuelled HCCI Engine Equipped with an Electromagnetic Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1898, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1898.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A., and Itoh, T., “Expansion of HCCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, Negative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0749, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 0749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaahaaina, N., Simon, A., Caton, P., and Edwards, C., “Use of Dynamic Valving to Achieve Residual-Affected Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0549, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0549.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koopmans, L. and Denbratt, I., “A Four Stroke Camless Engine, Operated in Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Mode with Commercial Gasoline,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3610, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brassat, A., Thewes, M., Müther, M., Pischinger, S. et al., “Analysis of the Effects of Certain Alcohol and Furan-Based Biofuels on Controlled Auto Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1135, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01- 0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat Release with Vaporization-Cooling-Induced Thermal Stratification using Ethanol,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):7-27, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1760.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Fuyuto, T., Nishikawa, K., Nakakita, K. et al., “Dual- Fuel PCI Combustion Controlled by In-Cylinder Stratification of Ignitability,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0028, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., “Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Heavy-Duty Engine Operation at Mid-and High-Loads with Conventional and Alternative Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0363, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kakuho, A., Nagamine, M., Amenomori, Y., Urushihara, T. et al., “In-Cylinder Temperature Distribution Measurement and Its Application to HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01- 1202, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hultqvist, A., Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Richter, M. et al., “The HCCI Combustion Process in a Single Cycle - Speed Fuel Tracer LIF and Chemiluminescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0424, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuss, D. and Sick, V., “Inhomogeneities in HCCI Combustion: An Imaging Study,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2122, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">RICHTER, M., ENGSTRÖM, J., FRANKE, A., ALDÉN, M. et al., “The Influence of Charge Inhomogeneity on the HCCI Combustion Process,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2868, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2868.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graf, N., Gronki, J., Schulz, C., Baritaud, T. et al., “In-Cylinder Combustion Visualization in an Auto-Igniting Gasoline Engine using Fuel Tracer- and Formaldehyde-LIF Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1924, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1924.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, W., Dec, J., and Sjöberg, M., “Fuel Stratification for Low-Load HCCI Combustion: Performance &amp; Fuel-PLIF Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4130, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahl, D., Andersson, M., and Denbratt, I., “The role of charge stratification for reducing ringing in gasoline engine homogeneous charge compression ignition combustion investigated by optical imaging,” Int. J. Engine Res. 14(5):525-536, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothamer, D., Snyder, J., Hanson, R., and Steeper, R., “Two- Wavelength PLIF Diagnostic for Temperature and Composition,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):520-533, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01- 1067.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Hwang, W., “Characterizing the Development of Thermal Stratification in an HCCI Engine Using Planar- Imaging Thermometry,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):421-438, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0650.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiser, S., Schild, M., and Schulz, C., “Thermal stratification in an internal combustion engine due to wall heat transfer measured by laser-induced fluorescence,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 34:2911-2919, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dronniou, N. and Dec, J., “Investigating the Development of Thermal Stratification from the Near-Wall Regions to the Bulk-Gas in an HCCI Engine with Planar Imaging Thermometry,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1046-1074, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kohse-Höinghaus, K. and Jeffries, J. B., “Applied combustion diagnostics,” Taylor and Francis, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wieske, P., Wissel, S., Grünefeld, G., and Pischinger, S., “Improvement of LIEF by wavelength-resolved acquisition of multiple images using a single CCD detector,” Appl. Phys. B 83:323-329, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasegawa, R., Sakata, I., Yanagihara, H., Aldén, M. et al., “Quantitative Analysis of the Relation between Flame Structure and Turbulence in HCCI Combustion by Two-Dimensional Temperature Measurement,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0061, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0061.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weikl, M., Beyrau, F., and Leipertz, A., “Simultaneous Temperature and Exhaust-Gas Recirculation-Measurements in a Homogeneous Charge-Compression Ignition Engine by Use of Pure Rotational Coherent Anti-Stokes Raman Spectroscopy,” Appl. Optics 45(15):3646-3651, 2006, doi:10.1364/AO.45.003646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Francqueville, L., Thirouard, B., and Ricordeau, V., “Measurement of Residual Gas Fraction Using IR Absorption,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3337, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3337.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, D. and Steeper, R., “Examination of Iso-octane/Ketone Mixtures for Quantitative LIF Measurements in a DISI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0837, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01- 0837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tong, K., Quay, B., Zello, J., and Santavicca, D., “Fuel Volatility Effects on Mixture Preparation and Performance in a GDI Engine During Cold Start,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3650, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3650.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, B., Ewart, P., Stone, R., Ma, H. et al., “Multi-Component Quantitative PLIF: Robust Engineering Measurements of Cyclic Variation in a Firing Spray-Guided Gasoline Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1073, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grünefeld, G., Beushausen, V., Andresen, P., and Hentschel, W., “Spatially Resolved Raman Scattering for Multi-Species and Temperature Analysis in Technically Applied Combustion Systems: Spray Flame and Four-Cylinder In-Line Engine,” Appl. Phys. B 58:333-342, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P., “Raman line imaging for spatially and temporally resolved mole fraction measurements in internal combustion engines,” Appl. Opt. 38(9):1714-1732, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, W., Dec, J. E., and Sjöberg, M., “Spectroscopic and chemical-kinetic analysis of the phases of HCCI autoignition and combustion for single- and two-stage ignition fuels,” Combust. Flame 154:387-409, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grünefeld, G., Beushausen, V., Andresen, P., and Hentschel, W., “A Major Origin of Cyclic Energy Conversion Variations in SI Engines: Cycle-by-Cycle Variations of the Equivalence Ratio and Residual Gas of the Initial Charge,” SAE Technical Paper 941880, 1994, doi:10.4271/941880.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berntsson, A., Andersson, M., Dahl, D., and Denbratt, I., “A LIFstudy of OH in the Negative Valve Overlap of a Spark-assisted HCCI Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0037, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0037.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collin, R., Nygren, J., Richter, M., Aldén, M. et al., “Simultaneous OH- and Formaldehyde-LIF Measurements in an HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3218, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01- 3218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berntsson, A. and Denbratt, I., “Optical study of HCCI Combustion using NVO and an SI Stratified Charge,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0012, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anders, H., Christensen, M., Johansson, B., Franke, A. et al., “A Study of the Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Combustion Process by Chemiluminescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3680, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3680.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., Hwang, W., and Sjöberg, M., “An Investigation of Thermal Stratification in HCCI Engines Using Chemiluminescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1518, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01- 1518.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Juretzka, A., “Steuerung der Selbstzündung bei Ottomotoren,” Ph.D. thesis, (in German), Universität Karlsruhe, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zigler, B., Keros, P., Helleberg, K., Fatouraie, M. et al., “An experimental investigation of the sensitivity of the ignition and combustion properties of a single-cylinder research engine to spark-assisted HCCI,” Int. J. Engine Res. 12(4):353-375, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, D., “Experimentelle Untersuchungen der innermotorischen Gemischbildung bei variabler Einspritzung,” Ph.D. thesis, (in German), RWTH Aachen University, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, D., Stratmann, J., Pischke, P., Kneer, R. et al., “Experimental Investigation of the Interaction of MultipleGDI Injections using Laser Diagnostics,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):372- 388, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoffmann, T., Hottenbach, P., Koss, H., Pauls, C. et al., “Investigation of Mixture Formation in Diesel Sprays under Quiescent Conditions using Raman, Mie and LIF Diagnostics,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0945, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01- 0945.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hottenbach, P., Brands, T., Hülser, T., Grünefeld, G. et al., “An Experimental Investigation on the Mixture Formation in Diesel-Like Sprays Emanating from Parallel and Divergent Cluster Nozzles by Using Spontaneous Raman Scattering,” JSAE 20119025, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eckbreth, A., “Averaging Considerations for Pulsed, Laser Raman Signals From Turbulent Combustion Media,” Combust. Flame 31:231-237, 1978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hottenbach, P., Brands, T., and Grünefeld, G., “An Experimental Investigation on the Evaporation Characteristics of a Two- Component Fuel in Diesel-Like Sprays,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):800-812, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0688.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hottenbach, P., Brands, T., Hülser, T., and Grünefeld, G., “An Experimental Investigation on the Evaporation Characteristics of Alkane-Alcohol Mixtures in Diesel-Like Sprays Under High- Pressure and High-Temperature Conditions by Spontaneous Raman Scattering,” JSAE 20119024, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brands, T., Hottenbach, P., Koss, H., Grünefeld, G. et al., “Quantitative Fuel-Air-Mixing Measurements in Diesel-Like Sprays Emanating from Convergent and Divergent Multi-Layer Nozzles,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):430-445, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01- 0464.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aleiferis, P., Hardalupas, Y., Taylor, A., Ishii, K. et al., “Flame Chemiluminescence Studies of Cyclic Combustion Variations and Air-to-Fuel Ratio of the Reacting Mixture in a Lean-Burn Stratified- Charge Spark-Ignition Engine,” Combust. Flame 136:72-90, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2003.09.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuwahara, K. and Ando, H., “Diagnostics of in-cylinder flow, mixing and combustion in gasoline engines,” Meas. Sci. Technol. 11:95- 111, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kojima, J., Ikeda, Y., and Nakajima, T., “Spatially resolved Measurement of OH*, CH*, and C2* Chemiluminescence in the Reaction Zone of laminar Methane/Air premixed Flames,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 28:1757-1767, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J. E., Dronniou, N., and Sjöberg, M., “Tailoring HCCI Heat-Release Rates with Partial Fuel Stratification: Comparison of Two-Stage and Single-Stage-Ignition fuels,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 33(2):3047-3055, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2010.06.114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J. and Santavicca, D., “Experimental Diagnostics for the Study of Combustion Instabilities in Lean Premixed Combustors,” J. Prop. Power 19(5):735-750, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” McGraw-Hill Science/Engineering/Math, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Dec, J., and Hwang, W., “Thermodynamic and Chemical Effects of EGR and Its Constituents on HCCI Autoignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0207, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, Y., Dec, J., Dronniou, N., Sjöberg, M. et al., “Partial Fuel Stratification to Control HCCI Heat Release Rates: Fuel Composition and Other Factors Affecting Pre-Ignition Reactions of Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1903-1920, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Birkigt, A., Michels, K., Theobald, J., Seeger, T. et al., “Investigation of compression temperature in highly charged spark-ignition engines,” Int. J. Engine Res. 12:282-292, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Belmont, M., Hancock, M., and Buckingham, D., “Statistical Aspects of Cyclic Variability,” SAE Technical Paper 860324, 1986, doi:10.4271/860324.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Martin, J., Plee, S., and Remboski, D., “Burn Modes and Prior- Cycle Effects on Cyclic Variations in Lean-Burn Spark-Ignition Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 880201, 1988, doi:10.4271/880201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H., “HCCI and CAI Engines for the Automotive Industry,” Crc Press, Woodhead Publishing Limited, Cambridge, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
