<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023197</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>The Law and Macroeconomics of Fiscal Policy</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Stealth Fiscal Policy via the Income Tax Code</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>13</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023197"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Looking at conventional legislative enactments such as TARP and EESA understates the change in fiscal policy that followed the Great Recession. Other, less obvious, legal mechanisms implicitly created “stealth” fiscal policies, with far less attention. For example, IRS technical interpretations of tax law changed in response to the financial crisis and Great Recession. In total, the two largest IRS technical rulings reduced revenue by as much as $100 billion-- much greater than TARP’s $27 billion cost. This paper examines the IRS’s implicit fiscal policy, which provides a concrete example of a regulatory law and macroeconomic intervention. I then evaluate the wisdom of the IRS’s policy from a macroeconomic perspective. I argue that a shortage of aggregate demand or risk of financial crisis does not support all legal interventions designed to address these problems. Instead, legal decisionmakers should ask both 1. How does the proposed intervention affect aggregate demand or the risk of financial crisis? and 2. How does the proposed intervention compare with possible alternative interventions for accomplishing the same goal.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <fn id="fn1">
            <label>1</label> 
            <p>GM $18.6 billion. <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramseyer and Rasmussen page 12</mixed-citation>. Citigroup Citigroup, for example, claimed “tax assets” of $46.1 billion at the end of 2009. R and R at 12, AIG, AIG claimed “Deferred tax assets: Losses and tax credit carryforwards” of $26.2 billion at the end of 2009. R and R at 13. Wells Fargo, Willens says Wells Fargo's entire $17.96 billion in tax breaks could easily have come from the Wachovia deal -- adding up to considerably more than what Wells Fargo paid to acquire the bank.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn2">
            <label>2</label> 
            <p>In “Can the Treasury Exempt Its Own Companies from Tax? The $45 Billion GM NOL Carryforward”, 2011 Cato Papers on Public Policy,, J. Mark Ramseyer and Eric B. Rasmuse provide an excellent analysis and powerful critique of these tax rulings. Ramseyer and Rasmussen do not examine the IRS actions from a macroeconomic policy perspective, however.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn3">
            <label>3</label> 
            <p>See <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office, “Report on the Troubled Asset Relief Program—April 2014, available at https://www.cbo.gov/publication/45260</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn4">
            <label>4</label> 
            <p>The Euro zone provided support for financial institutions in a more roundabout fashion. National governments provided assistance to their own struggling financial institutions. Because this support for the financial system overwhelemed the fund raising capacity of several European countries (e.g. Greece, Ireland, Portugal, Cyprus) the Euro zone enacted the European Financial Stability Facility and European Stability Mechanism. These mechanisms “rais[ed] funds in capital market to finance loans for euro area member states.” http://www.efsf.europa.eu/about/index.htm.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn5">
            <label>5</label> 
            <p>See, e.g., <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Binayaim Applebaum, Washington Post 2009, available at http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/12/15/AR2009121504534.html</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn6">
            <label>6</label> 
            <p>GM $18.6 billion. Ramseyer and Rasmussen page 12. Citigroup Citigroup, for example, claimed “tax assets” of $46.1 billion at the end of 2009. R and R at 12, AIG, AIG claimed “Deferred tax assets: Losses and tax credit carryforwards” of $26.2 billion at the end of 2009. R and R at 13. Wells Fargo, Willens says Wells Fargo's entire $17.96 billion in tax breaks could easily have come from the Wachovia deal -- adding up to considerably more than what Wells Fargo paid to acquire the bank.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn7">
            <label>7</label> 
            <p>In “Can the Treasury Exempt Its Own Companies from Tax? The $45 Billion GM NOL Carryforward”, 2011 Cato Papers on Public Policy,, J. Mark Ramseyer and Eric B. Rasmuse provide an excellent analysis and powerful critique of these tax rulings. Ramseyer and Rasmussen do not examine the IRS actions from a macroeconomic policy perspective, however. </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn8">
            <label>8</label> 
            <p>26 U.S.C. Section 382.”</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn9">
            <label>9</label> 
            <p>26 U.S.C. Section 382(c) which provides that “if the new loss corporation [which would include a corporation that just buys another corporation’s NOLs] does not continue the business enterprise of the old loss corporation at all times during the 2-year period beginning on the change date, the section 382 limitation for any post-change year shall be zero.”</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn10">
            <label>10</label> 
            <p>26 U.S.C. Section 382(b) provides that the acquirer of the company with NOLs can use the acquired company’s NOLs so long as the NOLs do not exceed the value of the acquired company multiplied by “the long term tax exemt rate.” For example, suppose our company, call it “A” with $80 in NOLs was worth $100 before it was acquired in March 2015. The long term tax exempt rate was 2.19% in March 2015, see IRS Revenue Ruling 2015-4, available at http://www.pmstax.com/afr/rr20154.pdf. The acquiring company can only use $100*.0219=$2.19 of A’s NOLs in 2015, 2016, 2017, etc. Because NOLs can only be carried forward 20 years, the acquiring company will not be able to use all of company A’s NOLs. </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn11">
            <label>11</label> 
            <p>For citations, use http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wachovia.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn12">
            <label>12</label> 
            <p>In ordinary times, the FDICIA requires the FDIC to choose the “least cost method” reorganization to the FDIC’s insurance fund. Citigroup’s proposal may not have been the least cost method. The systemic risk exception allows the FDIC to bypass the least cost method if it “would have serious adverse effects on economic conditions or financial stability” and if bypassing the least cost method would “avoid or mitigate such adverse effects.” https://www.fdic.gov/news/news/speeches/archives/2007/chairman/spmay0307.html. Citigroup’s requirements may not have been the least cost method of resolving Wachovia, but Federal Reserve officials encouraged the FDIC to invoke the “systemic risk” exception. <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FDIC Report at 368-369</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn13">
            <label>13</label> 
            <p>In return for this support, Citigroup issued preferred stock to the FDIC. FCIC Report.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn14">
            <label>14</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FCIC Report at 369</mixed-citation>. </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn15">
            <label>15</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FCIC Report at 368-69</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn16">
            <label>16</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FCIC Report at 370</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn17">
            <label>17</label> 
            <p>For a summary of the criticisms, see Rich Delmar, memorandum for Inspector General <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eric M. Thorson, “Inquiry Regarding IRS Notice 2008-83,” September 3, 2009, pp. 3, 5, 11–12</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn18">
            <label>18</label> 
            <p>See http://www.jonesday.com/files/Publication/3feb30bb-253d-40f6-89b9-9e543a0622e2/Presentation/PublicationAttachment/6764f6b7-b547-4020-b67f-a151ff60a3d7/Revisiting%20Notice.pdf.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn19">
            <label>19</label> 
            <p>http://taxprof.typepad.com/taxprof_blog/2008/11/nols-and-the-rule-of-law.html</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn20">
            <label>20</label> 
            <p>See, e.g., <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amit R. Paley, A Quiet Windfall For U.S. Banks: With Attention on Bailout Debate, Treasury Made Change to Tax Policy, WASH. POST, Nov. 10, 2008, at A01 (discussing many interviews with tax lawyers who considered the Notice to exceed Treasury's scope of authority)</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn21">
            <label>21</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Delmar memo at 4</mixed-citation>. </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn22">
            <label>22</label> 
            <p>Get Cite.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn23">
            <label>23</label> 
            <p>http://www.thestreet.com/story/11306521/1/how-wells-fargo-won-the-tax-dodging-trophy.html </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn24">
            <label>24</label> 
            <p>The analysis in this subsection draws heavily upon Ramseyer and Rasmussen. Unlike R and R, I view Notice 2010-2 within the broader context of tax/financial regulation issued in response to the Great Recession.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn25">
            <label>25</label> 
            <p>
               <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramseyer and Rasmussen at 8</mixed-citation>.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn26">
            <label>26</label> 
            <p>Tax assets are not discounted to reflect the fact that they will reduce tax in the future rather than in the present. In addition, the value of tax assets are not adjusted for the probability that they will not be used due to a lack of profits. See Ramseyer and Rasmussen.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn27">
            <label>27</label> 
            <p>Two changes of control occurred for the purpose of Section 382 with respect to each company. The first occurred when Treasury increased its stake in the company from zero to greater than 50%. For AIG and Citgroup, both transactions appeared to trigger Section 382 change of control provisions. With respect to GM, only the sale of stock from the Treasury to the public or back to GM should have triggered Section 382(g). Treasury’s initial acquisition of GM stock did not triggers 382(g) because, among other reasons, it was exempted by Section 382(n). In all three cases, at least one of the pattern of transactions by Treasury triggered 382(g).</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn28">
            <label>28</label> 
            <p>Although the Treasury never owned more than 50% of Citigroup, Citigroup issued a great deal of equity to private shareholders during the period. As a result, more than 50% of ownership changed hands from one set of large shareholders to another, trigerring Section 382(g).</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn29">
            <label>29</label> 
            <p>Most of the Treasury’s initial investments came in the form of debt, preferred stock, and/or warrants (company issued stock options). Sections A and B of Notice 2010-2 explained that such investments did not count as stock ownership for purposes of Section 382.. Many of these investments were later converted to common stock.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn30">
            <label>30</label> 
            <p>Notice 2010-2 Sections D and E explain that sales of stock by the Treasury, either directly to the company itself (Part D), or to other shareholders (Part E)do not trigger Section 382 change of control restrictions.</p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn31">
            <label>31</label> 
            <p>http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/12/15/AR2009121504534.html. </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn32">
            <label>32</label> 
            <p>Ramseyer and Rasmussen</p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
