<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">91</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198799</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44724673</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Soil Dynamics: A Review of Theory and Application</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>R. D.</given-names>
                  <surname>Wismer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1982</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2266</fpage>
         <lpage>2278</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1983 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44724673"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Soil dynamics is defined as a special body of scientific knowledge that deals with the high rate of strain and resulting large strain failure of off-highway vehicles interacting with soil. The development of soil dynamics knowledge is traced from its origin in classical soil mechanics and foundation engineering to the current practical engineering capability for the design, development, and utilization of off-highway machines. Examples of research results and engineering applications in traction, tillage, and earthmoving are presented and discussed. Although soil dynamics research can lead to the creation of radically new and different machines, it is concluded that its greatest impact on off-highway machinery is in design optimization and evaluation. The combination of improved measurement and computational systems assure continued growth of soil dynamics knowledge and engineering capability in an evolutionary way.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
        <ref id="d85e205a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e209" publication-type="other">
Bekker, M. G., Theory of Land Locomotion, University of Michigan Press, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1 956.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e216a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e220" publication-type="other">
Bernstein, R., Problems zur experimentellen motorpflugmechanik. Der Motorwagen, Vol. 16, 1913.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e231" publication-type="other">
Coulomb, C. A., Essai sur une application des reg/es des maximis et minimis a quelques problèmes
de statique relatifs a l'architecture, Mem. acad. roy. pres. divers savants, Vol. 7, Paris: 1776.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e241a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e245" publication-type="other">
Freitag, D. R., A Dimensional Analysis of the Performance of Pneumatic Tires on Soft Soils, USAE
Waterways Experiment Station Technical Report No. 3-688, 1965.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e260" publication-type="other">
Freitag, D. R., Schafer, R. L., Wismer, R. D., Young, D. F., Similitude of Soil-Machine Systems, ASAE
Publication 3-77, 1977.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e270a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e274" publication-type="other">
Garrity, R. J., Kolthoff, C. P., Reaves, C. A. and Schafer, R. L., A Test Comparison of Model and Full-
Size Bulldozer Blades, SAE Paper 680612, 1968.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e288" publication-type="other">
Goryachkin, V. P., Collected Works in Three Volumes, USDA, Washington, D.C., 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e295a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e299" publication-type="other">
Hassan, A. E., Trafficability Study of a Cable Skidder, ASAE Paper No. 75-1508, 1975.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e306a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e310" publication-type="other">
Harrison, W. L., Jr., Analytical Prediction of Performance for Full-Size and Sma/I-Scale Model
Vehicles, Proceedings of 1st International Conference of ISTVS, July 1961.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e320a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e324" publication-type="other">
Hettiaratchi, D. R. P., Whitney, B. D., Reece, A. R., The Calculation of Passive Pressure in Two-
Dimensional Soil Failure, Journal of Agricultural Engineering Research, Vol. 11, No. 2, 1966.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e339" publication-type="other">
Janosi, Z., An Analysis of Pneumatic Tire Performance on Deformable Soils, Proceedings 1st Inter-
national Conference of ISTVS, July 1961.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e349a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e353" publication-type="other">
Knight, S. J., A Summary of Trafficability Studies through 1955, USAE Waterways Experiment
Station, TM No. 3-240, Fourteenth Supplement, 1956.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e363a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e367" publication-type="other">
Kahle, G. W. and Hung, H. M., Economic Assessment of Turbine Powered Industrial Vehicles, SAE
Transactions Vol. 75 (1967), Paper 66-6-5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e377a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e381" publication-type="other">
Larson, L. W., Lovely, W. G., Bockhop, C. W., Predicting Draft Forces Using Model Moldboard Plows
in Agricultural Soils, ASAE Paper No. 66-127, 1966.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e391a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e395" publication-type="other">
Larson, D. L., Smith, D. W., and Liljedahl, J. B., Dyanmics of Three-Dimensional Tractor Motion,
ASAE Transactions, Vol. 19, No. 1, 1976.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e405a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e409" publication-type="other">
McKibben, E. G., Some Kinematic and Dynamic Studies of Rigid Transport Wheels for Agricultural
Equipment, Iowa State University, Agricultural Experiment Station, Research Bulletin No. 231, 1938.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e420a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e424" publication-type="other">
Micklethwait, E. W. E., Tracks for Fighting Vehicles, School of Tank Technology, 1944.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e431a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e435" publication-type="other">
Murphy, G., Similitude in Engineering, Ronald Press, New York, 1950.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e442a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e446" publication-type="other">
Nuttall, C. J., Jr., Scaled Vehicle Mobility Factors -Final Report, WNRE Report No. 18-2, 1956.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e457" publication-type="other">
Osman, M. S., The Mechanics of Soil Cutting Blades, Journal of Agricultural Engineering Research,
Vol. 9, No. 4, 1964.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e467a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e471" publication-type="other">
Payne, P. C. J., The Relationship between the Mechanical Properties of Soil and the Performance of
Simple Cultivation Implements, Journal of Agricultural Engineering Research, Vol. 1, 1956.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e481a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e485" publication-type="other">
Pavlics, F., Locomotion Energy Requirements for Lunar Surface Vehicles, SAE Paper No. 660149,
1966.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e496a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e500" publication-type="other">
Perumpral, J. V., and Desai, C. S., A Generalized Model for a Soil-Tillage Tool Interaction, ASAE
Paper No. 79-1546, 1979.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e510a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e514" publication-type="other">
Pershing, R. L., Simulating Tractor Performance, SAE Paper No. 710525, 1971.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e521a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e525" publication-type="other">
Proctor, R. R., Description of Field and Laboratory Methods, Engineering News-Record, 1933.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e532a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e536" publication-type="other">
Reaves, C. A., Similitude in Performance Studies of Soil-Chisel Systems, ASAE Paper No. 68-124,
1968.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e546a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e550" publication-type="other">
Reece, A. R„ Theory and Practice of Off-The-Road Locomotion, Institute of Mechanical Engineers
Annual Conference, 1964.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e560a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e564" publication-type="other">
Reece, A. R., The Fundamental Equation of Earth-Moving Mechanics, Proceedings of Institute of
Mechanical Engineers, Vol. 1979, 1965.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e575a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e579" publication-type="other">
Rula, A. A., and Nuttall, C. J., Jr., An Analysis of Ground Mobility Models (ANAMOB), Technical
Report M-71-4, USAE Waterways Experimental Station, 1971.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e589a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e593" publication-type="other">
Schafer, R. L., Reaves, C. A., Young, D. R., An Interpretation of Distortion in the Similtude of Certain
Soil-Machine Systems, ASAE Paper No. 68-123, 1968.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e603a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e607" publication-type="other">
Söhne, W., Some Basic Considerations of Soil Mechanics as Applied to Agricultural Engineer,
Grundlagen der Landtechnik, Vol. 7, 1956.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e621" publication-type="other">
Söhne, W., The Mechanics of Soil-Vehicle Systems with Particular Respect to Agricultural Tractors,
Grundlagen der Landtechnik, Vol. 17, 1963.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e631a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e635" publication-type="other">
Sullivan, R. J., Earthmoving in Miniature, SAE Paper No. 897B, 1964.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e642a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e646" publication-type="other">
Terzaghi, K., Theoretical Soil Mechanics, J. Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, 1944.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e658" publication-type="other">
Turnage, G. W., Tire Selection and Performance Prediction for Off -Road Wheeled-Vehicle Operations,
Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference of the International Society for the Terrain Vehicle
Systems, Vol. 1, Stockholm, Sweden, 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e671a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e675" publication-type="other">
Wismer, R. D„ and Luth, H. J., Off-Road Traction Prediction for Wheeled Vehicles, ASAE Paper No.
72-619, 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e685a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e689" publication-type="other">
Wismer, R. D„ Luth, H. J., Brixius, W. W., Field Testing of Soil-Machine Systems, Proceedings of
the Sixth International Conference of ISTVS, August 1978.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e699a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e703" publication-type="other">
Yong, R. N., and Fattah, E. A., Prediction of Wheel-Soil Interaction and Performance Using the Finite
Element Method, Journal of Terramechanics, Vol. 13, 1976.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e713a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e717" publication-type="other">
Yong, R. N., and Hanna, A. W., Finite Element Analysis of Plane Soil Cutting, Journal of Terra-
mechanics, Vol. 14, 1977.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e727a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e731" publication-type="other">
Yong, R. N., Fattah, E. A., and Boonsinsuk, P., Analysis and Prediction of Type-Soil Interaction and
Performance Using Finite Elements, Journal of Terramechanics, Vol. 15, 1978.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e742a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e746" publication-type="other">
Zelenin, A. N., Basic Physics of the Theory of Soil Cutting, Moscow, 1950.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d85e753a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d85e757" publication-type="other">
Zoz, F. M., Predicting Tractor Field Performance, ASAE Paper No. 70-118, 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


