<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277757</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Dual Grid Curved Beam Finite Element Model of Piston Rings for Improved Contact Capabilities</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Baelden</surname>
                  <given-names>Camille</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tian</surname>
                  <given-names>Tian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>May 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277742</issue-id>
         <fpage>156</fpage>
         <lpage>171</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277757"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Piston rings are large contributors to friction losses in internal combustion engines. To achieve higher engine efficiency, low friction ring packs that can maintain good sealing performance must be designed. To support this effort, simulation tools have been developed to model the performance of piston rings during engine operation. However, the challenge of predicting oil consumption, blow by, and ring pack friction with sufficient accuracy remains. This is mostly due to the complexity of this system. Ring dynamics, deformation, interaction with liner and piston, gas and lubricant flow must all be studied together to make relevant predictions. In this paper, a new curved beam finite element model of piston rings is proposed. Ring structural deformation and contact with the liner are treated on two separate grids. A comparison with ring models in the literature and analytical solutions shows that it can provide accurate results efficiently. The proposed model can serve as a numerical framework to couple ring structural deformation, interaction with liner and piston, and predict oil transport. The new model is used to study conformability of piston rings to distorted bore. Results show that the differences between existing conformability criteria can be explained by the singular behavior of the ring gap region.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Holmberg K., Andersson P., and Erdemir A., “Global energy consumption due to friction in passenger cars,” Tribology International, 47:221-234, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.triboint.2011.11.022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prescott J., “The bending of thin rings,” Automobile engineer, 9(130):295-302, 1919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swift H. W., “Elastic deformation of piston rings,” Engineering, 163:161-165, 1947.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dragoni E., and Strozzi A., “Analysis of a split ring inserted into a circular housing,” The Journal of Strain Analysis for Engineering Design, 21(2):59-70, 1986, doi:10.1243/03093247V212059.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller R., “Zur Frage des Formfüllungsvermögen von Kolbenringen in von der Kreisform abweichenden Bohrungen gleicher Umfangslänge,” MTZ, 31:79-82, 1970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dunaevsky V. V., “Analysis of distortions of cylinders and conformability of piston rings,” Tribology transactions, 33(1):33-40, 1990, doi:10.1080/10402009008981927.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dunaevsky V. V., “Development of conformability model of piston rings with consideration of their three-dimensional torsional distortions and Fourier series representation of cylinder bore geometry,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-3131, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-3131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dunaevsky V., and Rudzitis J., “Clarification of a Semi-Empirical Approach in Piston Ring-Cylinder Bore Conformability Prediction,” Journal of Tribology, 129(2):430, 2007, doi:10.1115/1.2647800.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomanik, E., “Piston Ring Conformability in a Distorted Bore,” SAE Technical Paper 960356, 1996, doi:10.4271/960356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomanik E., “Improved Criterion for Ring Conformability Under Realistic Bore Deformation,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0190, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ejakov M. A., Schock H. J., and Brombolich L. J., “Modeling of Ring Twist For an IC Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 982693, 1998, doi:10.4271/982693.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu L., Tian T., and Rabuté R., “Development and Applications of an Analytical Tool for Piston Ring Design,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3112, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu L., and Tian T., “A Three-Dimensional Model for Piston Ring- Pack Dynamics and Blow-By Gas Flow,” ASME 2004 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference ICEF2004- 0968, 2004, doi:10.1115/ICEF2004-0968.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Timoshenko S. P., Strength of Materials: Elementary theory and problems, Krieger Publishing Company, Florida, ISBN 978- 0898746211:93-96, 362-384, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenwood J. A., and Tripp J. H., “The contact of two nominally flat rough surfaces,” Proceedings of the institution of mechanical engineers, 185(1):625-633, 1970, doi:10.1243/PIME_PROC_1970_185_069_02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Li, Y., and Tian, T., “A Novel Approach to Model the Lubrication and Friction between the Twin-Land Oil Control Ring and Liner with Consideration of Micro Structure of the Liner Surface Finish in Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1613, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1613.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu Y., Cheng H. S., Arai T., Kobayashi Y., and Aoyama S., “Numerical simulation of piston ring in mixed lubrication: a nonaxisymmetrical analysis,” Journal of tribology, 116(3):470-478, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Press W. H., Numerical recipes 3rd edition: The art of scientific computing, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge UK, ISBN 978-0521880688:110-119, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Love A. E. H., A Treatise on the Mathematical Theory of Elasticity Fourth Edition, Dover Publications, New York, ISBN 978- 0486601748:444-450, 1927.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
