<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910146</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of the Space and Cyber Force Composition Analysis for the US Air Force</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Terry</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mr. Michael Terry is a senior operations research analyst with HQ Air Force Space Command, Directorate of Strategic Plans, Requirements and Analysis Division, Strategic Analysis Branch at Peterson AFB, Colorado. He is the MAJCOM lead for space and cyberspace contributions in the Joint Staff-led Support for Strategic Analysis effort, which establishes the strategic analytical baseline for the Department of Defense. Additionally, he has extensive wargaming experience in various capacities, having supported more than 20 Title X or equivalent wargames across the Department of Defense, such as Global Engagement, Futures, Schriever, Thors Hammer, Army Transformation, and Navy Global. He is the Air Force Space Command lead analyst for the space and cyberspace missions in the Total Force Continuum (TF-C) study, which supported the Chief of Staff of the Air Force (CSAF). Mr. Terry has a BS degree in biology from the University of North Carolina at Pembroke, a master’s degree in public administration from the University of Oklahoma, an MS in systems engineering from the Naval Postgraduate School, and a master’s degree in military operational arts and sciences from Air University.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lindner</surname>
                  <given-names>Blake “Buddah”</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mr. Blake “Buddah” Lindner is a Deputy Chief for Strategic Requirements, Integration and Analysis Division with HQ Air Force Space Command, Directorate of Strategic Plan, Requirements and Analysis at Peterson AFB, CO. Mr. Lindner was a Weapon Systems Operator for F-4s during his Air Force career. He served as Commander, 501st Combat Support Wing, based at RAF Alconbury, UK as well as Deputy Director for Strategic Plans and Requirements at United States Air Force Europe (USAFE) and the Pentagon in Headquarters Air Force, Strategic Plans and Programs before retiring as a Colonel. As a Senior Operations Research Analyst he served as Director of Analysis, Assessments and Lessons Learned at USAFE prior to his current assignment. Mr. Lindner was the Chief Analyst for HQ Air Force Space Command in support of this Air Force Space Command led effort supporting the Chief Staff of the Air Force directed Total Force Continuum (TF-C) effort. Mr. Lindner is a United States Air Force Academy graduate with a B.S. in Mathematics and a Master’s in Business Administration.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Eberle</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Captain Scott Eberle is an Executive Officer to the Directorate of Strategic Plans, Programs, Requirements and Analysis, Headquarters United States Air Force Space Command. Captain Eberle entered the US Air Force Academy in June 2002 and was commissioned following graduation in May 2006. He is a Scientific Analyst and Aircraft Maintenance Officer with assignments in Weapons and Tactics Analysis, Aircraft Maintenance Operations, and Space and Cyberspace analysis. He has deployed to Iraq, Afghanistan, Djibouti, and Guam in support to Operations Iraqi Freedom, Enduring Freedom, and the Continuous Bomber Presence. Captain Eberle is a 2011 graduate of Squadron Officer School.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>December 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>48</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910130</issue-id>
         <fpage>54</fpage>
         <lpage>63</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910146"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Welsh, M. 2013. Air Force News Briefing. Pentagon Briefing Room. Lecture conducted from Secretary of the Air Force Michael B. Donley, General Mark A. Welsh, and Brig General Les Kodlick, Washington DC (January 11).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">James, D. 2014. National Commission on the Structure of the Air Force. Air Force Presentation to the Senate Armed Services Committee. Written remarks provided from Secretary of the Air Force Deborah Lee James, Washington DC (April 29).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gates, R. 2011. Defense Spending. American Enterprise Institute. Lecture conducted from Secretary of Defense Robert M. Gates, Washington DC (May 24).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
