<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26142244</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Asset Prices and Risk Sharing in Open Economies</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Andreas</given-names>
                  <surname>Stathopoulos</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">30</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26142242</issue-id>
         <fpage>363</fpage>
         <lpage>415</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/26142244"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper proposes a two-country model that features time-varying heterogeneity in conditional risk aversion across countries, endogenously arising from the interaction between external habit formation and preference home bias. The model generates high international correlation of state prices along with modest cross-country consumption growth correlation and matches the empirical disconnect between exchange rate changes and consumption growth rate differentials. The key mechanism is endogenous time variation in conditional consumption growth volatility: the conditionally less risk averse country insures the more risk averse one, offsetting cross-country heterogeneity in conditional risk aversion and leading to significant international comovement in marginal utility growth.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1097e275a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1097e282" publication-type="other">
The latter would constitute "deep habits", as defined by Ravn, Schmitt-Grohe, and Uribe (2006). For international
finance models that feature deep habits, see Ravn, Schmitt-Grohe, and Uribe (2007); Heyerdahl-Larsen (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1097e292a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1097e299" publication-type="other">
This result provides a theoretical justification for the findings of Menkhoff, Sarno, Schmeling, and Schrimpf
(2012), who argue that conditional exchange rate volatility is a risk factor with pricing power for the cross-
section of currency returns. In our model, conditional exchange rate volatility should be priced in all asset classes
because it proxies for global conditional risk aversion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1097e315a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1097e322" publication-type="other">
There is one exception to the return volatility pattern: when risk aversion is very high in either country, further
increases in conditional risk aversion decrease the return volatility of both endowment claims, as valuation
changes become smoother. This is because when conditional risk aversion becomes very large in either country,
the P/D ratio of both claims approaches so the volatility of valuation changes shuts down. In that region,
increases in conditional risk aversion also induce reductions in risk premiums, for the same reason.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1097e341a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1097e348" publication-type="other">
The kurtosis of the risk aversion ratio is 5.58 on average, suggesting that the likelihood of states characterized
by large cross-country dispersion in conditional risk aversion, albeit small, is non-trivial. The average skewness
of the risk aversion ratio is 0.47, but it varies a lot across simulation paths; its 95% confidence interval is
[-1.49,2.63].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1097e365a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1097e372" publication-type="other">
To evaluate statistical significance, I use the bootstrap distribution, which typically implies wider confidence
intervals than intervals calculated using the bootstrap standard errors when the sample size is small.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1097e382a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1097e389" publication-type="other">
We also consider twelve-quarter changes, which are not reported in the interests of space as the results are
qualitatively very similar to those for eight-quarter changes: all statistically significant coefficients (nine out of
fifteen) have the model-implied sign.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1097e411a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e415" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. B. 1990. Asset prices under habit formation and catching up with the Joneses. American Economic
Review 80:38^42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e425a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e429" publication-type="other">
Aydemir, C. A. 2008. Risk sharing and counter-cyclical variation in market correlations. Journal of Economic
Dynamics and Control 32:3084-112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e439a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e443" publication-type="other">
Backus, D. K., and G W. Smith. 1993. Consumption and real exchange rates in dynamic exchange economies
with non-traded goods. Journal of International Economics 35:297-316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e453a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e457" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and I. K. Shaliastovich. 2013. A long-run risks explanation of predictability puzzles in bond and
currency markets. Review of Financial Studies 26:1-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e468a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e472" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and A. Yaron. 2004. Risks for the long run: A potential resolution of asset pricing puzzles. Journal
of Finance 59:1481-509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e482a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e486" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J. 2006. Rare disasters and asset markets in the twentieth century. Quarterly Journal of Economics
121:823-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e496a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e500" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G 1996. The time variation of risk and return in foreign exchange markets: A general equilibrium
perspective. Review of Financial Studies 9:427-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e510a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e514" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, E. Engstrom, and S. R. Grenadier. 2010. Stock and bond returns with moody investors. Journal of
Empirical Finance 17:867-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e524a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e528" publication-type="other">
Boldrin, M., L. J. Christiano, and J. D. M. Fisher. 2001. Habit persistence, asset returns and the business cycle.
American Economic Review 91:149-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e538a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e542" publication-type="other">
Brandt, M. W., J. H. Cochrane, and R Santa-Clara. 2006. International risk sharing is better than you think, or
exchange rates are too smooth. Journal of Monetary Economics 53:671-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e553a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e557" publication-type="other">
Buraschi A., and A. Jiltsov. 2007. Habit formation and macroeconomic models of the term structure of interest
rates. Journal of Finance 62:3009-63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e567a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e571" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y., and J. H. Cochrane. 1999. By force of habit: A consumption-based explanation of aggregate
stock market behavior. Journal of Political Economy 107:205-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e581a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e585" publication-type="other">
Chan, Y. L., and L. Kogan. 2002. Catching up with the Joneses: Heterogeneous preferences and the dynamics of
asset prices. Journal of Political Economy 110:1255-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e595a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e599" publication-type="other">
Colacito R., and M. M. Croce. 2011. Risks for the long run and the real exchange rate. Journal of Political
Economy 119:153-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e609a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e613" publication-type="other">
. 2013. International asset pricing with recursive preferences. Journal of Finance 68:2651-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e620a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e624" publication-type="other">
Cole H. L., and M. Obstfeld. 1991. Commodity trade and international risk sharing: How much do financial
markets matter? Journal of Monetary Economics 28:3-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e635a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e639" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, G M.. 1990. Habit formation: A resolution of the equity premium puzzle. Journal of Political
Economy 98:519^13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e649a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e653" publication-type="other">
Detemple, J. B., and F. Zapatero. 1991. Asset prices in an exchange economy with habit formation. Econometrica
59:1633-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e663a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e667" publication-type="other">
Engle, R. F. 2002. Dynamic conditional correlation: A simple class of multivariate generalized autoregressive
conditional heteroskedasticity models. Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 20:339-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e677a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e681" publication-type="other">
Epstein, L. G, and S. E. Zin. 1989. Substitution, risk aversion and the temporal behavior of consumption and
asset returns: A theoretical framework. Econometrica 57:937-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e691a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e695" publication-type="other">
Farhi, E., and X. Gabaix. 2016. Rare disasters and exchange rates. Quarterly Journal of Economics 131:1-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e702a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e706" publication-type="other">
Ferson, W. E., and G M. Constantinides. 1991. Habit persistence and durability in aggregate consumption:
Empirical tests. Journal of Financial Economics 29:199-240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e717a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e721" publication-type="other">
Hassan, T. A. 2013. Country size, currency unions and international asset returns. Journal of Finance
68:2269-308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e731a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e735" publication-type="other">
Heaton, J. 1995. An empirical investigation of asset pricing with temporally dependent preference specifications,
Econometrica 63:681-717.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e745a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e749" publication-type="other">
Heyerdahl-Larsen, C. 2014. Asset prices and real exchange rates with deep habits. Review of Financial Studies
27:3280-317.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e759a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e763" publication-type="other">
Jeimann, U. J. 1998. Asset pricing in production economies. Journal of Monetary Economics 41:257-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e770a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e774" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. E. Jr. 1982. Interest rates and currency prices in a two-country world. Journal of Monetary Economics
10:335-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e784a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e788" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H., and A. Verdelhan. 2007. The cross-section of foreign currency risk premia and consumption growth
risk. American Economic Review 97:89-117.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e799a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e803" publication-type="other">
Martin, I. 2011. The forward premium puzzle in a two-country world. Working Paper No. 17564, NBER.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e810a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e814" publication-type="other">
Menkhoff,L.,L. Sarno,M. Schmeling,andA. Schrimpf. 2012. Carry trades and global foreign exchange volatility.
Journal of Finance 67:681-718.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e824a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e828" publication-type="other">
Menzly, L., T. Santos, and P. Veronesi. 2004. Understanding predictability. Journal of Political Economy
112:1-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e838a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e842" publication-type="other">
Moore, M. J., and M. J. Roche. 2010, Solving exchange rate puzzles with neither sticky prices nor trade costs.
Journal of International Money and Finance 29:1151-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e852a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e856" publication-type="other">
Obstfeld, M., and K. Rogoff. 2000. The six major puzzles in international macroeconomics: Is there a common
cause? Working Paper No. 7777, NBER.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e866a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e870" publication-type="other">
Pavlova, A., and R. Rigobon. 2007. Asset prices and exchange rates. Review of Financial Studies 20:1139-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e878a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e882" publication-type="other">
Ravn, M. O., S. Schmitt-Grohe, and M. Uribe. 2006. Deep habits. Review of Economic Studies 73:195-218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e889a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e893" publication-type="other">
. 2007. Pricing to habits and the law of one price. American Economic Review 97:232-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e900a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e904" publication-type="other">
Rietz, T. A. 1988. The equity risk premium: A solution. Journal of Monetary Economics 22:117-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e911a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e915" publication-type="other">
Santos, T., and P. Veronesi. 2010. Habit formation, the cross section of stock returns and the cash-flow risk puzzle.
Journal of Financial Economics 98:385-413.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e925a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e929" publication-type="other">
Serrât, A. 2001. A dynamic equilibrium model of international portfolio holdings. Econometrica 69:1467-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e936a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e940" publication-type="other">
Shore, S. H., and J. S. White. 2006. External habit formation and the home bias puzzle, Working Paper, Johns
Hopkins University and University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e951a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e955" publication-type="other">
Sundaresan, S. 1989. Intertemporally dependent preferences and the volatility of consumption and wealth. Review
of Financial Studies 2:73-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e965a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e969" publication-type="other">
Verdelhan, A. 2010. A habit-based explanation of the exchange rate risk premium. Journal of Finance 65:123-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e976a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e980" publication-type="other">
Wächter, J. A. 2006. A consumption-based model of the term structure of interest rates. Journal of Financial
Economics 79:365-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1097e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1097e994" publication-type="other">
Zapatero, F. 1995. Equilibrium asset prices and exchange rates. Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control
19:787-811.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
