<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272339</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Study of Controlled Auto-Ignition in Small Natural Gas Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Koga</surname>
                  <given-names>Hibiki</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kiura</surname>
                  <given-names>Toshiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Honda R&amp;D Co., Ltd.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>2133</fpage>
         <lpage>2139</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright @2013 SAE Japan and Copyright @ 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272339"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Research has been conducted on Controlled Auto-Ignition (CAI) engine with natural gas. CAI engine has the potential to be highly efficient and to produce low emissions. CAI engine is potentially applicable to automobile engine. However due to narrow operating range, CAI engine for automobile engine which require various speed and load in real world operation is still remaining at research level. In comparison some natural gas engines for electricity generation only require continuous operation at constant load. There is possibility of efficiency enhancement by CAI combustion which is running same speed at constant load.</p>
            <p>Since natural gas is primary consisting of methane (CH4), high auto-ignition temperature is required to occur stable auto-ignition. Usually additional intake heat required to keep stable auto-ignition. To keep high compression temperature, single cylinder natural gas engine with high compression ratio (CR=26) was constructed.</p>
            <p>Since high compression ratio (CR=26), CAI engine with natural gas would improve thermal efficiency due to higher theoretical thermal efficiency. However, indicated thermal efficiency of CAI engine does not improved as expected due to increasing heat loss from cylinder wall. To increase indicated thermal efficiency, combustion chamber shape modification is also required.</p>
            <p>To analyze combustion chamber shape effect, comparison between standard engine with same stroke and bore (S/B=1.0) and modified engine with same displacement, longer stroke and smaller bore (S/B=2.1) was conducted. Brake thermal efficiency of longer stroke engine (S/B=2.1) was 39.1% while keeping low NOx level, which was an increase of 9.2 points over the 29.9% for the conventional engine (S/B=1.0). Heat release analysis shows major factor of enhanced efficiency is reduced heat loss from cylinder wall and exhausted unburned fuel.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koga, H., and Watanabe, S., “Research on Extended Expansion General-Purpose Engine - Heat Release and Friction -,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-32-0003, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-32-0003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kono, S., Koga, H., and Watanabe, S., “Research on Extended Expansion General-Purpose Engine-Efficiency Enhancement by Natural Gas Operation-,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-32-0007, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-32-0007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takita, Y., Kono, S., and Naoi, A., “Study of Methods to Enhance Energy Utilization Efficiency of Micro Combined Heat and Power Generation Unit Equipped with an Extended Expansion Linkage Engine and Reduction of Waste Energy,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-32-0574, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-32-0574.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ohnishi, S., et al, “Active Thermo-atmosphere Combustion (ATAC) A New Combustion Process for Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 790501,1979, doi:10.4271/790501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishibashi, Y. and Asai, M., “Improving the Exhaust Emissions of Two- Stroke Engines by Applying the Activated Radical Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 960742, 1996, doi:10.4271/960742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coward, H.F. and Jones, G.W., “Limits of Flammability of Gases and Vapors”, Bulletin 503, U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Mines, 1952.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fiveland, S., Agama, R., Christensen, M., Johansson, B. et al., “Experimental and Simulated Results Detailing the Sensitivity of Natural Gas HCCI Engines to Fuel Composition,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3609, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3609.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tominaga, R., Morimoto, S., Kawabata, Y., Matsuo, S. et al., “Effects of Heterogeneous EGR on the Natural Gas Fueled HCCI Engine Using Experiments, CFD and Detailed Kinetics,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0945, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0945.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yap, D., Megaritis, A., Wyszynski, M., and Xu, H., “Residual Gas Trapping for Natural Gas HCCI,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1973, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jun, D. and Iida, N., “A Study of High Combustion Efficiency and Low CO Emission in a Natural Gas HCCI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1974, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1974.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tamura, M., and Hagi, S., “An Investigation of A Natural-Gas-Fueled Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine for High- Performance Co-Generation Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-32-0005, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-32-0005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawasaki, K., Takegoshi, A., Yamane, K., Ohtsubo, H. et al., “Combustion Improvement and Control for a Natural Gas HCCI Engine by the Internal EGR by Means of Intake-valve Pilot-opening,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0208, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ohtsubo, H., Nakazono, T., Shirouzu, T., Yamane, K. et al., “Application of a Multi-Cylinder Natural Gas PCCI Engine with Spark Ignition to Generator,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0015, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, S., Hu, L., Nakazono, T., Ohtsubo, H. et al., “Oxidation Catalysts for Natural Gas Engine Operating under HCCI or SI Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):326-337, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0807.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
