<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278380</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>EGR Effects on Boosted SI Engine Operation and Knock Integral Correlation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hoepke</surname>
                  <given-names>Bjoern</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jannsen</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kasseris</surname>
                  <given-names>Emmanuel</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Wai K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>May 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278342</issue-id>
         <fpage>547</fpage>
         <lpage>559</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278380"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The effects of cooled exhaust gas recirculation (EGR) on a boosted direct-injection (DI) spark ignition (SI) engine operating at stoichiometric equivalence ratio, gross indicated mean effective pressure of 14-18 bar, and speed of 1500-2500 rpm, are studied under constant fuel condition at each operating point. In the presence of EGR, burn durations are longer and combustion is more retard. At the same combustion phasing, the indicated specific fuel consumption improves because of a decrease in heat loss and an increase in the specific heat ratio. The knock limited spark advance increases substantially with EGR. This increase is due partly to a slower combustion which is equivalent to a spark retard, as manifested by a retarded value of the 50% burn point (CA50), and due partly to a slower ignition chemistry of the diluted charge, as manifested by the knock limited spark advance to beyond the value offered by the retarded CA50. The latter part adds 0.5 ms to the spark advance per 10% increase in EGR rate. A knock correlation based on the Livengood-Wu integral method is developed to include the effect of EGR on the ignition delay. A 10% point increment of the EGR rate corresponds to approximately a 3% increase in the effective fuel octane number.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lake, T., Stokes, J., Murphy, R., Osborne, R. et al., “Turbocharging oncepts for Downsized DI Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0036, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petitjean, D., Bernardini, L., Middlemass, C., and Shahed, S., “Advanced Gasoline Engine Turbocharging Technology for Fuel conomy Improvements,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0988, 2004, oi:10.4271/2004-01-0988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grandin, B., Ångström, H., Stålhammar, P., and Olofsson, E., “Knock uppression in a Turbocharged SI Engine by Using Cooled EGR,” SAE echnical Paper 982476, 1998, doi: 10.4271/982476.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grandin, B. and Ångström, H., “Replacing Fuel Enrichment in a Turbo harged SI Engine: Lean Burn or Cooled EGR,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3505, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duchaussoy, Y., Lefebvre, A., and Bonetto, R., “Dilution Interest on urbocharged SI Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0629, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., Chauvet, T., and Dimitrova, Z., “Synergies between High GR Operation and GDI Systems,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):101-114, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T. and Mangold, B., “Dedicated EGR: A New Concept in High fficiency Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):620-631, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Potteau, S., Lutz, P., Leroux, S., Moroz, S. et al., “Cooled EGR for a urbo SI Engine to Reduce Knocking and Fuel Consumption,” SAE echnical Paper 2007-01-3978, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roth, D., Keller, P., and Becker, M., “Requirements of External EGR ystems for Dual Cam Phaser Turbo GDI Engines,” SAE Technical aper 2010-01-0588, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiser, M., Krueger, U., Harris, R., and Cruff, L., “Doing More with ess” - The Fuel Economy Benefits of Cooled EGR on a Direct Injected park Ignited Boosted Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0589, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0589.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A., Blaxill, H., and Irlam, G., “Exhaust Gas Recirculation for mproved Part and Full Load Fuel Economy in a Turbocharged Gasoline ngine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0047, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harrington, J., “Water Addition to Gasoline-Effect on Combustion, missions, Performance, and Knock,” SAE Technical Paper 820314, 1982, doi: 10.4271/820314.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livengood, J.C., Wu, P.C., “Correlation of Autoignition Phenomena in nternal Combustion Engines and Rapid Compression Machines,” 5th ymp. (International) on Combustion, pp. 347-356, Reinhold Publ. orp., 1955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Halstead, M.P., Kirsch, L. J., Prothero, A., and Quinn, C.P., “A athematical Model for Hydrocarbon Autoignition at High Pressures,” roc. R. Soc. Lond., A, 346, pp. 515-538, 1975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cox, R.A., Cole, J.A., “Chemical Aspects of the Autoigntiion of ydrocarbon-Air Mixtures,” Comb. &amp; Flame, 60, pp. 109-123, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rassweiler, G. and Withrow, L., “Motion Pictures of Engine Flames orrelated with Pressure Cards,” SAE Technical Paper 380139, 1938, oi: 10.4271/380139.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cheng, W., Hamrin, D., Heywood, J., Hochgreb, S. et al., “An Overview f Hydrocarbon Emissions Mechanisms in Spark-Ignition Engines,” AE Technical Paper 932708, 1993, doi: 10.4271/932708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Douaud, A. and Eyzat, P., “Four-Octane-Number Method for Predicting he Anti-Knock Behavior of Fuels and Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 780080, 1978, doi: 10.4271/780080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
