<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>אגוד הבנקים בישראל</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">ג'</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</issue>
         <issue-id>i24010132</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24011971</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comments and Rejoinder / תשובה להערותיו של מר חת</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>אלקנה</given-names>
                  <surname>ינון</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Yinon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1963</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>49</fpage>
         <lpage>54</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24011971"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Mr. Yinon reitrates that the dollar serves as a relatively stable common denominator for the purpose of comparing the balance sheet figures of the Bank of Israel. He points out that the local currency's purchasing power has declined greatly during the past decade, making futile a comparison in terms of Israel Pounds. He argues, that Mr. Het was at fault in his contention that a proper way to arrive at the Central Bank's contribution to the liquidity of the economy is by comparing the balance sheets of the Bank of Israel in Israel Pounds, because the Central Bank was required to deal with a monetary expansion expressed in Israel Pounds. Mr. Yinon then proceeds to compare the 1961 and 1962 balance sheets expressed in Israel Pounds, as suggested by Mr. Het, and shows that the Central Bank's assets grew by 72% in a year in which the Israel Pound was devalued. He demonstrates that a comparison of the balance sheets converted at the effective rate of exchange, viz : of IL 2.70 = $ 1.00 in 1961 and at the official rate of IL 3.— = $ 1.00 in 1962, shows a growth of 54.6% only in the assets of the Central Bank. He, accordingly, emphasizes that a comparison in terms of dollars is both more realistic and, incidentally, also fairer to the Bank of Israel. He then points out, that the Bank of Israel is indeed helpless, if it cannot fight monetary expansion by restraining the growth in its assets. He stresses that experience in Israel has shown how ineffective monetary measures have so far been. It is pointed out that this was, inter alia, because of the existing arrangements with the Government, whereby the Bank of Israel has agreed to purchase foreign currency offered it, without limitation, (with new money printed by it). Discussing the very high interest rate levels in Israel, Mr. Yinon states that there is no conflict between a state of a high liquidity and a low interest rate. He rejects the Central Bank's claim that a highly liquid economy, always calls for an increase in the interest rate, and contends that the high interest rates now prevailing in Israel have not reduced the demand for credit. He asks whether the public sector's demand for credit should not be curbed, instead of placing unrelenting pressure on the private sector? He blames the Bank of Israel for recommending to the Government payment of a high rate of interest (approximately 9% free of income tax) on the Government short term loan (similar to Treasury Bills), which has pushed up considerably all interest rates in the money market.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>[הערות שוליים]</title>
        <ref id="d15e119a1310">
            <label>*</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e126" publication-type="other">
) אם נחשב את נכסי בנק ישראל לסוף 1961 (להוציא חשבונות מקבילים), לפי 2.50 ל"י
לדולר, שהיה השער האפקטיבי ביצוא לפני הפחות, יתברר כי נכסי בנק ישראל במטבע יציב גדלו
בשנת 1962 לעומת שנת 1961 ב-168.9 מיליון דולר («-391.5 מיליון דולר ב"1961 ל-560.4 מיליון
דולר ב-1962), כלומר, גידול בשיעור של 43.1 אחוזים, אף גידול זה הוא עצום בשנה של פיחות המטבע.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


