<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2/3</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000402</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40007735</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Lexical Choice for Complex Noun Phrases: Structure, Modifiers, and Determiners</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <surname>Elhadad</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1996</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>159</fpage>
         <lpage>184</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1996 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40007735"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper presents a lexical choice component for complex noun phrases. We first explain why lexical choice for NPs deserves special attention within the standard pipeline architecture for a generator. The task of the lexical chooser for NPs is more complex than for clauses because the syntax of NPs is less understood than for clauses, and therefore, syntactic realization components, while they accept a predicate-argument structure as input for clauses, require a purely syntactic tree as input for NPs. The task of mapping conceptual relations to different syntactic modifiers is therefore left to the lexical chooser for NPs. The paper focuses on the syntagmatic aspect of lexical choice, identifying a process called "NP planning". It focuses on a set of communicative goals that NPs can satisfy and specifies an interface between the different components of the generator and the lexical chooser. The technique presented for NP planning encapsulates a rich lexical knowledge and allows for the generation of a wide variety of syntactic constructions. It also allows for a large paraphrasing power because it dynamically maps conceptual information to various syntactic slots.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d3000064e159a1310">
               <label>5</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e166" publication-type="other">
"marginal data from the exceptional dative verbs and from the relatively small
class of spray/load verbs" [29] p. 657.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d3000064e185a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e189" publication-type="other">
J. Anscombre and O. Ducrot: 1993, L'argumentation dans la langue. Pierre Mardaga, Bruxelles.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e196a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e200" publication-type="other">
D. Appelt:1985, Planning Natural Language Utterances. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e207a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e211" publication-type="other">
J. Barwise and R. Cooper: 1981, Generalized Quantifiers in English, Linguistics and Philosophy
4, 159-219.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e221a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e225" publication-type="other">
R. Block and H. Horacek: 1990, Generating Referring Expressions Using Multiple Knowledge
Sources, in Proceedings of COLING 90, Vol 2, pp. 24-29, Helsinki.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e236a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e240" publication-type="other">
D. Bruxelles, S. Carcagno and C. Fournier: 1988, Vers une construction automatique des topoi
à partir du lexique, CC AI-Journal for the Integrated Study of Artificial Intelligence Cognitive
Science and Applied Epistemology 6(4), 309-328.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e253a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e257" publication-type="other">
S. Bruxelles and P. Raccah: 1991, Argumentation et Semantique: leparti-pris du lexique.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e264a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e268" publication-type="other">
J. Coch and R. David: 1994, Une application de génération de textes, in Actes de TALN-94, pp.
37-45, Marseille, France.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e278a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e282" publication-type="other">
R. Dale: 1988, Generating Referring Expressions in a Domain of Objects and Processes. PhD
thesis, University of Edinburgh.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e292a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e296" publication-type="other">
R. Dale and E. Reiter: 1995, Computational Interpretations of the Gricean Maxims in the Gen-
eration of Referring Expressions, Cognitive Science 19, 233-263.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e306a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e310" publication-type="other">
L. Danlos: 1986, The Linguistic Basis of Text Generation. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e318a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e322" publication-type="other">
K. Donnellan: 1966, Reference and Definite Description, Philosophical Review 75, 281-304.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e329a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e333" publication-type="other">
O. Ducrot and T. Todorov: 1979, Encyclopedic Dictionary of the Sciences of Language. The John
Hopkins Universty Press. Translated from French by Catherine Porter.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e343a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e347" publication-type="other">
M. Elhadad: 1990, Types in Functional Unification Grammars, in Proceedings of the 28th Annual
Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Pittsburgh, PA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e357a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e361" publication-type="other">
M. Elhadad: 1992, Using Argumentation to Control Lexical Choice: A Unification-Based Imple-
mentation. PhD thesis, Computer Science Department, Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e371a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e375" publication-type="other">
M. Elhadad: 1 995, Using Argumentation in Text Generation, Journal of Pragmatics 24, 189-220.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e382a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e386" publication-type="other">
M. Elhadad, K. McKeown, and J. Robin: To appear, Floatings Constraints in Lexical Choice,
Computational Linguistics.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e397a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e401" publication-type="other">
M. Elhadad and J. Robin: 1996, An Overview of Surge: A Reusable Comprehensive Syntactic
Realization Component. Technical Report 96-03, Department of Computer Science, Ben Gurion
University, Beer Sheva, Israel (April).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e414a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e418" publication-type="other">
P. Fries: 1970, Tagmeme Sequences in the English Noun Phrase. Summer Institute of Linguistics
Publications in Linguistics and Related Fields, Number 36. Benjamin F. Elson for The Church
Press Inc., Glendale, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e431a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e435" publication-type="other">
P.-J. Gailly : 1988, Expressing Quantifier Scope in French Generation, in Proceedings of COLING
88, Budapest</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e445a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e449" publication-type="other">
M. Halliday: 1985, An Introduction to Functional Grammar. Edward Arnold, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e456a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e460" publication-type="other">
E. Hovy: 1988, Generating Natural Language under Pragmatic Constraints. L. Erlbaum Asso-
ciates, Hillsdale, N.J.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e470a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e474" publication-type="other">
M. Kay: 1979, Functional Grammar, in Proceedings of the 5th Annual Meeting of the Berkeley
Linguistic Society.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e485a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e489" publication-type="other">
E. Keenan and Y. Stavi: 1986, A Semantic Characterization of Natural Language Determiners,
Linguistics and Philosophy 9, 253-326.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e499a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e503" publication-type="other">
A. Kronfeld: 1981, The Referential-Attributive Distinction and the Conceptual-Descriptive
Theory of Reference. PhD thesis, University of California, Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e513a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e517" publication-type="other">
K. Kukich: 1983, Knowledge-Based Report Generation: A Knowledge Engineering Approach to
Natural Language Report Generation. PhD thesis, University of Pittsburgh.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e527a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e531" publication-type="other">
K. Kukich, K. McKeown, J. Shaw, J. Robin, N. Morgan, and J. Phillips: 1994, User-Needs
Analysis and Design Methodology for an Automated Document Generator, in A. Zampolli,
N. Calzolari, and M. Palmer (eds), Current Issues in Computational Linguistics: In Honor of
Don Walker. Kluwer Academic, Boston.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e547a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e551" publication-type="other">
J. Lester: 1 994, Generating Natural Language Explanations from Large-Scale Knowledge Bases.
PhD thesis, Computer Science Department, Universtity of Texas at Austin.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e561a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e565" publication-type="other">
J. N. Levi: 1978, The Syntax and Seniantics of Complex Nominals. Academic Press, New York.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e573a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e577" publication-type="other">
B. Levin and M. Rappaport: 1986, The Formation of Adjectival Passives, Linguistic Inquiry 17,
623-661.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e587a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e591" publication-type="other">
D. McDonald: 1980, Natural Language Generation as a Process of Decision-Making under
Constraints. PhD thesis, MIT.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e601a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e605" publication-type="other">
K. McKeown: 1985, Using Discourse Strategies and Focus Constraints to Generate Natural
Language Text. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e615a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e619" publication-type="other">
M. Meteer: 1990, The Generation Gap: The Problem of Expressibility in Text Planning. PhD
thesis, University of Massachussets at Ahmerst.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e629a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e633" publication-type="other">
R. Passoneau, K. Kukich, J. Robin, and L. Lefkowitz: 1996, Generating Executive Summaries
of Workflow Diagrams.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e643a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e647" publication-type="other">
R. Quirk, S. Greenbaum, G. Leech, and J. Svartvik: 1985, A Comprehensive Grammar of the
English Language. Longman, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e658a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e662" publication-type="other">
E. Reiter: 1990, Generating Appropriate Natural Language Object Description. PhD thesis,
Center for Research in Computing Technology, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e672a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e676" publication-type="other">
E. Reiter: 1994, Has a Consensus Natural Language Generation Architecture Appeared and is
it Psycholinguistically Plausible?, in Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Natural
Language Generation, pp. 163-170.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e689a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e693" publication-type="other">
E. Reiter: 1995, NLG vs Templates, in Proceedings of the 5th European Workshop on Natural-
Language Generation (ENLGW-95), Leiden, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e703a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e707" publication-type="other">
E. Reiter and R. Dale: 1992, A Fast Algorithm for the Generation of Referring Expressions, in
Proceedings of the 14th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING-92),
pp. 232-238, Nantes, France.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e720a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e724" publication-type="other">
E. Rosch: 1978, Principles of Categorization, in E. Rosch and B. Lloyd (eds), Cognition and
Categorization, pp. 27-48. Lawrence Erlbaum, Hillsdale, NJ.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e734a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e738" publication-type="other">
J. Searle: 1979, Referential and Attributive, in Expression and Meaning: Studies in the Theory
of Speech-Acts. Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e749a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e753" publication-type="other">
Z. Vendler: 1968, Adjectives and Nominalizations. Mouton, The Hague.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000064e760a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000064e764" publication-type="other">
E. Williams: 1980, Predication, Linguistic Inquiry, 11, 203-238.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
