<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465645</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465653</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Financial Market Dislocations</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Paolo</given-names>
                  <surname>Pasquariello</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1868</fpage>
         <lpage>1914</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465653"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Dislocations occur when financial markets, operating under stressful conditions, experience large, widespread asset mispricings. This study documents systematic dislocations in world capital markets and the importance of their fluctuations for expected asset returns. Our novel, model-free measure of these dislocations is a monthly average of hundreds of individual abnormal absolute violations of three textbook arbitrage parities in stock, foreign exchange, and money markets. We find that investors demand statistically and economically significant risk premiums to hold financial assets performing poorly during market dislocations, that is, when both frictions to the trading activity of speculators and arbitrageurs and their marginal utility of wealth are likely to be high.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d50e263a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e270" publication-type="other">
For instance, Kashyap, Berner, and Goodhart (2011) argue that a satisfactory "macroprudential toolkit" should
include instruments to assess and prevent the occurrence of price dislocations in financial markets because they are
likely to magnify the effects of a financial crisis on economic performance. Accordingly, new macroprudential
authorities, such as the Financial Stability Board (FSB), the European Systemic Risk Board (ESRB), or the
Financial Policy Committee (FPC), have been charged with the responsibility of identifying dislocations in
financial markets and mitigating the risk of widespread financial distress (e.g., Agresti, Borgioli, and Poloni
2011; ESRB 2012; Brinkhoff et al. 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e296a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e303" publication-type="other">
A comprehensive survey of this vast body of literature is beyond the scope of this paper. Recent studies find
violations of the triangular arbitrage parity (Lyons and Moore 2009; Kozhan and Tham 2012), covered interest
rate parity (Akram, Rime, and Sarno 2008; Coffey et al. 2009; Griffoli and Ranaldo 2011), cross-listed stock
pairs parity (Pasquariello 2008; Gagnon and Karolyi 2010), Siamese twins parity (Mitchell, Pulvino, and Stafford
2002), closed-end fund parity (Pontiff 1996), exchange-traded fund parity (Chacko, Das, and Fan 2012), TIPS-
Treasury arbitrage parity (Campbell, Shiller, and Viceira 2009; Fleckenstein, Longstaff, and Lustig 2013), off-the-
run Treasury bond-note parity (Musto, Nini, and Schwarz 2011), CDS-bond yield parity (Duffie 2010; Garleanu
and Pedersen 2011), convertible bond parity (Mitchell and Pulvino 2010), futures-cash parity (Roll, Schwartz,
and Subrahmanyam 2007), and put-call parity (Lamont and Thaler 2003a; Ofek, Richardson, and Whitelaw
2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e338a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e345" publication-type="other">
Arbitrage activity may be impeded by such financial frictions as transaction costs, taxes, (inventory) holding
costs, exchange controls, illiquidity, short-sale and other investment restrictions (surveyed in Gagnon and
Karolyi [2010]), information problems (Grossman and Miller 1988), agency problems (De Long et al. 1990;
Shleifer and Vishny 1997), idiosyncratic risk (Pontiff 2006), (counterparty) default risk (e.g., Adler and Dumas
1976), execution risk (Stein 2009; Kozhan and Tham 2012), noise trader risk (e.g., Shleifer 2000), opportunity
cost of capital (Pontiff 1996) supply factors (Fleckenstein, Longstaff, and Lustig 2013), fire sales and market
freezes (Kashyap, Berner, and Goodhart 2011; Shleifer and Vishny 2011; Acharya, Shin, and Yorulmazer 2013),
competition (Kondor 2009), margin constraints (Garleanu and Pedersen 2011), and funding liquidity constraints
and slow-moving capital (e.g., Brunnermeier and Pedersen 2009; Duffie 2010; Gromb and Vayanos 2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e377a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e384" publication-type="other">
For example, Amihud and Mendelson (1986), Constantinides (1986), Brennan and Subrahmanyam (1996),
Brennan et al. (1998), Vayanos (1998), Shleifer (2000), Amihud (2002), Huang (2003), Pastor and Stambaugh
(2003), Acharya and Pedersen (2005), Duffie, Garleanu, and Pedersen (2005, 2007), Baker and Wurgler (2006),
Sadka and Scherbina (2007), Brunnermeier and Pedersen (2009), Avramov et al. (2010), Stambaugh, Yu, and
Yuan (2011), Hu, Pan, and Wang (2013), and Alti and Tetlock (2013), among others. See also the survey in
Harvey, Liu, and Zhu (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e408a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e415" publication-type="other">
For instance, Griffoli and Ranaldo (2011 ) report evidence of sizable actual CIRP profits (i.e., at actionable quotes
and net of execution costs) during the 2008 financial crisis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e425a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e434" publication-type="other">
LIBOR rates are computed by the British Bankers Association (BBA) as arithmetic averages of contributor
banks' interbank offers at around 11 a.m. GMT. For simplicity and uniformity across exchange rates (e.g., when
considering national holidays, weekends, special circumstances for fixing and value dates, as well as evolving
day-count conventions [and their different, possibly conflicting interpretations] over the sample period; see, e.g.,
Miron and Swannell 1991; Deng et al. 2012), interest rates are compounded using a 30/360 convention. The
effect of employing "market" day-count conventions (when feasible) on our analysis is immaterial.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e457a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e464" publication-type="other">
Exchange and money market rates for EUR/USD, GBP/EUR, CHF/EUR, and JPY/EUR are available in
Datastream since the introduction of the euro in 1999; prior forward and LIBOR data for such European currencies
as DEM, FRF, or ITL is not.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e477a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e484" publication-type="other">
We filter this dataset for potential data errors and exclude daily CIRP deviations of 10% or more,that is, when
CIRPij &gt;1,000 bps. The evidence that follows is unaffected by our filtering procedure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e494a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e501" publication-type="other">
Investigations by media and regulators suggest that some of the LIBOR contributor banks may have under-
reported their offer rates to the BBA during the recent financial crisis (e.g., see the coverage of the LIBOR
probe on the Wall Street Journal Web site, at http://stream.wsj.com/story/the-libor-investigation/SS-2-32262/).
This is unlikely to meaningfully affect our analysis. Griffoli and Ranaldo (2011) compute similarly large CIRP
violations in 2008 and 2009 to those in Figure la when using alternative (secured and unsecured) interest rates
(in the repo and overnight index swap [OIS] markets, respectively). Furthermore, all of our ensuing inference is
insensitive to removing 2008 and 2009 from the sample (see Section 1.3).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e527a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e536" publication-type="other">
We filter this dataset for errors (and unreasonably large TAP deviations) using the same procedure employed for
CIRP deviations in Section 2.1.1. We also verify that observed TAP violations in our dataset are not due to rounding
of prices from Equation (2) and/or from direct-to-indirect quote conversion (i.e., from StA/B = (St,B/A) *)•
We accommodate any deviation from the latter in the dataset by considering TAP violations of either S* AjB or
S* b/a separately-</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e556a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e563" publication-type="other">
We note here that DEM, FRF, and ITL exit our database only on the first trading day of the euro (January 4,1999),
leaving 60 TAP permutations in T A Pm. Removing cross-rates relative to FRL and ITL from the full sample has
little impact on T A Pm. Kozhan and Tham (2012) report TAP violations (net of bid-ask spreads) of comparable
magnitude from 2003-2004 using tick-by-tick data from the Reuters Dealing 3000 trading system.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e579a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e586" publication-type="other">
A minority of companies, mostly Canadian, cross-list their stock in the U.S. in the form of ordinary shares.
"Canadian" ordinaries are identical certificates trading in both the U.S. and a foreign market (i.e., with a bundling
ratio of one; see Bekaert and Hodrick 2009); "global registered shares" (GRSs) are ordinaries trading in multiple
foreign markets. In the U.S., ordinaries trade like U.S. firms' stock, require no depositary bank, but are subject to
specific clearing and transfer arrangements. The literature typically groups ordinaries together with ADRs (e.g.,
Gagnon and Karolyi 2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e609a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e616" publication-type="other">
Consistently, Gagnon and Karolyi (2010, 79) observe that "the mechanics of arbitrage in the market for cross-
listed stocks is complex and the institutional features of this marketplace make it difficult to judge the actual
profitability of such trading strategies."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e629a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e636" publication-type="other">
The number of cross-listings from emerging markets prior to their financial liberalizations is small in our sample.
Accordingly, excluding from the analysis cross-listings from those countries over the portion of the sample when
these restrictions were in place has virtually no effect on our inference. In addition, as we explain in Section 1.2,
our index of financial market dislocations is based on differences between observed arbitrage parity violations
and their historical means, as the latter may capture the persistent effect of those direct barriers to arbitrage.
We examine the relation between financial market dislocations and explicit measures of time-varying capital
controls in Section 1.3 (footnote 25).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e662a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e669" publication-type="other">
For instance, Gagnon and Karolyi (2010) address nonsynchronicity between foreign stock and ADR prices by
employing available intraday price and quote data for the latter (from TAQ) at a time corresponding to the closing
time of the equity market for the underlying (if their trading hours are at least partially overlapping). However,
the trading hours of Asian markets do not overlap with U.S. trading hours. In addition, TAQ data is available
only from January 1, 1993.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e688a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e695" publication-type="other">
We cross-check the accuracy of Datastream pairings by comparing them with those reported in the Bank of New
York Mellon Depositary Receipts Directory (available at www.adrbnymellon.com/dr_directory.jsp).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e706a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e713" publication-type="other">
Sponsored ADRs are initiated by the foreign company of the underlying shares; unsponsored ADRs are initiated
by a depositary bank. Most developed cross-listings in our sample are from Canada (67), the Euro area (58),
the United Kingdom (43), Australia (30), and Japan (24); emerging cross-listings include stocks traded in Hong
Kong (54, a third of which are H-shares of firms incorporated in mainland China), Brazil (23), South Africa (14),
and India (10), among others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e732a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e739" publication-type="other">
As for CIRP and TAP violations in Sections 1.1.1 and 1.1.2, we filter this dataset for errors and unreasonably large
ADRP deviations. We also exclude deviations in correspondence with ADR prices below $5 or above $1,000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e749a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e756" publication-type="other">
Summary statistics for ADRPmaie similar to (albeit slightly smaller than) those reported in Gagnon and Karolyi
(2010, their Table 2) for signed log-price differences based on synchronous prices when possible.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e766a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e773" publication-type="other">
Consistently, Pasquariello (2008) finds evidence of greater ADRP violations for stocks of emerging markets during
the financial crises of the 1990s and early 2000s (Mexico, East Asia, Russia, Brazil, Turkey, and Argentina).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e783a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e790" publication-type="other">
To that end, on any day t, we exclude parity deviations with less than twenty-two past and current realizations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e797a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e804" publication-type="other">
For instance, several recent studies use equal-weighted cross-sectional averages of stock-level liquidity measures
(i.e., potentially affected by idiosyncratic shocks) to produce a more precise assessment of commonality in
liquidity (Amihud 2002; Pastor and Stambaugh 2003; Acharya and Pedersen 2005). Monthly averaging smooths
potentially spurious daily variability in these normalized arbitrage parity violations (e.g., due to price staleness
or nonsynchronicity), but at the potential cost of aggregating away shorter-lived abnormal mispricings (i.e., of
underestimating dislocation risk). According to Figures Id to If, CIRP^, TAP^, and ADRP£ are statistically
significant, at the 10% level, in 47% (and also positive in 11%), 46% (41%), and 72% (8%) of all available months
over the sample period 1973-2009, respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e834a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e841" publication-type="other">
Overall, as shown in Figure 2, M DIm is statistically significant, at the 10% level, in 62% (and also positive in
19%) of the 444 months in the sample period 1973-2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e851a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e858" publication-type="other">
Unreported analysis indicates that most of these variables (listed next) are persistent, or highly autocorrelated,
time series over our sample period. Regressions in changes help mitigate biases caused by the presence of such
regressors (see, e.g., Jansson and Moreira 2006 and references therein). Regressing MDIm on either raw or
similarly normalized levels of these variables yields similar inference.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e874a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e881" publication-type="other">
The above inference is unaffected by the further inclusion of the difference between the VIX index and realized
S&amp;P 500 return volatility (a proxy for time-varying variance risk premiums in the U.S. stock market; Bollerslev
et al. 2009) or the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis' financial stress index (capturing the comovement of 18
financial variables such as stock and bond returns and return volatility, various yield spreads, and TIPS breakeven
inflation rates) in the regressions of Table 2. In unreported analysis, we also find M DIm to be only weakly related
to the measure of U.S. investor sentiment introduced by Baker and Wurgler (2006, 2007; e.g., a slope coefficient
of -0.014 [r = — 1.42] over 1973-2009) and to either cross-country averages of the unsmoothed or price-smoothed
proxy for the intensity of capital controls in emerging markets proposed by Edison and Warnock (2003; e.g., slope
coefficients of 0.027 [?=0.04] and —0.066 [t = —0.09], respectively, over the available sample period 1989-2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e913a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e920" publication-type="other">
Unreported analysis yields similar inference from studying either a larger (100) or a smaller (10) number of
portfolios sorted on size and book-to-market. Lewellen, Nagel, and Shanken (2010) argue that the strong factor
structure of size and book-to-market portfolios makes asset pricing tests based on the cross-section of their returns
potentially misleading, and suggest (among others) constructing portfolios of stocks sorted by their loadings on
the proposed factor. We do so in Section 2.1.3.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e939a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e946" publication-type="other">
World and developed country portfolio returns are available from January 1973, with the exception of Finland
(January 1982), Greece, Ireland, New Zealand, and Portugal (January 1988). Emerging country returns are
available from January 1988, with the exception of China, Colombia, India, Israel, Pakistan, Peru, Poland, South
Africa, and Sri Lanka (January 1993) and Czech Republic, Egypt, Hungary, Morocco, and Russia (January 1995).
Hence, these countries are excluded from the OLS estimation of Equations (4) and (5) over earlier subperiods.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e965a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e972" publication-type="other">
For instance, the estimates of MDI betas in Tables 3 and 4 imply that monthly excess returns of U.S. and
international stock portfolios decline on average by 0.62% and 1.61%, respectively, from a one-standard-deviation
shock to MDIm (in Panel B of Table 1). Estimating Equation (4) using country-level returns in local currency
yields similar inference. We examine the relationship between financial market dislocations and currency returns
in Section 2.2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e992a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1001" publication-type="other">
Annualized risk premium estimates are computed multiplying monthly estimates by 12. Their t-statistics are
obtained by applying the errors-in-variables correction described in Shanken's (1992) to the corresponding
conventional standard errors. Because of M Dim's relatively large variance (see, e.g., Panel B of Table 1), this
correction has virtually no effect on the inference. The joint GMM estimation of ßi^MDI ^ kjDl m Section
2.1.2 (and Tables Al and A2 and footnote 39) yields heteroscedasticity-robust inference as well (e.g., Cochrane
2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1024a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1031" publication-type="other">
For instance, the corresponding cross-sectional relative to the U.S. and world market alone (or the U.S. and
global market, size, and value factors) are 23% and 15% (or 75% and 21 %), respectively. We consider multivariate
MDI beta estimation and pricing in Section 2.1.2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1044a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1051" publication-type="other">
Those uneven subperiods are chosen to correspond to the even subperiods (1978-1993, 1994-2009) stemming
from the analysis of the cross-section of U.S. stock returns in Section 2.2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1061a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1068" publication-type="other">
Specifically, returns on the three (four) global Fama-French portfolios, formed by sorting stocks of twenty-three
developed countries, are jointly available exclusively from July (November) 1990 and onward.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1078a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1085" publication-type="other">
For instance, Tables 1 and 7 imply that the monthly returns of both H MLm and PSm decline on average by
roughly 0.5% in correspondence with a one-standard-deviation shock to MDIm over the full sample 1973-2009.
The (untabulated) market-adjusted dislocation betas of H M Lm and PSm are discussed next.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1098a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1105" publication-type="other">
For instance, Cochrane (2001, 441) observes that a typical value firm "has a price that has been driven down
from a long string of bad news, and is now in or near financial distress. Stocks bought on the verge of bankruptcy
have come back more often than not, which generates the high average returns of this strategy. This observation
suggests a natural interpretation of the value premium: If a credit crunch, liquidity crunch, flight to quality or
similar financial event comes along, stocks in financial distress will do very badly, and this is just the sort of time
at which one particularly does not want to hear that one's stocks have become worthless!"</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1129a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1136" publication-type="other">
The estimation of Equation (6) also produces lower, but still positive and significant intercepts (as in Fama and
French [2006]);for instance, ßi Q=5.27% per annum (/=3.16) for HMLm (versus a CAPM-only 6.56% [/ = 3.93])
and 5.44% (t = 2.60) for PSm (versus 6.58% [/ = 3.16]) over 1973-2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1149a1310">
            <label>36</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1158" publication-type="other">
As is customary, this restriction excludes Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs), closed-end funds, Shares of
Beneficial Interest (SBIs), certificates, units, Americus Trust Components, companies incorporated outside the
United States, and American Depositary Receipts (ADRs). The latter is important because ADR mispricings
contribute to our financial market dislocation index. When forming MDI beta-sorted portfolios, we also exclude
stocks with prices below $5 or above $ 1,000.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1177a1310">
            <label>37</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1184" publication-type="other">
The ten portfolios contain an approximately equal number of stocks in each month. On average, each portfolio
contains 124 stocks. No portfolio contains less (more) than 71 (181) stocks. Notably, on each portfolio formation
month, this procedure sorts stocks using exclusively information available up to that month.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1197a1310">
            <label>38</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1204" publication-type="other">
In unreported analysis, we also find that the null hypothesis that all decile portfolio alphas in Table 10 are jointly
zero is always rejected by the F-statistic of Gibbons, Ross, and Shanken (1989), except for CAPM alphas and
in the earlier subperiod (1978-1993). Postranking MDI betas and alphas are more often statistically significant,
but less disperse, for equally weighted decile portfolios.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1220a1310">
            <label>39</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1227" publication-type="other">
Similar insights on the dislocation risk premium come from its direct estimation using all ten MDI beta decile
portfolios, via the multivariate GMM procedure of Pastor and Stambaugh (2003). For instance, untabulated GMM
estimates of &gt;^mdi ßi,MDl after accounting for priced sensitivities to the three, four, or five aforementioned
traded factors in Equation (6) yield annualized MDI risk premiums per average MDI beta (Xmdißi,MDl) °f
no less than 0.48% 0=2.37) over the full sample (1978-2009) and as high as 0.82% 0=2.06) over the later
subperiod (1994-2009), in line with those estimated for the 25 size and book-to-market stock portfolios in Panel
B of Table 5. The MDI risk premiums for the 1-10 spread portfolio &amp;MDI (ß,MDI ~ ß0,M Dl))3*^ larger—for
instance, ranging between 6.85% 0=2.89) with five traded factors and 7.80% 0=2.87) with three traded factors
from 1994-2009—and comparable with the estimates reported in Table 10.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1259a1310">
            <label>40</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1266" publication-type="other">
For example, these estimates imply that monthly excess returns of the currency portfolios in Table 11 decline on
average by 0.27% from a one-standard-deviation shock to MDIm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d50e1277a1310">
            <label>41</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d50e1284" publication-type="other">
Consistently, Brunnermeier, Nagel, and Pedersen (2008), Lustig, Roussanov, and Verdelhan (2011), Menkhoff
et al. (2012), and Hu, Pan, and Wang (2013) find returns to carry trades to be related to such potential sources
of systematic risk as shocks to Treasury yield curve noise, U.S. and global equity volatility, and global foreign
exchange volatility. However, the unreported estimation of Equation (8) indicates that M DIm is not redundant
relative to RX and HMLpx&gt; f°r instance, yielding an intercept cq = —0.022 (t = — 2.35) from 1983-2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e1312a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1316" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V., and L. Pedersen. 2005. Asset pricing with liquidity risk. Journal of Financial Economics 77:385^110.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1323a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1327" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V., H. Shin, and T. Yorulmazer. 2013. A theory of arbitrage capital. Review of Corporate Finance Studies
2:62-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1337a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1341" publication-type="other">
Adler, M., and B. Dumas. 1976. Portfolio choice and the demand for forward exchange. American Economic
Review 66:332-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1355" publication-type="other">
Adrian, T., D. Covitz, and N. Liang. 2013. Financial stability monitoring. Working Paper, Federal Reserve Board
of Governors.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1370" publication-type="other">
Adrian, T., E. Etula, and T. Muir. Forthcoming. Financial intermediaries and the cross section of asset returns.
Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1380a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1384" publication-type="other">
Agresti, A., S. Borgioli, and P. Poloni. 2011. Enhancements to ECB statistics for financial stability analysis. IFC
Bulletin 34:18-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1394a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1398" publication-type="other">
Akram, Q., D. Rime, and L. Sarno. 2008. Arbitrage in the foreign exchange market: Turning on the microscope.
Journal of International Economics 76:237-253.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1408a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1412" publication-type="other">
Alti, A., and P. Tetlock. 2013. Biased beliefs, asset prices, and investment: A structural approach. Journal of
Finance Published online 2013. 10.1111/jofi. 12089.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1422a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1426" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y. 2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: Cross-section and time-series effects. Journal of Financial Markets
5:31-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1440" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y., and H. Mendelson. 1986. Asset pricing and the bid-ask spread. Journal of Financial Economics
17:223-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1451a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1455" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., R. Hodrick, Y. Xing, and X. Zhang. 2006. The cross-section of volatility and expected returns. Journal
of Finance 61:259-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1465a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1469" publication-type="other">
Auguste, S., K. Dominguez, H. Kamil, and L. Tesar. 2006. Cross-border trading as a mechanism for capital flight:
ADRs and the Argentine crisis. Journal of Monetary Economics 53:1259-1295.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1479a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1483" publication-type="other">
Avramov, D., T. Chordia, G Jostova, and A. Philipov. 2010. Anomalies and financial distress. Working Paper,
University of Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1493a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1497" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., and J. Wurgler. 2006. Investor sentiment and the cross-section of stock returns. Journal of Finance
61:1645-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1507a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1511" publication-type="other">
. 2007. Investor sentiment and the stock market. Journal of Economic Perspectives 21:129-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1518a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1522" publication-type="other">
Bank for International Settlements (BIS). 2010. Report on global foreign exchange market activity in 2010.
Triennial Central Bank Survey.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1533a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1537" publication-type="other">
Banks, E. 2003. The simple rules of risk: Revisiting the art of financial risk management. Hoboken: John Wiley
&amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1551" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., and R., Thaler. 2003. A survey of behavioral finance. In Handbook of the economics of finance, eds.
G, Constantinides, M. Harris, and R. Stulz, 1053-1123. Amsterdam: North-Holland Publishing Company.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1561a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1565" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. 2006. Rare disasters, and asset markets in the twentieth century. Quarterly Journal of Economics
121:823-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1575a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1579" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Rare disasters, asset prices, and welfare costs. American Economic Review 99:243-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1590" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, and R. Hodrick. 2009. International financial management. Upper Saddle River: Pearson-Prentice
Hall, Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1604" publication-type="other">
Berk, J., and P. DeMarzo. 2007. Corporate finance. Upper Saddle River: Pearson-Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1616" publication-type="other">
Bollerslev, T., G Tauchen, and H. Zhou. 2009. Expected stock returns and variance risk premia. Review of
Financial Studies 22:4463-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1626a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1630" publication-type="other">
Bollerslev, T., and V. Todorov. 2011. Tails, fears, and risk premia. Journal of Finance 66:2165-211.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1637a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1641" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M., T. Chordia, and A. Subrahmanyam. 1998. Alternative factor specifications, security characteristics,
and the cross-section of expected stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics 49:345-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1655" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M., and A. Subrahmanyam. 1996. Market microstructure and asset pricing: On the compensation for
illiquidity in stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics 41:441-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1665a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1669" publication-type="other">
Brinkhoff, J., S. Langfield, F. Mazzaferro, C. Salleo, and O. Weeken. 2013. Risk management through the lens
of macroprudential policy. Journal of Risk Management in Financial Institutions 6:120-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1679a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1683" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier, M., and L. Pedersen. 2009. Market liquidity and funding liquidity. Review of Financial Studies
22:2201-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1694a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1698" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier, M., S. Nagel, and L. Pedersen. 2008. Carry trades and currency crashes. NBER Macroeconomics
Annual 23:313^17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1708a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1712" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. 1996. Understanding risk and return. Journal of Political Economy 104:298-345.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1719a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1723" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J., A., Lo, and C. MacKinlay. 1997. The econometrics of financial markets. Princeton: Princeton
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1733a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1737" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J., R. Schiller, and L. Viceira. 2009. Understanding inflation-indexed bond markets. NBER Working
Paper No. 15014.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1747a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1751" publication-type="other">
Carhart, M. 1997. On persistence in mutual fund performance. Journal of Finance 52:57-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1758a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1762" publication-type="other">
Chacko, G, S. Das, and R. Fan. 2012. An index-based measure of liquidity. Working Paper, Santa Clara
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1773a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1777" publication-type="other">
Chauvet, M., and J. Piger. 2008. A comparison of the real-time performance of business cycle dating methods.
Journal of Business and Economic Statistics 26:42-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1791" publication-type="other">
Chinn, M., and H. Ito. 2006. What matters for financial development? Capital controls, institutions, and
interactions. Journal of Development Economics 61:163-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1801a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1805" publication-type="other">
Chordia, T., R. Roll, and A. Subrahmanyam. 2001. Market liquidity and trading activity. Journal of Finance
56:501-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1815a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1819" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. 2001. Asset pricing. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1826a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1830" publication-type="other">
. 2011. Fama-French and the cross-section of stock returns. Lecture Notes, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1837a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1841" publication-type="other">
Coffey, N., W. Fining, H. Nguyen, and A. Sarkar. 2009. The global financial crisis and offshore dollar markets.
FRBNY Current Issues in Economics and Finance 15:1-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1852a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1856" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, G 1986. Capital market equilibrium with transaction costs. Journal of Political Economy
94:842-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1866a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1870" publication-type="other">
De Long, J., A. Shleifer, L. Summers, and R. Waldmann. 1990. Noise trader risk in financial markets. Journal of
Political Economy 98:703-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1880a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1884" publication-type="other">
Deng, G, T. Dulaney, T. Husson, and C. McCann. 2012. Isolating the effect of day-count conventions on the
market value of interest rate swaps. Working Paper, SLCG</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1894a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1898" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D. 2010. Presidential address: Asset price dynamics with slow-moving capital. Journal of Finance
65:1237-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1908a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1912" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D., N. Garleanu, and L. Pedersen. 2005. Over-the-counter markets. Econometrica 73:1815-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1919a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1923" publication-type="other">
. 2007. Valuation in over-the-counter markets. Review of Financial Studies 20:1865-900.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1931a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1935" publication-type="other">
Edison, H., and F. Warnock. 2003. A simple measure of the intensity of capital controls. Journal of Empirical
Finance 10:81-103.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1945a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1949" publication-type="other">
European Systemic Risk Board. 2012. ESRB Annual Report 2011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1960" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 1993. Common risk factors in the returns of stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial
Economics 33:3-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1970a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1974" publication-type="other">
. 1998. Value versus growth: The international evidence. Journal of Finance 53:1975-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1985" publication-type="other">
. 2006. The value premium and the CAPM. Journal of Finance 61:2163-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e1992a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e1996" publication-type="other">
. 2012. Size, value, and momentum in international stock returns, Journal of Financial Economics
105:457-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2007a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2011" publication-type="other">
Fleckenstein, M., F. Longstaff, and H. Lustig. 2013. The TIPS-Treasury bond puzzle. Journal of Finance
Published online 2013. 10.1111/jofi.l2032.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2025" publication-type="other">
Fong, W., G Valente, and K. Fung. 2010. Covered interest arbitrage profits: The role of liquidity and credit risk.
Journal of Banking and Finance 34:1098-107.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2039" publication-type="other">
Frenkel, J., and R. Levich. 1975. Covered interest arbitrage: Unexploited profits. Journal of Political Economy
83:325-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2049a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2053" publication-type="other">
. 1977. Transaction costs and interest arbitrage: Tranquil versus turbulent periods. Journal of Political
Economy 85:1209-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2067" publication-type="other">
Gagnon, L., and A. Karolyi. 2010. Multi-market trading and arbitrage. Journal of Financial Economics 97:53-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2074a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2078" publication-type="other">
Garleanu, N., and L. Pedersen. 2011. Margin-based asset pricing and deviations from the law of one price. Review
of Financial Studies 24:1980-2022.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2093" publication-type="other">
Gibbons, M., S. Ross, and J. Shanken. 1989. A test of the efficiency of a given portfolio. Econometrica 57:1121-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2100a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2104" publication-type="other">
Goldman Sachs. 2009. 2008 annual report. New York: The Goldman Sachs Group.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2111a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2115" publication-type="other">
. 2012. 2011 annual report. New York: The Goldman Sachs Group.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2122a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2126" publication-type="other">
Golub, B., and C. Crum. 2010. Risk management lessons worth remembering from the credit crisis of 2007-2009.
Journal of Portfolio Management 36:21-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2136a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2140" publication-type="other">
Griffoli, T., and A. Ranaldo. 2011. Limits to arbitrage during the crisis: Funding liquidity constraints and covered
interest parity. Working Paper, Swiss National Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2150a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2154" publication-type="other">
Gromb, D., and D. Vayanos. 2010. Limits to arbitrage: The state of the theory. Working Paper, INSEAD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2162a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2166" publication-type="other">
Grossman, S., and M. Miller. 1988. Liquidity and market structure. Journal of Finance 43:617-633.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2177" publication-type="other">
Harvey, C., Y. Liu, and H. Zhu. 2013. and the cross-section of expected returns. Working Paper, Duke University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2188" publication-type="other">
Hou, K., A. Karolyi, and B. Kho. 2011. What factors drive global stock returns? Review of Financial Studies
24:2527-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2202" publication-type="other">
Hu, X., J. Pan, and J. Wang. 2013. Noise as information for illiquidity. Journal of Finance 68:2341-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2209a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2213" publication-type="other">
Huang, M. 2003. Liquidity shocks and equilibrium liquidity premia. Journal of Economic Theory 109:104-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2220a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2224" publication-type="other">
Hubrich, K., and R. Tetlow. 2011. Financial stress and economic dynamics: The transmission of crises. Working
Paper, European Central Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2235a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2239" publication-type="other">
Jansson, M., and M. Moreira. 2006. Optimal inference in regression models with nearly integrated regressors.
Econometrica 74:681-714.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2249a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2253" publication-type="other">
Karolyi, A. 2006. The world of cross-listings and cross-listings of the world: Challenging conventional wisdom.
Review of Finance 10:73-115.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2263a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2267" publication-type="other">
Kashyap, A., R. Berner, andC. Goodhart. 2011. The macroprudential toolkit. IMF Economic Review 59:145-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2278" publication-type="other">
Kondor, P. 2009. Risk in dynamic arbitrage: Price effects of convergence trading. Journal of Finance 64:638-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2285a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2289" publication-type="other">
Kozhan, R., and W. Tham. 2012. Execution risk in high-frequency arbitrage. Management Science 58:2131^4-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2296a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2300" publication-type="other">
Lamont, O., and R. Thaler. 2003a. Can the market add and subtract? Mispricings in tech stock carve-outs. Journal
of Political Economy 111:227-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2311a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2315" publication-type="other">
. 2003b. The law of one price in financial markets. Journal of Economic Perspectives 17:191-202.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2322a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2326" publication-type="other">
Lettau, M., and S. Ludvigson. 2001. Resurrecting the (C)CAPM: A cross-sectional test when risk premia are
time-varying. Journal of Political Economy 109:1238-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2336a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2340" publication-type="other">
Lewellen, J., S. Nagel, and J. Shanken. 2010. A skeptical appraisal of asset pricing tests. Journal of Financial
Economics 96:175-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2354" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H., N. Roussanov, and A. Verdelhan. 2011. Common risk factors in currency markets. Review of Financial
Studies 24:3731-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2368" publication-type="other">
Lyons, R., and M. Moore. 2009. An information approach to international currencies. Journal of International
Economics 79:211-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2378a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2382" publication-type="other">
Matvos, G, and A. Seru. 2011. Resource allocation within firms and financial market dislocation. Working Paper,
University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2393a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2397" publication-type="other">
McLean, D., and J. Pontiff. 2013. Does academic research destroy stock return predictability? Working Paper,
Boston College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2411" publication-type="other">
Menkhoff, L., L. Sarno, M. Schmeling, and A. Schrimpf. 2012. Carry trades and global foreign exchange volatility.
Journal of Finance 67:681-718.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2421a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2425" publication-type="other">
Miron, P., and P. Swannell. 1991. Pricing and hedging swaps. London: Euromoney Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2432a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2436" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, M., and T. Pulvino. 2010. Arbitrage crashes and the speed of capital. Working Paper, CNH Partners.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2443a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2447" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, M., T. Pulvino, and E. Stafford. 2002. Limited arbitrage in equity markets. Journal of Finance
57:551-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2457a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2461" publication-type="other">
Musto, D., G Nini, and K. Schwarz. 2011. Notes on bonds: Liquidity at all costs in the great recession. Working
Paper, University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2472a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2476" publication-type="other">
Ofek, E., M. Richardson, and R. Whitelaw. 2004. Limited arbitrage and short sales restrictions: Evidence from
the options markets. Journal of Financial Economics 74:305-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2486a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2490" publication-type="other">
O'Hara, M. 2008. Bubbles: Some perspectives (and loose talk) from history. Review of Financial Studies
21:11-17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2500a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2504" publication-type="other">
Pasquariello, P. 2008. The anatomy of financial crises: Evidence from the emerging ADR market. Journal of
International Economics 76:193-207.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2514a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2518" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and R. Stambaugh. 2003. Liquidity risk and expected stock returns. Journal of Political Economy
111:642-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2532" publication-type="other">
Petkova, R. 2006. Do the Fama-French factors proxy for innovations in predictive variables? Journal of Finance
59:581-612.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2542a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2546" publication-type="other">
Pontiff J. 1996. Costly arbitrage: Evidence from closed-end funds. Quarterly Journal of Economics 111:1135-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2558" publication-type="other">
. 2006. Costly arbitrage and the myth of idiosyncratic risk. Journal of Accounting and Economics 42:35-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2565a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2569" publication-type="other">
Roll, R., E. Schwartz, and A. Subrahmanyam. 2007. Liquidity and the law of one price: The case of the futures-cash
basis. Journal of Finance 62:2201-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2579a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2583" publication-type="other">
Sadka, R., and A. Scherbina. 2007. Analyst disagreement, mispricing, and liquidity. Journal of Finance
62:2367-403.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2593a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2597" publication-type="other">
Shanken, J. 1992. On the estimation of beta-pricing models. Review of Financial Studies 5:1-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2604a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2608" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A. 2000. Inefficient markets: An introduction to behavioral finance. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2615a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2619" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A., and R. Vishny. 1997. The limits of arbitrage. Journal of Finance 52:35-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2627a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2631" publication-type="other">
. 2011. Fire sales in finance and macroeconomics. Journal of Economic Perspectives 25:29-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2638a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2642" publication-type="other">
Stambaugh, R., J. Yu, and Y. Yuan. 2011. The short of it: Investor sentiment and anomalies. NBER Working
Paper No. 16898.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2652a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2656" publication-type="other">
Stein, J. 2009. Presidential address: Sophisticated investors and market efficiency. Journal of Finance
64:1517—48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2666a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2670" publication-type="other">
Vayanos, D. 1998. Transaction costs and asset prices: A dynamic equilibrium model. Review of Financial Studies
11:1-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2680a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2684" publication-type="other">
Veronesi, P. 2004. The peso problem hypothesis and stock market returns. Journal of Economic Dynamics and
Control 28:707-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e2694a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e2698" publication-type="other">
Whaley, R. 2000. The investor fear gauge. Journal of Portfolio Management 26:12-17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


