<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794401</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Profit Shifting</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Case Against BEPS</article-title>
            <subtitle>Lessons for Tax Coordination</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Herzfeld</surname>
                  <given-names>Mindy</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>38</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794401"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In 2013 the OECD, at the behest of the G20, embarked upon an ambitious project of coordinating and harmonizing countries’ international tax rules under the guise of curtailing multinational companies’ cross-border tax planning, generally referred to as base erosion and profit shifting, or BEPS. The project was finalized with great fanfare in November 2015. But the proclamations of success masked real underlying differences between participant countries. I argue that the project suffered from a number of flaws that largely precluded effective coordination, as a result of which the project’s recommendations largely gloss over key differences in participants’ goals and commitments while doing nothing to solve the systemic problems it was seeking to address. For example, while a key stated goal of the project was to align the taxation of profits with value creation, there was no attempt made to define the location of value creation, nor to address the fact that this principle is fundamentally at odds with the arm’s length principle that serves as the backbone of transfer pricing rules.</p> 
            <p>The project left in its wake a system even more broken than before, but one papered over with rhetoric suggesting the illusion of consensus and general agreement on new rules. Broadly worded anti-abuse rules allow different countries to go off in their own, preferred directions in interpretation, implementation and enforcement. They thus open the door to unprincipled and aggressive tax agents and an increase in multilateral tax disputes with no clearer path to resolution. Poor outcomes were largely predictable from the project’s premises, which merely sought to reinforce the existing rules, but never questioned whether those rules needed updating to adjust for global economic changes and to lead to a fairer allocation of taxing rights. Furthermore, the project failed to acknowledge the bias in the existing system that meant that the outcomes were likely to benefit more powerful countries at the expense of smaller and weaker ones. While the project may have succeeded in its overt goal of limiting multinationals’ international tax avoidance, it never addressed the more systemic failures of the system that underpinned the broad consensus it achieved in obtaining initial agreement on its action plan.</p> 
            <p>The BEPS project thus holds important lessons for the future of international coordination efforts, as efforts to fix a broken international tax system, restore public confidence in multinational corporations, and achieve real agreement on the underlying principles of the rules must continue, if only to minimize the flood of disputes expecting to result from the recent changes in law and policy.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="fn1">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c1">Hugh Ault and Brian Arnold, Comparative Income Taxation - A Structural Analysis (3d ed. 2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn2">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c2">Michael Graetz and Michael O’Hear, The ‘OriginalIntent’ of U.S. International Taxation, 46 Duke L.J. 1021 (1997) (hereinafter Graetz and O ’Hear).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn3">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c3">Michael Graetz, The David R. Tillinghast Lecture: Taxing International Income: Inadequate Principles, Outdated Concepts, and Unsatisfactory Policies, 54 Tax L. Rev. 261 (2001) (hereinafter Graetz, Tillinghast Lecture)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c4">Edward D. Kleinbard, Stateless Income, 11 Flor. Tax Rev. 699 (2011)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c5">Edward D. Kleinbard, The Lessons of Stateless Income, 65 Tax L. Rev. 99 (2011)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c6">Reuven Avi-Yonah, Globalization, Tax Competition and the Fiscal Crisis of the Welfare State, 113 Harv. L. Rev. 1573 (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn4">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c7">Yariv Brauner, What the BEPS? 16 Fl. Tax Rev. 55 (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn5">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c8">Firms’ secret tax avoidance schemes cost UK billions, The Guardian (Feb. 1, 2009)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c9">Reuters, Special Report: How Starbucks avoids UK taxes (Oct. 15, 2012) at http://www.reuters.com/article/us-britain-starbucks-tax-idUSBRE89E0EX20121015</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c10">Charles Duhigg and David Kocieniewski, How Apple Sidesteps Billions in Taxes NYT (Apr 28, 2012) at http://www.nytimes.com/2012/04/29/business/apples-tax-strategy-aims-at-low-tax-states-and-nations.html?action=click&amp;contentCollection=Busmess%20Dav&amp;module=RelatedCoverage&amp;region=EndQfArticle&amp; pgtype=article.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn6">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c11">Press Release, OECD launches Action Plan on Base Erosion and Profit Shifting, (Jul. 19, 2013), available at http://www.oecd.org/ctp/beps/closing-tax-gaps-oecd-launches-action-plan-on-base-erosion-and-profit-shifting.htm</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn7">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c12">Action Plan on Base Erosion and Profit Shifting, OECD (2013) (OECD Publishing). Available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264202719-en (hereinafter “BEPS Action Plan”).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn8">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c13">Stephanie Soong Johnston, OECD Releases Final BEPS Package, Tax Notes Today (Oct. 19, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn9">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c14">Mindy Herzfeld, Whither the International Tax System, 85 Tax Notes Int’l 22 (Jan. 2, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn10">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c15">Alex Raskolnikov, From Deterrence to Compliance: Legal Uncertainty Reexamined (2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn11">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c16">Graetz, Tillinghast Lecture.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn12">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c17">Tsilly Dagan, International Tax Policy: Between Competition and CooPERATiON_(forthcoming Cambridge University Press 2018).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn13">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c18">G-20 Leaders’ Declaration (Jun. 19, 2012)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c19">www.g20mexico.org/images/stories/docs/g20/conclu/G20 Leaders Declaration 2012.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c20">Itai Grinberg, The New International Tax Diplomacy, 104 Geo. L.J. 1137 (2016)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn14">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c21">Grinberg, supra.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c22">Mindy Herzfeld, Why BEPS is Just the Beginning, 79 Tax Notes Int’l 983 (Sept. 21, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn15">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c23">Kleinbard, Stateless Income.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn16">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c24">BEPS Action Plan; Developing a Multilateral Instrument to Modify Bilateral Tax Treaties, Action 15-2015 Final Report, OECD/G20 Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Project, Par. 3 Available at http://dx. doi. ore/10.1787/9789264241688-en .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn17">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c25">Avi-Yonah, Reuven S. and Xu, Haiyan, Evaluating BEPS (Jan. 15, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c26">U of Michigan Public Law Research Paper No. 493. Available at https://ssrn.com/abstract=2716125</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c27">Swapneshwar Goutam, Critical account of the OECD’s Action Plan on Base Erosion and Profit Shifting, 8 Madras L. J. 9 (2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c28">The BEPS Monitoring Group, Explanation and Analysis of The Multilateral Convention to Implement Tax Treaty Related Measures to Prevent Base Erosion and Profit Shifting (MC-BEPS) (Mar. 2017). Available at https://bepsmonitoringgroup.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/explanation-and-analvsis-of-mc-beps.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn18">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c29">Stephanie Johnston, Kristen Parillo and David Stewart, OECD BEPS Action Plan Draws Praise, Criticism, 140 Tax Notes 437 (Jul. 29, 2013)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c30">Sol Picciotto, Can the OECD Mend the International Tax System? 71 Tax Notes Int’l 1105 (Sept. 16, 2013)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn19">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c31">OECD Policy Brief, BEPS Update No. 3 (Oct. 2015). Available at http://www.oecd.org/ctp/policy-brief-beps-2015.pdf .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn20">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c32">OECD, Preventing the Granting of Treaty Benefits in Inappropriate Circumstances, Action 6 - 2015 Final Report, OECD Publishing (2015) DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264241695-en [hereinafter BEPS Action 6 Report].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn21">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c33">OECD, Preventing the Artificial Avoidance of Permanent Establishment Status, Action 7 - 2015 Final Report OECD Publishing (2015). DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264241220-en [hereinafter BEPS Action 7 Report].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn22">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c34">OECD, Developing a Multilateral Instrument to Modify Bilateral Tax Treaties, Action 15 - 2015 Final Report, OECD (2015), DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264241688-en</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c35">0ECD/G20 Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Project Action 15: A Mandate for the Development of a Multilateral Instrument on Tax Treaty Measures to Tackle BEPS (2015) available at http://www.oecd.org/ctp/beps-action-15-mandate-for-development-of-multilateral-instrument.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn23">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c36">Aligning Transfer Pricing Outcomes with Value Creation, Actions 8-10 - 2015 Final Reports, OECD (2015) DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264241244-en [hereinafter “BEPS Transfer Pricing Report”]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn24">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c37">Countering Harmful Tax Practices More Effectively, Taking into Account Transparency and Substance, Action 5 -2015 Final Report, OECD (2015) DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264241190-en [hereinafter “BEPS Action 5 Report”].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn25">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c38">Ryan Finley, U.K. Seeks Public Comment on BEPS Interest Deductibility Rules, Worldwide Tax Daily (Oct. 23, 2015), 2015 WTD 205-2</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c39">Ryan Finley, HM Treasury Issues Proposals to Modify U.K. Patent Box, WORLDWIDE Tax Daily (Oct. 26, 2015) 2015 WTD 206-3</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c40">Mindy Herzfeld, U.K. Leads on BEPS While the U.S. Dithers, 80 Tax Notes Int’l 727 (NOV. 30, 2015)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c41">Mindy Herzfeld, The U.K. Embraces Tax Competition and BEPS, 75 Tax Notes Int’l 85 (JULY 14, 2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c42">Mindy Herzfeld, Will the United States Take Action on the BEPS Action Plan? 79 Tax Notes Int’l 817 (Sept. 7, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c43">EU COUNCIL DIRECTIVE 2016/1164 (Jul.12 2016) at http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L .2016.193.01.0001.01.ENG&amp;toc=0J:L:2016:193:T0C</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn26">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c44">Explanatory Statement, 0ECD/G20 Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Project, OECD (2015) available at www.oecd.org/tax/beps-explanatory-statement-2015.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn27">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c45">Graetz, Tillinghast Lecture at 262-3</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn28">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c46">Graetz and O’Hear at 1023</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn29">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c47">Klaus Vogel, Double Tax Treaties and Their Interpretation, 4 Int'l Tax &amp; Bus. Law. 1 (1986), available at: http://scholarship.law.berkelev.edu/biil/vol4/iss1/1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c48">Wei Cui, Minimalism about Residence and Source, 38 Mich. J. Int’l L_(2016) http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract id=2677429</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn30">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c49">Graetz and O’Hear at 1023.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn31">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c50">Dan Throop Smith, The Functions of Tax Treaties, 12 Nat’l Tax. J. 317 (1959)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c51">David S. Foster, The Importance of Tax Treaties, 5 Hastings Int'l &amp; Comp. L. Rev. 565 (1981-1982).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn32">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c52">Cui, Minimalism at 17.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn33">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c53">Graetz &amp; O ’Hear; Michael Lang and Jeffrey Owens, The Role of Tax Treaties in Facilitating Development and Protecting the Tax Base, WU Int’l Tax’n Rsch Paper Series No. 2014-03 (2014) http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm7abstract id=2398438</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c54">Veronika Daurer, Tax Treaties and Developing Countries, 42 Intertax 695-701 (2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c55">Cym Lowell &amp; Bret Wells, Income Tax Treaty Policy in the 21st Century: Residence vs. Source, 5 Colum. J. Tax L. 1, 30 (2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn34">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c56">Richard Vann, International Aspects of Income Tax 10 in Tax Law Design and Drafting vol. 2 (Victor Thuronyi, ed., 1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn35">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c57">Lowell &amp; Wells at 22.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn36">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c58">Mindy Herzfeld, The U.N. Rewrites International Tax Rules, 76 Tax Notes Int’1 477 (Nov. 10, 2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c59">Mindy Herzfeld, Implementing BEPS (or Not) in the Developing World 80 Tax Notes Int’l 475 (Nov. 9, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn37">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c60">United Nations Practical Manual on Transfer Pricing for Developing Countries (United Nations 2d ed. 2017) http://www.un.org/esa/ffd/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Manual-TP-2017.pdf .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn38">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c61">Preface to the United Nations Handbook on Selected Issues in Administration of Double Tax Treaties for Developing Countries iii (A. Trepelkov, H. Tonino and D. Halka eds. 2013)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c62">Brian Arnold, An Introduction to Tax Treaties 5 available at http://www.un.org/esa/ffd////wp-content/uploads/2015/10/TT Introduction Eng.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn39">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c63">Tsilly Dagan, The Tax Treaties Myth, 32 NYU J. Int’l L. &amp; Pol 939 [at *3].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c64">Elisabeth Owens, United States Income Tax Treaties: Their Role in Relieving Double Taxation, 17 Rutgers L. Rev. 428 (1963)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c65">Julie Roin, Rethinking Tax Treaties in a Strategic World with Disparate Tax Systems, 81 Va. L. Rev. 1753 (1995).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn40">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c66">Dagan, Tax Treaties Myth at [*4].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c67">Lowell &amp; Wells at 34.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn41">
            <label>42</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c68">Dagan, Tax Treaties Myth at 40</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c69">Lowell &amp; Wells at 34.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn42">
            <label>43</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c70">IMF Policy Paper, Spillovers in International Corporate Taxation (May 9, 2014) (available at https://www.imf.org/external/np/pp/eng/2014/050914.pdf ) at 12 (hereinafter IMF Spillover Paper).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn43">
            <label>44</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c71">IMF Spillover Paper; Options for Low Income Countries' Effective and Efficient Use of Tax Incentives for Investment, A Report to the G-20 Development Working Group by the IMF, OECD, UN and World Bank (Oct. 15, 2015) [hereinafter IMF Incentives Paper].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c72">Mindy Herzfeld, The Backlash Against Tax Treaties and Free Trade, 84 Tax Notes Int’l 438 (Oct. 31, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn44">
            <label>45</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c73">Graetz &amp; O’Hear at 1040, 1059 (1997)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn45">
            <label>46</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c74">Graetz &amp; O’Hear at 1045-46.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn46">
            <label>47</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c75">Graetz &amp; O’Hear n. 106</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c76">Roswell Magill &amp; William C. Schaab, American Taxation of Income Earned Abroad, 13 TAX L. REV. 115, 118 (1958).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn47">
            <label>48</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c77">Graetz &amp; O’Hear at 1072.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn48">
            <label>49</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c78">Graetz, Tillinghast Lecture</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c79">Reuven Avi-Yonah, Globalization, Tax Competition, and the Fiscal Crisis of the Welfare State, 113 Harv. L. Rev. 1573 (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn49">
            <label>50</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c80">Graetz, Tillinghast Lecture.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn50">
            <label>51</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c81">Brauner, What the BEPS? at 64.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn51">
            <label>52</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c82">Nick Somerlad, Six firms including Google and Facebook made £14 BILLION last year but paid just 0.3% UK tax, Mirror (Jan. 31, 2015) http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/business/six-firms-including-google-facebook-5081824http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/business/six-firms-including-google-facebook-5081824</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c83">Starbucks: No UK Tax Paid Since 2009, SkyNews (Oct. 16, 2012) http://news.sky.com/storv/998230/starbucks-no-uk-tax-paid-since-2009</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c84">Bonnie Kavoussi, Google Avoids $2 Billion In Taxes By Offshoring Profits In Bermuda, Huffington Post (Dec. 10, 2012)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c85">Lisa O’Carroll, If Google is in Ireland for tax reasons, why are most of its profits in Bermuda?, The Guardian (Mar. 24, 2011)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c86">Matt Warman, Google’s £6 billion Bermuda tax shelter, The Telegraph (Jan. 2, 2013) http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/google/9775216/Googles-6billion-Bermuda-tax-shelter.html</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c87">Renai LeMay, Australian Govt pledges action on Google tax avoidance, Delimiter (Nov. 23, 2012) https://delimiter.com.au/2012/11/23/australian-govt-pledges-action-on-google-tax-avoidance/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c88">Vanessa Barford &amp; Gerry Holt, Google, Amazon, Starbucks: The rise of'tax shaming ’” BBC News Magazine (May 21, 2013). http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-20560359</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn52">
            <label>53</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c89">Brauner, What the BEPS?</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c90">Andrew Morriss and Lotta Moberg, Cartelizing Taxes: Understanding the OECD’s Campaign Against ‘Harmful Tax Competition,’” 4 Columb. J. Tax L. 1, 52 (2012)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn53">
            <label>54</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c91">Vanessa Houlder, Business Leaders Attack UK ‘Google Tax, ’ FT (Dec. 10, 2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn54">
            <label>55</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c92">Remarks by Angel Gurria, Secretary-General of the OECD (Jul. 20, 2013) (available at 2013 TNT 141-19).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn55">
            <label>56</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c93">G20 Leaders’ Declaration par. 50 (Sept. 2013). https://g20.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Saint Petersburg Declaration ENG 0.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c94">European Union Tax Commissioner Algirdas Semeta (Jul. 20, 2013) (MEMO/13/711, available at 2013 WTD 141-16</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn56">
            <label>57</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c95">Stephanie Soong Johnston, Tax Evasion and Avoidance Now Politically Untenable, OECD Chief Says, 72 Tax Notes Int’l 814 (DEC. 2, 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn57">
            <label>58</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c96">BEPS Action Plan at 8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn58">
            <label>59</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c97">Developing a Multilateral Instrument to Modify Bilateral Tax Treaties, Action 15-2015 Final Report, OECD/G20 Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Project (OECD 2015) http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264241688-en .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn59">
            <label>60</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c98">Alexander Lewis, U.S. Multinationals Losing Tax Reform Debate, Stack Says, 81 Tax Notes Int’l 756 (Feb. 29, 2016)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c99">Mindy Herzfeld, Bursting Global Tax Bubbles, 82 Tax Notes Int’l 315 (Apr. 25, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn60">
            <label>61</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c100">G20 LEADERS' DECLARATION (Sept. 2013), available at http://www.g20.utoronto.ca/2013/2013-0906-declaration.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn61">
            <label>62</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c101">BEPS Action Plan at 10.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c102">European Comm’n Memo (Jul. 20, 2013) available at http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release MEMO-13-711 en.htm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn62">
            <label>63</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c103">A Report by the Committee on Fiscal Affairs (Oct. 8, 1998), available at http://www.oecd.org/ctp/consumption/1923256.pdf .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c104">Taxation and Electronic Commerce: Implementing the Ottawa Taxation Framework Conditions (2001), available at http://www.oecd.org/tax/consumption/Taxation%20and%20eCommerce%202001.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn63">
            <label>65</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c105">U.S. Model Income Tax Convention (Feb. 27, 2016), available at https://www.treasury.gov/resource-center/tax-policy/treaties/Documents/Treaty-US%20Model-2016.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c106">IRC § 482 and accompanying regulations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn64">
            <label>66</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c107">Eric Zolt, Tax Incentives: Protecting the Tax Base, Paper for U.N. Workshop on Tax Incentives and Base Protection (Apr. 2015), available at http://www.un.org/esa/ffd/wp- content/uploads/2015/04/2015TIBP PaperZolt.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c108">U.N. Conf. on Trade and Dvlp’t, World Investment Report 2015: Reforming International Investment Governance, Chapter V, UN Publ. No. E.15.II.D.5, available at http://unctad.org/en/PublicationsLibrary/wir2015 en.pdf [hereinafter UNCTAD paper].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn65">
            <label>67</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c109">Lowell &amp; Wells at 33</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c110">SelectUSA statistics at https://www. selectusa. gov/servlet/servlet.FileDownload?file=015t0000000LKSn.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn66">
            <label>68</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c111">BRICS and the Emergence of International Tax Coordination (Yariv Brauner, Pasquale Pistone, eds. 2015)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c112">Amanda Athanasiou, Source Versus Residence Debate Sparks Candid Comments on BEPS, 81 Tax Notes Int’l 44 (Jan. 4, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn67">
            <label>69</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c113">Stephanie Soong Johnston, OECD Proposes 'Striking' Inclusive Framework for BEPS Implementation, 81 Tax Notes Int’l 727 (Feb. 29, 2016)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c114">Stephanie Soong Johnston, OECD Inclusive Framework Gets Moving on BEPS Implementation Efforts, 83 Tax Notes Int’l 32 (Jul. 4, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c115">Lowell &amp; Wells at 39.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn68">
            <label>71</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c116">Lowell &amp; Wells at 39</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c117">Sol Picciotto, Can the OECD Mend the International Tax System? 71 Tax Notes Int’l 1105 (Sept. 16, 2013)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c118">India Responses to U.N. Questionnaire on Countries’ experiences regarding base erosion and profit shifting issues, available at http://www.un.org/esa/ffd/tax/Beps/CommentsIndia BEPS.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn69">
            <label>72</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c119">Lowell &amp; Wells at 35</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn70">
            <label>73</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c120">Lowell &amp; Wells at 4</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c121">Dagan, Between Competition and Cooperation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c122">Mindy Herzfeld, Who Will Control the Future of International Tax Policy? 78 Tax Notes Int’l 419 (May 4, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn71">
            <label>74</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c123">Letter from M.S. Puri to H.E. Mr. Milos Koterec, President of the Economic and Social Council, United Nations (Aug. 13, 2012) http://www.un.org/esa/ffd/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/ta-unmodel-LetterIndia 13aug12.pdf .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c124">Mindy Herzfeld, India and the United States - Half a World Apart on Tax, 84 Tax Notes Int’l 953 (Dec. 12, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn72">
            <label>75</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c125">Stephanie Soong Johnston, G-20 Finance Ministers Approve BEPS Framework, 81 Tax Notes Int’l 819 (Mar. 7, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn73">
            <label>76</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c126">Joint Communique issued after Two Day meeting of the heads of Revenue of Brics Countries, January 18, 2013 (announcing the cooperation agreement between Brazil, Russia, India, China, and South Africa), reprinted at 2013 WTD 15-27, Tax Doc. 2013-1498</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn74">
            <label>77</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c127">Yariv Brauner &amp; Pasquale Pistone, Eds., Brics and the International Tax Regime (IBFD 2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn75">
            <label>79</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c128">BRICS Countries Launch New Development Bank International Centre for Trade and Sustainable Development, 18 Bridges 26 (Jul. 17, 2014) http://www.ictsd.org/bridges-news/bridges/news/brics-countries-launch-new-development-bank.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn76">
            <label>80</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c129">Gabriel Wildau, New Brics bank in Shanghai to challenge major institutions, FT (Jul. 21, 2015) http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/0/d8e26216-2f8d-11e5-8873-775ba7c2ea3d.html#axzz3q4SpN4DZ .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c130">Gabriel Wildau and Charles Clover, AIIB launch signal China’s new ambition, FT (Jun. 29, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn77">
            <label>81</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c131">Cartelizing Taxes at 4</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn78">
            <label>83</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c132">Joint Committee on Taxation, Background, Summary, and Implications of the OECD/G20 Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Project (JCX-139-15) (Nov. 30, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn79">
            <label>84</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c133">Grinberg, Breaking BEPS at 9.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn80">
            <label>85</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c134">Philip Baker, Is There a Cure for BEPS? 5 Brit. Tax. Rev. 605 (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn81">
            <label>86</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c135">Cartelizing Taxes at 57.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c136">Stephanie Soong Johnston, Pascal Saint-Amans -The Face of BEPS, 2014 WTD 245-1 (Dec. 22, 2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c137">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qUy- gHe-Mg</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn82">
            <label>88</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c138">Kevin Rivett, Henry Nothhaft and David Kline, Discovering New Value in Intellectual Property, HBR (2000) at https://hbr.org/2000/01/discovering-new-value-in-intellectual-property.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn83">
            <label>89</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c139">Robert Stack, The Progress and Future of BEPS (Remarks delivered to the OECD/U.S. Council for International Business tax conference (Jun. 10, 2015)), reprinted at 147 Tax Notes 1593 (Jun. 29, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn84">
            <label>90</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c140">Ryan Finley, Stack Reflects on Turbulent Days at Treasury, Future of the OECD, 85 Tax Notes Int’l 1045 (Mar. 20, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn85">
            <label>91</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c141">infra.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn86">
            <label>92</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c142">https://www.oecd.org/tax/transfer-pricing/BEPS-discussion-draft-on-the-revised-guidance-on-profit-splits.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn87">
            <label>93</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c143">Comments on Discussion Draft on the Use of Profit Splits in the Context of Global Value Chains, China International Tax Center/ IFA China Branch (Feb. 6, 2015), available at http://www.oecd.org/tax/transfer-pricing/public-comments-action-10-profit-splits-global-value-chains.pdf [hereinafter China IFA Comments]</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c144">Mindy Herzfeld, Splitting Profits with Communists, 79 Tax Notes Int’l 467 (Aug. 10, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn88">
            <label>94</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c145">China IFA Comments. The comments state that: “Both value creation and value realization enable a value becomes a value. In this way, the role of the enterprises and markets are clearer and their contribution to the value will be easier to be identified and differentiated.”</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn89">
            <label>95</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c146">Id.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn90">
            <label>96</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c147">BEPS Action Plan Actions 8, 9 and 10.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c148">Michael Devereaux and John Vella, Are We Heading Towards a Corporate Tax System Fit for the 21st Century? 35 Fiscal Studies 449 (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn91">
            <label>99</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c149">OECD, Addressing the Tax Challenges of the Digital Economy, Action 1 - 2015 Final Report, (2015). Available at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264241046-en [hereinafter Action 1 Report].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn92">
            <label>100</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c150">BEPS Monitoring Group, Overall Evaluation of the G20/OECD Base Erosion and Profit Shifting (BEPS) Project (Oct. 5, 2015), available at 2015 WTD 193-33 (Oct. 6, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn93">
            <label>101</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c151">Amanda Athanasiou, Source versus Residence Debate Sparks Candid Comments on BEPS, 150 TAX NOTES 67 (JAN. 4, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn94">
            <label>102</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c152">Reuters, China's outbound investment jumps, catching up with FDI (Jun. 18, 2015), available at http://uk.reuters.com/article/uk-china-investment-fdi-idUKKBN00Y07420150618.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn95">
            <label>103</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c153">Yariv Brauner &amp; Pasquale Pistone, Eds., Brics and the International Tax Regime (IBFD 2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn96">
            <label>104</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c154">Letter from M.S. Puri, Ambassador/Deputy Permanent Representative from India to the United Nations, to Milos Koterec President of the U.N. Economic and Social Council (Aug. 13, 2012), accessible at http://www.un.org/esa/ffd/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/ta-unmodel-LetterIndia 13aug12.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn97">
            <label>105</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c155">Mindy Herzfeld, India and the United States: Half a World Apart on Tax, 84 TAX NOTES INT'L 953 (DEC. 12, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn98">
            <label>106</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c156">OECD Background Brief: Inclusive Framework on BEPS (Jan. 2017), available at http://www.oecd.org/tax/beps/background-brief-inclusive-framework-for-beps-implementation.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn99">
            <label>107</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c157">The 2017 version of the U.N. model treaty includes a new article that greatly expands taxation at source. See U.N. Comm. of Experts on Int’l Cooperation in Tax Matters Seventh Session, Taxation of Services Report of the Coordinator E/C.18/2016/CRP.1. Available at http://www.un.org/esa/ffd/wp- content/uploads/2016/10/12STM CRP1 Services.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c158">Andres Baez Moreno, The Taxation of Technical Services under the United Nations Model Double Taxation Convention: A Rushed - Yet Appropriate - Proposal for (Developing) Countries? 7 World Tax J. 3 (2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn100">
            <label>108</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c159">James Hines, High Tax Heresy [working paper Jan. 2016], available at http://www.law.georgetown.edu/faculty/symposia-lectures/tax-law-public-finance/upload/High-Tax-Heresy-Jan-2016.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn101">
            <label>109</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c160">Julie Roin, Taxation without Coordination, 31 J. Legal Studies 61, [xx].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn102">
            <label>110</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c161">Roin, Taxation without Coordination at [xx].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn103">
            <label>111</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c162">Roin, Taxation without Coordination at [xx].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn104">
            <label>112</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c163">Amanda Athanasiou, Competitive Interests Preventing Consensus on CFCs, Stack Says, 2015 WTD 96-3 (May 19, 2015); Robert Stack, Remarks delivered at OECD/USCIB tax conference (June 2015), available at 2015 WTD 124-14.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c164">Graetz &amp; O’Hear at 1042</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn105">
            <label>113</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c165">Alexander Klemm and Stefan Van Parys, Empirical Evidence on the effects of Tax Incentives, 19 Int’l Tax &amp; Publ. Fin. 393 (2012)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn106">
            <label>114</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c166">IMF Incentives Paper, supra n. [xx].</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn107">
            <label>115</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c167">IMF Incentives Paper at 6.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn108">
            <label>116</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c168">IMF Incentives Paper at 28.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn109">
            <label>117</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c169">IMF Incentives Paper at 28; see also UNCTAD paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn110">
            <label>118</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c170">Mindy Herzfeld, The Politics of the U.S. Patent Box 79 Tax Notes Int’l 905 (Sept. 14, 2015);</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn111">
            <label>120</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c171">European Commission, "Patent Boxes Design, Patents Location and Local R&amp;D," June 2015, available athttp://goo.gl/ikHIXt.)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn112">
            <label>121</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c172">Id.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn113">
            <label>122</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c173">Lisa Evers, Helen Miller, and Christoph Spengel, Intellectual Property Box Regimes: Effective Tax Rates and Tax Policy Considerations, 22:3 Int'l Tax Publ. Fin. 502 (2015), available at http://goo.gl/I2AIsP.)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c174">Martin Sullivan, A History Lesson for a Future Patent Box, 148 Tax Notes 1036 (Sept. 7, 2015)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c175">Martin Sullivan, Do Patent Boxes Move More Than Patents? 148 Tax Notes 243 (Jul. 20, 2015)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c176">Martin Sullivan, Can a Patent Box Promote Advanced Manufacturing? 147 Tax Notes 1347 (Jun. 22, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn114">
            <label>123</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c177">Evers, Miller and Spengel, Intellectual Property Box Regimes, id.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c178">Jt. Comm. On Tax’n, Present Law and Background Related to Proposals to Reform the Taxation of Income of Multinational Enterprises JCX-90-14 (Jul. 21, 2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c179">Domenico Borzumato and Annalisa Vergati, Italy’s Finance Bill - Tax as a Tool for Growth, WTD (Nov. 24, 2014)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c180">J.P. Finet, IP Box, Country-by-Country Reporting Featured in Irish Budget, 2015 WTD 198-3 (Oct. 14, 2015)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c181">American Action Forum, Patent Boxes, Technological Innovation and Implications for Corporate Tax Reform (Aug. 24, 2015), available at: http://americanactionforum.org/research/patent-boxes-technological-innovation-and-implications-for-corporate# ftn47.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c182">Amanda Athanasiou, Singapore's 2017 Budget Gives Nods to BEPS, Innovation, WTD (Feb. 22, 2017)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c183">Stephanie Soong Johnston, Mauritius Proposes Innovation Box, Moving in Line With Global Tax Norms, 2017 WTD 111-4 (Jun. 12, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn115">
            <label>124</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c184">H.R. 2605 (introduced by Rep. Allyson Schwartz in the 113th Congress)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c185">Jane G. Gravelle, A Patent/Innovation Box as a Tax Incentive for Domestic Research and Development, Cong. Rsch. Svc. 7-5700 (Jun. 13, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn116">
            <label>125</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c186">Stephen Cooper, Innovation Box Proposal Still Evolving, Neal Says, 2016 TNT 101-5 (May 25, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn117">
            <label>126</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c187">Stephanie Baker, U.K. Cuts Corporation Tax Rate Again in a Boon to Britain Plc, Bloomberg News (Mar. 16, 2016) available at https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-03-16/u-k-cuts-corporation-tax-rate-again-in-a-boon-to-britain-inc</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c188">HMRC Policy Paper, Corporation Tax to 17% in 2020 (Mar. 16, 2016), available at https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/corporation-tax-to-17-in-2020/corporation-tax-to-17-in-2020</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c189">Instit. For Fiscal Studies Briefing Note, What’s been happening to corporation tax? (May 10, 2017) available at https://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/9207 .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn118">
            <label>127</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c190">2016 WTD 224-26 (Nov. 17, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn119">
            <label>128</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c191">Dagan, International Tax Policy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn120">
            <label>129</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c192">BEPS Action 5.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn121">
            <label>130</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c193">Devereaux and Vella, Are We Heading Towards a Corporate Tax System Fit for the 21st Century? 35 Fiscal Studies 449 (2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn122">
            <label>131</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c194">David Stewart, 'Value Creation' Understanding Key to Transfer Pricing’s Future, 2015 TNT 142-4 (Jul. 24, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn123">
            <label>132</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c195">OECD Background Brief, Inclusive Framework on BEPS, (Jan. 2017) available at https://www.oecd.org/ctp/background-brief-inclusive-framework-for-beps-implementation.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c196">EY Tax Insights, Deciphering BEPS: What do the Categories Mean? (Apr. 26, 2016), available at http://taxinsights.ey.com/archive/archive-articles/deciphering-beps-what-do-the-categories-mean.aspx .</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn124">
            <label>133</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c197">Oecd Explanatory Statement to the Multilateral Convention To Implement Tax Treaty Related Measures To Prevent Base Erosion And Profit Shifting, available at https://www.oecd.org/tax/treaties/explanatory-statement-multilateral-convention-to-implement-tax-treaty-related-measures-to-prevent-BEPS.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c198">International Tax Group, available at http://www.oecd.org/ctp/treaties/public-comments-received-discussion-draft-Development-of-MLI-to-Implement-Tax-Treaty-related-BEPS-Measures.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn125">
            <label>134</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c199">Ryan Finley, Germany Passes Anti-Patent-Box Law as Neighbors Keep Pre-BEPS Regimes, 2017 WTD 16-2 (Jan. 26, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn126">
            <label>135</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c200">KPMG, BEPS Action 13-Latest Country Implementation (updated weekly) available at https://home.kpmg.com/xx/en/home/insights/2016/04/beps-countrv-bv-countrv-implementation.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn127">
            <label>136</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c201">David Ernick, Can the OECD Remain an International Tax Standard-Setting Organization? 45 T.Mgt.Int’l J. 745 (Dec. 9, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn128">
            <label>137</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c202">Kleinbard, Stateless Income at 721</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c203">Lawrence Lokken, Whatever Happened to Subpart F U.S. CFC Legislation After the Check-the-Box Regulations, 7 Fla. Tax Rev. 185 (2005)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c204">Stephanie Soong Johnston, Politics Shouldn 't Steer BEPS Implementation Policy, Stack Says, 81 Tax Notes Int’l 929 (Mar. 14, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn129">
            <label>138</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c205">Reuters, How Treasury’s tax loophole mistake saves companies billions each year, (May 30, 2013), available at http://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-tax-checkthebox-insight-idUSBRE94T17K20130531.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn130">
            <label>139</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c206">Mindy Herzfeld, The U.S. Treasury and the BEPS Mess, 78 Tax Notes Int’l (Jun. 22, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn131">
            <label>140</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c207">Alexander Lewis, U.S. Using BEPS Project to Safeguard Tax Base, Stack Says, 2016 TNT 94-7 (May 16, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn132">
            <label>141</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c208">Hatch Statement at Finance Hearing on OECD BEPS Reports (Dec. 1, 2015), available at https://www.finance.senate.gov/chairmans-news/hatch-statement-at-finance-hearing-on-oecd-beps-reports</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c209">Letter to Treasury Secretary Lew from Senator Orrin Hatch and Representative Paul Ryan (Aug. 27, 2015), available at https://waysandmeans.house.gov/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Letter-to-Secretary-Lew-on-BEPS.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c210">Letter to Treasury Secretary Lew from Orrin Hatch and Paul Ryan expressing concerns about “several other proposals of the BEPS project, including, among others, [and] modifying the permanent establishment (PE) rules, using subjective general anti-abuse rules (GAAR) in tax treaties.” (Jun. 9, 2015), available at https://www.finance.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Hatch,%20Ryan%20Call%20on%20Treasury%20to%20Engage%20 Congress%20on%200ECD%20Intemational%20Tax%20Proiect.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn133">
            <label>143</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c211">Neil McCabe, Will This Global Bureaucracy Get U.S. Tax Data? WorldNetDaily (May 8, 2015) at http://mobile.wnd.com/2015/05/will-this-global-bureaucracy-get-u-s-tax-data/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c212">Brian McNicoll, Obama Advocates European Ideas on Taxes, (May 18, 2015) http://humanevents.com/2015/05/08/obama-advocates-european-ideas-on-taxes/).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn134">
            <label>144</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c213">Letter dated June 9, 2015, available at http://waysandmeans.house.gov/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Hatch-Ryan-Call-on-Treasury-to-Engage-Congress-on-OECD-Intemational-Tax-Proiect.pdf</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c214">Republicans Attack New Global Insurance Rules, FT (Apr. 28, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn135">
            <label>145</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c215">Mindy Herzfeld, Making Bets on CbC Reporting, 78 Tax Notes Int’l 595 (May 18, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn136">
            <label>146</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c216">Hatch Statement on OECD BEPS Reports (Dec. 1, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn137">
            <label>147</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c217">Margaret Burow, Kristin Parillo, and David Stewart, Stack Provides Insights on BEPS Reports, Outlines Next Steps, 144 Tax Notes 1497 (Sept. 29, 2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c218">Kristen Parillo, Robert Stack -- BEPS and the United States, 76 Tax Notes Int’l 1055 (Dec. 22, 2014).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn138">
            <label>148</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c219">Ryan Finley, Stack Reflects on Turbulent Days at Treasury, Future of the OECD, 85 Tax Notes Int’l 1045 (Mar. 20, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn139">
            <label>149</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c220">Indian Finance Act, 2016, Chapter (VIII).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn140">
            <label>151</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c221">Ryan Finley, Forget 'DEMPE' Label, McDonald Says, 2017 WTD 59-4 (Mar. 29, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn141">
            <label>152</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c222">Philip Morrison, BEPS 2015 Final Report Regarding Transfer Pricing of Intangibles, 45 TMIJ 224 (April 8, 2016)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c223">David Ernick, New OECD Rules Seek Broad Expansion of Tax Authority Power to Disregard Transactions, 45 Tax Mgt. Int’l J. 90 (Feb. 12, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn142">
            <label>153</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c224">Ryan Finley, BEPS Report on Transfer Pricing 'Could Have Been Worse,' Hickman Says, 151 Tax Notes 1440 (Jun. 13, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn143">
            <label>154</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c225">Mindy Herzfeld, Will the OECD’s ‘Pragmatic Fudge ’ Save Transfer Pricing? 83 Tax Notes Int’l 360 (Aug. 1, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn144">
            <label>155</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c226">Wolfgang Schoen, International Taxation of Risk, WP of the Max Planck Instit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c227">Tax Law &amp; Publ. Fin. No. 2014-03 (Feb. 28, 2014). Available at https://ssrn.com/abstract=2402612.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn145">
            <label>156</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c228">BEPS Transfer Pricing Report ^ D.1.2.1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn146">
            <label>157</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c229">Jens Wittendorff, At Arm’s Length: BEPS Actions 8-10: Birth of a New Arm's-Length Principle, 81 Tax Notes Int’l 331 (Jan. 25, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn147">
            <label>158</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c230">David Stewart, OECD to Address Cash Boxes Without Special Guidance, 148 Tax Notes 172 (Jul. 13, 2015.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn148">
            <label>159</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c231">EY Global Tax Alert, Israel Proposes New Innovation Box Regime to Attract IP Investment (Jul. 19, 2016), available at http://www.ey.com/gl/en/services/tax/international-tax/alert--israel-proposes-new-innovation-box-regime-to-attract-ip-investment.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn149">
            <label>160</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c232">Mindy Herzfeld, Have Treasury's Anti-Inversion Rules Backfired? 149 Tax Notes 1214 (Dec. 7, 2015)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn150">
            <label>162</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c233">BIAC Letter to the OECD on revised Action 7 discussion draft (Jun. 12, 2015), available at http://biac.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Final-BIAC-Comments-Action-71.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn151">
            <label>163</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c234">The U.S. has said it would not commit to the revised PE standards without the final guidance on the attribution of profits. See Ryan Finley, U.S. Taking Cautious Approach to Adoption of New PE Standard, 2016 TNT 89-19 (May 9, 2016).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn152">
            <label>164</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c235">Richard Collier, More Guidance Needed on PE Threshold Issues, 80 Tax Notes Int’l 249 (OCT. 19, 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn153">
            <label>166</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c236">Part 3 UK Finance Act 2015 (Mar. 3, 2015), available at http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2015/11/part/3/enacted</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c237">Explanatory Notes to UK Finance Act 2015, §§ 78 et seq. available at http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2015/11/notes/division71/78</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c238">H.M. Rev. &amp; Customs Consultation Draft on Diverted Profits Tax (Dec. 10, 2104), available at https://www.gov.uk/govemment/publications/finance-bill-2015-diverted-profits-tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn154">
            <label>167</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c239">Shinasa Wasimi, Jai Nario, and Kathryn Bertram, Diverted Profits Tax: U.K., Australian, and New Zealand Approaches, 87 Tax Notes Int’l 349 (Jul. 24, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn155">
            <label>168</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c240">Mindy Herzfeld, The Multilateral Instrument and Permanent Establishments, 86 Tax Notes Int’l 1029 (JUN. 19, 2017).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="fn156">
            <label>169</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c241">Weisbach, Neutralities at 3, citing Graetz (2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="c242">Cui, Minimalism at 18.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
   </back>
</article>
