<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278193</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Thermal Mapping of an Automotive Rear Drive Axle</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Xu</surname>
                  <given-names>Hai</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Singh</surname>
                  <given-names>Avinash</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Maddock</surname>
                  <given-names>Don</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kahraman</surname>
                  <given-names>Ahmet</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ohio State Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hurley</surname>
                  <given-names>Joshua</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ohio State Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>888</fpage>
         <lpage>901</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278193"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In recent years, there has been a sustained effort by the automotive OEMs and suppliers to improve the vehicle driveline efficiency. This has been in response to customer demands for greater vehicle fuel economy and increasingly stringent government regulations. The automotive rear axle is one of the major sources of power loss in the driveline, and hence represents an area where power loss improvements can have a significant impact on overall vehicle fuel economy. Both the friction induced mechanical losses and the spin losses vary significantly with the operating temperature of the lubricant. Also, the preloads in the bearings can vary due to temperature fluctuations. The temperatures of the lubricant, the gear tooth contacting surfaces, and the bearing contact surfaces are critical to the overall axle performance in terms of power losses, fatigue life, and wear. It is therefore important to understand the temperature variations in an automotive rear axle as a function of operating loads and speeds. However, quantitative understanding of the axle thermal behavior is limited and published information is sparse. This study attempts to bridge this gap.</p>
            <p>In this paper, an automotive rear drive axle is used to investigate the thermal behavior and power losses under a range of speed and load conditions developed from a typical EPA fuel economy driving cycle. The test axle is instrumented with thermocouples at various critical locations on the rotating and stationary components. A wireless telemetry system was used to extract the temperature readings of those rotating thermocouples. The axle tests were run on a dynamometer with simulated wind cooling and the tests were run till the lubricant reached steady state conditions. Findings from these tests will be discussed in this paper.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goodwin, M.C. and Haviland, M.L., “Fuel Economy Improvements in EPA and Road Tests with Engine Oil and Rear Axle Lubricant Viscosity Reduction,” SAE Technical Paper 780596, 1978, doi: 10.4271/780596.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hobson, D.E., “Axle Efficiency - Test Procedures and Results,” SAE Technical Paper 790744, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790744.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Axle Efficiency Test Procedure,” SAE Standard J1266, Rev. April 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Porrett, D.C., Miles, S.D., Werderits, E.F., and Powell, D.L., “Development of a Laboratory Axle Efficiency Test,” SAE Technical Paper 800804, 1980, doi: 10.4271/800804.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katoh, H., Inoh, T., and Umezawa, K., “Exact Measurement of Power Loss in Automotive Transmission and Axle for Fuel Economy,” SAE Technical Paper 830573, 1983, doi: 10.4271/830573.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ko, Y. and Hosoi, K., “Measurement of Power Losses in Automobile Drive Train,” SAE Technical Paper 840054, 1984, doi: 10.4271/840054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winter, H. and Wech, L., “Measurements and Optimization of the Efficiency of Hypoid Axle Drives of Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 885127, 1988, doi: 10.4271/885127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, N. and Maddock, D., “Development of a Standardized Axle Efficiency Test Methodology”, 2nd CTI Symposium, Automotive Transmissions North America, Detroit, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akucewich, E.S., Vinci, J.N., Qureshi, F.S., and Cain, R.W., “Developing Next Generation Axle Fluids: Part I - Test Methodology to Measure Durability and Temperature Reduction Properties of Axle Gear Oils,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1691, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1691.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Connor, B.M., Schiemann, L.F., and Johnson, R.L., “Axle Efficiency - Response to Synthetic Lubricant Components,” SAE Technical Paper 821181, 1982, doi: 10.4271/821181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bala, V., Rollin, A.J., and Brandt, G., “Rheological Properties Affecting the Fuel Economy of Multigrade Automotive Gear Lubricants,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2051, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wincierz, C., Hedrich, K., and Müller, M., “Formulation of Multigrade Gear Oils for High Efficiency and Low Operating Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2822, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2822.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vinci, J.N., Akucewich, E.S., Cain, R.W., and Qureshi, F.S., “Developing Next Generation Axle Fluids: Part II - Systematic Formulating Approach,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1692, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1692.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akucewich, E.S., O'Connor, B.M., Vinci, J.N., and Schenkenberger, C., “Developing Next Generation Axle Fluids, Part III: Laboratory CAFE Simulation Test as Key Fluid Development Tool,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3235, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vinci, J.N., Grisso, B.A., Schenkenberger, C., Qureshi, F.S. et al., “Systematic Formulation of Efficient and Durable Axle Lubricants for Light Trucks and Sport Utility Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3030, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-3030.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baker, M.R., Grisso, B.A., Rhoads, G., Schenkenberger, C. et al., “Breaking the Viscosity Paradigm: Formulating Approaches for Optimizing Efficiency and Vehicle Life,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3860, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3860.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baker, M.R., Schenkenberger, C., Rhoads, G., and Grisso, B.A., “Breaking the Viscosity Paradigm: Formulating Approaches for Optimizing Efficiency and Axle Life - Part II,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3272, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-3272.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gangopadhyay, A., Asaro, S., Schroder, M., Jensen, R. et al., “Fuel Economy Improvement Through Frictional Loss Reduction in Light Duty Truck Rear Axle,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2821, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2821.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bjornen, K.K., Chambers, H., and DeGonia, D., “Development of a Fuel Efficient Multipurpose 75W-90 Gear Lubricant,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1992, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogino, S., Kobayashi, S., and Suzaki, S., “Improvement of Rear Axle Cooling Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 881738, 1988, doi: 10.4271/881738.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hurley, J. D., “An Experimental Investigation of Thermal Behavior of an Automotive Rear Axle”, MS thesis, The Ohio State University, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
