<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169286</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Assessment of the Accuracy of Certain Reduced Order Models used in the Prediction of Occupant Injury during Under-Body Blast Events</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kulkarni</surname>
                  <given-names>Kumar B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ESI US Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ramalingam</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaisankar</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>US Army TARDEC</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Thyagarajan</surname>
                  <given-names>Ravi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>US Army TARDEC</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169277</issue-id>
         <fpage>307</fpage>
         <lpage>319</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169286"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>It is of considerable interest to developers of military vehicles, in early phases of the concept design process as well as in Analysis of Alternatives (AoA) phase, to quickly predict occupant injury risk due to under-body blast loading. The most common occupant injuries in these extremely short duration events arise out of the very high vertical acceleration of vehicle due to its close proximity to hot high pressure gases from the blast. In a prior study [16], an extensive parametric study was conducted in a systematic manner so as to create look-up tables or automated software tools that decision-makers can use to quickly estimate the different injury responses for both stroking and non-stroking seat systems in terms of a suitable blast load parameter. The primary objective of this paper is to quantitatively evaluate the accuracy of using such a tool in lieu of building a detailed model for simulation and occupant injury assessment.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilson. C., “Improvised Explosive Devices (IEDs) in Iraq and Afghanistan: Effects and Countermeasures”, CRS Report for Congress, RS22330, 28 August 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird, S., and Fairweather. C., “Recent military fatalities in Afghanistan (and Iraq) by cause and nationality”, MRC Biostatistics Unit, UK, February 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farago. J., “IED Casualties in Afghanistan Soaring”, http://www.newser.com/story/55161/ied-casualties-inafghanistan-soaring.html, 3 April 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thyagarajan, R., “End-to-end System level M&amp;S tool for Underbody Blast Events”, 27th Army Science Conference, Army Technology Showcase, Orlando, FL, Nov 29 - Dec 2. DTIC Report # ADA550921, TARDEC Registration # 21365, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weed, R., Moore, C., Thyagarajan, R., “Enhancements and Analysis of CTH Software for Underbody Blast”, DTIC Report # ADA571176, TARDEC Registration # 23676, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vlahopoulos, N. Zhang, G, “Validation of a Simulation Process for Assessing the Response of a Vehicle and Its Occupants to an Explosive Threat”, 27th Army Science Conference, Orlando, FL, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moral, R., Danielson, K., and Ehrgott, J., “Tactical Wheeled Vehicle Survivability: Comparison of Explosive-Soil-Air-Structure Simulations to Experiments Using the Impulse Measurement Device,” Army Corp of Engineers Technical Report ERDC/GSL TR- 10-27, August, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kerley, G., “Numerical Modeling of Buried Mine Explosions”, ARLCR- 461, Army Research Laboratory, Aberdeen Proving Ground, MD, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, K., McClennan, S., Durocher, R, St-Jean, B., Trembelay, J., “Validation of a Loading Model for Simulating Blast Mine Effects on Armoured Vehicles,” 7th International LS-DYNA Users Conference, Detroit, MI 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, K., McClennan S., “A numerical analysis of mine blast effects on simplified target geometries: Validation of loading models,” Defense R&amp;D Canada-Valcartier, DRDC Valcartier TM 2002-260, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dooge, D., Dwarampudi, R., Schaffner, G., Miller, A., Thyagarajan, R., Vunnam, M., Babu, V., “Evolution of Occupant Survivability Simulation Framework Using FEM-SPH Coupling,” 2011 NDIA Ground Vehicle System Engineering and Technology Symposium (GVSETS), MSTV Mini-Symposium Paper, Dearborn, Michigan, August 9-11, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Final Report of HFM-090 Task Group 25, “Test Methodology for Protection of Vehicle Occupants against Anti-Vehicular Landmine Effects”, NATO RTO TECHNICAL REPORT TR-HFM-090, April 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arepally, S., Gorsich, D., Hope, K., Gentner, S., and Dortleff, K., “Application of mathematical modeling in potentially survivable blast threats in military vehicles”, 26th Army Science Conference, Orlando, FL, 1-4 December 2008, DTIC Report# ADA496843</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rangarajan, N., Moore, J., Gromowski, P., Rinaldi, J., Yoganandan, N., Pintar, F., Mariman, D., and McEntire, J., “Response of dummies to high onset rate Gz loading on sled”, unpublished report.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sheng, J. and Arepally, S., “Crew Injury Risk Assessment - Effective g vs. Delta V”, Internal TARDEC brief, December 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulkarni, K.B., Ramalingam, J., and Thyagarajan, R., “Evaluating the Effectiveness of Various Blast Loading Descriptors as Occupant Injury Predictors for Underbody Blast Events”, 2013 NDIA Ground Vehicle Systems Engineering and Technology Symposium (GVSETS) Modeling &amp; Simulation, Testing and Validation (MSTV) Mini-Symposium August 21-22, 2013 - Troy, Michigan</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, L., Stowe, N., Vlahopoulos, N., Mohammad, S., Barker, C., Thyagarajan, R., “Utilization of Fast Running Models in Buried Blast Simulations of Ground Vehicles for Significant Computational Efficiency”, 2013 NDIA Ground Vehicle Systems Engineering and Technology Symposium (GVSETS) Modeling &amp; Simulation, Testing and Validation (MSTV) Mini-Symposium August 21-22, 2013 - Troy, Michigan</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
