<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830683</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830685</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>STOCK MARKET, MACROECONOMIC VARIABLES, AND CAUSALITY: THE BANGLADESH CASE / BOURSE DES VALEURS, VARIABLES MACROÉCONOMIQUES ET CAUSALITÉ: LE CAS DU BANGLADESH</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>M. Farid</given-names>
                  <surname>Ahmed</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1999</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>109</fpage>
         <lpage>130</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830685"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This study is an attempt to explore the relationship between stock market and macroeconomic variables of Bangladesh using the technique of Granger-causality tests. In some respects the evidences of this study are consistent with similar other studies while others provide evidence of diversity. The findings of the study suggest the direction of relationship from stock price changes to consumption expenditures. This in turn indicates the existence of wealth effect. It also demonstrates the causal relationship from stock prices to investment made by the firms. This may be viewed in terms of the fact that firms invest to earn profits and activity in the stock market represents an attempt by investors to evaluate the magnitudes of that stream of profits. However, if the total national investment is considered, unidirectional causality from investment to stock prices is found. Further, this study indicates a weak relationship between stock prices and GDP but stock prices are likely to have leads over GDP. Instantaneous causality between stock prices and industrial production appears to be absent or very weak with monthly data suggesting the market is not informationally efficient. Cette étude se propose d'analyser le relation entre la bourse des valeurs et les variables macroéconomiques au Bangladesh en utilisant la technique des tests de causalité de Granger. Pour certains aspects, les résultats obtenus sont semblables à ceux d'autres études, tandis que pour d'autres ils témoignent de quelques différences. Les résultats de cette étude suggèrent la direction de la relation des variations des prix des valeurs aux frais de consommation ce qui, à son tour, indique l'existence d'un effet richesse. Cela pourrait être vu comme le résultat du fait que les entreprises investissent pour en tirer des bénéfices et que l'activité de la bourse des valeurs représente l'essai de la part des investisseurs d'évaluer le volume du flux des bénéfices. Toutefois, si on considère le total des investissements nationaux, on observe une causalité unidirectionnelle des investissements au prix des valeurs mobilières. En outre, cette étude indique qu'il n'y aurait qu'une relation faible entre les prix des valeurs et le PNB, où les prix des valeurs ont probablement le pas sur le PNB et aussi qu'il n'y aurait pas de causalité immédiate entre les prix des valeurs et la production ou que, si elle existe, elle serait très faible. Les données mensuelles, d'autre part, temoignent d'un manque d'efficience du marché au niveau de l'information.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d15e172a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e179" publication-type="other">
Ahmed, 1997</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e186a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e193" publication-type="other">
Moore, 1975</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e199" publication-type="other">
Zarnowitz and Boschan, 1975</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e205" publication-type="other">
Pierce, 1983.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d15e221a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e228" publication-type="other">
Mookerjee (1988)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e234" publication-type="other">
USA Moore (1975)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e240" publication-type="other">
Pakistan Nishat and Shagir (1991).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e247a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e254" publication-type="other">
World Bank (1996)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e261a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e268" publication-type="other">
Hamilton (1994)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e274" publication-type="other">
Jacobi, Learner and Ward (1979).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e290a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e294" publication-type="other">
Ahmed, M. Farid, Capital Markets and Institutions in Bangladesh: Some Implications of Japanese Experience,
Ashgate Publishing Ltd.: England, 1997.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e308" publication-type="other">
Ahmed, M. Farid, Khan, H.R. and Islam, M.S., Industrial Financing Through Capital Market in Bangladesh: A
Study on the Demand Side' Asia Foundation and Bureau of Economic Research, University of Dhaka:
Dhaka, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e321a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e325" publication-type="other">
Ando, A. And Modigliani, F, The Life Cycle Hypothesis of Saving: Aggregate Implications and tests' American
Economic Review, Vol. 53, No 1, 1963, pp. 55-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e339" publication-type="other">
Apte, Prakash G., 'Money, Stock Prices and Industrial Activity in India: Long-Run Relationships and Causa-
lity', Indian Economic Review, Vol. XXXII, July-Dec, 1997, pp. 179-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e350a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e354" publication-type="other">
Arena J., 'Postwar Stock Market Changes and Consumer Spending', Review of Economics and Statistics,
Vol. 47, No. 4, November, 1965, pp. 379-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e364a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e368" publication-type="other">
Bangladesh Bank, Economic Trends (monthly)- various issues, Bangladesh Bank: Dhaka.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e375a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e379" publication-type="other">
., Index Numbers of Stock Exchange Share Prices (quartely) - various issues, Bangladesh Bank:
Dhaka.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e389a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e393" publication-type="other">
Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics, Ministry of Planning, Government of Bangladesh, Statistical Yearbook of
Bangladesh - various issues, Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics: Dhaka.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e403a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e407" publication-type="other">
., Statistical Pocketbook - various issues, Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics: Dhaka.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e414a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e418" publication-type="other">
Batten, D.S. and Thorton, D.L., 'Log Length Selection and Granger Causality Between Money and Income',
Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, 1985, pp. 164-178.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e429a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e433" publication-type="other">
Baumol, W., Stock Market and Economic Efficiency, Fordham University Press: New York, 1965.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e440a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e444" publication-type="other">
Bhatia, K., 'Capital Gains and the Aggregate Consumption Function', American Economic Review, Vol. 62,
No. 13-15, 1972, pp. 866-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e454a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e458" publication-type="other">
Blume, M.E., Crockett, J. and Friend, I., 'Stockownership in the United States Characteristics and Trends',
Survey of Current Business, Vol. 54, 1974, pp. 16-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e468a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e472" publication-type="other">
Bosworth, B., 'The Stock Market and the Economy' Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Vol. 2, 1975, pp.
257-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e482a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e486" publication-type="other">
Brainard, W.C. and Tobin, J., 'Pitfalls in Financial Model Building', American Economic Review, Vol. 58, 1968,
pp. 99-122.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e496a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e500" publication-type="other">
Chen, Nai-Fu; Roll, R. and Ross, S.A., 'Economic Forces and Stock Market', Journal of Business, Vol. 59, No.
3, 1986, pp. 383-403.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e511a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e515" publication-type="other">
Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), DSE Factbook (various Issues), DSE: Dhaka.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e522a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e526" publication-type="other">
., DSE Monthly Review - various issues.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e533a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e537" publication-type="other">
Dow, J., And Gorton, G., 'Stock Market Efficiency and Economic Efficiency: Is There a Connection?, The Jour-
nal of Finance, Vol. Lll, July 1997, pp. 1087-1129.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e547a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e551" publication-type="other">
Drake, P.J., Money, Finance and Development, Martin Robertson: Oxford, 1980.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e558a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e562" publication-type="other">
Fazzari, S.M., Hub-bard, R.G. and Peterson, B.C., 'Financing Constraints and Corporate Investlent', Brookings
Papers on Economic Activity, Vol. I, 1988, pp. 141-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e572a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e576" publication-type="other">
Fiege, E. And Pearce, D., The Causal Relationship Between Money and Income: Some Caveats for Time Se-
ries Analysis', Review of Economics and Statistics, November, 1979, pp. 521-533.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e587a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e591" publication-type="other">
Friend, I. And Liebarman, C, 'Short-run Asset Effects on Household Saving and Consumption: The Cross-
section Evidence', American Economic Review, Vol. 65, 1975, pp. 624-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e601a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e605" publication-type="other">
Geweke, J., 'Measurement of Linear Dependenceand Feedback Between Multiple Time Series', Journal of
American Statistical Association, Vol. 77, June 1982, pp. 304-324.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e615a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e619" publication-type="other">
Goldfeld, S.N. and Blinder, A.S., 'Some Implications of Endogenous Stabilization Policy', Brookings Papers on
Economic Activity, 1972, pp. 585-640.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e629a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e633" publication-type="other">
Granger, C.W.J., 'Investigating Causal Relation by Economic Model and Cross Spectral Analysis' Econometri-
ca, Vol. 37, No. 3, 1969, pp. 424-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e643a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e647" publication-type="other">
.and Newbold, P., 'Spurious Regression in Econometrics' Journal of Econometrics, 1974, pp. 111-
120.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e657a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e661" publication-type="other">
Guilkey, D.K. and Salemi, M.K., 'Small Sample Properties of Three Tests for Granger - Causal Ordering in a
Bivariate Stochastic System', Review of Economics and Statistics, November, 1982, pp. 668-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e676" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, J.D., Time Series Analysis, Princeton University Press, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e687" publication-type="other">
Hymans, S.H., 'On the Use of Leading Indicators to Predict Cyclical Turning Points', Brookings Papers on
Economic Activity, 2, 1973, pp. 339-384.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e701" publication-type="other">
Jacobi, R.L.; Learner, E.E. and Ward, M.P., 'The Difficulties with Testing for Causation', Economic Inquiry, Vol.
17, 1979, pp. 401-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e715" publication-type="other">
Jorgenson, D., 'The Theory of Investment Behavior' in R. Ferber (ed.), Determinants of Investment Behavior,
Columbia University Press: New York, 1967, pp. 120-155.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e729" publication-type="other">
Keirstead, M., An Essay in the Theory of Profit and Income Distribution, Oxford: Blackwell, 1953.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e736a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e740" publication-type="other">
Keynes, J.M., The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money, Harcourt, Brace and Company, New
York, 1936.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e751a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e755" publication-type="other">
Khan, A.R., 'A Quarter Century of Economic Development in Bangladesh: Successes and Failures', The Ban-
gladesh Development Studies, Vol. XXIII, No. 3 &amp; 4, 1995, pp. 1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e765a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e769" publication-type="other">
.and Hossain, M., The Strategy of Development in Bangladesh, London, Macmillan, 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e776a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e780" publication-type="other">
Kitchen, R., Finance for the Developing Countries, Wiley and Sons: New York, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e791" publication-type="other">
Ministry of Finance, Govt. Of Bangladesh, Economic Survey of Bangladesh - various issues.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e798a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e802" publication-type="other">
Miller, M.H. and Modigliani, F., 'Dividend Policy, Growth and the Valuation of Shares', Journal of Business,
Vol. 34, No. 4, 1961, pp. 411-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e812a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e816" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F. And Miller, M.H., 'The Cost of Capital, Corporate Finance and the Theory of Investment', Ameri-
can Economic Review, Vol. 48, 1958, pp. 261-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e827a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e831" publication-type="other">
Mookerjee, R., 'The Stock Market and the Economy: The Indian Experience 1949-1981', The Indian Econo-
mic Journal, Vol. 36, No. 2, 1988, pp. 30-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e841a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e845" publication-type="other">
Moore, G.H., 'Stock Prices and the Business Cycle', Journal of Portfolio Management, Vol. 1, No. 3, 1975, pp.
59-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e855a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e859" publication-type="other">
.and Shiskin, J., Indicators of Business Expansion and Contractions, Occasional Paper No. 103, Co-
lumbia University Press for the National Bureau of Economic Research, 1967.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e869a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e873" publication-type="other">
Myers, S., 'Determinants of Corporate Borrowing', Journal of Financial Economics, Vol. 5, 1977, pp. 147-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e880a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e884" publication-type="other">
., 'The Capital Structure Puzzle', Journal of Finance, Vol. 39, No. 3, 1984, pp. 575-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e891a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e895" publication-type="other">
., 'Comment on Investment Patterns and Financial Leverage' in Friedman, B. (Ed.) Corporate Capital
Structure in the United States, University of Chicago Press, Chicago, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e906a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e910" publication-type="other">
.and Majluf, N.S., 'Corporate Financing and Investment Decisions When Firms Have Information that
Investors Do Not Have', Journal of Financial Economics, Vol. 13, 1984, pp. 187-21.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e924" publication-type="other">
Nishat, M. and Saghir, M., 'The Stock Market and Pakistan Economy', Savings and Development, Vol. 2, No.
XV, 1991, pp. 131-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e934a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e938" publication-type="other">
Pierce, D.K., 'Stock Prices and the Economy', Economic Review, Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City, No-
vember, 1983, pp. 7-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e948a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e952" publication-type="other">
Sims, C.H., 'Money Income and Causality', American Economic Review, September, 1972, pp. 540-552.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e959a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e963" publication-type="other">
Tobin, J., 'Ageneral Equilibrium Approach to Monetary Theory', Journal of Money Credit and Banking, Fe-
bruary, 1969, pp. 15-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e973a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e977" publication-type="other">
Wai, U.T. and Patrick, H.T., 'Stock and Bond Issues and Capital Markets in Less Developed Countries, IMF
Staff Papers, July, 1973, pp. 253-317.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e988a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e992" publication-type="other">
World Bank, Bangladesh Annual Economic Update: Recent Economic Development and Medium-Term
Reform Agenda, July Washington, D.C., 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e1002a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1006" publication-type="other">
Zamowitz, V. and Boschan, C. 'Cyclical Indicators: An Evaluation of New Leading Indexes', Business Condi-
tion Digest, 1975, pp. V-XIX.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


