<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278138</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Torque Converter Clutch Optimization</article-title>
            <subtitle>Improving Fuel Economy and Reducing Noise and Vibration</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Robinette</surname>
                  <given-names>Darrell</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Grimmer</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Horgan</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeremy</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kennell</surname>
                  <given-names>Jevon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Vykydal</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>General Motors Company</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>94</fpage>
         <lpage>105</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278138"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The torque converter and torque converter clutch are critical devices governing overall power transfer efficiency in automatic transmission powertrains. With calibrations becoming more aggressive to meet increasing fuel economy standards, the torque converter clutch is being applied over a wider range of driving conditions. At low engine speed and high engine torque, noise and vibration concerns originating from the driveline, powertrain or vehicle structure can supersede aggressive torque converter clutch scheduling. Understanding the torsional characteristics of the torque converter clutch and its interaction with the drivetrain can lead to a more robust design, operation in regions otherwise restricted by noise and vibration, and potential fuel economy improvement. The objective of this paper is to present a generalized integration summary for torque converter clutches (TCC) to enable aggressive apply at high engine torques and engine speeds below 1500 rpm without adversely affecting noise and vibration (N&amp;V) performance. The focus is on optimizing existing damper technologies found in a large percentage of current production automatic transmissions. The overall goal is to demonstrate that through proper hardware selection and TCC calibration, a balance between N&amp;V and fuel economy can be achieved. A validated lumped parameter modeling technique for optimizing torque converter clutch hardware that comprehends the complete powertrain and driveline system is used to investigate required TCC hardware. A torsional isolation metric across the powertrain is presented for comparing the performance of various damper designs. For operating points with inadequate isolation a controlled amount of slip across the torque converter clutch is required to increase isolation. An analytical methodology for minimizing the amount of slip required to satisfy noise and vibration targets and maximize fuel economy is reported. The effect of gear state, torque converter slip and power delivered to the driveline on fuel economy are also discussed based upon powertrain dynamometer measurements.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiramatsu, T., Akagi, T., and Yoneda, H., “Control Technology of Minimal Slip-Type Torque Converter Clutch,” SAE Technical Paper 850460, 1985, doi: 10.4271/850460.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abe, H., Tsuruoka, M., Muto, A., Kato, M. et al., “Development of Super Ultra Flat Torque Converter with Multi Plate Lock-up Clutch,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):48-55, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Otanez, P., Samie, F., Lee, C.J., and Kao, C.-K., “Aggressive Torque Converter Clutch Slip Control and Driveline Torsional Velocity Measurements,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):883-892, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1584.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, T., Song, J., Jang, J., and Joo, I., “Dynamic Analysis of Damper System in Torque Converter,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3749, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schwab, M., “Electronically-Controlled Transmission Systems - Current Position and Future Developments,” SAE Technical Paper 901156, 1990, doi: 10.4271/901156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hage, A., Szatkowski, A., and Li, Z., “Improving Low Frequency Torsional Vibrations NVH Performance through Analysis and Test,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-2242, SAE Transactions - Journal of Pass. Cars - Mech. Sys., 117, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-2242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jandasek, V. J., “The Design of a Single-Stage Three- Element Torque Converter,” SAE Technical Paper 610576, SAE Transactions - Design Practices: Pass. Car Auto., 3rd Ed., 1961, doi: 10.4271/610576.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice, “Hydrodynamic Drive Test Code,” SAE Standard J643, Reaf. April 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsangarides, M.C. and Tobler, W.E., “Dynamic Behavior of a Torque Converter with Centrifugal Bypass Clutch,” SAE Technical Paper, 850461, 1985, doi: 10.4271/850461.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogawa, H., Hayashi, E., Yoshida, O., Hayakawa, Y. et al., “Mechanism of Shudder Phenomena in Torque Converter and System Simulation Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0243, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
