<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023201</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>International Taxation, Lockout, and Jurisdictional Competition</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Foreign or Domestic Tax Havens</article-title>
            <subtitle>The Location Decision for Intangible Property by U.S. Firms</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lindsey</surname>
                  <given-names>Bradley P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>North Carolina State University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wilson</surname>
                  <given-names>Wendy M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Texas Christian University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>35</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023201"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This study examines the characteristics associated with the decision by U.S. firms to transfer ownership of intangible property to subsidiaries located in foreign and domestic tax havens. It is well-documented that U.S. firms take advantage of transfer pricing strategies to shift profits from high-tax jurisdictions to low or zero-tax jurisdictions, both in the foreign and domestic tax arenas. We acknowledge the reality that U.S. firms have a choice between transferring intangible assets to subsidiaries operating in tax havens overseas or at home in Delaware. Using Exhibit 21 data on the geographic location of the subsidiaries of U.S. firms, we model the firm-level characteristics that are associated with the use of tax haven jurisdictions. We find that U.S. firms with the greatest operational wherewithal and higher tax incentives to engage in profit shifting are more likely to locate corporate subsidiaries in domestic or foreign tax havens. In addition, we find that U.S. firms with higher U.S. federal marginal tax rates, greater free cash flow, and more foreign operations are more likely to have a subsidiary located in a foreign haven country. We do not find results consistent with the predicted associations between firm-level characteristics and the use of domestic haven subsidiaries, in that firms with greater average state tax rates are less likely to use a Delaware tax haven. This study is of interest to academic researchers and tax policymakers as it provides the first attempt to investigate the choice U.S. firms have to locate intangible assets in both foreign and domestic tax havens.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Campbell, J., D.Dhaliwal, L. Krull, and C. Schwab, C. 2014. US multinational corporations’ foreign cash holdings: an empirical estimate and its valuation consequences. Working paper, The University of Georgia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Daines, R.M. 2001. Does Delaware law improve firm value? Journal of Financial Economics 62, 525-558.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Simone, L. and B. Stomberg. 2013. Do investors differentially value tax avoidance of income mobile firms? Working paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, M., Foley, C., and J. Hines. 2006. The demand for tax haven operations. Journal of Public Economics, 90(3), 513-531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dischinger, M. and N. Riedel. 2011. Corporate taxes and the location of intangible assets within multinational firms. Journal of Public Economics, 95(7), 691-707.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donohoe, M., G. McGill, and E. Outslay. 2012. Through a glass darkly: What can we learn about a US multinational corporation's international operations from its financial statement disclosures? National Tax Journal, 65(4), 961-984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, S., M. Hanlon, and E. Maydew. 2008. Long Run Corporate Tax Avoidance. The Accounting Review 83: 61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, S., and B. Lindsey. 2009. Using financial accounting data to examine the effect of foreign operations located in tax havens and other countries on U.S. multinational firms’ tax rates. Journal of Accounting Research 47, 1283–1316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, S., B. Lindsey, and J. Thornock. 2013. Exploring the role Delaware plays as a domestic tax haven. Journal of Financial Economics 108:3, June 2013, 751 – 772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, J. 1996. Proxies for the Corporate Marginal Tax Rate. Journal of Financial Economics 42, 187-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grubert, H. 2003. Intangible income, Intercompany Transactions, Income Shifting, and the Choice of Location. National Tax Journal 56, 221-242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klassen, K. and S. Laplante. 2012. Are U.S. multinational corporations becoming more aggressive income shifters? Journal of Accounting Research 50, 1245–1285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markle, K. 2014. A comparison of the tax-Motivated income shifting of multinationals in territorial and worldwide countries. Working paper, The University of Iowa.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rego, S. 2003. Tax-avoidance activities of U.S. multinational corporations. Contemporary Accounting Research, 20(4), 805-833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
