<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i20869260</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">20869265</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Bank Mergers on Loan Prices: Evidence from the United States</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Isil</given-names>
                  <surname>Erel</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1068</fpage>
         <lpage>1101</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/20869265"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Bank mergers can increase or decrease loan spreads, depending on whether the increased market power outweighs efficiency gains. Using proprietary loan-level data for U.S. commercial banks, I find that, on average, mergers reduce loan spreads, with the magnitude of the reduction being larger when postmerger cost savings increase. My results suggest that the relation between spreads and the extent of the market overlap between merging banks is nonmonotonic. The market overlap increases cost savings and consequently lowers spreads, but when the overlap is sufficiently large, spreads increase, potentially due to the market-power effect dominating the cost savings. Furthermore, the average reduction in spreads is significant for small businesses.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d105e217a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e224" publication-type="other">
Akhavein, Berger, and Humphrey (1997)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e230" publication-type="other">
Berger, Demsetz, and Strahan (1999)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e236" publication-type="other">
Walter
(2004)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d105e246a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e253" publication-type="other">
Farrell and Shapiro (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d105e260a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e267" publication-type="other">
Park and Pennacchi (2009)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d105e274a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e281" publication-type="other">
Petersen (2009)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d105e289a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e296" publication-type="other">
Houston and Ryngaert (1997)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e302" publication-type="other">
DeLong (1998)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e308" publication-type="other">
Kane (2000)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e315" publication-type="other">
Houston, James, and Ryngaert (2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e321" publication-type="other">
Penas and Unal (2004)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d105e328a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e335" publication-type="other">
Houston and Ryngaert (1997)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d105e341" publication-type="other">
Houston, James, and Ryngaert (2001)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d105e357a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e361" publication-type="other">
Akhavein, J. D., A. N. Berger, and D. B. Humphrey. 1997. The Effects of Mega-Mergers on Efficiency and
Prices: Evidence from a Bank Profit Function. Review of Industrial Organization 12:95-139.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e375" publication-type="other">
Andrade, G., M. Mitchell, and E. Stafford. 2001. New Evidence and Perspectives on Mergers. Journal of
Economic Perspectives 15:103-20.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e385a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e389" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., R. Demsetz, and P. Strahan. 1999. The Consolidation of Financial Services Industry: Causes,
Consequences, and Implications for the Future. Journal of Banking and Finance 23:135-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e399a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e403" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., W. S. Frame, and N. H. Miller. 2005. Credit Scoring and the Availability, Price, and Risk of Small
Business Credit. Journal of Money, Credit and Banking 37:191-222.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e414a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e418" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., A. K. Kashyap, and J. M. Scalise. 1995. The Transformation of the US Banking Industry: What a
Long, Strange Trip It's Been. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 4:55-218.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e428a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e432" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., N. H. Miller, M. A. Petersen, R. G. Rajan, and J. C. Stein. 2005. Does Functional Form Follow
Organizational Form? Evidence from the Lending Practices of Large and Small Banks. Journal of Financial
Economics 76:237-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e445a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e449" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., R. J. Rosen, and G. F. Udell. 2001. The Effect of Market Size Structure on Competition: The Case
of Small Business Lending. Proceedings of the 37th Annual Conference on Bank Structure and Competition,
Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e462a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e466" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., A. Saunders, J. M. Scalise, and G. F. Udell. 1998. The Effects of Bank Mergers and Acquisitions
on Small Business Lending. Journal of Financial Economics 50:187-229.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e476a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e480" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., and G. F. Udell. 1990. Collateral, Loan Quality, and Bank Risk. Journal of Monetary Economics
25:21-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e490a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e494" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., and G. F. Udell. 1996. Universal Banking and Future of Small Business Lending. In A. Saunders
and I. Walter (eds.), Financial System Design: The Case for Universal Banking. Homewood, IL: Irwin Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e505a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e509" publication-type="other">
Berger, A. N., and G. F. Udell. 2002. Small Business Credit Availability and Relationship Lending: The Impor-
tance of Bank Organizational Structure. Economic Journal 112:F32-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e519a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e523" publication-type="other">
Black, S. E., and P. Strahan. 2002. Entrepreneurship and Bank Credit Availability. Journal of Finance 57:2807-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e530a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e534" publication-type="other">
Bonaccorsi di Patti, E., and G. Gobbi. 2007. Winners or Losers? The Effect of Banking Consolidation on
Borrowers. Journal of Finance 62:669-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e548" publication-type="other">
Cole, R. A., L. G. Goldberg, and L. J. White. 2004. Cookie-Cutter versus Character: The Microstructure of
Small-business Lending by Large and Small Banks. Journal of Financial &amp; Quantitative Analysis 39:227-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e558a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e562" publication-type="other">
Calomiris, C. W., and J. Karceski. 2000. Is the Bank Merger Wave of the 1990s Efficient? Lessons from Nine
Case Studies. In S. Kaplan (ed.), Mergers and Productivity. NBER, IL: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e572a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e576" publication-type="other">
Calomiris, C. W., and T. Pornrojnangkool. 2005. Monopoly-Creating Bank Consolidation? The Merger of Fleet
and BankBoston. NBER Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e587a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e591" publication-type="other">
Correa, R. 2007. Bank Integration and Financial Constraints: Evidence from U.S. Firms. Board of Governors of
the Federal Reserve System Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e601a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e605" publication-type="other">
Degryse, H., N. Masschelein, and J. Mitchell. 2005. SMEs and Bank Relationships: The Impact of Mergers.
CEPR Discussion Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e615a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e619" publication-type="other">
DeLong, G. L. 1998. Domestic and International Bank Mergers: The Gains from Focusing vs. Diversifying, PhD
Thesis, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e629a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e633" publication-type="other">
DeYoung, R., D. Glennon, and P. Nigro. 2008. Borrower-Lender Distance, Credit Scoring, and the Performance
of Small Business Loans. Journal of Financial Intermediation 17:113-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e643a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e647" publication-type="other">
Drucker, S. 2005. Information Asymmetries and the Effects of Banking Mergers on Firm-Bank Relationships.
Columbia Business School Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e657a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e661" publication-type="other">
Farrell, J., and C. Shapiro. 1990. Horizontal Mergers: An Equilibrium Analysis. American Economic Review
80:107-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e676" publication-type="other">
Focarelli, D., and F. Panetta. 2003. Are Mergers Beneficial to Consumers? Evidence from the Market for Bank
Deposits. American Economic Review 93:1152-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e686a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e690" publication-type="other">
Garmaise, M. J., and T. J. Moskowitz. 2006. Bank Mergers and Crime: The Real and Social Effects of Credit
Market Competition. Journal of Finance 61:495-538.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e700a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e704" publication-type="other">
Hannan, T. H., and R. A. Prager. 1998. Do Substantial Horizontal Mergers Generate Significant Price Effects?
Evidence from the Banking Industry. Journal of Industrial Economics 46:433-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e714a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e718" publication-type="other">
Houston, J. F., C. M. James, and M. D. Ryngaert. 2001. Where Do Merger Gains Come from? Bank Mergers
from the Perspectives of Insiders and Outsiders. Journal of Financial Economics 60:285-331.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e728a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e732" publication-type="other">
Houston, J. F., and M. D. Ryngaert. 1994. The Overall Gains from Large Bank Mergers. Journal of Banking and
Finance 18:1155-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e742a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e746" publication-type="other">
Houston, J. F., and M. D. Ryngaert. 1997. Equity Issuance and Adverse Selection: A Direct Test Using Conditional
Stock Offers. Journal of Finance 52:197-219.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e761" publication-type="other">
James, C., and P. Wier. 1987. Returns to Acquirers and Competition in the Acquisition Market: The Case of
Banking. Journal of Political Economy 95:355-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e771a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e775" publication-type="other">
Jayaratne, J., and P. E. Strahan. 1998. Entry Restrictions, Industry Evolution and Dynamic Efficiency: Evidence
from Commercial Banking. Journal of Law and Economics 41:239-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e785a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e789" publication-type="other">
Kahn, C., G. Pennacchi, and B. J. Sopranzetti. 2005. Bank Consolidation and the Dynamics of Consumer Loan
Interest Rates. Journal of Business 78:99-134.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e799a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e803" publication-type="other">
Kane, E. J. 2000. Incentives for Banking Megamergers: What Motives Might Regulators Infer from Event Study
Evidence? Journal of Money, Credit and Banking 32:671-701.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e813a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e817" publication-type="other">
Karceski, J., S. Ongena, and D. C. Smith. 2005. The Impact of Bank Consolidation on Commercial Borrower
Welfare. Journal of Finance 60:2043-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e827a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e831" publication-type="other">
Kroszner, R. S., and R Strahan. 1999. What Drives Deregulation? Economics and Politics of the Relaxation of
Bank Branching Restrictions. Quarterly Journal of Economics 114:1437-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e842a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e846" publication-type="other">
Mulherin, H. J., and A. L. Boone. 2000. Comparing Acquisitions and Divestitures. Journal of Corporate Finance
6:117-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e856a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e860" publication-type="other">
Park, K., and G. Pennacchi. 2009. Harming Depositors and Helping Borrowers: The Disparate Impact of Bank
Consolidation. Review of Financial Studies 22:1-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e870a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e874" publication-type="other">
Peek, J., and E. S. Rosengren. 1996. Small Business Credit Availability: How Important Is Size of Lender. In
A. Saunders and Ingo Walter (eds.), Financial System Design: The Case for Universal Banking. Homewood, IL:
Irwin Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e887a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e891" publication-type="other">
Penas, M. F., and H. Unal. 2004. Gains in Bank Mergers: Evidence from Bond Markets. Journal of Financial
Economics 74:149-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e901a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e905" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M. 2009. Estimating Standard Errors in Finance Panel Data Sets: Comparing Approaches. Review of
Financial Studies 22:435-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e915a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e919" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M., and R. G. Rajan. 1994. The Benefits of Lending Relationships: Evidence from Small Business
Data. Journal of Finance 49:3-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e930a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e934" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M., and R. G. Rajan. 1995. The Effect of Credit Market Competition on Lending Relationships. The
Quarterly Journal of Economics 110:407-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e944a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e948" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M., and R. G. Rajan. 2002. Does Distance Still Matter? The Information Revolution in Small Business
Lending. Journal of Finance 57:2533-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e958a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e962" publication-type="other">
Sapienza, P. 2002. The Effects of Banking Mergers on Loan Contracts. Journal of Finance 57:329-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e969a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e973" publication-type="other">
Stein, J. 2002. Information Production and Capital Allocation: Decentralized versus Hierarchical Firms. Journal
of Finance 57:1891-921.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e983a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e987" publication-type="other">
Strahan, P. E., and J. P. Weston. 1998. Small Business Lending and the Changing Structure of the Banking
Industry. Journal of Banking and Finance 22:821-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e997a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e1001" publication-type="other">
Walter, I. 2004. Mergers and Acquisitions in Banking and Finance: What Works, What Fails, and Why. New
York: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e1012a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e1016" publication-type="other">
Williamson, O. E. 1968. Economics as an Anti-trust Defense: The Welfare Tradeoffs. American Economic Review
58:18-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e1026a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e1030" publication-type="other">
Williamson, O. E. 1975. Markets and Hierarchies: Analysis and Antitrust Implications. New York: Collier
Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d105e1040a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d105e1044" publication-type="other">
Zarutskie, R. 2006. Evidence on the Effects of Bank Competition on Firm Borrowing and Investment. Journal
of Financial Economics 81:503-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


