<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26840427</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Performance, Fuel Economy, and Economic Assessment of a Combustion Concept Employing In-Cylinder Gasoline/Natural Gas Blending for Light-Duty Vehicle Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wallner</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pamminger</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Scarcelli</surname>
                  <given-names>Riccardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Powell</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Simeu</surname>
                  <given-names>Severin Kamguia</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wooldridge</surname>
                  <given-names>Steven</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boyer</surname>
                  <given-names>Brad</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iqbal</surname>
                  <given-names>Asim</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reese</surname>
                  <given-names>Ron</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26840424</issue-id>
         <fpage>271</fpage>
         <lpage>290</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26840427"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In current production natural gas/gasoline bi-fuel vehicles, fuels are supplied via port fuel injection (PFI). Injecting a gaseous fuel in the intake port significantly reduces the volumetric efficiency and consequently torque as compared to gasoline. In addition to eliminating the volumetric efficiency challenge, direct injection (DI) of natural gas (NG) can enhance the in-cylinder flow, mixing, and combustion process resulting in improved efficiency and performance.</p>
            <p>A computational fluid dynamics (CFD) approach to model high-pressure gaseous injection was developed and validated against X-ray data from Argonne’s Advanced Photon Source. NG side and central DI of various designs and injection strategies were assessed experimentally along with CFD correlation. Significant effects on combustion metrics were quantified and explained via improved understanding of the in-cylinder flow effects due to NG injection.</p>
            <p>On-demand in-cylinder blending using E10 PFI and NG DI provides an additional lever to adjust in-cylinder turbulence as well as knock resistance across the engine speed and load range. NG DI improves part-load dilution tolerance due to higher in-cylinder turbulence and the high knock resistance of NG compared to E10 improves wide open throttle (WOT) performance while enabling increased compression ratios (CR).</p>
            <p>Vehicle level simulations suggest that implementing this strategy on a ½ ton pick-up truck with a naturally aspirated engine at 12.5:1 CR improves energy consumption on the aggressive US06 drive cycle by 15.5% compared to E10 operation, and gives a petroleum reduction of 78% over the blended range.</p>
            <p>There are challenges regarding market acceptance and widespread adoption of dual-fuel NG-gasoline vehicle applications beyond the performance degradation when the vehicle runs out of natural gas. Those challenges include practical concerns such as loss of cargo volume and payload due to the NG storage tank, extended NG refueling times, fueling convenience due to gasoline and NG fuel tanks, and limited NG fueling infrastructure.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">U.S. Energy Information Administration, “Annual Energy Outlook 2017 with Projections to 2050”.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Pipitone, E. and Beccari, S., “Performance Improvements of a S. I. CNG Bi-Fuel Engine by Means of Double-Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0058, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0058.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Obiols, J., Soleri, D., Dioc, N., and Moreau, M., “Potential of Concomitant Injection of CNG and Gasoline on a 1.6L Gasoline Direct Injection Turbocharged Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1995, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Shiga, S., Araki, M., Obokata, T., Huang, Z. et al., “Basic Aspect of Combustion of CNG Incylinder Direct-Injection with Spark-Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-26-352, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-26-352.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Kalam, M., Masjuki, H., Mahlia, T., Fuad, M. et al., “Experimental Test of a New Compressed Natural Gas Engine with Direct Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1967, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Douailler, B., Ravet, F., Delpech, V., Soleri, D. et al., “Direct Injection of CNG on High Compression Ratio Spark Ignition Engine: Numerical and Experimental Investigation,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0923, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">http://automobiles.honda.com/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Anderson, J., Miers, S., Wallner, T., Stutenberg, K. et al., “Performance and Efficiency Assessment of a Production CNG Vehicle Compared to Its Gasoline Counterpart,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-2694, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Szybist, J. and Splitter, D., “Effects of Fuel Composition on EGR Dilution Tolerance in Spark Ignited Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):819-831, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0715.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Wimmer, A., Wallner, T., Ringler, J., and Gerbig, F., “H2-Direct Injection - A Highly Promising Combustion Concept,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0108, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Ferrera, M., “Integrated GAS Powertrain - Low Emissions, CO2 Optimised and Efficient CNG Engines for Passenger Cars (PC) and Light Duty Vehicles (LDV),” Project Final Report, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Volkswagen, A.G., “EcoFuel Natural Gas Drive with 1.4l 110kW TSI Engine,” Service Training, Self-study Porgramme 425, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">FY 2014 Vehicle Technologies Program Wide Funding Opportunity Announcement (FOA) Number: DEFOA- 0000991, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Husted, H. et al, “Direct Injection of CNG for Driving Performance with Low CO2,” in 23rd Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Bartolucci, L., Scarcelli, R., Wallner, T., Swantek, A. et al., “CFD and X-Ray Analysis of Gaseous Direct Injection from an Outward Opening Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0850, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0850.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Swantek, A., Duke, D., Kastengren, A., Sovis, N. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Gas Fuel Injection with X-ray Radiography,” Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 87:15-29, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Sevik, J., Pamminger, M., Wallner, T., Scarcelli, R. et al., “Performance, Efficiency and Emissions Assessment of Natural Gas Direct Injection compared to Gasoline and Natural Gas Port-Fuel Injection in an Automotive Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):1130-1142, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Pamminger, M., Wallner, T., Sevik, J., Scarcelli, R. et al. “Performance, Efficiency and Emissions Evaluation of Gasoline Port-Fuel Injection, Natural Gas Direct Injection and Blended Operation,” in ASME Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, doi:10.1115/ ICEF2016-9370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Sevik, J., Pamminger, M., Wallner, T., Scarcelli, R. et al., “Influence of Injector Location on Part-Load Performance Characteristics of Natural Gas Direct-Injection in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(4):2262-2271, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2364.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Caton, J.A., “Thermodynamic Considerations Regarding the Use of EGR for Conventional and High Efficiency Engines,” in ASME Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, ASME 2016 Internal Combustion Engine, 2016</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Gerty, M. and Heywood, J., “An Investigation of Gasoline Engine Knock Limited Performance and the Effects of Hydrogen Enhancement,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0228, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Pamminger, M., Sevik, J., Scarcelli, R., Wallner, T. et al., “Influence of Compression Ratio on High Load Performance and Knock Behavior for Gasoline Port-Fuel Injection, Natural Gas Direct Injection and Blended Operation in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0661, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0661.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">https://www.autonomie.net/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Moawad, A., Kim, N., Shidore, N., and Rousseau, A., “Assessment of Vehicle Sizing, Energy Consumption and Cost through Large Scale Simulation of Advanced Vehicle Technologies,” Report to the US Department of Energy, Report ANL/ESD-15/28, March 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">U.S. Department of Energy, Clean Cities Alternative Fuel Price Report, July 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">SAE International J2841_201009, “Utility Factor Definitions for Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles Using Travel Survey Data,” https://doi.org/10.4271/J2841_201009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Ratio of Brent crude oil price to Henry Hub spot natural gas price in energy-equivalent terms, 2000-2050 [1]. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Single-cylinder research engine specifications 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Cylinder head rendering. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Fuel specifications 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Validation of CFD results against X-ray data at free (left) and impinging (right) jet conditions (injection pressure = 15 bar, ambient pressure = 1 bar, for both conditions). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Effect of the minimum mesh size on the accuracy of CFD results. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Evaluation of mixture homogeneity and turbulent kinetic energy during compression for side and central DI. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Comparison of in-cylinder gas jet development for side and central DI configurations (outward opening injector) as well as central DI with multi-hole injector tips (3 holes with an angle of 45° and 60° with respect to the injector axis). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Evaluation of mixture homogeneity and turbulent kinetic energy during compression for three central DI configurations (outward, 3 holes at 45°, and 3 holes at 60°). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Experimental matrix 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Effect of mixture stratification (equivalence ratio distribution) at spark timing on indicated efficiency, for side and central DI at three different SOI values (300, 240, and 120). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Effect of turbulence (turbulent kinetic energy distribution) at spark timing on flame development angle, for side and central DI at three different SOI values (300, 240, and 120). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>ITE and EGR dilution tolerance for NG DI injector in the side location (w/ and w/o tumble plates) and NG DI injector in the central location (w/o tumbles plates w/ insert, w/ tumble plates w/o insert, w/ tumble plates w/o insert). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>ITE and IMEP at WOT operation for different injector locations and turbulence ratios. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Influence of blend ratio on part load performance and EGR dilution tolerance with NG DI injector in the side location w/o tumble plates. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Influence of blend ratio on attainable WOT efficiency and IMEP as a function of compression ratio. The black dashed line in the bottom plot indicates the knock threshold of 1bar. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Indicated efficiency map showing efficiency and peak load improvements with optimal NG/E10 blend at 12.5:1 CR compared to E10 baseline at 10.5:1 CR. Low and part load engine conditions (3.2bar and 5.6bar) were operated with EGR at a predetermined COV<sub>IMEP</sub> limit around 3%. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Indicated efficiency map showing efficiency and peak load improvements with optimal NG/E10 blend at 14.5:1 CR compared to E10 baseline at 10.5:1 CR. Low and part load engine conditions (3.2 bar and 5.6 bar) were operated with EGR at a predetermined COV<sub>IMEP</sub> limit around 3%. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Vehicle specifications for sedan and pick-up truck 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Fuel levels and cumulative energy consumption benefits as a function of distance traveled on HWFET cycle for the pick-up truck. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Range, petroleum reduction, and energy consumption improvement for a pick-up truck with 10% NG tank size by energy across drive cycles compared to operation on 100% E10 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Incremental cost estimate for CNG tank and fuel system components as a function of vehicle type and tank size. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Incremental cost per mile as a function of distance traveled for E10 baseline and blended strategy on HWFET cycle for a pick-up truck. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Incremental cost of ownership for the E10 baseline case for a pick-up truck on HWFET cycle (top) and cost ratio of driving between the optimum blend case and E10 (bottom). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Cost ratio, optimum blend case vs E10 baseline for a pick-up truck on HWFET cycle. Total distance traveled vs CNG tank cost. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Fuel efficiency maps for E10 PFI, 25, 50, 75% blend ratio as well as 100% NG DI with injector in the side location at CR 10.5, 12.5, and 14.5:1. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.2</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Incremental cost per mile as a function of distance traveled for E10 baseline and blended strategy on HWFET cycle for a sedan. 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE A.1</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Range, petroleum reduction, and energy consumption improvement for a sedan with 10% NG tank size by energy across drive cycles compared to operation on 100% E10 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE A.3</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Incremental cost of ownership for the E10 baseline case for a sedan on HWFET cycle (top) and cost ratio of driving between the optimum blend case and E10 (bottom). 2019 Argonne National Laboratory; FCA US LLC; Ford Motor Company</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
