<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440239</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Public Investment under Fiscal Constraints</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Emanuele</given-names>
                  <surname>Bacchiocchi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Elisa</given-names>
                  <surname>Borghi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Alessandro</given-names>
                  <surname>Missale</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">32</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440236</issue-id>
         <fpage>11</fpage>
         <lpage>42</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2011 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440239"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The new member states (NMS) of the European Union must comply with the Stability and Growth Pact (SGP) and the investment goals implied by the Lisbon Agenda. However, the SGP rules may result in underinvestment or distortions in the allocation of public expenditure. This paper provides new evidence on the effects of debt sustainability and the SGP fiscal constraints on government expenditure on fixed capital, education and health in OECD countries by estimating government expenditure reaction functions to public debt and cyclical conditions. We find that, at high levels of debt, government capital expenditure and education expenditure are significantly reduced as the debt ratio increases in all OECD countries independently of EMU (or EU) membership. By contrast, neither capital expenditure nor education expenditure is affected by the debt ratio in low-debt countries. These findings are robust to the inclusion of the government deficit in the estimated reaction functions. Hence, it appears that EU countries have been constrained in their investment decisions more by the need to ensure debt sustainability than by the rules of the SGP. In low-debt NMS countries, public investment even increases with the debt ratio, a finding that is reassuring for their growth prospects. However, a less optimistic picture emerges when we focus on expenditures on public health and education, as it appears that NMS governments cut such expenditures – even at low levels of debt – as the deficit increases. Problems in controlling total expenditure together with the preventive arm of the SGP may have penalised investment in human capital in the NMS while leaving fixed capital investment unaffected.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e211a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e218" publication-type="other">
Submitted April 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e225a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e232" publication-type="other">
For details on the SGP, see http://ec.europa.eu/economv finance/sgp/index en.htm.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e239a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e246" publication-type="other">
Afonso and Alves (2006) argue that in catching-up economies, under certain conditions, running
higher deficits can help ensure convergence.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e256a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e263" publication-type="other">
Composition effects of budget cuts on economic growth were first investigated by Alesina and Perotti
(1996). They show that fiscal adjustments occurring with a reduction in public investment are more likely
to be soon reversed, while adjustments through cuts in transfers and social security last longer and have a
growth-enhancing effect.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e280a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e287" publication-type="other">
A similar approach has been applied by Buti, Franco and Ongena (1997) to study the effect of cyclical
downturns on the fiscal policy adopted by EU-15 member states in the presence of the SGP. They show
that during periods of severe recession, defined as a fall in GDP by at least 0.75 per cent, countries with
higher debt and deficit ratios actually tighten their fiscal policy by reducing their structural primary
deficits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e306a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e313" publication-type="other">
If a distortionary tax rate on private income, R W, were considered, an externality would be introduced
into the model that would lead to lower private capital accumulation than would otherwise be optimal. In
this case, a welfare-maximising government would choose public capital so as to raise the ratio of public
relative to private capital in order to increase the marginal product of private capital and partly offset the
negative effect of the tax rate on consumption growth.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e332a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e339" publication-type="other">
The present-value Hamiltonian is equal to
H, =u(C,)e-BI + Â,(Kl~aK^ -C,-G-I0)e'a + A,q,(&lt;/)IG)e~ei.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e349a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e356" publication-type="other">
To cast the analysis in the most favourable conditions for public capital, we assume that the public-
capital share of income, RgKo, is earned by the government - i.e. the return on public capital adds to
government revenues - unlike in the growth models stemming from Barro (1990). This is a reasonable
hypothesis in the case of physical but not human capital.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e372a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e379" publication-type="other">
To obtain equation (17), note that g and q are functions oiK^Y.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e386a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e393" publication-type="other">
This is purely indicative, since a balanced growth path model requires that growth be strictly positive.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e401a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e408" publication-type="other">
Following Gall and Perotti (2003), we exclude in both cases net capital transfers (capital transfers
payable less receivable).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e418a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e425" publication-type="other">
We did not use central government debt because of significant differences in the levels of
government across OECD countries. However, we obtained very similar results when, as a robustness
check, we estimated the panel using central government debt. It is worth noting that data from other
sources, such as the Inter-American Development Bank (IADB), are also for central government debt (see
Jaimovich and Panizza (2010)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e444a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e451" publication-type="other">
It is worth noting that gross capital formation is under the government's control; unlike taxes and
social expenditures, it is not a cyclical component of the government budget.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e461a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e468" publication-type="other">
The OECD overestimates US government financial liabilities because it counts the holdings of non-
marketable government securities (7.6 per cent of GDP in 2005) by government employee pension funds
as a liability of the government sector on the basis that these schemes are partially funded and, as such,
included in the private sector (see OECD 2009 Economic Outlook, annex tables 32 and 33).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e484a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e491" publication-type="other">
In particular, Finland and Ireland would be classified as low-debt countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e498a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e505" publication-type="other">
See Gali and Perotti (2003) for a detailed discussion of this issue.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e513a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e520" publication-type="other">
The deficit is measured as net borrowing (from OECD National Accounts), which is the relevant
definition for the SGP. It is the only variable not in logs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e530a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e537" publication-type="other">
interestingly, when the output gap is used in place of GDP growth in order to capture a possible
reaction to cyclical downturns, a significant countercyclical reaction of capital expenditure (relative to
trend GDP) is detected for both groups of highly indebted countries (see column 6).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e550a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e557" publication-type="other">
It is, however, worth noting that no reaction of capital expenditure to the deficit is observed for low-
debt EU member states (see columns 7 and 8 of Table 3).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e567a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e574" publication-type="other">
We do not present estimates with a time trend as the latter turned out to be not significant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e581a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e588" publication-type="other">
The elasticity of education expenditure to total expenditure is less than 1 (see column 8).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d29e604a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e608" publication-type="other">
Afonso, O. and Alves, R. H. (2006), 'To deficit or not to deficit: should European fiscal rules
differ among countries?', Universidade do Porto, Faculdade de Economia do Porto (FEP),
Working Paper no. 219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e621a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e625" publication-type="other">
Agenor, P. R. and Neanidis, K. C. (2006), 'The allocation of public expenditure and economic
growth', University of Manchester, School of Economics, Discussion Paper no. 0608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e635a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e639" publication-type="other">
Alesina, A. and Perotti, R. (1996), 'Fiscal adjustments in OECD countries: composition and
macroeconomic effects', National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper
no. 5730.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e652a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e656" publication-type="other">
Balassone, F. and Franco, D. (2000), 'Public investment, the Stability Pact and the "golden
rule'", Fiscal Studies, vol. 21, pp. 207-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e667a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e671" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J. (1990), 'Government spending in a simple model of endogenous growth', Journal
of Political Economy, vol. 98, pp. S103-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e681a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e685" publication-type="other">
Bassanini, A. and Scarpetta, S. (2001), 'Does human capital matter for growth in OECD
countries? A pooled mean-group approach', Economics Letters, vol. 74, pp. 399—405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e695a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e699" publication-type="other">
Benhabib, J. and Spiegel, M. M. (1994), 'The role of human capital in economic
development: evidence from aggregate cross-country data', Journal of Monetary
Economics, vol. 34, pp. 143-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e712a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e716" publication-type="other">
Blanchard, O. and Giavazzi, F. (2004), 'Improving the SGP through a proper accounting of
public investment', Centre for Economic Policy Research (CEPR), Discussion Paper no.
4220; reproduced in G. Perry, L. Servén and R. Suescün (eds), Fiscal Policy,
Stabilization, and Growth, Washington, DC: World Bank, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e736" publication-type="other">
Bloom, D. E., Canning, D. and Sevilla, J. (2004), 'The effect of health on economic growth: a
production function approach', World Development, vol. 32, pp. 1-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e746a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e750" publication-type="other">
Buiter, W. H. (1984), 'Measuring aspects of fiscal and financial policy', National Bureau of
Economic Research (NBER), Working Paper no. 1332.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e761a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e765" publication-type="other">
— (1997), 'Aspects of fiscal performance in some transition economies under Fund-supported
programs', International Monetary Fund (IMF), Working Paper no. 97/31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e775a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e779" publication-type="other">
Buti, M., Franco, D. and Ongena, H. (1997), 'Budgetary policies during recessions:
retrospective application of the Stability and Growth Pact to the post-war period',
Recherches Economiques de Louvain, vol. 63, pp. 321-66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e792a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e796" publication-type="other">
De la Fuente, A. and Ciccone, A. (2003), 'Human capital in a global and knowledge-based
economy', Unitat de Fonaments de l'Anàlisi Econômica (UAB) and Institut d'Anàlisi
Econômica (CSIC), UFAE and IAE Working Paper no. 562.03.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e809a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e813" publication-type="other">
—, Domenech, R. and Jimeno, J. F. (2003), 'Human capital as a factor of growth and
employment at the regional level: the case of Spain', Unitat de Fonaments de l'Anàlisi
Econômica (UAB) and Institut d'Anàlisi Econômica (CSIC), UFAE and IAE Working
Paper no. 610.04.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e829a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e833" publication-type="other">
Easterly, W. (1999), 'When is fiscal adjustment an illusion?', World Bank Policy Research
Working Paper no. 2109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e843a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e847" publication-type="other">
—, Irwin, T. and Servén, L. (2008), 'Walking up the down escalator: public investment and
fiscal stability', World Bank Policy Research Working Paper no. 4158, World Bank
Research Observer, vol. 23, pp. 37-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e861a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e865" publication-type="other">
Florio, M. (2004), The Great Divestiture: Evaluating the Welfare Impact of British
Privatizations 1979-1997, Cambridge: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e875a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e879" publication-type="other">
— (2007), 'A note on privatization and public sector net worth: what (not) to learn from the
UK experience', Université degli Studi di Milano, Dipartimento di Scienze Economiche
Aziendali Statistiche (DEAS), Working Paper no. 2007-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e892a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e896" publication-type="other">
Gall, J. and Perotti, R. (2003), 'Fiscal policy and monetary integration in Europe', Economic
Policy, vol. 18, pp. 533-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e906a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e910" publication-type="other">
Hanushek, E. A. (2002), 'Publicly provided education', in A. Auerbach and M. Feldstein
(eds), Handbook of Public Economics, Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e920a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e924" publication-type="other">
Jaimovich, D. and Panizza, U. (2010), 'Public debt around the world: a new data set of central
government debt', Applied Economics Letters, vol. 17, pp. 19-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e934a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e938" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. E. (1988), 'On the mechanics of economic development', Journal of Monetary
Economics, vol. 22, pp. 3—42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e949a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e953" publication-type="other">
McMahon, W. H. (1999), Education and Development: Measuring the Social Benefits,
Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e963a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e967" publication-type="other">
Orbàn, G. and Szapàry, G. (2004), 'The Stability and Growth Pact from the perspective of the
new member states', Journal of Policy Modeling, vol. 26, pp. 839-64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e977a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e981" publication-type="other">
Rivera, B. and Currais, L. (1999), 'Economic growth and health: direct impact or reverse
causation?', Applied Economics Letters, vol. 6, pp. 761-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e991a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e995" publication-type="other">
Sawyer, M. (2011), 'Budget deficits, public debt and the level of public investment', in M.
Florio (ed.), Public Investment, Growth, and Fiscal Constraints, Cheltenham: Edward
Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
