<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007101</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Wind Tunnel Testing of Airfoils for Wind Turbine Applications</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kuester</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Brown</surname>
                  <given-names>Kenneth</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Meyers</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Intaratep</surname>
                  <given-names>Nanyaporn</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Borgoltz</surname>
                  <given-names>Aurélien</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Devenport</surname>
                  <given-names>William J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Department of Aerospace and Ocean Engineering, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, VA</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>6</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007095</issue-id>
         <fpage>651</fpage>
         <lpage>660</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007101"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Accurate wind tunnel measurements of the lift and drag of airfoil sections are critical for the design and performance evaluation of wind turbine blades. As blades continue to increase in size, the demand for highly accurate wind tunnel results at progressively larger Reynolds numbers has also increased. Performing these wind tunnel measurements requires precise experimental control, and three challenges for these measurements are model surface quality, pressure tap effects, and model deflections under aerodynamic loading. These challenges were systematically studied in the Virginia Tech Stability Wind Tunnel using a DU96-W-180 airfoil geometry at a chord Reynolds number (Re<sub>c</sub>) of 3.0 x 10<sup>6</sup>. Naphthalene sublimation showed turbulent wedges caused by surface imperfections; removing these imperfections increased the lift curve slope by 3%. Pressure tap diameter effects were investigated by placing taps of varying size at the same chord location on the airfoil. These measurements showed a steady pressure bias correlated to tap diameter when making measurements in turbulent boundary layers, and naphthalene visualizations showed a turbulent wedge created by pressure taps at the leading edge. Finally, laser distance sensors were used to measure model deflections/rotations under aerodynamic loading, improving upon the traditional angle of attack measurement. Addressing these challenges has improved the accuracy of lift measurements in the Stability Wind Tunnel and emphasized the need for precise experimental controls when performing these types of wind tunnel measurements.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCroskey, W. J. A critical assessment of wind tunnel results for the NACA 0012 airfoil. Technical report, DTIC Document, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Niels Troldborg, Christian Bak, Helge Aagaard Madsen, and Witold Robert Skrzypinski. DAN-AERO MW: Final Report. Technical report, DTU Wind Energy, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">William J. Devenport, Ricardo A. Burdisso, Aurelien Borgoltz, Patricio A. Ravetta, Matthew F. Barone, Kenneth A. Brown, and Michael A. Morton. The kevlar-walled anechoic wind tunnel. Journal of Sound and Vibration, 332(17): 3971–3991, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kenneth Brown, William Devenport, and Aurélien Borgoltz. Exploiting the characteristics of kevlar-wall wind tunnels for conventional aerodynamic measurements. AIAA Paper 2014–2110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">WA Timmer and AP Schaffarczyk. The effect of roughness at high reynolds numbers on the performance of du 97-w-300mod. In Proceedings of the conference The Science of making Torque from Wind, pages 71–77, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Freudenreich, Kaiser, Schaffarczyk, Winkler, and Stahl. Reynolds number and roughness effects on thick airfoils for wind turbines. Wind Engineering, 28(5): 529–546, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ece Sagol, Marcelo Reggio, and Adrian Ilinca. Issues concerning roughness on wind turbine blades. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 23:514–525, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. S. Ehrmann and E. B. White. Effect of blade roughness on transition and wind turbine performance. Wind Energy, Under Review.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liselle A. Joseph, Aurélien Borgoltz, Matthew S. Kuester, William Devenport, and Julien O. Fenouil. Aerodynamic effects of natural surface roughness of wind turbine blade sections. AIAA Paper 2015–3384.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Shaw. The influence of hole dimensions on static pressure measurements. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 7(04): 550–564, 1960.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McKeon, B. J. and Smits, A. J. Static pressure correction in high reynolds number fully developed turbulent pipe flow. Measurement Science and Technology, 13(10):1608, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert L. Watzlavick, James P. Crowder, and Frank L. Wright. Comparison of model attitude systems: active target photogrammetry, precision accelerometer, and laser interferometer. AIAA Paper 1996–2252.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AW Burner and Tianshu Liu. Videogrammetric model deformation measurement technique. Journal of Aircraft, 38(4): 745–754, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tom Finley and Ping Tcheng. Model attitude measurements at nasa langley research center. AIAA Paper 1992–0764.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
