<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278267</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Intake Oxygen Concentration on Particle Size Distribution Measurements from Diesel Low Temperature Combustion</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Payri</surname>
                  <given-names>Francisco</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Benajes</surname>
                  <given-names>Jesús</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Novella</surname>
                  <given-names>Ricardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kolodziej</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Universidad Politécnica de Valencia</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1888</fpage>
         <lpage>1902</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278267"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Concepts of premixed Diesel Low Temperature Combustion (LTC) have been shown to be advantageous in greatly reducing engine-out nitrogen oxide (NO ₓ ) and particulate matter (PM) emissions, even below the minimum detection limit of standard opacity-based PM mass instruments. Previous research has revealed that significant changes to the PM size and number emissions still occur for changes to the LTC engine operating conditions. This work investigates the influence of reductions in intake oxygen concentration on PM (mass, size, and number), NO ₓ , hydrocarbon (HC), and carbon monoxide (CO) emissions from select LTC engine operating conditions.</p>
            <p>Exhaust particle size distributions were measured for multiple engine operating conditions of premixed Diesel LTC within a range of five intake oxygen concentrations from 9% to 13% (by volume) at three intake pressures from 1.325 to 1.6 bar. For each intake oxygen concentration and intake pressure engine operating condition, particle size distributions were measured at the early-LTC injection timing of minimum PM mass concentration emissions. Reductions in inlet oxygen concentration limited the oxygen available during the combustion process. This prolonged the fuel and air premixing time before the start of combustion, and decreased the temperatures during the combustion process. At the early minimum PM injection timing (−27 and −24°aTDC, depending on intake pressure), decreasing engine intake oxygen concentration caused emissions of higher numbers of smaller particles. In addition, a comparison is made between the particle size and number emissions with the in-cylinder combustion processes and exhaust HC emissions for reductions in intake oxygen concentration within the premixed Diesel LTC operating regime.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamimoto, T., Bae, M. H., “High Combustion Temperature for the Reduction of Particulate in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 880423, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takeda, Y., Keiichi, N., Keiichi, N., “Emissions Characteristics of Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion with Extremely Early Staged Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 961163, 1996, doi: 10.4271/961163.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suzuki, H., Koike, N., Ishii, H., Odaka, M., “Exhaust Purification of Diesel Engines by Homogeneous Charge with Compression Ignition Part 1: Experimental Investigation of Combustion and Exhaust Emission Behavior Under Pre- Mixed Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Method,” SAE Technical Paper 970313, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970313.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yokota, H., Kudo, Y., Nakajima, H., Kakegawa, T., Suzuki, T., “A New Concept for Low Emissions Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 970891, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970891.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimazaki, N., Akagawa, H., Tsujimura, K., “An Experimental Study of Premixed Lean Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0181, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0181.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S., Enomoto, Y., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High- Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S., Dean, A. M., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y., Aiyoshizawa, E., “Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low- Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, R. M., Green, J. B.Jr., Dam, T. Q., Edwards, K. D., Storey, J. M., “Simultaneous Low Engine-Out NOx and Particulate Matter with Highly Diluted Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0262, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okude, K., Mori, K., Shiino, S., Moriya, T., “Premixed Compression Ignition (PCI) Combustion for Simultaneous Reduction of NOx and Soot in Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1907, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raatz, T., Mueller, E., “Examination of Particle Size Distribution of Homogeneous and Conventional Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3576, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3576.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C. S., Wagner, R. M., Storey, J. M. E., Lewis, S., “Implications of Particulate and Precursor Compounds Formed During High-Efficiency Clean Combustion in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3844, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3844.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolodziej, C., Wirojsakunchai, E., Foster, D. E., Schmidt, N., Kamimoto, T., Kawai, T., Akard, M., Yoshimura, T., “Comprehensive Characterization of Particulate Emissions from Advanced Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1945, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1945.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Storey, J. M. E., Lewis, S. A.Sr., Parks, J. E.II, Szybist, J. P., Barone, T. L., Prikhodko, V. Y., “Mobile Source Air Toxics (MSATs) from High Efficiency Clean Combustion: Catalytic Exhaust Treatment Effects,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):1157-1166, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Natti, K. C., Henein, N. A., Poonawala, Y., Bryzik, W., “Particulate Matter Characterization Studies in an HSDI Diesel Engine under Conventional and LTC Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):735-745, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., Arthozoul, S., Kolodziej, C., “Particle Size Distribution Measurements from Early to Late Injection Timing Low Temperature Combustion in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):567-581, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Novella, R., Arthozoul, S., Kolodziej, C., “Injection Timing Effects on Premixed LTC Particle Emissions from Light and Heavy Duty Diesel Engines,” Poster and Extended Abstract, 14th ETH-Zurich Conference on Combustion Generated Nanoparticles, Aug., 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noehre, C., Andersson, M., Johansson, B., Hultqvist, A., “Characterization of Partially Premixed Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3412, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-3412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huestis, E., Erickson, P. A., Musculus, M. P. B., “In- Cylinder and Exhaust Soot in Low-Temperature Combustion Using a Wide-Range of EGR in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4017, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-4017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W. F., Miles, P. C., Oh, S., “Effect of Intake Pressure on Performance and Emissions in an Automotive Diesel Engine Operating in Low Temperature Combustion Regimes,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4063, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-4063.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albrecht, W., Dohle, U., Gombert, R., Krauss, J., Leonhard, R., Wannenwetsch, P., “Das innovative Bosch Common Rail System für die neue Generation von schweren DaimlerChrysler Nutzfahrzeug-Dieselmotoren,” 28. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta, M., Armas, O., Hernández, J. J., “Diagnostic of D.I. Diesel Combustion from In-Cylinder Pressure Signal by Estimation of Mean Thermodynamic Properties of the Gas,” Applied Thermal Engineering, 19(5):513-529, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Molina, S., Martín, J., Armas, O., “Influence of Measurement Errors and Estimated Parameters on Combustion Diagnosis,” Applied Thermal Engineering, 26(2-3):226-236, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Way, R. J. B., “Methods for Determination of Composition and Thermodynamic Properties of Combustion Products for Internal Combustion Engine Calculations,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers. 190(60):686-697, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch, W., “The Fuel Rate Indicator: A New Measuring Instrument for Display of the Characteristics of Individual Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 660749, 1966, doi: 10.4271/660749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baumgard, K. J., Johnson, J. H., “The Effect of Fuel and Engine Design on Diesel Exhaust Particle Size Distributions,” SAE Technical Paper 960131, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bielaczyc, P., Merkisz, J., Kozak, M., “Analysis of the Influence of Fuel Sulfur Content on Diesel Engine Particulate Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2219, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-2219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitchell, K., Steere, D. E., Taylor, J. A., Manicom, B., Fisher, J. E., Sienicki, E. J., Chiu, C., Williams, P., “Impact of Diesel Fuel Aromatics on Particulate, PAH and Nitro-PAH Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 942053, 1994, doi: 10.4271/942053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Z. G., Vasys, V. N., Kittelson, D. B., “Nuclei-Mode Particulate Emissions and Their Response to Fuel Sulfur Content and Primary Dilution during Transient Operations of Old and Modern Diesel Engines,” Environmental Science Technology, 41(18):6479-6483, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Den Ouden, C. J. J., Clark, R. H., Cowley, L. T., Stradling, R. J., Lange, W. W., Maillard, C., “Fuel Quality Effects on Particulate Matter Emissions from Light- and Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 942022, 1994, doi: 10.4271/942022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdul-Khalek, I., Kittelson, D. B., Brear, F., “The Influence of Dilution Conditions on Diesel Exhaust Particle Size Distribution Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1142, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">TSI Incorporated, “Aerosol Instrument Manager® Software for Scanning Mobility Particle Sizer™ (SMPS™) Spectrometer,” User's Manual, P/N 1930038, Revision G, October, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C. S., Wagner, R. M., Lewis, S. A., Storey, J. M. E., “Exhaust Chemistry of Low-NOx, Low-PM Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0114, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Ra, Y., Gonzalez, D., M. A., Krieger, R., Reitz, R. D., Foster, D. E., Durrett, R. P., Siewert, R. M., “Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bohac, S. V., Han, M., Jacobs, T. J., López, A. J., Assanis, D. N., Szymkowicz, P. G., “Speciated Hydrocarbon Emissions from an Automotive Diesel Engine and DOC Utilizing Conventional and PCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0201, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merritt, P., Huang, Y., Khair, M., Pan, J., “Unregulated Exhaust Emissions from Alternate Diesel Combustion Modes,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3307, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-3307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C. P., Ra, Y., Krieger, R., Andrie, M., Foster, D. E., Siewert, R. M., Durrett, R. P., Ekoto, I., Miles, P. C., “Detailed Unburned Hydrocarbon Investigations in a Highly- Dilute Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Regime,” SAE Int J. Engines 2(1):858-879, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T. V., “Review of Diesel Emissions and Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):16-29, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D. B., “Engines and Nanoparticles: A Review,” J. Aerosol Science. 29(5):575-588, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montajir, R. M., Kawai, T., Goto, Y., Odaka, M., “Thermal Conditioning of Exhaust Gas: Potential for Stabilizing Diesel Nano-Particles,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0187, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0187.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, S. C., Sixteenth Symposium (International) on Combustion, The Combustion Institute, Pittsburg, p. 663, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wirojsakunchai, E., Schroeder, E., Kolodziej, C., Foster, D. E., Schmidt, N., Root, T., Kawai, T., Suga, T., Nevius, T., Kusaka, T., “Detailed Diesel Exhaust Particulate Characterization and Real-Time DPF Filtration Efficiency Measurements during PM Filling Process,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0320, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hinds, W.C., “Aerosol Technology: Properties, Behavior, and Measurement of Airborne Particles” John Wiley and Sons, New York, USA (1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmidt, N., Root, T., Wirojsakunchai, E., Schroeder, E., Kolodziej, C., Foster, D. E., Suga, T., Kawai, T., “Detailed Diesel Exhaust Particulate Characterization and DPF Regeneration Behavior Measurements for Two Different Regeneration Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1063, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1063.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
