<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277544</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Diesel Spray Ignition Detection and Spatial/Temporal Correction</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lillo</surname>
                  <given-names>Peter M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Persson</surname>
                  <given-names>Helena</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Oivind</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kook</surname>
                  <given-names>Sanghoon</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of New South Wales</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1330</fpage>
         <lpage>1346</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277544"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Methods for detection of the spatial position and timing of diesel ignition with improved accuracy are demonstrated in an optically accessible constant-volume chamber at engine-like pressure and temperature conditions. High-speed pressure measurement using multiple transducers, followed by triangulation correction for the speed of the pressure wave, permits identification of the autoignition spatial location and timing. Simultaneously, high-speed schlieren and broadband chemiluminescence imaging provides validation of the pressure-based triangulation technique. The combined optical imaging and corrected pressure measurement techniques offer improved understanding of diesel ignition phenomenon. Schlieren imaging shows the onset of low-temperature (first-stage) heat release prior to high-temperature (second-stage) ignition. High-temperature ignition is marked by more rapid pressure rise and broadband chemiluminescence. The use of multiple pressure sensors also permits charge-amplifier gain optimization tailored to characterize spray behavior rather than the global combustion chamber, thereby providing significantly improved pressure-rise measurement and derived heat-release rate for the fuel spray. Based on pressure data only, this study provides ignition measurement accuracy with temporal resolution below 20 μs, and with spatial resolution below 5 mm, thereby fulfilling the need for better model validation data.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gopalakrishnan, V. and Abraham, J., “An Investigation of Ignition and Heat Release Characteristics in a Diesel Engine Using an Interactive Flamelet Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1062, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1062.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Naik, C., Puduppakkam, K., Wang, C. et al., “Efficient Simulation of Diesel Engine Combustion Using Realistic Chemical Kinetics in CFD,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0178, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., Reitz, R., and Musculus, M., “Comparison of the Characteristic Time (CTC), Representative Interactive Flamelet (RIF), and Direct Integration with Detailed Chemistry Combustion Models against Optical Diagnostic Data for Multi-Mode Combustion in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0055, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucchini, T., D'Errico, G., Ettorre, D., Brusiani, F. et al., “Experimental and Numerical Investigation of High-Pressure Diesel Sprays with Multiple Injections at Engine Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0179, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrell, J., Cernansky, N., Dryer, F., Law, C. et al., “Development of an Experimental Database and Kinetic Models for Surrogate Diesel Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0201, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., Siebers, D., and Aradi, A., “Diesel-Spray Ignition and Premixed-Burn Behavior,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0940, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Kook, S., and Williams, T., “Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool-Flame, Ignition, High-Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High-Speed Imaging,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 439-459, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., and Idicheria, C., “Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polonowski, C., Mueller, C., Gehrke, C., Bazyn, T. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-Cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1812, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Espey, C., “Chemiluminescence Imaging of Autoignition in a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 982685, 1998, doi: 10.4271/982685.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bobba, M., Genzale, C., and Musculus, M., “Effect of Ignition Delay on In-Cylinder Soot Characteristics of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Operating at Low Temperature Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 911-924, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jansons, M., Brar, A., Estefanous, F., Florea, R. et al., “Experimental Investigation of Single and Two-Stage Ignition in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1071, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1071.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davis, R. and Patterson, G., “Cylinder Pressure Data Quality Checks and Procedures to Maximize Data Accuracy,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1346, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higuma, A., Suzuki, T., Yoshida, M., Oguri, Y. et al., “Improvement of Error in Piezoelectric Pressure Transducer,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0207, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Randolph, A., “Methods of Processing Cylinder-Pressure Transducer Signals to Maximize Data Accuracy,” SAE Technical Paper 900170, 1990, doi: 10.4271/900170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">König, G., Maly, R., Bradley, D., Lau, A. et al., “Role of Exothermic Centres on Knock Initiation and Knock Damage,” SAE Technical Paper 902136, 1990, doi: 10.4271/902136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liiva, P., Valentine, J., Cobb, J., and Acker, W., “Use of Multiple Pressure Transducers to Find In-Cylinder Knock Location,” SAE Technical Paper 922368, 1992, doi: 10.4271/922368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vressner, A., Lundin, A., Christensen, M., Tunestål, P. et al., “Pressure Oscillations During Rapid HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3217, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spicher, U., Kröger, H., and Ganser, J., “Detection of Knocking Combustion Using Simultaneously High-Speed Schlieren Cinematography and Multi Optical Fiber Technique,” SAE Technical Paper 912312, 1991, doi: 10.4271/912312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Genzale, C., Bruneaux, G., Malbec, L. et al., “Comparison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High-Temperature, High-Pressure Facilities,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):156-181, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D., “Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Manin, J., Genzale, C., Siebers, D. et al., “Relationship Between Diesel Fuel Spray Vapor Penetration/Dispersion and Local Fuel Mixture Fraction,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):764-799, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and Siebers, D., “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C. and Pickett, L., “Formaldehyde Visualization Near Lift-off Location in a Diesel Jet,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3434, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Settles, G.S., Schlieren and Shadowgraph Techniques, Springer-Verlag, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mueller, C. and Martin, G., “Effects of Oxygenated Compounds on Combustion and Soot Evolution in a DI Diesel Engine Broadband Natural Luminosity Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1631, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1631.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., “Measurements of the Influence of Soot Radiation on In- Cylinder Temperatures and Exhaust NOx in a Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0925, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network data archive for diesel spray combustion. http://www.sandia.gov/ECN/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
