<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308430</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Enabling Study of Diesel Low Temperature Combustion via Adaptive Control</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tan</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuyu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Ming</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reader</surname>
                  <given-names>Graham T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Xiaoye</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
                  <given-names>Meiping</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Windsor</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>750</fpage>
         <lpage>763</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308430"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Low temperature combustion (LTC), though effective to reduce soot and oxides of nitrogen (NOx) simultaneously from diesel engines, operates in narrowly close to unstable regions. Adaptive control strategies are developed to expand the stable operations and to improve the fuel efficiency that was commonly compromised by LTC. Engine cycle simulations were performed to better design the combustion control models. The research platform consists of an advanced common-rail diesel engine modified for the intensified single cylinder research and a set of embedded real-time (RT) controllers, field programmable gate array (FPGA) devices, and a synchronized personal computer (PC) control and measurement system. Up to 12 fuel injection pulses per cylinder per cycle have been applied to modulate the homogeneity history of the cylinder charge in hybrid combustion modes in order to improve the phasing and completeness of combustion under independently controlled exhaust gas recirculation, intake boost, and exhaust backpressure.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, M., Kumar, R., Tan, Y., and Reader G.T., “Heat Release Pattern Diagnostics to Improve Diesel Low Temperature Combustion” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):1242-1258, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, Y. Tan, M.C. Mulenga, and M. Wang, “Thermal Efficiency Analyses of Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Cycles”, SAE Transactions 2007-01-4019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G. Reader, U. Asad, Y. Tan, M. Wang, “Adaptive Control to Improve Low Temperature Diesel Engine Combustion”, the 7th COMODIA, International Conference on Modeling and Diagnostics for Advanced Engine Systems, Japan, 2008, DE-1-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, U. Asad, G. Reader, Y. Tan, M. Wang, “Energy efficiency improvements for a diesel engine in low temperature combustion”, International Journal of Energy Research, ER-08-0581.R1, accepted in July 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G.T. Reader, Y. Tan, and M. Wang, “Adaptive Combustion Control to Improve Diesel HCCI Fuel Efficiency”; Proc. of the ASME IC Engine Division, October 14-17, 2007, Charleston, SC, USA, ASME Paper ICEF2007-1630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Kumar, M. Zheng, U. Asad, and G.T. Reader, “Heat Release Based Adaptive Control to Improve Low Temperature Diesel Engine Combustion”, SAE Paper 2007-01-0771.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Hiroyasu, S. Yoshikawa, K. Nishida, M. Arai, H. Oda and M. Suzuki, “Total In-cylinder Sampling Experiments on Emission Formation Processes in a DI Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 902062.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Zhao, G. Lowry and N. Ladommatos, “Time- Resolved Measurements and Analysis of In-cylinder Gases and Particulates in Compression-Ignition Engines”, SAE Transactions, Paper No. 961168.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G.T. Reader and J.G Hawley, “Diesel Engine Exhaust Gas Recirculation – A Review on Advanced and Novel Concepts”, International Journal of Energy Conversion and Management, Vol. 45, Issue 6, pp 883-900, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Johnson, “Diesel Emission Control Technology in Review”; &amp; “Light Duty Diesels in the United States – Some Perspectives”, 11th DEER, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Helmantel and I. Denbratt, “HCCI Operation of a Passenger Car Common-Rail Di Diesel Engine with Early Injection of Conventional Diesel Fuel”, SAE paper 2004-01-0935.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.O. Olsson, P. Tunestal and B. Johansson, “Boosting for High Load HCCI”, SAE paper 2004-01- 0940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. Kodama, I. Nishizawa, T. Sugihara, N. Sato, T. Iijima and T. Yoshida, “Full-load HCCI Operation with Variable Valve Actuation System in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2007-01-0215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng and G.T. Reader et al.; “Adaptive Control to Improve Low Temperature Diesel Engine Combustion”, 12th Diesel Engine-Efficiency and Emission Reduction Conference (DEER), 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W.L. Hardy, R.D. Reitz; “An Experimental Investigation of Partially Premixed Combustion Strategies Using Multiple Injections in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2006-01-0917.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Ogawa, N. Miyamoto, H. Shimizu, S. Kido; “Characteristics of Diesel Combustion in Low Oxygen Mixtures with Ultra-High EGR”, SAE Paper 2006-01-1147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, U. Asad, R. Kumar, G.T. Reader, M.C. Mulenga, M. Wang and J. Tjong, “An Investigation of EGR Treatment on the Emission and Operating Characteristics of Modern Diesel Engines”; SAE Paper 2007-01-1083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R.H. Stanglmaier and C.E. Roberts, “Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI): Benefits, Compromises, and Future Engine Applications”, PT- 100, SAE Paper 1999-01-3682.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Christensen, A. Hultqvist, B. Johansson, “Demonstrating the Multi-Fuel Capability of a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine with Variable Compression Ratio”, SAE paper 1999- 01-3679.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C.K. Westbrook, “Challenges in Combustion”; GCEP Research Symposium, Meeting the Challenge of Reducing Global GHG Emissions through Energy Research, June 13-16, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Sjöberg and J.E. Dec; “Effects of Fuel Type and Engine Speed on Required Intake Temperature and Completeness of Combustion in a Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine”, 9th DEER 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X. Han U. Asad, R. Kumar, M.C. Mulenga, S. Banerjee, M. Wang, G.T. Reader and M. Zheng, “Empirical Studies of the Diesel Low Temperature Combustion on a Modern Diesel Engine”, Combustion Institute/Canadian Section, 2007 Spring Technical Meeting, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, M.C. Mulenga, G.T. Reader, D.S-K. Ting and M. Wang, “Influence of Biodiesel Fuel on Diesel Engine Performance and Emissions in Low Temperature Combustion”, SAE Paper 2006-01- 3281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, M. C. Mulenga, G. T. Reader, Y. Tan, M. Wang, J. Tjong, “Neat Biodiesel Fuel Engine Tests and Preliminary Modelling”, SAE Paper 2007-01- 0616.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, M. C. Mulenga, X. Han, Y. Tan, M. Kobler, S. J. Ko, M. Wang, J. Tjong, “Low Temperature Combustion of Neat Biodiesel Fuel on a Commonrail Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2008-01-1396.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Akihama, Y. Takatori, K. Inagaki, S. Sasaki and A.M Dean, “Mechanisms of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature”, SAE Paper 2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Kitamura, T. Ito, J. Senda and H. Fujimoto, “Mechanism of smokeless diesel combustion with oxygenated fuels based on the dependence of the equivalence ratio and temperature on soot particle formation”, International Journal of Engine Research, Vol. 3, No 4, pp 223-248, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G.T. Reader, Raj Kumar; “Adaptive Fuel Injection Tests to Extend EGR Limits on Diesel Engines”, SAE Paper 2006-01-3426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng, G. T. Reader, “Preliminary Investigation of Cycle-to-Cycle Variations in a Nonair-Breathing Diesel Engine”, Transactions of the ASME, pp.24-28, Vol. 117, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Zheng; “Thermodynamic Modeling and Experimental Investigation of a Synthetic Atmosphere Diesel Engine System”. PhD Thesis, University of Calgary, July 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., et al., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature”, SAE 2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
