<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23026310</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>BEYOND THE RISK FACTOR: BANK LENDING TO SMALL-SCALE PEASANT FARMS IN NIGERIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>S. O.</given-names>
                  <surname>Olubiyo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>G. P.</given-names>
                  <surname>Hill</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2003</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23026308</issue-id>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>22</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23026310"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Availability of credit has been identified as a major constraint to agricultural development in peasant economies. Small-scale farmers dominate the agricultural sectors of these countries. Whilst there are often considerable opportunities to increase production and farm incomes by adopting new technology this potential can only be realized if farmers can gain access to funds to finance the additional inputs that are invariably required. All to frequently small-scale farmers have insufficient savings to finance the investment in additional inputs. Under these circumstances the obvious solution for farmers is to borrow against the improved returns they expect to achieve by adopting improved technology. Unfortunately, the desired credit is not available. This is largely because institutional lenders are reluctant to advance credit to a sector where historically there is a high incidence of default. In part this can be attributed to the dependence of agricultural production on nature and the high covariance of risk from adverse weather and the incidence of disease between producers in any given location. The failure to realize the potential increase in agricultural production has forced the Nigerian government to introduce programmes to address the problem of risk in small-scale farming. The government has introduced two programmes. The first one is the Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme Fund that guarantees bank loans against defaults not arising from adverse natural occurrences, and the second is a subsidized insurance scheme (Nigerian Agricultural Insurance Scheme) that insures bank loans against the occurrence of risks of nature that can cause loan default. However, in spite of these programmes the banks still appear reluctant to lend to the farm sector. This paper examines changes in bank lending to the farm sector before and since the inception of the subsidised credit insurance in Nigeria. It also identifies the pattern of bank lending to different agricultural sub-sectors. The findings from the study suggest that there is the need for the government to review its policy of underwriting loans as an instrument to encourage increased bank lending to small-scale farmers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d50e184a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e188" publication-type="other">
Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme Fund Act Decree 20 (1978), Federal Government Gazette, Lagos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e195a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e199" publication-type="other">
Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme Fund (1993). Proceedings of the 14th Annual Conference of Agricultural
Credit Officers of the Central Bank of Nigeria, Enugu, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e209a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e213" publication-type="other">
Adams, D. W and Von Pischke, J. D (1992). "Microenterprise Credit Programs: Deja Vu", World Development Vol.
20, No 10, pp. 1463-1470.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e223a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e227" publication-type="other">
Akande, S. O and Oni, T. O (1999). "Problems Militating Against the Supply of Agricultural Credit in Nigeria", in
Agricultural Finance Issues in Nigeria; edited by Olomola. A. S and S. O Akande.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e238a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e242" publication-type="other">
Adeyefa F. K. A (1995). "The Nigerian Agricultural Insurance Corporation and Lending Institutions Linkages:
Progress, Problems and Prospects". Paper presented at the National Extension Workshop for Agricultural Risk
Management and Credit Delivery; Organised by NAIC in ARMTI, llorin, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e255a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e259" publication-type="other">
Balogun E. D and M. F. Otu (1991). "Credit Policies and Agricultural Development in Nigeria". Economics and
Financial Review (CBN), Vol. 29 No 2 pp. 138-156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e269a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e273" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria (1986). "Nigerian Agricultural Credit System: Analysis of Operation and Performance"
Report of the Nigerian Agricultural Credit Study Team, Volume II, Institutional Analysis and Survey Report, CBN, Lagos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e283a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e287" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria (1989). Monetary and Fiscal Policy Guidelines for 1989 and 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e294a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e298" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria (1995). Statistical Bulletin; Various Issues.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e305a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e309" publication-type="other">
Central Bank of Nigeria (1999). "Contribution of the ACGS to improved Agricultural Financing in Nigeria: Past,
Present and Future", in Agricultural Finance Issues in Nigeria: edited by Olomola. A. S and S. O Akande.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e320a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e324" publication-type="other">
Emeotu, S. (1993) "Lessons of Nigerian Agricultural Co-operative Bank Ltd; in the operations of the Agricultural
Credit Guarantee Scheme". Proceedings of the 14'" Annual Conference of Agricultural Credit Officers of the Central
Bank of Nigeria, Enugu, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e337a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e341" publication-type="other">
Evbuomwan. G. O.; E. U. Okeke and F. A. Afelumo (1993), Review of Policy and Developmental Objectives in
Agricultural and Agro-Based Industrial Financing. Bullion Vol. 17, No. 4 pp.41-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e351a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e355" publication-type="other">
Famoriyo, S. and E.C. Nwagbo (1981). "Problems of Agriculture and Agricultural Finance in Nigeria". Proceedings
of a seminar organised by Central Bank of Nigeria April 27-30, pp. 123-148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e365a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e369" publication-type="other">
Federal Office of Statistics (1996). Nigerian Agricultural and Household Surveys; Various Issues, Lagos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e376a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e380" publication-type="other">
Herath, G. (1994). "Rural Credit Markets and Institutional Reform in Developing Countries: Potential and
Problems". Savings and Development, No. 2 pp. 169-192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e390a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e394" publication-type="other">
Herath. G (1996). "Rural Credit Markets and Imperfect Information: A New Perspective". Savings and Development
2 pp. 241-253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e405a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e409" publication-type="other">
Ijere, M. O (1985). "Farm Finance, Farm Management and Farm Input Subsidies". Proceedings of Farm
Management Association of Nigeria Vol. 1 No.1 pp. 97-108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e419a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e423" publication-type="other">
Jimoh, J. (1994). A Comparative Study of the Impact of People's Bank and Community Banks on Investment
Patterns in llorin, Nigeria, An Unpublished B.Agriculture Thesis submitted to the Department of Agricultural Economics
and Farm Management, University of llorin, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e436a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e440" publication-type="other">
Lot, C. A. (1993). "Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme - The UBA Experience". Proceedings of the 14lh Annual
Conference of Agricultural Credit Officers of the Central Bank of Nigeria, Enugu, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e450a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e454" publication-type="other">
Lewis, P. and H. Stein (1997), "Shifting Fortunes: The Political Economy of Financial Liberation in Nigeria". World
Developmentsol. 25 pp. 5-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e464a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e468" publication-type="other">
Muhammed, M. A (1981). "Commercial Banks and Agricultural Finance: Problems and Prospect", in Proceedings
of a Seminar on Agricultural Credit and Finance in Nigeria Problems and Prospects, Organised by Central Bank of
Nigeria, Lagos.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e481a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e485" publication-type="other">
Ojo, M. O. (1991). Food Policy and Economy Development in Nigeria. Page Publishers Services Ltd.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e493a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e497" publication-type="other">
Ojo M. O; E. D Balogun and G. O. Evbuowman (1993). "Sustaining Agricultural Production in a Deregulated
Economy". CBN Economic and Financial Review, Vol. 31 No. 2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e507a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e511" publication-type="other">
Okorie, A. (1993) Agricultural Credit Policies and Administration in Nigeria: A Review. Proceedings of the 14th
Annual Conference of Agricultural Credit Officers of the Central Bank of Nigeria, Enugu, Nigera.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e521a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e525" publication-type="other">
Olomola, A. S. (1992) Interlinked Credit Transactions in the Nigerian Rural Credit System. Monograph Nigerian
Institute of Social and Economic Research, Ibadan, Oyo State.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e535a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e539" publication-type="other">
Olomola, A. S. (1993). "Food Production Variability and the Challenges of Food Security in Nigeria". Nigeria Rural
Sociological Association, Vol. 1 pp 1-14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e549a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e553" publication-type="other">
Olomola, A. S. (1999) "Agricultural Credit Market Imperfection and Implications for Lending to Smalllholders in
Nigeria", in Agricultural Finance Issues in Nigeria; edited by Olomola. A. S. and S. O. Akande.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e563a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e567" publication-type="other">
Onucheyo, E. (1998). Political Decisions in the Nigerian Agricultural Industry. Tamaza Publishin Co., Zaria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e579" publication-type="other">
Orngudwen, J. I. (1993). "Operations of Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme: A Farmer's Point of View in A
Review". Proceedings of the 14'" Annual Conference of Agricultural Credit Officers of the Central Bank of Nigeria,
Enugu, Nigera.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e592a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e596" publication-type="other">
Osemeobo. G. J. (1992). "Impact of Nigerian Agricultural Policies on Crop Production and the Environment". The
Environmentalist, Vol. 12 no. 2 pp 101-108</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d50e606a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d50e610" publication-type="other">
Srinivas, H. and Y. Higuichi (1996). "A Continuum of Informality of Credit: What Can Informal Lenders Teach Us?"
Savings and Development No. 2 pp. 207-223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
