<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023248</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>International Tax Planning</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tax Savings for U.S.-Headquartered, Non-U.S.-Incorporated Multinational Firms</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Allen</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Assistant Professor, Leventhal School of Accounting, University of Southern California.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Morse</surname>
                  <given-names>Susan C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Assistant Professor, University of Texas School of Law.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>39</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023248"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahern, Kenneth R., Daniele Daminelli, and Cesare Fracassi, [2015]. “Lost in Translation? The Effect of Cultural Values on Mergers Around the World.” Journal of Financial Economics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, Eric J., 2015. “The Information Content of the Deferred Tax Valuation Allowance: Evidence From Venture Capital Backed IPO Firms.” Working paper, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, Eric J. and Susan C. Morse, 2013. “Tax-Haven Incorporation for U.S.-Headquartered Firms: No Exodus Yet.” National Tax Journal 66 (2), 395-420.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Altshuler, Rosanne, and Harry Grubert, 2002. “Repatriation Taxes, Repatriation Strategies and Multinational Financial Policy.” Journal of Public Economics 87 (1), 73-107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Armstrong, Christopher S., Jennifer L. Blouin, and David F. Larcker, 2012. “The Incentives for Tax Planning.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 53 (__) 391-411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bebchuk, Lucian A., and Alma Cohen, 2003. “Firms’ Decisions Where to Incorporate.” Journal of Law and Economics 46 (2), 383-425.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird, Andrew, Alexander Edwards and Terry Shevlin, 2014. “Does Earnings Lockout Make U.S. Multinationals Attractive to Foreign Acquirers?” working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blouin, Jennifer L., Linda K. Krull and Leslie A. Robinson, 2014 “The Location, Composition, and Investment Implications of Permanently Reinvested Earnings.” Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Broughman, Brian J., Jesse M. Fried and Darian M. Ibrahim, 2014. “Delaware Law as Lingua Franca: Theory and Evidence” forthcoming, Journal of Law and Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clausing, Kimberly A., 2009. “Multinational Firm Tax Avoidance and Tax Policy.” National Tax Journal 52 (4), 703-725.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cloyd, C. Brian, Lillian F. Mills, and Connie D. Weaver, 2003. “Firm Valuation Effects of the Expatriation of U.S. Corporations to Tax Haven Countries.” Journal of the American Taxation Association 25 (1), 87-109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, Mihir A., 2009. “The Decentering of the Global Firm.” The World Economy 32 (9), 1271-1290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, Mihir A., and Dhammika Dharmapala, 2010. “Do Strong Fences Make Strong Neighbors?” National Tax Journal 54 (4),</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, Mihir A., and James R. Hines Jr., 2002. “Expectations and Expatriations: Tracing the Causes and Consequences of Corporate Inversions.” National Tax Journal 55 (3), 409-440.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dharmapala, Dhammika., 2014. “What do we know about base erosion and profit shifting? A review of the empirical literature.” CESifo Working Paper, No. 4612.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dharmapala, Dhammika, and James R. Hines Jr., 2009. “Which Countries Become Tax Havens?” Journal of Public Economics 93 (9-10), 1058-1068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, Scott D., Michelle Hanlon, and Edward L. Maydew, 2008. “Long-Run Corporate Tax Avoidance.” The Accounting Review 83 (1), 61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, Scott D., Michelle Hanlon, Edward L. Maydew, and Jacob R. Thornock, 2014. “Changes in Corporate Effective Tax Rates Over the Past Twenty-Five Years.” Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, Scott D. and Bradley P. Lindsey, 2009. “Using Financial Accounting Data to Examine the Effect of Foreign Operations Located in Tax Havens and Other Countries on U.S. Multinational Firms’ Tax Rates.” Journal of Accounting Research 47 (5), 1283-1316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fleming, J. Clifton Jr., Robert J. Peroni, and Stephen E. Shay, 2009. “Worse Than Exemption.” Emory Law Journal 59 (1), 79-149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Financial Accounting Standards Board, 2008. Financial Accounting Standard Number 131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frankel, Jeffrey A. and David Romer, 1999. “Does Trade Cause Growth?” American Economic Review 89 (3), 379-399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, John R., Michelle Hanlon and Terry Shevlin, 2010. “Barriers to Mobility: The Lockout Effect of U.S. Taxation of Worldwide Corporate Profits.” National Tax Journal 63 (4), 1111-1114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gravelle, Jennifer, 2012. “Who Will Benefit From a Territorial Tax? Characteristics of Multinational Firms.” National Tax Association Proceedings, 105th Annual Conference on Taxation, available at http://www.ntanet.org/images/stories/pdf/proceedings/12/15_gravelle.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grubert, Harry, 2012. “Foreign Taxes and the Growing Share of U.S. Multinational Company Income Abroad: Profits, Not Sales, Are Being Globalized.” National Tax Journal 65 (2), 247-282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grubert, Harry, and Rosanne Altshuler, 2008. “Corporate Taxes in the World Economy: Reforming the Taxation of Cross-Border Income.” In Diamond, John W. and George R. Zodrow (eds.), Fundamental Tax Reform: Issues, Choices, and Implications, 319-354. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hines Jr., James R., and Eric M. Rice, 1994. “Fiscal Paradise: Foreign Tax Havens and American Business.” Quarterly Journal of Economics 109 (1), 149-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hurt, Christine, 2006. “Regulating Public Morals and Private Markets: Online Securities Trading, Internet Gambling, and the Speculation Paradox.” Boston University Law Review 86 (_), 371-___.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kane, Mitchell A., and Edward B. Rock, 2008. “Corporate Taxation and International Charter Competition.” Michigan Law Review 106 (7), 1229-1283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klassen, Kenneth J. and Stacie K. LaPlante, 2012. “Are U.S. Multinational Corporations Becoming More Aggressive Income Shifters?” Journal of Accounting Research 50 (5), 1245-1285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleinbard, Edward A., 2014. “Competitiveness’ Has Nothing to Do With It.’” Tax Notes 144 ( ), 1055-___.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleinbard, Edward A., 2011. “Stateless Income.” Florida Tax Review 11 (9), 699-774.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Litvak, Kate, 2007. “The Effect of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act on Non-U.S. Companies Cross-Listed in the U.S.” Journal of Corporate Finance 13 (2), 195-228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lokken, Lawrence, 2005. “Whatever Happened to Subpart F?” Florida Tax Review 7 (__), 185-___.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markle, Kevin S., 2014. “A Comparison of the Tax-Motivated Income Shifting of Multinationals in Territorial and Worldwide Countries.” Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markle, Kevin S. and Douglas A. Shackelford, 2014. “The Impact of Headquarter and Subsidiary Locations on Multinationals’ Effective Tax Rates.” Tax Policy and the Economy 28 (1), 33-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Markle, Kevin S. and Douglas A. Shackelford, 2012. “Cross-Country Comparisons of Corporate Income Taxes.” National Tax Journal 65 (3), 493-528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morse, Susan C., 2013. “Startup Ltd.: Tax Planning and Initial Incorporation Location.” Florida Tax Review 14 (8), 219-360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OECD, 2013. Action Plan on Base Erosion and Profit Shifting.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development, 2000. Towards Global Tax Cooperation: Progress in Identifying and Eliminating Harmful Tax Competition. OECD, Paris, France.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rego, Sonia Olhoft, 2003. “Tax-Avoidance Activities of U.S. Multinational Corporations.” Contemporary Accounting Research 20 (4), 805-833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scholes, Myron S., Mark A. Wolfson, Merle M. Erickson, Michelle L. Hanlon, Edward L. Maydew, and Terrence J. Shevlin, 2014. Taxes and Business Strategy: A Planning Approach.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seida, Jim A., and William F. Wempe, 2004. “Effective Tax Rate Changes and Earnings Stripping Following Corporate Inversions.” National Tax Journal 57 (4), 805-828.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shaviro, Daniel, 2011. “The Rising Tax Electivity of Corporate Residence.” Tax Law Review 64 (3), 377-430.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shay, Stephen E., 2014. “Mr. Secretary, Take the Tax Juice Out of Corporate Expatriations.” Tax Notes [144 ( )], 473-478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shay, Stephen E., 2004. “Exploring Alternatives to Subpart F.” Taxes 82 (__), 29-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Department of the Treasury, 2007. Report to the Congress on Earnings Stripping, Transfer Pricing and U.S. Income Tax Treaties. U.S. Department of the Treasury, Office of Tax Policy, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Department of the Treasury, 2002. Corporate Inversion Transactions: Tax Policy Implications. U.S. Department of the Treasury, Office of Tax Policy, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Voget, Johannes, 2011. “Relocation of Headquarters and International Taxation” J. Pub. Econ. 95 (2011), 1067-1081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wells, Bret, 2010. “What Corporate Inversions Teach About International Tax Reform” Tax Notes __ (__), 1345-1367.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">White House and U.S. Department of the Treasury, 2012. The President’s Framework for Business Tax Reform. White House and U.S. Department of the Treasury, Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
