<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169056</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optimization of the Series-HEV Control with Consideration of the Impact of Battery Cooling Auxiliary Losses</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Xueyu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson-ICAR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ivanco</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrej</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson-ICAR</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tao</surname>
                  <given-names>Xinran</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wagner</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson Univ</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Filipi</surname>
                  <given-names>Zoran</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Clemson-ICAR</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>July 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169049</issue-id>
         <fpage>234</fpage>
         <lpage>243</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169056"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper investigates the impact of battery cooling ancillary losses on fuel economy, and optimal control strategy for a series hybrid electric truck with consideration of cooling losses. Battery thermal model and its refrigeration-based cooling system are integrated into vehicle model, and the parasitic power consumption from cooling auxiliaries is considered in power management problem. Two supervisory control strategies are compared. First, a rule-based control strategy is coupled with a thermal management strategy; it controls power system and cooling system separately. The second is optimal control strategy developed using Dynamic Programming; it optimizes power flow with consideration of both propulsion and cooling requirement. The result shows that battery cooling consumption could cause fuel economy loss as high as 5%. When dynamic programming coordinates control of the powertrain and the cooling system in an optimal way, the fuel consumption penalty due to cooling losses is reduced to 3.7%, and battery duty cycle becomes milder. Finally, rules are extracted from the optimal strategy, and a refined rule-based strategy is presented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCE</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, Y. and Filipi, Z., “Series Hydraulic Hybrid Propulsion for a Light Truck - Optimizing the Thermostatic Power Management,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0080, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Filipi, Z., Kim, Y., “Hydraulic Hybrid Propulsion for Heavy Vehicles: Combining the Simulation and Engine-in-the-Loop Techniques to Maximize the Fuel Economy and Emission Benefits”, Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology - Revue de l'Institut Francais du Petrole, Vol. 65, No. 1, pp. 155-178, 2010, doi:10.2516/ogst/2009024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jalil, N., Kheir, N.A., Salman, M., “A rule-based energy management strategy for a series hybrid vehicle,” American Control Conference, 1997, Proceedings of the 1997, vol.1, no., pp.689,693 vol.1, 4-6 Jun 1997, doi:10.1109/ACC.1997.611889.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salman, M., Schouten, N.J., Kheir, N.A., “Control strategies for parallel hybrid vehicles,” American Control Conference, 2000. Proceedings of the 2000, vol.1, no.6, pp.524,528 vol.1, Sep 2000, doi:10.1109/ACC.2000.878955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, A., Guezennec, Y., Rizzoni, G., “Optimal energy management in series hybrid electric vehicles,” American Control Conference, 2000. Proceedings of the 2000, vol.1, no.6, pp.60,64 vol.1, Sep 2000, doi:10.1109/ACC.2000.878772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Peng, H., Grizzle, J.W., Kang, K-M., “Power management strategy for a parallel hybrid electric truck,” Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on, vol.11, no.6, pp.839,849, Nov. 2003, doi:10.1109/TCST.2003.815606.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, X., Ivanco, A., and Filipi, Z., “Optimization of Rule-Based Control Strategy for a Hydraulic-Electric Hybrid Light Urban Vehicle Based on Dynamic Programming,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 1(1):249-259, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Peng, H., Grizzle, J.W., “A stochastic control strategy for hybrid electric vehicles,” American Control Conference, 2004. Proceedings of the 2004, vol.5, no., pp.4710,4715 vol.5, June 30 2004-July 2 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johri, R. and Filipi, Z., “Low-Cost Pathway to Ultra Efficient City Car: Series Hydraulic Hybrid System with Optimized Supervisory Control,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):505-520, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0065.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrao, L., Onori, S., Rizzoni, G., “ECMS as a realization of Pontryagin's minimum principle for HEV control,” American Control Conference, 2009. ACC '09, vol., no., pp.3964,3969, 10-12 June 2009, doi:10.1109/ACC.2009.5160628.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musardo, C., Rizzoni, G., Staccia, B., “A-ECMS: An Adaptive Algorithm for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Management,” Decision and Control, 2005 and 2005 European Control Conference. CDC-ECC '05. 44th IEEE Conference on, vol., no., pp.1816,1823, 12-15 Dec. 2005, doi:10.1109/CDC.2005.1582424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rios, J., Pisu, P., “A Comparative Analysis of Optimization Strategies for a Power-Split Powertrain Hybrid Electric Vehicle”, Proceedings of the FISITA 2012 World Automotive Congress, Volume 3, pp 541-550, doi:10.1007/978-3-642-33777-2_44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onori, S., Serrao, L., “On Adaptive-ECMS strategies for hybrid electric vehicles”, 2nd International scientific conference on hybrid and electric vehicles RHEVE 2011, Rueil-Malmaison, France 6-7 December 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borhan, H., Vahidi, A., Phillips, A.M., Kuang, M.L., Kolmanovsky, I.V., Di Cairano, S., “MPC-Based Energy Management of a Power- Split Hybrid Electric Vehicle,” Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on, vol.20, no.3, pp.593,603, May 2012, doi:10.1109/TCST.2011.2134852.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nüesch, T., Wang, M., Voser, C., Guzzella, L., “Optimal energy management and sizing for hybrid electric vehicles considering transient emissions”, in 2012 IFAC Workshop on Engine and Powertrain Control Simulation and Modeling. 2012: Paris, France, doi:10.3182/20121023-3-FR-4025.00015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrao, L., Onori, S., Sciarretta, A., Guezennec, Y., Rizzoni, G., “Optimal energy management of hybrid electric vehicles including battery aging,” American Control Conference (ACC), 2011, vol., no., pp.2125,2130, June 29 2011-July 1 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ebbesen, S., Elbert, P., Guzzella, L., “Battery State-of-Health Perceptive Energy Management for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” Vehicular Technology, IEEE Transactions on, vol.61, no.7, pp.2893,2900, Sept. 2012, doi:10.1109/TVT.2012.2203836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johri, R., Salvi, A., and Filipi, Z., “Optimal Energy Management for a Hybrid Vehicle Using Neuro-Dynamic Programming to Consider Transient Engine Operation”, Proceedings of 4th Annual Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalil, G., “Challenges of hybrid electric vehicles for military applications,” Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, 2009. VPPC '09. IEEE, vol., no., pp.1,3, 7-10 Sept. 2009, doi:10.1109/VPPC.2009.5289878.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vetter, J., Novák, P., Wagner, M.R., Veit, C., Möller, K.-C., Besenhard, J.O., Winter, M., Wohlfahrt-Mehrens, M., Vogler, C., Hammouche, A., “Ageing mechanisms in lithium-ion batteries,” Journal of Power Sources, Volume 147, Issues 1-2, 9 September 2005, Pages 269-281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prenninger, K., Ackerl, M., Hager, J., Winter, M., Nakesch, H., “Simulation and Energy Management of Hybrid Commercial Vehicles with Attention to the Thermal System Behaviour,” in FISTA World Automitive Congress. 2010. Budapestm Hungary.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forgez, C., Do, D.V., Friedrich, G., Morcrette, M., et al., “Thermal Modeling of a Cylindrical LiFePO4/graphite Lithium-ion Battery”, Journal of Power Sources, Vol. 195, pp. 2961-2968, May 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertsekas, D.P., “Dynamic programming and optimal control”, 3rd Edition, Athena Scientific, ISBNs: 1-886529-26-4, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
