<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277707</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Integration of Engine Start/Stop Systems with Emphasis on NVH and Launch Behavior</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wellmann</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Govindswamy</surname>
                  <given-names>Kiran</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tomazic</surname>
                  <given-names>Dean</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>FEV Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1368</fpage>
         <lpage>1378</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277707"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Automatic engine start/stop systems are becoming more prevalent and increasing market share of these systems is predicted due to demands on improving fuel efficiency of vehicles. Integration of an engine start/stop system into a “conventional” drivetrain with internal combustion engine and 12V board system is a relatively cost effective measure to reduce fuel consumption. Comfort and NVH aspects will continue to play an important role for customer acceptance of these systems. Possible delay during vehicle launch due to the engine re-start is not only a safety relevant issue but a hesitating launch feel characteristic will result in reduced customer acceptance of these systems. The engine stop and re-start behavior should be imperceptible to the driver from both a tactile and acoustic standpoint. The lack of masking effects of the engine during the engine stop phases can cause other “unwanted” noise to become noticeable or more prominent. Other comfort related criteria like a stable 12V board supply during the engine start phase or A/C usage during the engine stop phase need to be considered as well.</p>
            <p>This paper provides an overview of start/stop systems and starter concepts. The requirements for different transmission types and the associated start/stop challenges are described. The phases of an engine start are described in detail, and their influence on the vehicle vibration investigated. NVH related metrics for describing the engine start/stop and vehicle launch are introduced. Key design parameters of the powertrain and driveline on the start/stop NVH behavior are studied. In addition, the impact of engine start on the vehicle's launch behavior is analyzed. Comparisons of different start/stop systems are conducted and results from case studies on the influence to launch delay and “change-of-mind” engine restart are provided. Finally, the effect of missing masking noise during the engine stop phases is discussed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolff Stefan: Auto Start-Stop Funktion - Eine Herausforderung an die Integration in die Gesamtfahrzeugarchitecktur, Haus der Technik, Tagung “Automatische Motor-Start-Stopp-Systeme”, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Denso Technology Overview: Start/Stop Technology, North American International Autoshow, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knorr Rainer: Start/Stop systems on the home straight, ATZ 9/2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asada Toshiaki, Sakai Kazuhito: The New Toyota Stop &amp; Start System, 17. Aachener Kolloquium 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinette, D. and Powell, M., “Optimizing 12 Volt Start -Stop for Conventional Powertrains,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):850-860, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0699.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuang, M., “An Investigation of Engine Start-Stop NVH in A Power Split Powertrain Hybrid Electric Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1500, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1500.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horste, K., “Objective Measurement of Automatic Transmission Shift Feel Using Vibration Dose Value,” SAE Technical Paper 951373, 1995, doi: 10.4271/951373.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Govindswamy, K., Wellmann, T., and Eisele, G., “Aspects of NVH Integration in Hybrid Vehicles,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 2(1):1396-1405, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2085.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reik Wolfgang, Seebacher Roland, Kooy Ad: Dual Mass Flywheel; 6th LuK Symposium, 1998</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fesefeldt Thomas Frank: Ganzheitliche Betrachtung zur Auswahl der Starteinrichtung des Verbrennungsmotors eines Parallel-Hybrids mit Trennkupplung; Dissertation TU Darmstadt, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knoth Heiko, Wilstermann Hartung: Automatisches Stopp-Start-System mit riemengetriebenen Starter-Generator am Beispiel der A/B-Klasse von Mercedes Benz, Haus der Technik, Tagung “Automatische Motor- Start-Stopp-Systeme”, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eisele, G., Wolff, K., Wittler, M., Abtahi, R., et al. “Acoustics of Hybrid Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1402, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1402.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vafidis Constantinos, Cimmino Francesco: FPT's high torque density dual dry clutch transmission CTI 2009 (Berlin)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rudolph F., Schäfer M., Damm A., Metzner F.-T., Steinberg I.: The Innovative Seven Speed Dual Clutch Gearbox for Volkswagen's Compact Cars, 28. Internationales Wiener Motorensymposium 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scherer, H., Bek, M., and Kilian, S., “ZF New 8-speed Automatic Transmission 8HP70 - Basic Design and Hybridization-,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):314-326, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bek Manfred, Schiele Peter: Hydraulic Impulse Oil Storage - How ZF Automatic Transmissions Contribute to CO2 Reduction, 29. Internationales Wiener Motorensympsoium 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kees Marcus, Meyer Christian, Jiang Hong, Schmitz Harald: Start-Stop Technology Challenges for Planetary and Dual Clutch Transmissions, 9th CTI, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiang, H., “Transmission Control Challenges including Hybridization (Stop/Start) and More Speeds,” Presentation at SAE 2012 Transmission &amp; Driveline Symposium: Competition for the Future, Oct. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lechner Gisbert, Naunheimer Harald, Ryborz Joachim: Automotive Transmissions, Springer, 1999</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
