<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169029</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Benchmarking Hybrid Concepts</article-title>
            <subtitle>On-Line vs. Off-Line Fuel Economy Optimization for Different Hybrid Architectures</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dingel</surname>
                  <given-names>Oliver</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pini</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicola</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Trivic</surname>
                  <given-names>Igor</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ross</surname>
                  <given-names>Joerg</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cavina</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicolo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cerofolini</surname>
                  <given-names>Alberto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rioli</surname>
                  <given-names>Mauro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IEV srl</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169025</issue-id>
         <fpage>456</fpage>
         <lpage>470</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169029"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The recent advance in the development of various hybrid vehicle technologies comes along with the need of establishing optimal energy management strategies, in order to minimize both fuel economy and pollutant emissions, while taking into account an increasing number of state and control variables, depending on the adopted hybrid architecture.</p>
            <p>One of the objectives of this research was to establish benchmarking performance, in terms of fuel economy, for real time on-board management strategies, such as ECMS (Equivalent Consumption Minimization Strategy), whose structure has been implemented in a SIMULINK model for different hybrid vehicle concepts. The results obtained from these simulations have then been compared with those derived from a general purpose, off-line optimization technique, based on deterministic DP (Dynamic Programming), and capable of finding the numerical global optimum and of generating the optimal cycle-based control trajectory over a discretized multidimensional grid of the selected state and control variables. The paper investigates the structure of the DP problem and its interactions with the specific hybrid architecture, especially in terms of the most appropriate selection of state and control variables. The implications of the chosen modeling approach are also critically evaluated, searching for the best compromise between accurate simulation results and reliable comparisons between off-line and on-line optimization results.</p>
            <p>One of the outcomes is that the system model should be designed in order to be compatible with efficient DP techniques implementation, with the objective of obtaining robust optimal control policies while achieving acceptable computational costs.</p>
            <p>The concepts that have been analyzed in this work are the following two parallel hybrid architectures: HEV (Hybrid Electric Vehicle), normally applied in current hybrid vehicles production, and HSF-HV (High Speed Flywheel Hybrid Vehicle), an interesting and promising hybrid mechanical solution. An example of the influence of the selected gear has also been investigated by implementing a multi-dimensional DP optimization routine. In order to perform this analysis, a general purpose DP MATLAB function, including specifically designed algorithms to avoid numerical interpolation issues that typically occur in constrained problems, has been modified to run any SIMULINK-based engine-vehicle model.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dingel, O., Ross PhD, J., Trivic, I., Cavina, N. et al., “Model-Based Assessment of Hybrid Powertrain Solutions,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0070, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Trivic I., “Comparative Analysis of Alternative Hybrid Systems for Automotive Applications”, PhD Thesis, University of Bologna, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onori S., Serrao L., “On Adaptive-ECMS Strategies for Hybrid Electric Vehicles”, IFP Energies Nouvelles RHEVE, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sciarretta A., Back M., Guzzella L., “Optimal Control of Parallel Hybrid Electric Vehicles”, IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, Vol 12., No.2, May 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musardo C., Rizzoni G., Staccia B., “A-ECMS: An Adaptive Algorithm for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Management”, Proceedings of the 44th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control and the European Control Conference 2005, Seville, Spain, MoC13.2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kerem K., “Modeling and Control of a Hybrid Electric Vehicle for Drivability and Fuel Economy Improvements”, PhD Thesis, Ohio State University, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertsekas D.P., “Dynamic Programming and Optimal Control”, Athena Scientific, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bellman R. E., “Dynamic Programming”, Princeton University Press, NJ, 1957</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guzzella L., Sciarretta A., “Vehicle Propulsion Systems - Introduction to Modeling and Optimization”, 2nd edition, Springer Verlag Berlin, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rizzoni G., Guzzella L., Baumann B., “Unified Modeling of Hybrid Electric Vehicle Drivetrains”, IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics, Vol. 4, No. 3, September 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundström O., Guzzella L., “A Generic Dynamic Programming Matlab Function”, 18th IEEE International Conference on Control Applicactions, Saint Petersburg, Russia, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Berkel K., Rullens S., Hofman T., Voremen B., Steinbuch M., “Analysis of optimal mechanical-hybrid Powertrain Topologies”, 2012 IFAC Workshop (ECOSIM).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moro, D., Cavina, N., Trivić, I., and Ravaglioli, V., “Guidelines for Integration of Kinetic Energy Recovery System (KERS) based on Mechanical Flywheel in an Automotive Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1448, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1448.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrao L., Onori S., Rizzoni G., “ECMS as a realization of Pontryagin's minimum principle for HEV control”, 2009 American Control Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundström O., Ambühl D., Guzzella L., “On Implementation of Dynamic Programming for Optimal Control Problems with Final State Constraints”, Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology, Rev. IFP, Vol. 65, No. 1, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundström O., “Optimal Control and Design of Hybrid- Electric Vehicles”, PhD Thesis, ETH Zurich (diss. ETH No. 18543), 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Berkel K., Hofman T., Vroemen B., Steinbuch M., “Optimal Control of a Mechanical Hybrid Powertrain”, IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, Vol.61, No.2, February 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ambühl D., “Energy Management Strategies for Hybrid Electric Vehicles”, PhD Thesis, ETH Zurich (diss. ETH No. 18435), 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
