<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284988</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of Electrostatic Screen Battery for Emissions Control (ESBEC) with Diesel Emissions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Han</surname>
                  <given-names>Taewon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhen</surname>
                  <given-names>Huajun</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mainelis</surname>
                  <given-names>Gediminas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>December 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284959</issue-id>
         <fpage>2312</fpage>
         <lpage>2319</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284988"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>We recently developed a novel diesel emissions control device, Electrostatic Screen Battery for Emissions Control (ESBEC), where diesel exhaust particles are collected onto metal screens using electrostatic principle. This paper focuses on further development of this technology: design and integration of a particle charger and testing of ESBEC with diesel exhaust. Two units - 0.038 and 0.152 m (1.5 and 6 inches) in diameter - were fabricated using 3D printing. Both units feature cylinder-shaped housing integrating the electrical charger and up to seven pairs of metal screens, which collect airborne particles. In the small-scale version, particles are charged by ions emitted from a carbon fiber brush, while in the large-scale version, this is done by using two tungsten wires traversing the cross-section of ESBEC in a crisscross pattern. Small-scale version showed average collection efficiency of 80% over a wide range of diesel exhaust mass concentrations (5 to 400 mg/m³) and 1.5 m/s diesel exhaust face velocity. When ESBEC was tested continuously for 6 hours with diesel exhaust concentration of 300-400 mg / m³, it maintained collection efficiency of &gt;95%. The pressure drop across ESBEC during those six hours increased only minimally. In the next step, the large-scale version was challenged with diesel exhaust of 200 mg/m³ concentration. ESBEC removed 71-99% of exhaust particle mass entering the collector at different temperatures (40-77 °C). In the near future, a full version of ESBEC will be fabricated from a heat-resistant material, and its performance will be compared with a conventional diesel particulate filter.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCE</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hill, L.B., Zimmerman N.J., and Gooch J., "A multi-city investigation of the effectiveness of retrofit emissions controls in reducing exposures to particulate matter in school buses." 2005: Clean Air Task Force Boston, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guan, B., et al., Review of the state-of-theart of exhaust particulate filter technology in internal combustion engines. Journal of Environmental Management, 2015. 154: p. 225-258.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ziegler, T.B., Reducing Diesel Emissions, Improving Air Quality, and Promoting Environmental Justice in Southwest Detroit. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F., et al., Impact on vehicle fuel economy of the soot loading on diesel particulate filters made of different substrate materials. Energy, 2015. 86: p. 19-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Emissions, P.M. and Retrofits E.T., Diesel Retrofit Technology. 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ntziachristos, L. and Samaras Z., New directions: emerging demands for vehicle particle emission characterisation. Atmospheric Environment, 2003. 37(3): p. 441-442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayer, A., Egli, H., Burtscher, H., Czerwinski, J. et al., "Particle Size Distribution Downstream Traps of Different Design," SAE Technical Paper 950373, 1995, doi:10.4271/950373</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wirojsakunchai, E., Schroeder, E., Kolodziej, C., Foster, D. et al., "Detailed Diesel Exhaust Particulate Characterization and Real-Time DPF Filtration Efficiency Measurements During PM Filling Process," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0320, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sappok, A. and Wong, V., "Ash Effects on Diesel Particulate Filter Pressure Drop Sensitivity to Soot and Implications for Regeneration Frequency and DPF Control," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):380-396, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0811.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, N., Rutland, C., Foster, D., Narayanaswamy, K. et al., "Investigation into Different DPF Regeneration Strategies Based on Fuel Economy Using Integrated System Simulation," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1275, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bikas, G. and Zervas E., Regulated and Non-Regulated Pollutants Emitted during the Regeneration of a Diesel Particulate Filter. Energy &amp; Fuels, 2007. 21(3): p. 1543-1547.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A., et al., Regulated and Unregulated Emissions from Highway Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines Complying with U.S. Environmental Protection Agency 2007 Emissions Standards. Journal of the Air &amp; Waste Management Association, 2011. 61(4): p. 427-442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothe, D., et al., Emissions during active regeneration of a diesel particulate filter on a heavy duty diesel engine: Stationary tests. Journal of Aerosol Science, 2015. 90: p. 14-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xiancheng, W., Xiyan, G., Hua, R., and Shuyi, W., "Experimental Investigation on Electrostatic DPF," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01- 0194, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0194.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sato, S., et al. A removal system of diesel particulate using electrostatic precipitator with discharge plasma. in Industry Applications Conference, 2005. Fourtieth IAS Annual Meeting. Conference Record of the 2005. 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayashi, H., et al. Collection of diesel exhaust particle using electrostatic charging prior to mechanical filtration. Electrostatics Joint Conference. Boston, MA, USA. http://www.electrostaticanswers. com/2009ESJC/Session04/2009 Hayashi Collection of diesel exhaust particle using electrostatic charging. pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farnoud, A., Huang C., and Armendariz A.J., Using electrostatic precipitation to control diesel exhaust particulate emissions. 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mainelis, G., Han T., and Seshadri S., United States Patent: 8721767 -Electrostatic screen device and method for emission control. May 13, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, T., et al., Aerosol Deposition on Electroformed Wire Screens. Aerosol Science and Technology, 2009. 43(2): p. 112-119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, T. and Mainelis G., Design and development of an electrostatic sampler for bioaerosols with high concentration rate. Journal of Aerosol Science, 2008. 39(12): p. 1066-1078.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, T., An H.R., and Mainelis G., Performance of an Electrostatic Precipitator with Superhydrophobic Surface when Collecting Airborne Bacteria. Aerosol Science and Technology, 2010. 44(5): p. 339-348.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, T., et al., Collection efficiencies of an electrostatic sampler with superhydrophobic surface for fungal bioaerosols. Indoor Air, 2011. 21(2): p. 110-120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, T., Fennell D., and Mainelis G., Development and Optimization of the Electrostatic Precipitator with Superhydrophobic Surface (EPSS) Mark II for Collection of Bioaerosols. Aerosol Science and Technology, 2015. 49(4): p. 210-219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, T. and Mainelis G., Design and Development of an Electrostatic Screen Battery for Emission Control (ESBEC). Journal of Aerosol Science, 2015. Submitted.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dou, D., Application of Diesel Oxidation Catalyst and Diesel Particulate Filter for Diesel Engine Powered Non-Road Machines. Platinum Metals Review, 2012. 56(3): p. 144-154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhong, D., He, S., Tandon, P., Moreno, M. et al., "Measurement and Prediction of Filtration Efficiency Evolution of Soot Loaded Diesel Particulate Filters," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0363, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdul-Khalek, I., Kittelson, D., and Brear, F., "The Influence of Dilution Conditions on Diesel Exhaust Particle Size Distribution Measurements," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1142, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B., Recent measurements of nanoparticle emissions from engines. Current Research on Diesel Exhaust Particles, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhu, Y., et al., Study of ultrafine particles near a major highway with heavy-duty diesel traffic. Atmospheric Environment, 2002. 36(27): p. 4323-4335.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B., Engines and nanoparticles: a review. Journal of Aerosol Science, 1998. 29(5-6): p. 575-588.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hinds, W.C., Aerosol technology: properties, behavior, and measurement of airborne particles. 1999, New Jersey: Wiley-Blackwell.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
