<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023255</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Tax Avoidance and Tax Risk</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Tax Avoidance and Ex Ante Cost of Capital</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Cook</surname>
                  <given-names>Kirsten A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Texas Tech University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Moser</surname>
                  <given-names>William J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Miami University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Omer</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Nebraska – Lincoln</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>40</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023255"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We investigate the relationship between tax avoidance and ex ante cost of capital. We provide evidence that investors perceive tax avoidance differently at different levels. We find that, if low tax-avoidance firms increase tax avoidance, ex ante cost of capital declines. In contrast, if high tax-avoidance firms increase tax avoidance, ex ante cost of capital increases. These findings suggest a nonlinear, convex relationship between tax avoidance and ex ante cost of capital. We then estimate a firm-year-specific, expected level of tax avoidance for each sample observation and find that ex ante cost of capital increases as firms deviate from their expected levels of tax avoidance. On average, when firms deviate from their expected levels of tax avoidance in one year, they revert back toward their expected levels of tax avoidance in the following year. Finally, as firms move toward their expected levels of tax avoidance, they experience reductions in their ex ante cost of capital.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>cost of capital</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>tax avoidance</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>book-tax differences</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>effective tax rates</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayers, B. C., J. Jiang, and S. K. Laplante. 2009. Taxable income as a performance measure: The effects of tax planning and earnings quality. Contemporary Accounting Research 26 (1): 15-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blaylock, B., T. Shevlin, and R. J. Wilson. 2012. Tax avoidance, large positive temporary book-tax differences, and earnings persistence. The Accounting Review 87 (1): 91-120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown. J. L. 2011. The spread of aggressive corporate tax reporting: A detailed examination of the corporate-owned life insurance shelter. The Accounting Review 86 (1): 23-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, J. L., and K. D. Drake. 2014. Network ties among low-tax firms. The Accounting Review 89 (2): 483-510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Callahan, C., R. Smith, and A. Wheeler Spencer. 2012. An examination of the cost of capital implications of FIN 46. The Accounting Review 87 (4): 1105-1134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Claus, J., and J. Thomas. 2001. Equity premia as low as three percent? Evidence from analysts’ earnings forecasts for domestic and international stock markets. The Journal of Finance 56 (5): 1629-1666.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crocker, K. J., and J. Slemrod. 2005. Corporate tax evasion with agency costs. Journal of Public Economics 89 (9-10): 1593-1610.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Daske, H. L. Hail, C. Leuz, and R. Verdi. 2008. Mandatory IFRS reporting around the world: Early evidence on the economic consequences. Journal of Accounting Research 46 (5): 1085-1142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Simone, L. L. F. Mills, and B. Stomberg. 2014. What does income mobility reveal about the tax risk-reward tradeoff? Working paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Simone, L., and B. Stomberg. 2012. How do investors value tax avoidance? Working paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">De Waegenaere, A., R. C. Sansing, and J. Wielhouwer. 2010. Financial accounting measures of tax reporting aggressiveness. Working paper, Tilburg University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dechow, P. M., and I. D. Dichev. 2002. The quality of accruals and earnings: The role of accrual estimation errors. The Accounting Review 77 (4): 35-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, M. A., and D. Dharmapala. 2006. Corporate tax avoidance and high-powered incentives. Journal of Financial Economics 79(1): 145-179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desai, M. A., and D. Dharmapala. 2009. Corporate tax avoidance and firm value. The Review of Economics and Statistics 91 (3): 537-546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dhaliwal, D., L. Krull, O. Li, and W. Moser. 2005. Dividend taxes and implied cost of equity capital. Journal of Accounting Research 43 (5): 675-708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dhaliwal, D., S. Heitzman, and O. Z. Li. 2006. Taxes, leverage, and the cost of equity capital. Journal of Accounting Research 44 (4): 691-723.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dyreng, S. D., M. Hanlon, and E. L. Maydew. 2008. Long-run corporate tax avoidance. The Accounting Review 83 (1): 61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Easton, P. D. 2004. PE ratios, PEG ratios, and estimating the implied expected rate of return on equity capital. The Accounting Review 79 (1): 73-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Faulkender, M., M. J. Flannery, K. W. Hankins, and J. M. Smith. 2012. Cash flows and leverage adjustments. Journal of Financial Economics 103 (3): 632-646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flannery, M. J., and K. W. Hankins. 2013. Estimating dynamic panel models in corporate finance. Journal of Corporate Finance 19: 1-19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flannery, M. J., and K. P. Rangan. 2006. Partial adjustment toward target capital structures. Journal of Financial Economics 79 (3): 469-506.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Francis, J., R. LaFond, P. Olsson, and K. Schipper. 2004. Cost of equity and earnings attributes. The Accounting Review 79 (4): 967-1010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Francis. J., R. LaFond, P. Olsson, and K. Schipper. 2005. The market pricing of accruals quality. Journal of Accounting and Economics 39 (2): 295-327.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frank, M. M., L. J. Lynch, and S. O. Rego. 2009. Tax reporting aggressiveness and its relation to aggressive financial reporting. The Accounting Review 84 (2): 467-496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Friedman, M. 1970. The social responsibility of business is to increase its profits. New York Times, September 13, 122-126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frischmann, P. J., T. Shevlin, and R, Wilson. 2008. Economic consequences of increasing the conformity in accounting for uncertain tax benefits. Journal of Accounting and Economics 46 (2-3): 261-278.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gallemore, J., E. L. Maydew, and J. R. Thornock. 2014. The reputational costs of tax avoidance. 2014. Contemporary Accounting Research 31 (4): 1103-1133.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gebhardt, W. R., C. M. Lee, and B. Swaminathan. 2001. Toward an implied cost of capital. Journal of Accounting Research 39 (1): 135-176.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gode, D., and P. Mohanram. 2003. Inferring the cost of capital using the Ohlson-Juettner model. Review of Accounting Studies 8 (4): 399-431.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goh, B. W., J. Lee, C. Y. Lim, and T. Shevlin. 2013. The effect of corporate tax avoidance on the cost of equity. Working paper, Singapore Management University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graham, J. R., M. Hanlon, T. Shevlin, and N. Shroff. 2014. Incentives for tax planning and avoidance: Evidence from the field. The Accounting Review 89 (3): 991-1023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guenther, D. A., S. R. Matsunaga, and B. M. Williams. 2013. Tax avoidance and firm risk. Working paper, University of Oregon.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hail. L., and C. Leuz. 2006. International differences in the cost of equity capital: Do legal institutions and securities regulation matter? Journal of Accounting Research 44 (3): 485-531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanlon, M. 2005. The persistence and pricing of earnings, accruals, and cash flows when firms have large book-tax differences. The Accounting Review 80 (1): 137-166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanlon, M., and S. Heitzman. 2010. A review of tax research. Journal of Accounting and Economics 50: 127-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanlon, M., and J. Slemrod. 2009. What does tax aggressiveness signal? Evidence from stock price reactions to news about tax shelter involvement. Journal of Public Economics 93: 126-141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hutchens, M., and S. Rego. 2013. Tax risk and the cost of equity capital. Working paper, University of Iowa.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inger, K. K. 2014. Relative valuation of alternative methods of tax avoidance. Journal of the American Taxation Association 36 (1): 37-55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khurana, I. K., and W. J. Moser. 2013. Institutional shareholders’ investment horizons and tax avoidance. Journal of the American Taxation Association 35 (1): 111-134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, K. S. McGuire, S. Savoy, and R. Wilson. 2015. How quickly do firms adjust to target levels of tax avoidance? Working paper, University of Rochester.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, J.-B., Y. Li, and L. Zhang. 2011. Corporate tax avoidance and stock price crash risk: Firm-level analysis. Journal of Financial Economics 100 (3): 639-662.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koester, A. 2011. Investor valuation of tax avoidance through uncertain tax positions. Working paper, Georgetown University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kubick, T. R., D. P. Lynch, M. A. Mayberry, and T. C. Omer. 2015. Product market power and tax avoidance: Market leaders, mimicking strategies, and stock return. The Accounting Review 90 (2): 675-702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lambert, R., C. Leuz, and R. E., Verrecchia. 2007. Accounting information, disclosure, and the cost of capital. Journal of Accounting Research 45(2): 385-420.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leary, M. T., and M. R. Roberts. 2005. Do firms rebalance their capital structures? Journal of Finance 60 (6): 2575-2619.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manzon, G., and G. Plesko. 2002. The relation between financial and tax reporting measures of income. Tax Law Review 55: 175-214.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCarty, R. D. 2012. Optimal tax risk and firm value. Working paper, Northeastern University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McGuire, S. T., T. C. Omer, and J. H. Wilde. 2014. Investment opportunity sets, operating uncertainty, and capital market pressure: Determinants of investments in tax shelter activities? Journal of the American Taxation Association 36 (1): 1-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rego, S. O., and R. J. Wilson. 2012. Equity risk incentives and corporate tax aggressiveness. Journal of Accounting Research 50 (3): 775-810.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robinson, L. A., and A. P. Schmidt. 2013. Firm and investor responses to uncertain tax benefit disclosure requirements. Journal of the American Taxation Association 35 (2): 85-120.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scholes, M. S., M. A. Wolfson, M. Erickson, E. L. Maydew, and T. Shevlin. 2009. Taxes and Business Strategy: A Planning Approach. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sikes, S. A., and R. E. Verrecchia. 2014. Externalities of corporate tax avoidance. Working paper, University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Song, W.-L., and A. L. Tucker. 2008. Corporate tax reserves, firm value, and leverage. Working paper, Louisiana State University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilson, R. J. 2009. An examination of corporate tax shelter participants. The Accounting Review 84 (3): 969-999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
