<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26926850</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Guide to Uncertainty Quantification for Experimental Engine Research and Heat Release Analysis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gainey</surname>
                  <given-names>Brian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Longtin</surname>
                  <given-names>Jon P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lawler</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26926847</issue-id>
         <fpage>509</fpage>
         <lpage>290</lpage>
         <page-range>509-524, 289-290</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26926850"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Performing an uncertainty analysis for complex measurement tasks, such as those found in engine research, presents unique challenges. Also, because of the excessive computational costs, modeling-based approaches, such as a Monte Carlo approach, may not be practical. This work provides a traditional statistical approach to uncertainty analysis that incorporates the uncertainty tree, which is a graphical tool for complex uncertainty analysis. Approaches to calculate the required sensitivities are discussed, including issues associated with numerical differentiation, numerical integration, and post-processing. Trimming of the uncertainty tree to remove insignificant contributions is discussed. The article concludes with a best practices guide in the Appendix to uncertainty propagation in experimental engine combustion post-processing, which includes suggested post-processing techniques and down-selected functional relationships for uncertainty propagation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Najt, P. and Foster, D., “Compression-Ignited Homogeneous Charge Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 830264, 1983, doi:10.4271/830264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Thring, R., “Homogeneous-Charge Compression-Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 892068, 1989, doi:10.4271/892068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI): A Pathway to Controlled High-Efficiency Clean Combustion,” International Journal of Engine Research 12:209-226, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Dempsey, A., Walker, N., and Reitz, R., “Effect of Cetane Improvers on Gasoline, Ethanol, and Methanol Reactivity and the Implications for RCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):170-1871, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Lawler, B., Splitter, D., Szybist, J., and Kaul, B., “Thermally Stratified Compression Ignition: A New Advanced Low Temperature Combustion Mode with Load Flexibility,” Applied Energy 189:122-132, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Gainey, B., Hariharan, D., Yan, Z., and Lawler, B., “A Split Injection of Wet Ethanol to Enable Thermally Stratified Compression Ignition,” International Journal of Engine Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">RahimiBoldaji, M., Gainey, B., and Lawler, B., “Thermally Stratified Compression Ignition Enabled by Wet Ethanol with a Split Injection Strategy: A CFD Simulation Study,” Applied Energy, 2019, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2018.11.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Gainey, B., Yan, Z., Gohn, J., RahimiBoldaji, M. et al., “TSCI with Wet Ethanol: An Investigation of the Effects of Injection Strategy on a Diesel Engine Architecture,” SAE Technical Paper 2019-01-1146, 2019, doi:10.4271/2019-01-1146.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Operating a Heavy- Duty Direct-Injection Compression-Ignition Engine with Gasoline for Low Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1442, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Kolodziej, C., Kodavasal, J., Ciatti, S., Som, S. et al., “Achieving Stable Engine Operation of Gasoline Compression Ignition Using 87 AKI Gasoline Down to Idle,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0832, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0832.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Aoyama, T., Hattori, Y., Mizuta, J., and Sato, Y., “An Experimental Study on Premixed-Charge Compression Ignition Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 960081, 1996, doi:10.4271/960081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Babajimopoulos, A., Assanis, D.N., Flowers, D.L., Aceves, S.M. et al., “A Fully Coupled Computational Fluid Dynamics and Multi-Zone Model with Detailed Chemical Kinetics for the Simulation of Premixed Charge Compression Ignition Engines,” International Journal of Engine Research 6(5):497-512, 2005, doi:10.1243/146808705X30503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two-Stage Ignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Sjoberg, M. and Dec, J., “Smoothing HCCI Heat Release with Vaporization-Cooling-Induced Thermal Stratification Using Ethanol,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):7-27, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1760.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Guide to the Expression of Uncertainty in Measurement, ISO/IEC/OIML/BIPM, 1992 (1995).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Petitpas, G., McNenly, M., and Whitesides, R., “A Framework for Quantifying Measurement Uncertainties and Uncertainty Propagation in HCCI/LTGC Engine Experiments,” SAE Int. J. Engines 10(3):1275-1296, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0736.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Petitpas, G., Whitesides, R., Dernotte, J., and Dec, J., “Refining Measurement Uncertainties in HCCI/LTGC Engine Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 2018-01-1248, 2018, doi:10.4271/2018-01-1248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology Evaluation of measurement data - Supplement 1 to the “Guide to the expression of measurement” - Propagation of distributions using Monte Carlo method, JCGM, 2008, 101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Cox, M.G., Harris, P.M., and Siebert, B.R., “Evaluation of Measurement Uncertainty Based on the Propagation of Distributions Using Monte Carlo Simulation,” Measurement Technique 46:824-833, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Chew, G. and Walczyk, T., “A Monte Carlo Approach for Estimating Measurement Uncertainty Using Standard Spreadsheet Software,” Analytical and Bioanalytical Chemistry 402:2463-2469, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Farrance, I. and Frenkel, R., “Uncertainty in Measurement: A Review of Monte Carlo Simulation.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Li, H. and Rutland, C., “Uncertainty Quantification of Direct Injection Diesel and Gasoline Spray Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0836, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c23">The Uncertainty Tree, “Reducing the Uncertainty of Uncertainty Analysis Jon P Longtin,” Review of Scientific Instruments 73:3698, 2002, doi:10.1063/1.1505654.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Randolph, A., “Methods of Processing Cylinder-Pressure Transducer Signals to Maximize Data Accuracy,” SAE Technical Paper 900170, 1990, doi:10.4271/900170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Lee, K., Yoon, M., and Sunwoo, M., “A Study on Pegging Methods for Noisy Cylinder Pressure Signal,” Control Engineering Practice 16:922-929, 2008, doi:10.1016/j. conengprac.2007.10.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c26">McBride, B., Zehe, M., and Gordon, S., “NASA Glenn Coefficients for Calculating Thermodynamic Properties of Individual Species,” NASA/TP-2002-211556, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Hohenberg, G., “Advanced Approaches for Heat Transfer Calculations,” SAE Technical Paper 790825, 1979, doi:10.4271/790825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Woschni, G., “A Universally Applicable Equation for the Instantaneous Heat Transfer Coefficient in the Internal Combustion Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 670931, 1967, doi:10.4271/670931.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Chang, J., Güralp, O., Filipi, Z., Assanis, D. et al., “New Heat Transfer Correlation for an HCCI Engine Derived from Measurements of Instantaneous Surface Heat Flux,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2996, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Annand, W.J.D. and Ma, T.H., “Instantaneous Heat Transfer Rates to the Cylinder Head Surface of a Small Compression- Ignition Engine,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers 185:976-987, 1970-1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>The resulting standard deviation of 25 individual Monte Carlo simulations is performed with 10, 100, 1,000, 10,000, 100,000, and 1,000,000 trials. The spread of standard deviations is compared with a reference line, at y = 2.89, that depicts the standard deviation derived from a statistical approach. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Instrumentation used during fired engine experiments. The range and uncertainty (95% confidence) of each instrument are listed. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Ensemble-averaged cylinder pressure trace superimposed over 300 individual cycles with a measurement uncertainty trace in cylinder pressure (scaled ×5) showing high uncertainty in cylinder pressure near ignition due to cycle-to-cycle variations. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Cylinder pressure uncertainty tree. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Cylinder volume uncertainty tree, where l is the connecting rod length, a is the crank radius, P<sub>os</sub> is the piston pin offset, and A<sub>p</sub> is the piston crown area. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Bulk temperature uncertainty tree. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Square of sensitivity of bulk temperature to pressure, volume, and in-cylinder mass. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Comparison of bulk temperature standard uncertainty including or excluding pressure and volume terms. From this, it is clear that for most of the cycle, including during heat release, there is no significant loss of information by ignoring pressure and volume uncertainty. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Bulk temperature uncertainty tree after trimming unnecessary branches. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Qualitative figure showing how the uncertainty in the derivative (slope) of a set of data is overestimated when the step size is small (yellow) vs. when the step size is large (red). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Uncertainty tree for NHRR. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Square of sensitivity of NHRR to pressure, dP, volume, dV, and the ratio of specific heats. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Uncertainty tree for heat transfer rate, using the Hohenberg heat transfer correlation. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Square of sensitivity of convective heat transfer coefficient, h, to mean piston speed (v<sub>p</sub>), volume, pressure, and bulk temperature (T<sub>bulk</sub>). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Square of sensitivity of the HHTR to convective heat transfer coefficient (h), surface area (A<sub>s</sub>), bulk temperature (T<sub>bulk</sub>), wall temperature (T<sub>wall</sub>), and engine speed (N). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Uncertainty tree for the CGHR curve. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Square of sensitivity of heat transfer scaling factor to total heat release (Q<sub>in</sub>), maximum of CNHR, and maximum of CHT. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Square of sensitivity of CGHR to CNHR, heat transfer scaling factor (α), and CHT. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>MFB curve with curves showing uncertainty added/subtracted. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
