<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Association of Banks in Israel</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26908620</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>מהם הגורמים העיקריים המשפיעים על היצוא של ישראל ומהי תרומתם לפעילות?</article-title>
            <trans-title-group xml:lang="eng">
               <trans-title>What Are the Main Factors Affecting Israel's Exports and What Are Their Contributions to Economic Activity?</trans-title>
            </trans-title-group>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <name-alternatives>
                  <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                     <surname>טל</surname>
                     <given-names>אריה</given-names>
                  </string-name>
                  <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                     <surname>Tal</surname>
                     <given-names>Arie</given-names>
                  </string-name>
               </name-alternatives>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>תמוז תשע"ז / יוני 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">180</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26908615</issue-id>
         <fpage>41</fpage>
         <lpage>47</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26908620"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Israel is a small open economy, with exports of goods and services accounting for about 30 percent of gross domestic product. In this study we examined the extent to which several factors affect export growth using econometric models of the OLS type. We found that the main independent variable influencing exports is global growth, especially growth among Israel's major trading partners, including the United States and some major European economies. At the same time, we found that the impact of the exchange rate on exports is small relative to the variable of global growth. The effect of the real-effective exchange rate of the shekel, which is characterized by the appreciation against the global currency basket in recent years, of exports of services appears to be smaller than the effect of the exchange rate on exports of goods. In our assessment and other international economic institutions, global economic activity is expected to continue to expand at a moderate pace, which may support growth in Israeli exports this year and probably next year as well.</p>
            <p>In addition, as noted above, the appreciation of the exchange rate of the shekel has a greater impact on exports of goods than on exports of services, and was one of the factors that weighed on Israel's competitiveness in the world. This, along with other factors that weigh on the competitiveness of Israel's goods and services and the decrease in the ease of doing business in Israel. We believe that there is a need for long-term government programs aimed at improving the business environment in Israel and supporting a range of factors that could improve the level of productivity in Israel as well as the degree of competitiveness.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>תרשים 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>התרומה השנתית של המשתנים המסבירים במודל היצוא התעשייתי</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>תרשים 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>התרומה השנתית של המשתנים המסבירים במודל יצוא השירותים</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
