<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">93</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186401</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44434270</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Use of Computerized Accident Repair Statistics in Designing for Improved Damageability</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>STEVE</given-names>
                  <surname>STERBACK</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1984</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>590</fpage>
         <lpage>600</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1985 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44434270"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The proliferation of make/model insurance premium rating programs has encouraged auto manufacturers to design new models for reduced accident damage susceptibility and improved repairability. Computerized collision repair estimating has facilitated damageability analysis by providing "real world" accident statistics to evaluate current vehicle designs. Such information is useful in developing design "do's and don'ts" for future models, determining the competitive position of a manufacturer's products or parts pricing levels, establishing damageability objectives for future models and projecting status as the design evolves, determining the effects of downsizing or new materials and correlating damageability crash testing to field experience. Examples from ADP's historical estimate files illustrate these techniques. IN 1982, THE UNITED STATES FEDERAL GOVERNMENT introduced standards requiring passenger car bumpers to protect safety-related components. Throughout the 1970's, more stringent regulations were promulgated, requiring collision protection of all components, and eventually limiting the extent of damage to the bumper system itself. These rule-making actions compelled auto manufacturers to design bumpers for improved damageability. A concurrent development began in the late 1970's - the implementation of make/model premium rating programs by the auto physical damage insurance industry. These rating plans do not replace the normal practice of establishing premiums based on vehicle price and driver risk factors such as age, sex, driving record, garaging location and annual mileage. Rather, they complement traditional methods by relating premium costs to claim costs, based on vehicle damageability characteristics. If a particular model is involved in more accidents, is more easily damaged, or is more difficult and costly to repair once it is damaged than another comparable model, then it makes good business sense to charge higher premiums to insure it. Conversely, the vehicle that experiences lower losses relative to premiums deserves a favorable rating. For the auto manufacturers, make/model insurance ratings are an added factor affecting the marketability of their products. A typical premium discount of 15 - 30% can substantially reduce the annual cost of ownership, as a comparable premium surcharge would increase cost of ownership. These operating cost differences often influence new car buyers' purchase decisions. Manufacturers recognize the positive effect that favorable ratings and avoidance of premium surcharges can have on marketability and are designing new models for reduced damage susceptibility and improved repairability. The effect is analagous to that of fuel economy: Prior to 1974, when gasoline was inexpensive, the design philosophy was often "bigger is better". However, as fuel prices rose, the emphasis on designing smaller, lighter models with improved fuel economy has increased. As make/model rating programs have proliferated through the insurance industry, a similar trend to design for improved damageability has occurred. Though Federal bumper standards were relaxed for 1983 models (from 5mph to 2 1/2 mph), many manufacturers continue to offer bumper protection near the 5 mph level to obtain favorable insurance ratings.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


