<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910535</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Detecting IED Suicide Bombers</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fox</surname>
                  <given-names>William P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. William P. Fox is a professor in the Department of Defense Analysis at the Naval Postgraduate School. He received his BS degree from the United States Military Academy at West Point, New York, his MS at the Naval Postgraduate School, and his PhD at Clemson University. Previous he has taught at the United States Military Academy and Francis Marion University, where he was the chair of mathematics for eight years. He has many publications including books, chapters, journal articles, conference presentations, and workshops. He directs several math modeling contests through COMAP. His interests include applied mathematics, optimization (linear and nonlinear), mathematical modeling, statistical models for medical research, and computer simulations. He is Vice-President of the Military Application Society in INFORMS.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vesecky</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Professor John Vesecky studied electrical engineering at Rice University before attending graduate school at Stanford. After academic posts at the University of Leicester, UK, Stanford, and Michigan he was selected in 1999 as Founding Chairman of the Electrical Engineering Department in the new Jack Baskin Engineering School at the University of California, Santa Cruz. He has served as Chair or Associate Chair ever since. Recent teaching experience has focused on Capstone Design Courses for undergraduates and the impact of technological innovation on environmental challenges. In the 1990s he served on Vice-President Gore’s Environmental Task Force as Chair of the Sensors Panel. His areas of research expertise include radar and radar systems, Earth remote sensing, ocean sensors. and autonomous vehicles. He has a lifelong interest in amateur radio and holds an amateur extra class FCC license, AE6TL. He is an IEEE Fellow.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Laws</surname>
                  <given-names>Kenneth</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Adjunct Professor Kenneth Laws studied physics at the University of California, finishing with a doctorate in 2001. Since then he has done research on topics in radar applications to ocean remote sensing, emphasizing the use of HF (decameter wavelength) radars along the coast line to measure ocean currents. The main thrust of his research has been the analysis of errors in surface current measurements and tracking ships using HF radar. He has also worked with autonomous ocean surface vehicles and renewable energy projects in the coastal environment. His teaching experience includes engineering design classes and bringing the engineering and science aspects of sustainable energy to a wide spectrum of undergraduate students.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>MARCH 2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>44</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910522</issue-id>
         <fpage>12</fpage>
         <lpage>17</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2011, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910535"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bornstein, M H. and H. G. Bornstein. The pace of life, Nature 259. 1976, 557-559.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devore, J.L. Probability and Statistics for Engineering and the Sciences. 5th ed. Duxbury. 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dogaru, T., L. Nguyen, and C. Le. Computer models of the human body signature for sensing through the wall radar applications. Tech. Rpt. ARL-TR-4290, Army Research Laboratory. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fox, W.P., F. Giordano, S. Horton, and M. Weir. A First Course in Mathematical Modeling, 4th ed. Cengage Publishing. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kingsley, S. and S. Quegan. Understanding Radar Systems. McGraw Hill. 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
