<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">90006031</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Noise Source Localization on a Small Wind Turbine Using a Compact Microphone Array with Advanced Beamforming Algorithms</article-title>
            <subtitle>Part II – A Study of Mechanical Noise from Nacelle Using a Wind Turbine Drive Train Simulator</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Patel</surname>
                  <given-names>Hirenkumar</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ramachandran</surname>
                  <given-names>Rakesh C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Raman</surname>
                  <given-names>Ganesh</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jiang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yong</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shi</surname>
                  <given-names>Xiaodong</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Krishnamurthy</surname>
                  <given-names>Mahesh</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>MMAE Department, Illinois Institute of Technology, 10 W 32nd Street, Suite 243, Chicago, IL 60616, USA.</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>ECE Department, Illinois Institute of Technology, 3301 S Dearborn street, Suite 103, Chicago, IL 60616, USA.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">38</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e90006025</issue-id>
         <fpage>89</fpage>
         <lpage>100</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90006031"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The main goal of this study was to separate and evaluate the noise contribution of each sub-component of a small scale wind turbine drive train that contributes to the overall mechanical noise inside the nacelle of a small (8 kW) wind turbine. The experiments were performed in a drive train simulator that housed the drive train of a Viryd 8000 wind turbine. Different wind speeds were simulated on the test stand through a drive system consisting of a motor, gearbox and flywheel. In order to evaluate the overall sound generation single microphone acoustic measurements were made. The frequency of sound generation was observed to be the same as that of vibrations of the drive train measured using two accelerometers. Sound radiated by each component of the drive train was evaluated through acoustic beamforming using a compact microphone array in conjunction with advanced beamforming algorithms. A strong relationship between the drive train power generation, and sound emitted by various mechanical components was observed. A unique contribution of this study is our ability to localize, separate and quantify noise from sub-components in a complex functioning wind turbine drive train.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubbard, H.H., Shepherd, K.P., “Wind turbine acoustics,” NASA Technical Paper 3057 DOE/NASA/20320-77, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, S., Bareiss, R., Guidati, G., “Wind turbine noise”, Springer-Verlag, New York NY1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R.C. Ramachandran, H. Patel, G. Raman, Y. Jiang and M. Krishnamurthy, “Noise Source Localization on a Small Wind Turbine Using a Compact Microphone Array with Advanced Beamforming Algorithms: Part 1 – A Study of Aerodynamic Noise from Blades,” Wind Engineering, Vol. 38, No. 1, pp. 73-88, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kostic, S., Ognjanovic, M., “The noise structure of gear transmission units and the role of gearbox walls,” Faculty of Mechanical Engineering-Kraljevo, Dositejeva 19, 36000 Kraljevo, Serbia, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka, E., Houjoh, H., Mutoh, D., Motoshiromizu, H., Ohno, K., Tanaka, N., “Vibration and sound-radiation analysis for designing a low-noise gearbox with a multi-stage helical gear system,” JSME International Journal, Series C, Volume 46, Number 3, 1178-1185, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takatsu, N., Kato, M., Inoue, K., Ishikawa, M., “Analysis and experiment on the vibration transmission in a single stage gearbox,” Proceedings of the JSME International Conference on Motion and Power Transmissions, Hiroshima, Japan 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rigal, J.F., Karam, A., Play, D., Leneveu, G., “Analysis of a complex mechanical system in computer aided design,” Application to an Automobile Gearbox, Proceedings of the International Gearing Conference, University of Newcastle upon Tyne, UK, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda, Y., Hatamura, K., Kumano, S., Fujii, K., Kurisu, T., Miyauchi, Y., “Analytical approach of transmission gear noise,” Proceedings of the JSME International Conference on Motion and Power Transmissions, Fukuoka, Japan 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sabot, J., Perret-Liaudet, J., “Computation of noise radiated by a simplified gearbox,” Proceedings of the International Gearing Conference, University of Newcastle upon Tyne, UK, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, T., Kohler H.K., “A gearbox structural optimization procedure for minimizing noise radiation,” Proceedings of the International Gearing Conference, University of Newcastle upon Tyne, UK, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kato, M., Inoue, K., Shibata, K., “Evaluation of sound power radiated by a gearbox,” Proceedings of the international gearing conference, University of Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Igarashi, T., Nakayama, A., “Studies on the sound and vibration of a gearbox (1st report effect of gear errors on sound),” Transactions of JSME, Volume 53, Number 485, 176-181, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Igarashi, T., Nishizaki, T., “Studies on the sound and vibration of a gearbox (2nd report effect of casing rigidity on sound),” Transactions of JSME, Volume 54, Number 508, 3037-3042, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oswald, F., Townsend, D.P., Valco, M.J., Spencer, R.H., Drago, R.J., Lenski, J.W., “Influence of gear design parameters on gearbox radiated noise,” Proceedings of the International Gearing Conference, University of Newcastle upon Tyne, UK, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oswald, F., Zakrajsek, J., Atherton, W., Lin, H., “Effect of operating conditions on gearbox noise,” ASME Publication, DE-volume 43-2, 669-674, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Houser, D., “Gear noise,” Dudley’s Gear Handbook, Townsend, D., Edition, Mcgraw Hill Book Company, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosler, R.B., Bowes, M.A., Royal, A.C., “An analytical method for designing low noise helicopter transmissions” Helicopter Acoustics, NASA CP-2052, Part 2, 657-677, 1978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levine, L.S., DeFelice, J.J., “Civil helicopter research aircraft internal noise prediction,” NASA CR-145146, 1977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watanabe, Y., Rouverol, W.S., “Maximum-Conjugacy gearing,” Gear Design, Manufacturing and Inspection Manual, Society of Automotive Engineers, 57-71, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Girgis, R.S., Verma, S.P., “Methods for accurate determination of resonant frequencies and vibration behavior of stators of electrical machines,” IEE Proceedings, Volume 128, Part B, Number 1, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verma, S.P., Li, W., “Measurement of vibrations and radiated acoustic noise of electrical machines,” Sixth International Conference on Electrical Machines and Systems, Volume 2, 861-866, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Timar, P.L., Fazekas, A., Kiss, J., Miklos, A., Yang, S.J., “Noise and vibration of electrical machines,” Elsevier, New York NY1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wallace, A.K., Spee, R., Martin, L.G., “Current harmonics and acoustic noise in AC adjustable speed drives,” IEEE Conference Record, Industry Applications Society Annual Meeting, Volume 1, 483-488, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takahashi, I., Mochikawa, H., “Optimum waveforms of an inverter for decreasing acoustic noise of an induction motor,” IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications, Volume IA-22, Number 5, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Belmans, R., Verdyck, D., Findlay, R., “Electro-mechanical analysis of the audible noise of an inverter-fed squirrel-cage induction motor,” IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications, Volume 27, Number 3, 539-544, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brooks, T., Humphreys, W., “A deconvolution approach for the mapping of acoustic sources (DAMAS) determined from phased microphone arrays,” 10th AIAA/CEAS Aeroacoustic Conference, Manchester, UK, May 10-12 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sijtsma, P., “CLEAN based on spatial coherence,” 13th AIAA/CEAS Aeroacoustic Conference, Rome, May 21-23, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dougherty, R.P., “Phased array technology applied to aeroacoustics,” 15<sup>th</sup>AIAA/CEAS Aeroacoustics Conference, Miami, Florida, May 11-13 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramachandran, R., Raman, G., “Noise Source Localization Using a Compact Phased Array: Studies on a Full Scale Wind Turbine in a Wind Farm,” Wind Engineering, Multi-Science Publishing Company, Volume 36, No.5, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
