<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169064</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Real-Time Powertrain Models of Hybrid Electric Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Geng</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schulte</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ostwestfalen-Lippe UAS</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>May 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169060</issue-id>
         <fpage>34</fpage>
         <lpage>45</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169064"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Hybrid electric powertrains are developed for reducing the fuel consumption and consequently the emission of carbon dioxide. The fuel consumption of those systems depends significantly on the topology of the powertrain and the applied control strategy. For testing and improving the control strategy in terms of the overall system efficiency, Hardware-in-the-Loop (HIL) simulation can be applied. In order to operate the corresponding electronic control units in a virtual environment, it emulates the behavior of the actuator and sensor signals by a real-time simulation of the powertrain. Developing those powertrain models is a time-consuming task, due to high dynamics and high switching frequencies of the electrical subsystem and due to the large diversity of powertrain configurations. The electrical subsystem comprises the electric motor, inverter and battery whereas the different powertrain configurations are composed of the transmission, the combustion engine, the electric drives, etc.. Additionally, the correct power flow and losses within the powertrains components must be considered when HIL simulation is intended to be used for improving the control strategy.</p>
            <p>In this contribution a method for modeling arbitrary combinations of clutches and various types of gears is presented which enables an efficient modeling of transmission systems. The obtained models are real-time capable and the correct power flows and losses are considered. The method is applied to a powertrain with a two mode power-split transmission, which is a typical example comprising electric drives as well as shifting clutches. Finally simulation results will be presented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagener, A., Schulte, T., Waeltermann, P., and Schuette, H., “Hardware-in-the-Loop Test Systems for Electric Motors in Advanced Powertrain Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0498, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ehsani M., Gao Y., Miller J.M., “Hybrid Electric Vehicles: Architecture and Motor Drives,” Proceedings of the IEEE, Vol. 95, 4, pages 719-728, 2007, doi:10.1109/JPROC.2007.892492.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller J. M., “Hybrid Electric Vehicle Propulsion System Architectures of the e-CVT Type,” IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics, Vol. 21, 3, pages 756 - 767, 2006, doi:10.1109/TPEL.2006.872372.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grewe, T., Conlon, B., and Holmes, A., “Defining the General Motors 2-Mode Hybrid Transmission,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0273, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0273.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang Y., Emadi A., “Integrated electro-mechanical transmission systems in hybrid electric vehicles,” Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, 2011, doi:10.1109/VPPC.2011.6042985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Geng S., Schulte T., “Real-Time Models of Hybrid Electric Vehicle Powertrains”, 7th IFAC Symposium on Advances in Automotive Control, 2013, doi:10.3182/20130904-4-JP-2042.00106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pelchen C., Schweiger C., Ottter M., “Modeling and Simulating the Efficiency of Gearboxes and of Planetary Gearboxes,” 2nd International Modelica Conference, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Castillo J.M. Del, “The analytical expression of the efficiency of planetary gear trains,” Mechanism and Machine Theory, Vol. 37, Pages 197-214, 2002, doi:10.1016/S0094-114X(01)00077-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuria J., Kihiu J., “Prediction of Overall Efficiency in Multistage Gear Trains”, Journal of Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 5, 3, Pages 171-177, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraj A. Haj, “Dynamik und Regelung von Automatikgetrieben”, Fortschritt-Berichte VDI, Reihe 12, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Băţăuş M., Maciac A., Oprean M., Vasiliu N., “Automotive Clutch Models for Real Time Simulation”, Proceeding of the Romanian Academy, Vol.12, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wedepohl L.M., Jackson L., “Modified Nodal Analysis: An Essential Addition to Electric Circuit Theory and Analysis,” Engineering Science and Education Journal, Vol. 11, 3, 2002, doi:10.1049/esej:20020301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Natarajan S., “A systematic moethod for obtaining state equations using MNA”, Circuits Devices and System - IEE, Pages 341-346, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Geng S., Schulte T., “Real-Time Models of Powertrain Transmissions”, Powertrain Modeling and Control - PMC12, Bradford - UK, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kiffe A., Riediger W., Schulte T., “Advanced preprocessing and correction-methods for automated generation of FPGA-based simulation of power electronics,” IEEE Power Electronics and Applications, doi:10.1109/EPE.2013.6634677, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soucy J., “A Short Introduction to Padé Approximants,” 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
