<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100238</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">jmonecredbank</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Money, Credit and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00222879</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15384616</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley (Variant)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26614937</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Macroprudential Policies and Housing Prices</article-title>
            <subtitle>A New Database and Empirical Evidence for Central, Eastern, and Southeastern Europe</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>VANDENBUSSCHE</surname>
                  <given-names>JÉRÔME</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>VOGEL</surname>
                  <given-names>URSULA</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>DETRAGIACHE</surname>
                  <given-names>ENRICA</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>March-April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">47</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">S1</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Supplement 1</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26614915</issue-id>
         <fpage>343</fpage>
         <lpage>377</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 International Monetary Fund</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26614937"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Several countries in Central, Eastern, and Southeastern Europe used a rich set of prudential instruments during the recent credit and housing boom and bust cycles. We construct a comprehensive database of these policy measures covering 16 countries at a quarterly frequency. We use this database to investigate whether the policy measures had an impact on housing price inflation. The measures that appeared to be effective were capital measures (minimum capital adequacy ratio, maximum ratio of lending to households to share capital) and nonstandard liquidity measures (marginal reserve requirements (MRRs) on foreign funding, MRRs linked to credit growth).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>LITERATURE CITED</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Aiyar, Shekhar S., Charles W. Calomiris, and Tomasz Wieladek. (2014) “Does Macro-Prudential Regulation Leak? Evidence from a UK Policy Experiment.” Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, 46, 181–214.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Ambrose, Brent W., Piet Eichholtz, and Thies Lindenthal. (2013) “House Prices and Fundamentals: 355 Years of Evidence.” Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, 45, 477–91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bakker, Bas, and Christoph Klingen, eds. (2012) How Emerging Europe Came through the 2008/09 Crisis: An Account by the Staff of the IMF’s European Department. Washington, DC: International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Banai, Adam, Julia Kiraly, and Marton Nagy. (2011) “Home High Above and Home Deep Down Below—Lending in Hungary.”World Bank Policy ResearchWorking Paper No. 5836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Beck, Thorsten, Asli Demirguc-Kunt, Ross Levine, Martin Cihak, and Erik H.B. Feyen. (2013) Financial Development and Structure Data Set, November. http://econ.worldbank. org/WBSITE/EXTERNAL/EXTDEC/EXTRESEARCH/0,contentMDK:20696167Bpage PK:64214825BpiPK:64214943BtheSitePK:469382,00.html (accessed August 2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Blackburne, Edward. F., and Mark W. Frank. (2007) “Estimation of Nonstationary Heterogeneous Panels.” Stata Journal, 7, 197–208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Blanchard, Olivier, Giovanni Dell’Ariccia, and Paolo Mauro. (2012) “Rethinking Macroeconomic Policy.” Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, 42, 200–15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Breitung, Jorg and Mohammad Hashem Pesaran. (2005) “Unit Roots and Cointegration in Panels.” CESifo Working Paper No. 1565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Brown, Martin,Marcel Peter, and SimonWehrmuller. (2009) “Swiss FrancLending in Europe.” Aussenwirtschaft, 64, 167–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Celeska Frosina, Viktorija Gligorova, and Aneta Krstevska. (2011) “Macroprudential Regulation of Credit Booms and Busts—The Experience of the National Bank of the Republic of Macedonia.” World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5770.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Claessens, Stijn, Swati R. Ghosh, and Roxana Mihet. (2013) “Macro-Prudential Policies to Mitigate Financial System Vulnerabilities.” Journal of International Money and Finance, 39, 153–85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Craig, R. Sean, and Changchun Hua. (2011) “Determinants of Property Prices in Hong Kong S.A.R.: Implications for Policy.” IMF Working Paper No. 11/277.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Crowe, Christopher, Giovanni Dell’Ariccia, Deniz Igan, and Pau Rabanal. (2013) “How to Deal with Real Estate Booms: Lessons from Country Experiences.” Journal of Financial Stability, 9, 300–19.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dell’Ariccia, Giovanni, Deniz Igan, Luc Laeven, and Hui Tong, with Bas Bakker, and Jerome Vandenbussche. (2012) “Policies for Macrofinancial Stability: How to Deal with Credit Booms.” IMF Staff Discussion Note 12/06.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Egert, Balazs, and Dubravko Mihaljek. (2007) “Determinants of House Prices in Central and Eastern Europe.” Comparative Economic Studies, 49, 367–88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Enoch, Charles, and Inci Otker-Robe, eds. (2007) Rapid Credit Growth in Central and Eastern Europe—Endless Boom or Early Warning, 1st ed. Houndmills: Palgrave Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Frait, Jan, Adam Gersl, and Jakub Seidler. (2011) “Credit Growth and Financial Stability in the Czech Republic.” World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5771.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Galac, Tomislav. (2010) “The Central Bank as Crisis-Manager in Croatia—A Counterfactual Analysis.” Croatian National Bank Working Paper No. 27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gerlach, Stefan and Wengsheng Peng. (2005) “Bank Lending and Property Prices in Hong Kong” Journal of Banking and Finance, 29, 461–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Goodhart, Charles, and Boris Hofmann. (2007) House Prices and the Macroeconomy: Implications for Banking and Price Stability. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Igan, Deniz, and Heedon Kang. (2011) “Do Loan-to-Value and Debt-to-Income LimitsWork? Evidence from Korea.” IMF Working Paper No. 11/297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Igan, Deniz, and Prakash Loungani. (2012) “Global Housing Cycles.” IMF Working Paper No. 12/217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">International Monetary Fund. (2010) Regional Economic Outlook: Europe—Building Confidence. Washington, DC: International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">International Monetary Fund. (2013) “Key Aspects of Macroprudential Policies.” http://www.imf.org/external/np/pp/eng/2013/061013b.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Jasova, Martina, and Adam Gersl. (2012) “From Credit Boom to Credit Crunch: Effectiveness of Policy Measures in Central and Eastern Europe.” International Journal of Business, Economics and Law, 1, 58–88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Jimenez, Gabriel, Steven Ongena, Jose-Luis Peydro, and Jesus Saurina. (2012) “Macroprudential Policy, Countercyclical Bank Capital Buffers and Credit Supply: Evidence from the Spanish Dynamic Provisioning Experiments.” European Banking Center Discussion Paper No. 2012–011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Kenc, Turalay, Mustafa Ibrahim Turhan, and Onur Yildirim. (2011) “The Experience with Macro-Prudential Policies of the Central Bank of the Republic of Turkey in Response to the Global Financial Crisis.” World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Koetter, Michael, and Tigran Poghosyan. (2010) “Real Estate Prices and Bank Stability.” Journal of Banking and Finance, 34, 1129–38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Kraft, Evan, and Tomislav Galac. (2011) “Macroprudential Regulation of Credit Booms and Busts—The Case of Croatia.” World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Kruszka, Michal, and Michal Kowalczyk. (2011) “Macro-Prudential Regulation of Credit Boom and Busts—The Case of Poland” World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5832.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Kuttner, Kenneth N., and Ilhyock Shim. (2013) “Can Non-Interest Rate Policies Stabilize Housing Markets? Evidence from a Panel of 57 Economies.” BIS Working Papers No. 433.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Lim, Cheng Hoon, Francesco Columba, Alejo Costa, Piyabha Kongsamut, Akira Otani, Mustafa Saiyid,TorstenWezel, and XiaoyongWu. (2011) “Macroprudential Policy: What Instruments and How to Use Them? Lessons from Country Experiences.” IMFWorking Paper No. 11/238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Maddala, Gangadharrao S., and Shaowen Wu. (1999) “A Comparative Study of Unit-Root Tests with Panel Data and a New Simple Test.” Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 61, 631–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Malpezzi, Stephen. (1999) “A Simple Error Correction Model of Housing Prices.” Journal of Housing Economics, 8, 27–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">National Bank of Poland. (2006) Financial Stability Report 2006. Warsaw: National Bank of Poland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Oikarinen, Elias. (2009) “Interaction between Housing Prices and Household Borrowing: The Finnish Case.” Journal of Banking and Finance, 33, 747–56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Pereira da Silva, Luiz A., and Ricardo Eyer Harris. (2012) “Sailing through theGlobal Financial Storm: Brazil’s Experience with Monetary and Macroprudential Policies to Lean Against the Financial Cycle and Deal with Systemic Risks.” Central Bank of Brazil Working Paper No. 290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Persyn, Damiaan, and JoakimWesterlund. (2008) “Error Correction Based Cointegration Tests for Panel Data.” Stata Journal, 8, 232–41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">REAS (in cooperation with Jones Lang LaSalle). (2008–12) Residential Markets in Central European Capitals.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Shim, Ilhyock, Bilyana Bogdanova, Jimmy Shek, and Agne Subelyte. (2013) “Database for Policy Actions on Housing Markets.” BIS Quarterly Review, September, 83–95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Sutt, Andres, Helen Korju, and Kadri Siibak. (2011) “The Role of Macro-Prudential Policies in the Boom and Adjustment Phase of the Credit Cycle in Estonia.” World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5835.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Terrier,Gilbert, RodrigoValdes,Camilo Tovar, JorgeChan-Lau, Carlos Fernandez-Valdovinos, Mercedes Garcıa-Escribano, Carlos Medeiros,Man-Keung Tang, MercedesVera Martin, and ChrisWalker. (2011) “Policy Instruments to Lean against theWind in Latin America.” IMF Working Paper No. 11/159.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Tovar Camilo,Mercedes Garcia-Escribano, andMercedes Vera Martin. (2012) “Credit Growth and the Effectiveness of Reserve Requirements and Other Macroprudential Instruments in Latin America.” IMF Working Paper No. 12/142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Westerlund, Joakim. (2007) “Testing for Error Correction in Panel Data.” Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 69, 709–48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Wong, Eric, TomFong, Ka-fai Li, and Henry Choi. (2011) “Loan-to-Value Ratio as aMacroprudential Tool: Hong Kong’s Experience and Cross-Country Evidence.” Hong Kong Monetary Authority Working Paper No. 01/2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>CESEE Countries: Seasonally Adjusted Real Housing Price Index, 1997:Q1–2011:Q1.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>CESEE Countries: Household and Mortgage Lending</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Number of Macroprudential Policy Changes in the Database (by Category of Measure).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>CESEE Countries: Macroprudential Measures by Country</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>CESEE Countries: Cumulative Changes in Strength of Prudential Regulation, 1997:Q1–2011:Q1.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Summary Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Macroprudential Policies and Housing Prices—Preliminary Regressions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Macroprudential Policies and Housing Prices—Baseline Regression</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Dynamic Multiplier of Shock to Selected Macroprudential Policies.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Isolating the Effects of Changes in Macroprudential Policies That Are Known to Be Exogenous</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Isolating the Effects of Easing Macroprudential Measures during the Boom Period</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Macroprudential Measures and Household Credit</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
