<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440071</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The New Deal for Young People Five Years On</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Giacomo</given-names>
                  <surname>De Giorgi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2005</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440065</issue-id>
         <fpage>371</fpage>
         <lpage>383</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2005</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440071"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The New Deal for Young People is the major welfare-to-work programme in the UK. It is a mandatory multistage policy targeted at 18- to 24-year-old unemployed people. This paper investigates the long-term effectiveness of the programme in terms of enhancing the (re-)employment probability of participating men. It exploits the eligibility rule to identify a suitable counterfactual relying upon a simple regression discontinuity design. The combination of job-search assistance, training, wage subsidies and job experience enhances employability by about 4.6 per cent and this effect lasts over different cohorts.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1e141a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e148" publication-type="other">
The author would like to thank Erich Battistin, Richard Blundell, Pedro Carneiro, Hideiko Ichimura,
an editor and two anonymous referees for useful comments and suggestions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e158a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e165" publication-type="other">
JSA is the only unemployment insurance targeted at the group of interest in this work. In order to be
eligible, an unemployed person has to be willing and able to work (previous employment history is not
required); before the introduction of the New Deal, only weak requirements were imposed to ensure
receipt of JSA in principle indefinitely.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e181a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e188" publication-type="other">
The sanction for non-compliers is the withdrawal of benefit, at least temporarily.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e195a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e202" publication-type="other">
The NDYP is basically the only programme available to young men, whereas there are other
programmes for women which are not easily distinguishable and which are therefore a source of potential
identification problems. Furthermore, most of the treated individuals (75 per cent) are male.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e216a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e223" publication-type="other">
The starting date of the JSA should coincide with the start of the unemployment period. The 18-
month cut-off point is due to the fact that the control group that will be exploited later would enter an
ALMP after 18 months in open unemployment. A shorter period would not consider those participants
who take the education and training option (see Section H).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e239a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e246" publication-type="other">
This is due to the availability of data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e253a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e260" publication-type="other">
A limited number of unemployed people, not included in the analysis, can access the programme
earlier than the sixth month. This particular group is composed of ex-offenders, disabled people and
unemployed people lacking very basic skills (with reading and writing difficulties).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e273a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e280" publication-type="other">
This is not always the case since certain units of delivery tend to favour a particular option.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e287a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e296" publication-type="other">
Such a subsidy seems quite generous when compared with the sort of hourly rate (close to the
minimum wage) a typical participant would get. In a crude computation, the weekly subsidy plus the
one-off payment would amount to about 50 per cent of weekly pay for a minimum-wage worker;
however, the £750 has to compensate for the loss of production due to the minimum one-day-a-week
training. Under very simple assumptions (perfectly competitive markets), £750 would not be enough to
compensate for that loss. In fact, taking the latter into account, the subsidy would be no greater than 30
per cent, although this is still generous. However, job turnover could itself be quite costly, making such
an option not as appealing as it looks at first glance. This point seems to be confirmed by the low take-up
rate in the data - only a sixth of those entering an option go for the subsidised job.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e328a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e335" publication-type="other">
Formal derivation and technical details of identification and possible estimation strategies are
available in De Giorgi (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e346a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e353" publication-type="other">
The actions of potential participants before and after the programme, during the first six months of
unemployment, are not consistent with any sort of anticipatory behaviour (De Giorgi, 2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e363a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e370" publication-type="other">
The vast majority (about 90 per cent) of the treated would have completed their first option by that
time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e380a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e387" publication-type="other">
There may be anticipatory behaviour in the control groups, given that they are offered a similar
programme after 18 months in open unemployment. Concern regarding this possibility can be dismissed
by comparing the behaviour of 25- to 30-year-olds before and after the programme.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e400a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e407" publication-type="other">
This limit arises from the availability of data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e414a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e421" publication-type="other">
This refers to specifications (i) and (ii) since the higher-order terms in specification (iii) are
statistically insignificant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e431a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e438" publication-type="other">
Obviously, this would impose a much stronger identification structure - for example, constant
treatment effects.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e449a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e456" publication-type="other">
It is worth mentioning, as pointed out by a referee, that such displacement might also arise from
enhanced job search. However, in this respect, it might simply be that the matching function is improved
and vacancies are filled more efficiently, without affecting the outcome of the control groups.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e469a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e476" publication-type="other">
This computation does not involve any steady-state analysis; it only applies the point estimate (Table
1, column (ii)), plus or minus twice the standard error, to the pool of unemployed men (about 560,000)
involved in the programme up to December 2001.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e489a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e496" publication-type="other">
Confirming earlier findings from Blundell et al. (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e503a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e510" publication-type="other">
Unfortunately, the available data do not permit such analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1e526a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e530" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. (2002), 'Welfare-to-work: which policies work and why?', Keynes Lecture in
Economics, Proceedings of the British Academy, vol. 117, pp. 477-524.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e540a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e544" publication-type="other">
— and Costa-Dias, M. (2000), 'Evaluation methods for non-experimental data', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 21, pp. 427-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e554a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e558" publication-type="other">
—, —, Meghir, C. and Van Reenen, J. (2004), 'Evaluating the employment impact of a
mandatory job search program', Journal of the European Economic Association, vol. 2,
pp. 569-606.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e571a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e575" publication-type="other">
Boeri, T., Layard, R. and Nickell, S. (2000), Welfare-to-Work and the Fight against Long-
Term Unemployment, Research Report no. 206, London: Department for Education and
Employment.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e589a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e593" publication-type="other">
De Giorgi, G. (2005), 'Long-term effects of a mandatory multistage program: the New Deal
for young people in the UK', Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working Paper no. 05/08.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e603a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e607" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions (2004), Building on New Deal: Local Solutions Meeting
Individual Needs, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e617a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e621" publication-type="other">
Hahn, J., Todd, P. and van der Klaauw, W. (2001), 'Identification and estimation of treatment
effects with a regression-discontinuity design', Econometrica, vol. 69, pp. 201-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e631a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e635" publication-type="other">
Heckman, J., Lalonde, R. and Smith, J. (1999), 'The economics and econometrics of active
labor market programs', in O. Ashenfelter and D. Card (eds), Handbook of Labor
Economics, Volume 3, Amsterdam: Elsevier Science.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e648a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e652" publication-type="other">
Katz, L. (1998), 'Wage subsidies for the disadvantaged', in P. Gottschalk and R. Freeman
(eds), Generating Jobs: How to Increase Demand for Less-Skilled Workers, New York:
Russell Sage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e665a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e669" publication-type="other">
Thistlethwaite, D. and Campbell, D. (1960), 'Regression discontinuity analysis: an alternative
to the ex post facto experiment', Journal of Educational Psychology, vol. 51, pp. 309-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e680a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e684" publication-type="other">
van den Berg, G., van der Klaauw, B. and van Ours, J. (2004), 'Punitive sanctions and the
transition rate from welfare to work', Journal of Labor Economics, vol. 22, pp. 211-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e694a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e698" publication-type="other">
Van Reenen, J. (2003), 'Active labor market policies and the British New Deal for
unemployed youth in context', in R. Blundell, D. Card and R. Freeman (eds), Seeking a
Premier League Economy, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
