<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440151</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Opting for Opting-In? An Evaluation of the European Commission's Proposals for Reforming VAT on Financial Services</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Rita</given-names>
                  <surname>de la Feria</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Ben</given-names>
                  <surname>Lockwood</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">31</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440149</issue-id>
         <fpage>171</fpage>
         <lpage>202</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2010</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440151"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper provides a legal and economic analysis of the European Commission's recent proposals for reforming the application of VAT to financial services, with particular focus on their 'third pillar', under which firms would be allowed to opt in to taxation on exempt insurance and financial services. From a legal perspective, we show that the proposals' 'first and second pillars' would give rise to considerable interpretative and qualification problems, resulting in as much complexity and legal uncertainty as the current regime. Equally, an option to tax could potentially follow significantly different legal designs, which would give rise to discrepancies in the application of the option amongst Member States of the European Union (EU). On the economic side, we show that quite generally, when firms cannot coordinate their behaviour, they have an individual incentive to opt in on business-to-business (B2B) transactions, but not on business-to-consumer (B2C) transactions. We also show that opting-in eliminates the cost disadvantage that EU financial services firms face in competing with foreign firms for B2B sales. But these results do not hold if firms can coordinate their behaviour. An estimate of the upper bound on the amount of tax revenue that might be lost from allowing opting-in is provided for a number of EU countries.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d15e162a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e169" publication-type="other">
Submitted August 2009.
The authors would like to thank Michael Devereux for his helpful comments and discussions on earlier
drafts. Earlier versions of this paper were presented at the Seminar on VAT Treatment of Insurance and
Financial Services, organised jointly by the Centre for Business Taxation and the European Commission,
and held in Oxford on 10 December 2008, as well as at the European Tax Policy Forum (ETPF) Annual
Conference, held at the Institute for Fiscal Studies in London on 21 April 2009. The authors are grateful
for the comments received at those presentations, as well as for those of the editor, Antoine Bozio, and of
three anonymous referees. The Centre for Business Taxation has a number of sources of funding from
both public and private sectors, listed on its website at http://www.sbs.ox.ac.uk/centres/tax. This paper
forms part of the work undertaken under ESRC Grant RES-060-25-0033. The authors also gratefully
acknowledge separate funding from the ETPF for carrying out this research. The views expressed are
those of the authors; the Centre has no corporate views.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e211a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e218" publication-type="other">
Council Directive 2006/112/EC of 28 November 2006 on the common system of value added tax, OJ
L347, 11 December 2006, 1-118, hereafter 'VAT Directive'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e228a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e235" publication-type="other">
These are known as margin-based products.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e242a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e249" publication-type="other">
The cash-flow method and the TCA method are reviewed in Section V of this paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e257a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e264" publication-type="other">
Fiscalis is a training programme organised by the European Commission and directed at the officials
of national tax administrations. Its principal aim is to improve the operation of taxation systems in the
EU; see Decision 1482/2007/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 11 December 2007, OJ
L330, 15 December 2007, 1-7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e280a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e287" publication-type="other">
See Commission of the European Communities (2006) and case C-472/03, [2005] ECR 1-1719. For an
analysis of the Accenture ruling and its impact, see de la Feria (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e297a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e304" publication-type="other">
The Council's Working Party on Tax Questions - Indirect Taxation (VAT) has met over 15 times
since January 2008 to discuss these proposals. Agendas for those meetings are available as
Communications from the Council of the European Union.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e317a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e324" publication-type="other">
See Document 15793/08 FISC 156, 14 November 2008 from Presidency of the Council of the
European Union to the Working Party on Tax Questions - Indirect Taxation (VAT), at 3-6, and
Document 11013/08 FISC 80, 23 June 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e337a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e344" publication-type="other">
Borselli, 2009, p. 382.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e351a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e358" publication-type="other">
There are a few dissenting voices (Grubert and Mackie, 2000; Jack, 2000; Thuronyi, 2003, pp. 322-
4), but most of the objections raised are dealt with in Auerbach and Gordon (2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e369a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e376" publication-type="other">
For example, if the government can borrow at 12 per cent, the value of intermediation services
provided to the borrower would be £ 15 - £ 12 = £3.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e386a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e393" publication-type="other">
See Poddar and English (1997, example B).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e400a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e407" publication-type="other">
This does not mean that insurance products are exempt from tax. For example, the UK has an
insurance premium tax levied at a rate of either 5 per cent or 17.5 per cent on a range of standard
products.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e420a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e427" publication-type="other">
in fact, under the proposal, a financial services provider is obliged to define a 'taxable amount',
which is the value added on the transaction. But, of course, implicit in this is a price or fee for the service.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e437a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e444" publication-type="other">
If the customer base is largely outside the EU, for example, then much VAT will be recovered, as
input VAT is recoverable on exports to outside the EU.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e454a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e461" publication-type="other">
The UK Treasury estimates that in 2006, VAT revenue lost due to exemptions in the financial
services sector was £4,200 million, rising to £4,500 million in the following year (HM Treasury, 2007).
But, of course, this figure comprises any revenue lost from not imposing VAT on sales to VAT-exempt
customers (mainly the household sector), minus irrecoverable VAT paid by financial services firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e478a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e485" publication-type="other">
Case C-2/95, SDC, [1997] ECR 1-3017.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e492a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e499" publication-type="other">
Case C-235/00, CSC Financial Services, [2001] ECR 1-10237.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e506a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e513" publication-type="other">
Case C-169/04, Abbey National, [2006] ECR 1-4027.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e520a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e527" publication-type="other">
Case C-453/05, Volker Ludwig, [2007] ECR 1-5083.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e534a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e541" publication-type="other">
0n this regard, see various documents from the Presidency of the Council of the European Union to
the Working Party on Tax Questions - Indirect Taxation (VAT).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e551a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e558" publication-type="other">
Case C-168/07, OJ C129, 9 June 2007, p. 8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e566a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e573" publication-type="other">
By Court's Order of 11 August 2009.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e580a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e587" publication-type="other">
For an analysis of the legal design of the cost-sharing group provisions in Portugal, see Deloitte
(2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e597a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e604" publication-type="other">
The meaning of the expression 'reimbursement of their share of the joint expenses' in current Article
132(l)(f) was recently the object of debate in case C-407/07, Stichting Centraal Begeleidingsorgaan voor
de Intercollegiate Toetsing, Judgment of 11 December 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e617a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e624" publication-type="other">
The meaning of the reference to 'distortions of competition' in Article 132(l)(f) was the main issue
in case C-8/01, Assurandor-Societetet, [2003] ECR 1-13711.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e634a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e641" publication-type="other">
It has been noted that this bias is more intense in larger financial institutions, as 'smaller financial
firms are more likely to outsource rather than provide services in-house', thus perversely creating an
additional layer of competitive inequality between larger and smaller firms (Schenk, 2008, p. 40).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e654a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e661" publication-type="other">
Theoretically, the option may also be restricted only to B2C transactions, but in practice that would
seem to be an unlikely design.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e672a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e679" publication-type="other">
This assumption maximises the magnitude of the general equilibrium effect, and so subsequent
calculations should be interpreted as upper bounds on the size of this effect.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e689a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e696" publication-type="other">
Zee (2005) proposes a method for collecting an invoice-credit VAT on some margin-based
transactions, as an alternative to the TCA method.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e706a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e713" publication-type="other">
For more extensive discussion of this kind of example, see Poddar and English (1997) or Ebrill et al.
(2001, ch. 8).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e723a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e730" publication-type="other">
See also Commission of the European Communities (2000) for a detailed discussion of TCA.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e737a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e744" publication-type="other">
0ne could take the view that the inability to get the rate exactly right does not really matter much.
There are other areas of tax policy where we know we cannot get it exactly right - in setting depreciation
allowances, for example, and in transfer-pricing adjustments - but it is still considered to be worth doing,
even if imperfectly.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e760a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e767" publication-type="other">
For example, the C-efficiency ratio for the UK is 0.49.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e775a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e782" publication-type="other">
This methodology is obviously subject to the flaw that the pattern of consumption of intermediate
inputs by financial services is generally different from the pattern of aggregate consumption. But, given
data limitations, there is no satisfactory way of making further adjustments to deal with this problem.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e795a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e802" publication-type="other">
Article 6(2) of the UStG 1994.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e809a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e816" publication-type="other">
Article 44 of the Belgian VAT Code and Circular 79/018.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e823a1310">
            <label>37</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e830" publication-type="other">
Article 16(3) of the Estonian VAT Act.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e837a1310">
            <label>38</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e844" publication-type="other">
Article 85 of the Amended Finance Law 2004 No. 2004-1485 of 30 December 2004.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e851a1310">
            <label>39</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e858" publication-type="other">
For a comprehensive description of the French option to tax, see Pons (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e866a1310">
            <label>40</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e873" publication-type="other">
Article 9(1) of the German VAT Act.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d15e880a1310">
            <label>41</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e887" publication-type="other">
Article 28 of the Lithuanian VAT Act.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d15e903a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e907" publication-type="other">
Anderson, S. P., de Palma, A. and Kreider, B. (2001), 'Tax incidence in differentiated product
oligopoly', Journal of Public Economies, vol. 81, pp. 173-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e917a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e921" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. J. and Gordon, R. H. (2002), 'Taxation of financial services under a VAT',
American Economie Review, vol. 92, pp. 411-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e931a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e935" publication-type="other">
Barham, V., Poddar, S. N. and Whalley, J. (1987), 'The tax treatment of insurance under a
consumption type, destination basis VAT', National Tax Journal, vol. 40, pp. 171-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e945a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e949" publication-type="other">
Borselli, F. (2009), 'A sensible reform of the EU VAT regime for financial services',
International VAT Monitor, vol. 20, pp. 375-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e960a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e964" publication-type="other">
Cnossen, S. (1999), 'VAT treatment of financial services', in G. Lindenorwa, S. O. Lodin and
B. Wiman (eds), International Studies in Taxation: Law and Economics, The Hague:
Kluwer Law International.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e977a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e981" publication-type="other">
Commission of the European Communities (2000), The TCA System: A Detailed Description,
Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e991a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e995" publication-type="other">
— (2006), Consultation Paper on Modernising Value Added Tax Obligations for Financial
Services and Insurances, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1005a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1009" publication-type="other">
— (2007a), Proposal for a Council Regulation laying down implementing measures for
Directive 2006/112/EC on the common system of value added tax, as regards the
treatment of insurance and financial services, COM(2007) 746 final, 28 November,
Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1025a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1029" publication-type="other">
— (2007b), Proposal for a Council Directive amending Directive 2006/112/EC on the
common system of value added tax, as regards the treatment of insurance and financial
services, COM(2007) 747 final, 28 November, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1042a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1046" publication-type="other">
— (2007c), Impact Assessment Summary: Commission Staff Working Paper accompanying
the Proposal for a Directive amending Directive 2006/112/EC on the common system of
value added tax, as regards the treatment of insurance and financial services, SEC(2007)
1555, 28 November, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1063a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1067" publication-type="other">
— (2008), Proposals on VAT Treatment of Insurance and Financial Services: Case Studies,
Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1077a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1081" publication-type="other">
de la Feria, R. (2007), 'The EU VAT treatment of insurance and financial services (again)
under review', EC Tax Review, vol. 16, pp. 74-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1091a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1095" publication-type="other">
— and Walpole, M. (2009), 'Options for taxing financial supplies in value added tax: EU
VAT and Australian GST models compared', International and Comparative Law
Quarterly, vol. 58, pp. 897-932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1108a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1112" publication-type="other">
Deloitte (2008), 'Grupos de IVA e o Sector Financeiro', IVA - 21%, 21 Anos, 21 Temas,
Estoril: Principia.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1122a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1126" publication-type="other">
Ebrill, L., Keen, M., Bodin, J.-P. and Summers, V. (2001), The Modern VAT, Washington,
DC: International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1136a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1140" publication-type="other">
Ernst &amp; Young (2009), Design and Impact of the 'Option to Tax' System for Application of
VAT to Financial Services, report prepared for the European Banking Federation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1151a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1155" publication-type="other">
Grambeck, H. M. (2009), 'Outsourcing in the EU financial sector: where are we heading?',
International VAT Monitor, vol. 20, pp. 462-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1165a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1169" publication-type="other">
Grubert, H. and Mackie, J. (2000), 'Must financial services be taxed under a consumption
tax?', National Tax Journal, vol. 53, pp. 23-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1179a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1183" publication-type="other">
Henkow, O. (2008), Financial Activities in European VAT: A Theoretical and Legal Research
of the European VAT System and the Actual and Preferred Treatment of Financial
Activities, The Plague: Kluwer Law International.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1196a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1200" publication-type="other">
FIM Treasury (2007), Tax Ready Reckoner and Tax Reliefs, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1207a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1211" publication-type="other">
Floffman, L. A., Poddar, S. N. and Whalley, J. (1987), 'Taxation of banking services under a
consumption type, destination basis VAT', National Tax Journal, vol. 40, pp. 547-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1221a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1225" publication-type="other">
Fhiizinga, H. (2002), 'Financial services: VAT in Europe?', Economic Policy, vol. 35, pp.
499-534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1236a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1240" publication-type="other">
IBFD (2006), VAT Survey: Financial Services, survey on the recovery of input VAT in the
financial sector carried out for the European Commission, Amsterdam: International
Bureau of Fiscal Documentation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1253a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1257" publication-type="other">
Jack, W. (2000), 'The treatment of financial services under a broad-based consumption tax',
National Tax Journal, vol. 53, pp. 841-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1267a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1271" publication-type="other">
Jenkins, G. P. and Khadka, R. (1998), 'Value-added tax policy and implementation in
Singapore', International VAT Monitor, vol. 9, no. 2, pp. 35^47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1281a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1285" publication-type="other">
Kogels, H. A. (2003), 'Consumption taxes and financial services: general report', Cahiers de
Droit Fiscal International, vol. 88b, pp. 21-41.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1295a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1299" publication-type="other">
Lejeune, I., Stevens, D. and Killer, M. (2009), 'The international direction in the VAT
treatment of financial services', in M. Lang, P. Melz and E. Kristoffersson (eds), Value
Added Tax and Direct Taxation: Similarities and Differences, Amsterdam: International
Bureau of Fiscal Documentation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1315a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1319" publication-type="other">
OECD (1998), Indirect Tax Treatment of Financial Services and Instruments, Paris:
Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1330a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1334" publication-type="other">
— (2008), Consumption Tax Trends, Paris: Organisation for Economic Cooperation and
Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1344a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1348" publication-type="other">
Pallot, M. (2007), 'GST and financial services: rating zero-rating', in R. Krever and D. White
(eds), GST in Retrospect and Prospect, Wellington: Thomson Brookers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1358a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1362" publication-type="other">
Poddar, S. N. and English, M. (1997), 'Taxation of financial services under a value-added tax:
applying the cash-flow approach', National Tax Journal, vol. 50, pp. 89-111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1372a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1376" publication-type="other">
Pons, T. (2006), 'Option for taxation of financial services in France', International VAT
Monitor, vol. 17, pp. 182-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1386a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1390" publication-type="other">
PricewaterhouseCoopers (2006), Study to Increase the Understanding of the Economic Effects
of the VAT Exemption for Financial and Insurance Services: Final Report to the
European Commission, 2 November.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1403a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1407" publication-type="other">
Schenk, A. (2008), 'Financial services', in R. Krever (ed.), VAT in Africa, Pretoria: Pretoria
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1418a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1422" publication-type="other">
Swinkels, J. (2005), 'Combating VAT avoidance', International VAT Monitor, vol. 16, pp.
235-46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1432a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1436" publication-type="other">
— (2008), 'The EU VAT exemption for cost-sharing associations', International VAT
Monitor, vol. 19, pp. 13-21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1446a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1450" publication-type="other">
Thuronyi, V. (2003), Comparative Tax Law, The Hague: Kluwer Law International.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d15e1457a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d15e1461" publication-type="other">
Zee, H. H. (2005), 'A new approach to taxing financial intermediation services under a value-
added tax', National Tax Journal, vol. 53, pp. 77-92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
