<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277700</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>BSFC Improvement by Diesel-Rankine Combined Cycle in the High EGR Rate and High Boosted Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yamaguchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Takuya</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Kurume Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aoyagi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuzo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>New Ace Inst Co Ltd</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Osada</surname>
                  <given-names>Hideaki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>New Ace Inst Co Ltd</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shimada</surname>
                  <given-names>Kazuaki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>New Ace Inst Co Ltd</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Uchida</surname>
                  <given-names>Noboru</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>New Ace Inst Co Ltd</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1275</fpage>
         <lpage>1286</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277700"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In heavy duty diesel engines, waste heat recovery systems are remarkable means for fuel consumption improvement. In this paper, Diesel-Rankine combined cycle which is combined diesel cycle with Rankine cycle is studied to clarify the quantitative potential of fuel consumption improvement with a high EGR rate and high boosted diesel engine.</p>
            <p>The high EGR rate and high boosted diesel engine of a single cylinder research engine was used and it reaches brake specific fuel consumption (BSFC) of 193.3 g/kWh at full load (BMEP=2.0MPa). And its exhaust temperature reaches 370 C. The exhaust gas temperature does not exceed 400 C in high boosted diesel engine even at full load operating condition because of a high excess air ratio. On the other hand, exhaust gas quantity is larger due to a high boosting. So, it is estimated that the thermal energy of exhaust gas is enough for recovery in the high boosted diesel engine, although exhaust gas temperature is not so higher than that of an ordinary diesel engine.</p>
            <p>In the heat balance of the high boosted research diesel engine at medium engine speed, the exhaust loss is 38 % at full load. From this result, it is possible to recover the exhaust gas energy, when engine is operated above medium load condition. In this predictive study, water, methanol, toluene, HCFC-123, R134a and R245fa are compared as working fluid in Rankine cycle with superheating. As a result of this study, it is found that Diesel-Rankine combined cycle has a potential to improve BSFC for 2.6 - 3.0 % at full load condition.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoyagi, Y., Osada, H., Misawa, M., Hirosawa, T., Odaka, M. and Goto, Y., “Diesel Combustion and Emission Study using of High Boost and High Injection Pressure in a Single Cylinder Engine (Second Report)”, Transactions of Society of Automotive Engineers of Japan, Vol.36, No. 5, pp.59-64, (2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamaguchi, T., Aoyagi, Y., Osada, H., Shimada, K., Goto, Y. and Suzuki, H., “The Improvement of Thermal Efficiency by Increasing of Compression Ratio and the maximum Cylinder Pressure on High Boosted and High EGR Rate Diesel Combustion in a Single Cylinder Engine”, Transactions of Society of Automotive Engineers of Japan, Vol.42, No.3, pp.761-766, (2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoyagi, Y., Yamaguchi, T., Osada, H., Shimada, K., Goto, Y. and Suzuki, H., “Improvement of thermal efficiency of high-boosted diesel engine with focus on peak cylinder pressure”, International of Journal of ENGINE RESEARCH, Vol.12, No.3, pp.227-237, (2011), doi: 10.1177/1468087411403843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishikawa, M., Terauchi, M., Komori, T., Yasuraoka, J.: Development of High Efficiency Gas Turbine Combined Cycle Power Plant, Mitsubishi Heavy Industries Technical Review, 45(1), (2008) 15-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, S., Eitel, J., Pantow, E., Geskes, P. et al., “Waste Heat Recovery: The Next Challenge for Commercial Vehicle Thermomanagement,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 5(1):395-406, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Latz, G., Andersson, S., and Munch, K., “Comparison of Working Fluids in Both Subcritical and Supercritical Rankine Cycles for Waste- Heat Recovery Systems in Heavy-Duty Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1200, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ringler, J., Seifert, M., Guyotot, V., and Hübner, W., “Rankine Cycle for Waste Heat Recovery of IC Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 67-76, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mago, P J and Chamra L M, “Exergy analysis of a combined engineorganic Rankine cycle configuration”, proc. IMechE, Vol.222, Part A:J. Power and Energy, pp.761-770,(2008), doi: 10.1243/09576509JPE642.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ibaraki, S., Endo, T., Kojima, Y., Takahashi, K., Baba, T., Kawajiri, S.,: Study of Efficient On-board Waste Heat Recovery System using Ranking Cycle, Transactions of Society of Automotive Engineers of Japan, Vol.38, No.4, pp.73-78, (2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teng, H., Regner, G., and Cowland, C., “Waste Heat Recovery of Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines by Organic Rankine Cycle Part I: Hybrid Energy System of Diesel and Rankine Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0537, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0537.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teng, H., Regner, G., and Cowland, C., “Waste Heat Recovery of Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines by Organic Rankine Cycle Part II: Working Fluids for WHR-ORC,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0543, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0543.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">JSME steam tables, Japan Society of Mechanical Engineers, (1980)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NIST Standard Reference Database 69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">JIS Z 9204: General rules for energy evaluation method by available energy, (1991)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John Heywood B.: Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, New York, McGraw-Hill, Inc., (1988), p.130-131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
