<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275431</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling liquid break-up through a kinetic approach</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bella</surname>
                  <given-names>G.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Rome Tor Vergata</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chiappini</surname>
                  <given-names>D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Rome Tor Vergata</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ubertini</surname>
                  <given-names>S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Naples Parthenope</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>390</fpage>
         <lpage>399</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275431"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Liquid atomisation is an important technical field for a wide range of engineering and industrial applications, particularly in the field of internal combustion engines . In these engines, in fact, the amount of pollutants at the engine-out interface is directly related to the quality of the combustion process, which is in turn determined by the quality of the air-fuel mixture preparation in Direct Injection (DI) engines. As a consequence numerical-experimental research is crucial to their development. Despite the significant amount of research that has been carried out on DI engines simulation, breakup modelling is still a challenge.</p>
            <p>In this paper we present a new numerical model for multiphase flows that could be particularly suited for liquid jet and droplet breakup simulation. The model is based on a Lattice Boltzmann (LB) solver coupled to a higher order finite difference treatment of the kinetic forces arising from non-ideal interactions (potential energy). Direct comparisons with literature data for Rayleigh Taylor instability on a liquid jet and single droplet breakup are presented.</p>
            <p>The analysis on the single droplet allows highlighting different regimes of secondary break-up of a liquid drop immersed in a continuous medium under the influence of a gravitational force.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Han and G. Tryggvason, Secondary Breakup of axisymmetric liquid drops. I. Acceleration by a constant body force, Physics of Fluids 1999, Vol. 11</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Prosperetti, G. Tryggvason, Computational methods for multiphase flow, Cambridge University Press, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X. He, S. Chen and R. Zhang, A Lattice Boltzmann Scheme for Incompressible Multiphase Flow and Its Application in Simulation of Rayleigh-Taylor Instability, Journal of Computational Physics 152 (1999) 642-663.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T.Lee, C.-L. Lin, A stable discretization of the lattice Boltzmann equation for simulation of incompressible two-phase flows at high density ratio, Journal of Computational Physics 206 (2005) 16-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T.Lee, P.F. Fischer, Eliminating Parasitic currents in the lattice Boltzmann equation method for nonideal gasses, Phys. Rev. E 74 046709 (2006).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T.Lee, Effects of incompressibility on the elimination of parasitic currents in the lattice Boltzmann equation method for binary fluids, (2008)Pre-Paper Computers and Mathematics with Applications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">T. Lee, L. Liu, Wall boundary condition in the lattice Boltzmann equation method for nonideal gasses, Phys. Rev. E 78 017702 (2008).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D. Chiappini, G. Bella, S. Succi, F. Toschi and S. Ubertini, Improved Lattice Boltzmann without parasitic currents for Rayleigh-Taylor Instability, submitted to Communication in Computational Phisics Under Review (2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X. He, X. Shan, and G. D. Doolen, A discrete Boltzmann equation model for non-ideal gases, Phys. Rev. E 57, R13 (1998).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Tryggvason, Numerical Simulation of the Rayleigh-Taylor Instability, Journal of Computational Physics 75 (1988) 235-282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Bella, V. Rocco and S. Ubertini, Combustion and spray simulation of a DI Turbocharged Diesel Engine, 2002-01-2776.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. Postrioli, C.N. Grimaldi, G. Bella, S. Ubertini, Study of the influence of the Injection System in a Multi-dimensional Spray Simulation, 2005-24-088</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. Andreassi, S. Ubertini and L. Allocca, Experimental and numerical analysis of high pressure diesel spray-wall interaction, International Journal of Multiphase Flow, 33 (2007) 742-765.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Nomura, S. Koshizuka, Y. Oka and H. Obata , Numerical Analysis of Droplet Breakup Behavior using Particle Method, Journal of Nuclear Science and Technology, 38 (2001) 1057–1064.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Succi, The lattice Boltzmann Equation: for Fluid Dynamics and Beyond, Series Numerical Mathematics and Scientific Computation. Oxford University Press (2001).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Y. H. Quian, D. D’Humieres and P. Lallemand, Lattice BGK Models for Navier-Stokes Equation, Europhysics Letters 17 (6) 479-484 (1992).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. W. Cahn, C. M. Elliot and A. Novick-Cohen, The Cahn Hilliard equation with a concentration dependent mobility: motion by minus the Laplacian of the mean curvature, European Journal of Applied Mathematics (1996).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
