<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">quarbankrevi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016167</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Quarterly Banking Review / רבעון לבנקאות</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>אגוד הבנקים בישראל</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">05571480</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">ד'</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</issue>
         <issue-id>i24013654</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24023508</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Some Reflections on the Bank of Israel Law / הרהורים על חוק בנק ישראל</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>א.</given-names>
                  <surname>להמן</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>E.</given-names>
                  <surname>Lehman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>1964</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>17</fpage>
         <lpage>24</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24023508"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The tenth anniversary of the passing of the Bank of Israel Law provides Dr. Lehmann with an opportunity to review its effectiveness in the light of the Central Bank's monetary policy during its first decade. The article deals also with the need for amending the Law and points out the advantages that would accrue to the economy as a result of Central Bank activity. Dr. Lehmann stresses out the contradiction between the objectives of the Bank, which aim at stabilizing the currency and at the same time achieving a high level of production, employment, national income and investment. He suggests that the objectives of stabilizing the currency and achieving a maximum level of national income would have been a more appropriate way of defining the functions of the Bank of Israel. Full employment at all costs, he points out, is not necessarily the best way of enlarging the national "cake" and is a matter for social rather than economic policy. The author asks whether there is not also a contradiction between the implication of the Law, that the Central Bank is required to encourage growth and development and between its task of maintaining the value of the currency locally and abroad. He notes that in a period of full employment, attempts to increase national income by further capital investment must give rise to inflationary pressures. Dr. Lehmann stresses also that in such circumstances, the Central Bank is bound to apply a monetary policy which would discourage capital imports and at the same time reduce the liquidity of the economy by reducing bank credits. Thus, there is a contradiction in the basic objectives of the Bank. Furthermore, the writer indicates that an even greater problem is that of the stabilization of the external exchange value of the Israel Pound. Measures to repress inflation, he points out, should be resorted to only temporarily in order to give time to the Government to take the necessary steps to uproot the causes of inflation. If this is not done, Dr. Lehmann concludes, then devaluation will recur again and again, as has happened in fact. Yet, he reminds us, that the difficulty is, that any attempt to strike at the causes of inflation must imply (temporarily at least) giving up ideas of growth and development, beyond certain reasonable limits. Dr. Lehmann then analyses the organization of the Central Bank and the status of the Governor in considerable detail, and explains the reasons for the sometimes unsatisfactory compromises which were made in the past in order to bridge considerable differences of opinion. He highlights differing views on the position of the Central Bank; as to whether it should be in effect an autonomous institution or an executive arm of the Government. The writer stresses the need, in the light of experience the world over, for the Bank of Israel to be free of party political influences, although he notes that it is considered desirable that the Governor should share the ideas of the party in power. In Israel, Dr. Lehmann points out that the relative autonomy of the Central Bank has been due more to the personality of its first and only Governor, than to its "built-in" status according to the Law. Even so, he reminds us that the Bank of Israel is severely hampered in its credit policy by the Interest Law, the amendment of which is a delicate political issue and also, that any change in the liquidity regulations must be authorized by the Government. Dr. Lehmann criticizes the section of the Law which requires that every increase in the currency in circulation must be authorized by the Government. He points out that in the view of modern monetary theory the stability of the value of the currency — is not ensured by its "coverage". Referring to the Bank's balance-sheet he suggests that the "Treasury Bills" be converted into bonds or a non interest bearing loan to the Government. This is also proposed as a substitute for the naively termed "land-bills". Dr. Lehmann concludes that instead of the autonomous body required, a dependent Government Bank has been set up with an over-complicated and slow procedure for taking decisions, and which is unfortunately, subject to party political influences. These faults will become more apparent in the more distant future when the Bank may be headed by a less capable and less independent Governor. Nevertheless, in general, the Law has proved its worth during its first decade of existence. He believes that it provided the young Central Bank with the tools necessary for carrying out a practical monetary policy. The author notes that good fortune also favoured the Bank with an energetic and unusually talented first Governor, now re-appointed to a third 5-year term of office.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>heb</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>[הערות שוליים]</title>
        <ref id="d29e119a1310">
            <label>-•</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e126" publication-type="other">
) בקשר להתפתחות בישראל ראה מאמרי "אינפלציה מרוסנת" בעתון "הארץ" מ-.27.3
1963.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


