<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466833</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466835</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Fooling Some of the People All of the Time: The Inefficient Performance and Persistence of Commodity Trading Advisors</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Geetesh</given-names>
                  <surname>Bhardwaj</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gary B.</given-names>
                  <surname>Gorton</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>K. Geert</given-names>
                  <surname>Rouwenhorst</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3099</fpage>
         <lpage>3132</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466835"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Investors face significant barriers in evaluating the performance of investment advisors. We focus on commodity trading advisors (CTAs) and show that from 1994 to 2012, CTA excess returns to investors (i.e., net of fees) were insignificantly different from zero while gross excess returns (i.e., before fees) were 6.1%, which implies that managers captured the performance in fees. Moreover, we find that CTAs display no alpha relative to simple future strategies in the public domain. Our results have implications for all hedge fund studies in that we find the typical adjustments for biases in the hedge fund databases still leave upward bias in fund performance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d64e275a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e282" publication-type="other">
We use the term CTA (commodity trading advisor) to refer to the legal form of investment vehicles that trade in
futures markets and consequently register with the U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e292a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e299" publication-type="other">
See Waksman (2000). Academic research is in agreement with these CTA self-assessments. Fung and Hsieh
(1997) argue that CTAs have one dominant style factor, namely, trend following.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e309a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e316" publication-type="other">
See http://www.barclayhedge.com/research/indices/cta/Money_Under_Management.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e323a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e330" publication-type="other">
As explained below (Section 2.1), in the final sample we exclude 53,826 of the 72,132 available monthly
observations on fund performance. Three funds with total of 202 monthly observations were removed because
they only report returns gross of all fees, and 162 funds (with 6,839 monthly returns) were excluded because
they have a missing date of entry into the database. The remaining database with 962 funds has a total of 65,091
monthly returns; of these, 46,785 observations correspond to returns before the date of entry (backfilled).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e350a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e357" publication-type="other">
Section 3 will provide a fuller discussion of backfilled returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e364a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e371" publication-type="other">
In addition to Griffin and Xu (2009), there is a large literature on hedge funds. For example, Ackermann,
McEnally, and Ravenscraft (1999) analyze hedge funds, comparing hedge fund returns, volatility, and Sharpe
ratios to the returns and characteristics of the S&amp;P 500 and eight standard market indices. They conclude that
hedge funds outperform mutual funds, but not standard market indices. Brown, Goetzmann, and Ibbotson (1999)
also look at hedge funds and find little evidence of outperformance. Brown and Goetzmann (2003) used a
classification algorithm to group hedge funds into similar styles, which then becomes the benchmark for out-of-
sample performance evaluation. There are many other papers (e.g., Brown and Goetzmann 1997). Stulz (2007)
provides a survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e400a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e407" publication-type="other">
The CISDM database, while potentially broader in scope, lacks such a flag, which prevents us from identifying
backfilled returns. The Barclays database also lacks a backfill flag. The HFR database contains flags for backfilled
returns, but its coverage of CTAs is not as extensive as Lipper-TASS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e420a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e427" publication-type="other">
Data in two CTA modules (live and graveyard) partly overlap with the data in the other two fund modules. In CTA
modules individual funds are classified as either "managed futures" or "CTA." Funds classified as "managed
futures" in CTA modules are the same as the funds classified as "managed futures" in fund modules. Although
there are 1,219 unique CTAs in the CTA module, it does not record a flag for the date of first reporting by funds,
which would allow for backfill biases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e446a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e453" publication-type="other">
At the end of 2011, our sample contains 326 funds, of which 268 reported a combined MUM of $66.6 billion
over 2011. BarclayHedge estimated industry-wide MUM to be $314.3 billion for 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e463a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e470" publication-type="other">
The prohibition on advertising seems problematical with the Internet. One need only type "commodity trading
advisor" into Google to get a sense of what this means as a practical matter. On March 4, 2013, there were
1,950,000 hits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e484a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e491" publication-type="other">
Individual CTAs can publicly present performance data. The CFTC under Regulation 4.41(a) adopted "a rule
that leaves to the discretion of the [CPO, CTA, or principal] advertising results—whether actual, simulated or
hypothetical—the format of that presentation, so long as that format is not false, misleading or deceptive." See
Federal Register Vol. 71, no. 163 (Wednesday, August 23, 2006), p. 49388.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e507a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e514" publication-type="other">
See the "Market Lab" section of Barron's, which provides "Commodity Traders Advisors Performance." Barron's
provides the current monthly return, year-to-date, 12-month return, 3-year return, and 5-year return, the 12-month
annualized standard deviation, the 12-month maximum drawdown (%), and the assets under management. Not all
of this available for every fund listed. The performance data come from the CAS AM CISM Database (formerly
the MAR Database); see http://www.casamhedge.com/.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e533a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e540" publication-type="other">
Fung and Hsieh (2000), Brown, Goetzmann, and Ibbotson (1999), Ackermann, McEnally, and Ravenscraft
(1999), and Liang (2000), among others, use this method. The estimates of the bias range from 3.0 % (from
Fung and Hsieh) to 0.2 % (from Ackermann, McEnally, and Ravenscraft). Malkiel and Saha (2005) report that
the average difference between live hedge funds and defunct hedge funds is more than 830 basis points over the
period 1996-2003.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e559a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e566" publication-type="other">
These calculations do not exclude backfilled returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e573a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e580" publication-type="other">
A by-product of the look-back bias is that it makes it difficult to exactly replicate results of other researchers
unless the exact same version of the database is used. Lipper-TASS distributes only the most recent version of
the database to current subscribers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e593a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e600" publication-type="other">
Several papers have quantified this bias, including Posthuma and Van der Sluis (2003) and Malkiel and Saha
(2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e611a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e618" publication-type="other">
The bulk of the literature uses a 12-month screen. Examples are Avramov et al. (2011); Avramov, Barras, and
Kosowski (2012); and Joenväärä, Kosowski, and Tolonen (2012), just to give a few examples. In fact, Joenväärä,
Kosowski, and Tolonen (2012) "propose an industry standard in constructing an aggregate hedge fund database
by merging multiple commercial databases" (emphasis in original). Yet they use the 12-month screen. In other
cases, there is no discussion of the issue, e.g., Kosowski, Naik, and Teo (2007). Ackermann, McEnally, and
Ravenscraft (1999) use a 24-month screen and conclude that backfill bias is not a concern because using the full
sample does not differ significantly when the 24-month screen is used. This is clear in Table 2 but is not true
if the first reporting date flag is used. Fung and Hsieh (2000) use a 27-month screen for individual funds and a
16-month screen for funds of hedge funds, which have the same backfill bias problem.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e650a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e657" publication-type="other">
The five factors (PTFSBD, PTFSFX, PTFSCOM, PTFSIR, and PTFSSTK) have been constructed by Fung and
Hsieh (2001) to represent nonlinear trading strategies designed to capture "trend following" by CTAs. Each
acronym starts with the prefix "Primitive Trend-Following Strategy" and then includes Bonds (BD), Foreign
Exchange (FX), Commodity Markets (COM), Interest Rates (IR), and Stocks (STK). Construction of these
factors involves rolling a pair of look-back straddles for various asset classes. Applying the analysis to CTAs,
Fung and Hsieh interpret their results as supporting the view that CTAs follow nonlinear, option-like strategies.
Fung and Hsieh (2001, 337) conclude that the use of their nonlinear factors "supports our contention that trend
followers have nonlinear option-like strategies."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e686a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e693" publication-type="other">
The results for value-weighted CTA portfolio are qualitatively similar:
Rvw=0.93 +0.02 x PTFSBD +0.03 x PTFSFX +0.04 x PTFSCOM -0.01 x PTFSIR +0.04 x PTFSSTK
(4.68) (1.83) (3.23) (3.05) (-1.22) (2.61)
R2=0.19.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e709a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e716" publication-type="other">
See also Cremers, Petajisto, and Zitzewitz (2013) for a discussion of the effect of nonzero alphas of benchmark
indices on performance attribution.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e726a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e733" publication-type="other">
For the Mount Lucas Index (MLM), see https://www.mtlucas.com/about.aspx. On MLM, see Mulvey, Kaul, and
Simsek (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e743a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e750" publication-type="other">
Results are qualitatively similar for net-of-fee fund level returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e758a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e767" publication-type="other">
A potential difficulty with looking at the period January 2003 to July 2012 is that different CTAs are in existence
at different times, so an equally weighted index is reflecting a potentially varying population. To address this we
also looked at subperiods, where this issue is mitigated. Looking at the subperiods, there are no real differences
and these results are omitted.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e783a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e790" publication-type="other">
Prospective CTAs need to register with the National Futures Association. There is a nonrefundable fee of
$200 and a fee of $85 for fingerprinting for each individual principal. See http://www.nfa.futures.org/NFA-
registration/cta/index.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e803a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e810" publication-type="other">
Also see Galati and Heath (2007) and Galati, Heath, and McGuire (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e817a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e824" publication-type="other">
The currencies used are: AUD (Australian dollar), CAD (Canadian dollar), CHF (Swiss franc), DKK (Danish
krone), DEM (deutsche mark), EUR (euro), FRF (French franc), GBP (British pound), IEP (Irish pound), ITL
(Italian lira), JPY (Japanese yen), NLG (Dutch guilder), NZD (New Zealand dollar), NOK (Norwegian krone),
and SEK (Swedish krona).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e840a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e847" publication-type="other">
In some cases the forward contract trading at time t does not expire on the last day of the next month, for example
if the last day of the next month is a Friday, the forward contract might expire on the following Monday. In such
cases an interpolation rule following interest parity is used to figure out the forward price Ft t+j. Let F, be
the forward price at time/ on a contract that expires on t+k, and if we are interested in Ftt+j which corresponds
to the last day of the next month, then:</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d64e875a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e879" publication-type="other">
Ackermann, C., R. McEnally, and D. Ravenscraft. 1999. The performance of hedge funds: Risk, return, and
incentives. Journal of Finance 54:833-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e889a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e893" publication-type="other">
Aiken, A., C. Clifford, and J. Ellis. 2013. Out of the dark: Hedge fund reporting biases and commercial databases.
Review of Financial Studies 26:208-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e903a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e907" publication-type="other">
Akerlof, G 1970. The market for "lemons": Quality uncertainty and the market mechanism. Quarterly Journal
of Economics 84:488-500.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e917a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e921" publication-type="other">
Amin, G, and H. Kat. 2003. Hedge fund performance 1990-2000: Do the "money machines" really add value?
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 38:251-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e932a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e936" publication-type="other">
Arrow, K. 1971. Essays in the theory of risk-bearing. Chicago: Markham Publishing Co.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e947" publication-type="other">
Asness, C. 1997. The interaction between value and momentum strategies. Financial Analyst Journal 53:29-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e958" publication-type="other">
Asness, C., J. Liew, and R. Stevens. 1997. Parallels between the cross-sectional predictability of stock and country
returns. Journal of Portfolio Management (Spring): 79-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e972" publication-type="other">
Avramov, D., L. Barras, and R. Kosowski. 2012. Hedge fund return predictability under the magnifying glass.
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 48:1057-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e986" publication-type="other">
Avramov, D., R. Kosowski, N. Naik, and M. Teo. 2011. Hedge funds, managerial skill, and macroeconomic
variables. Journal of Financial Economics 99:672-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e996a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1000" publication-type="other">
Bal vers, R., Y. Wu, and E. Gilliland. 2000. Mean reversion across national stock markets and parametric contrarian
investment strategies. Journal of Finance 55:745-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1011a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1015" publication-type="other">
Barberis, N., and M. Huang. 2008. Stocks as lotteries: the implications of probability weighting for security
prices. American Economic Review 98:2066-2100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1025a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1029" publication-type="other">
Bhojraj, S., and B. Swaminathan. 2006. Macromomentum: Returns predictability in international equity indices.
Journal of Business 79:429-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1039a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1043" publication-type="other">
Bilson, J. 1981. The speculative efficiency hypothesis. Journal of Business 54:433-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1050a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1054" publication-type="other">
Brown, S., and W. Goetzmann. 1997. Mutual fund styles. Journal of Financial Economics 43:373-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1061a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1065" publication-type="other">
Brown, S., and W. Goetzmann. 2003. Hedge funds with style. Journal of Portfolio Management 29:101-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1072a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1076" publication-type="other">
Brown, S., W. Goetzmann, and R. Ibbotson. 1999. Offshore hedge funds: survival and performance 1989-1995.
Journal of Business 72:91-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1087a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1091" publication-type="other">
Brown, S., W. Goetzmann, and B. Liang. 2004. Fees on fees in funds of funds. Journal of Investment Management
2:39-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1101a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1105" publication-type="other">
Chan, K., A. Hameed, and W. Tong. 2000. Profitability of momentum strategies in the international equity
markets. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 35:153-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1115a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1119" publication-type="other">
Cremers, M., A. Petajisto, and E. Zitzewitz. 2013. Should benchmark indices have alpha? Revisiting performance
evaluation. Critical Finance Review 2:1-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1129a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1133" publication-type="other">
Dichev, I., and G Yu. 2011. Higher risk, lower returns: What hedge fund investors really earn. Journal of Financial
Economics 100:248-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1143a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1147" publication-type="other">
Elton, E., M. Gruber, and J. Rentzler. 1987. Professionally managed, publicly traded commodity funds. Journal
of Business 60:175-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1157a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1161" publication-type="other">
Elton, E., M. Gruber, and J. Rentzler. 1989. New public offerings, information, and investor rationality: The case
of publicly offered commodity funds. Journal of Business 62:1-15.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1172a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1176" publication-type="other">
Elton, E., M. Gruber, and J. Rentzler. 1990. The performance of publicly offered commodity funds. Financial
Analysts Journal 46:23-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1186a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1190" publication-type="other">
Erb, C., and C. Harvey. 2006. The strategic and tactical value of commodity futures. Financial Analysts Journal
62:69-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1200a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1204" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 1987. Commodity futures prices: Some evidence on forecast power, premiums, and
the theory of storage. Journal of Business 60:55-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1218" publication-type="other">
French, K. 2008, The cost of active investing. Journal of Finance 63:1537-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1229" publication-type="other">
Froot, K., and R. H. Thaler. 1990. Anomalies: Foreign exchange. Journal of Economic Perspectives
4:179-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1239a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1243" publication-type="other">
Fung, W., and D. Hsieh. 1997. The information content of performance track records: Investment style and
survivorship bias in the historical returns of commodity trading advisors. Journal of Portfolio Management
24:30-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1257a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1261" publication-type="other">
Fung, W., and D. Hsieh. 2000. Performance characteristics of hedge funds and commodity funds: Natural vs.
spurious biases. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 35:291-307.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1271a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1275" publication-type="other">
Fung, W., and D. Hsieh. 2001. The risk in hedge fund strategies: Theory and evidence from trend followers.
Review of Financial Studies 14:313-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1285a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1289" publication-type="other">
Fung, W., and D. Hsieh. 2004. Hedge fund benchmarks: A risk-based approach. Financial Analysts Journal
60:65-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1303" publication-type="other">
Galati, G, and A. Heath. 2007. What drives the growth in FX activity? Interpreting the 2007 triennial survey.
Bank for International Settlements Quarterly Review (December): 63-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1313a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1317" publication-type="other">
Galati, G, A. Heath, and P. McGuire. 2007. Evidence of carry trade activity. Bank for International Settlements
Quarterly Review (September): 27-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1327a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1331" publication-type="other">
Galati, G, and M. Melvin. 2004. Why has FX trading surged? Explaining the 2004 triennial survey. Bank for
International Settlements Quarterly Review (December): 67-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1342a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1346" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, F. Hayashi, and G Rouwenhorst. 2013. The fundamentals of commodity futures returns. Review of
Finance 17:35-105.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1356a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1360" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and G Rouwenhorst. 2006. Facts and fantasies about commodity futures. Financial Analysts Journal
62:47-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1370a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1374" publication-type="other">
Griffin, J., and J. Xu. 2009. How smart are the smart guys? A unique view from hedge fund stock holdings.
Review of Financial Studies 22:2531-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1384a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1388" publication-type="other">
Han, B., and A. Kumar. 2013. Speculative retail trading and asset prices. Working paper, McCombs School of
Business, University of Texas.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1398a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1402" publication-type="other">
Hasanhodzic, J., and A. Lo. 2007. Can hedge fund returns be replicated? The linear case. Journal of Investment
Management 5:5-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1412a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1416" publication-type="other">
Joenväärä, J., R. Kosowski, and R Tolonen. 2012. Revisiting "stylized facts" about hedge funds. Working paper,
Imperial College London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1431" publication-type="other">
Kosowski, R., N. Naik, and M. Teo. 2007. Do hedge funds deliver alpha? A Bayesian and bootstrap analysis.
Journal of Financial Economics 84:229-264.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1445" publication-type="other">
Levy, H., and M. Samrat. 1984. Portfolio and investment selection: Theory and practice. Englewood Cliffs, NJ:
Prentice-Hall International.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1459" publication-type="other">
Liang, B. 2000. Hedge funds: The living and the dead. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 35:309-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1466a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1470" publication-type="other">
Malkiel, B., and A. Saha. 2005. Hedge funds: Risk and return. Financial Analysts Journal 61:80-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1477a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1481" publication-type="other">
Markowitz, H. 1952. The utility of wealth. Journal of Political Economy 60:152-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1492" publication-type="other">
Miffre, J., and G Rallis. 2007. Momentum in commodity futures markets. Journal of Banking and Finance
31:1863-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1503a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1507" publication-type="other">
Mulvey J., S. Kaul, and K. Simsek. 2004. Evaluating a trend-following commodity index for multi-period asset
allocation. Journal of Alternative Investments 7:54-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1517a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1521" publication-type="other">
Park, J. 1995. Managed futures as an investment asset. PhD diss., Columbia University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1532" publication-type="other">
Pirrong, C. 2005. Momentum in futures markets. Working paper, Bauer College of Business, University of
Houston.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1542a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1546" publication-type="other">
Polkovnichenko, V. 2005. Household portfolio diversification: A case for rank-dependent preferences. Review of
Financial Studies 18:1467-1502.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1556a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1560" publication-type="other">
Posthuma, N., and P. Jelle van der Sluis. 2003. A reality check on hedge fund returns. Working paper, Free
University of Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1570a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1574" publication-type="other">
Richards, A. 1997. Winner-loser reversals in national stock market indices: Can they be explained?. Journal of
Finance 52:2129^14.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1589" publication-type="other">
Rogoff, K. 1979. Essays on expectations and exchange rate volatility. PhD diss., Massachusetts Institute of
Technology.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1603" publication-type="other">
Stulz, R. 2007. Hedge funds: past, present, and future. Journal of Economic Perspectives 21:175-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1610a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1614" publication-type="other">
Waksman, S. 2000. Commodity trading advisor survey: Adding equities to a managed futures portfolio. Journal
of Alternative Investments (Fall): 43^44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


