<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277844</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Novel Singular Perturbation Technique for Model-Based Control of Cold Start Hydrocarbon Emission</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Amini</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohammad Reza</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shahbakhti</surname>
                  <given-names>Mahdi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan Technological Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ghaffari</surname>
                  <given-names>Ali</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>K N Toosi Univ. of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1290</fpage>
         <lpage>1301</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277844"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>High hydrocarbon (HC) emission during a cold start still remains one of the major emission control challenges for spark ignition (SI) engines in spite of about three decades of research in this area. This paper proposes a cold start HC emission control strategy based on a reduced order modeling technique. A novel singular perturbation approximation (SPA) technique, based on the balanced realization principle, is developed for a nonlinear experimentally validated cold start emission model. The SPA reduced model is then utilized in the design of a model-based sliding mode controller (SMC). The controller targets to reduce cumulative tailpipe HC emission using a combination of fuel injection, spark timing, and air throttle / idle speed controls. The results from the designed multi-input multi-output (MIMO) reduced order SMC are compared with those from a full order SMC. The results show the reduced SMC outperforms the full order SMC by reducing both engine-out and tailpipe HC emission. This improved performance is caused by setting an optimum priority among the control inputs through the incorporation of SPA that evaluates the significance of the control variables/states on HC emission. The presented SPA approach can be applied for different automotive control applications that face the challenge of how to set the priority among different control actuators which often have conflicting impacts on desired control targets.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weilenmann, M., Favez, J.Y., and Alvarez, R., “Cold-start Emissions of Modern Passenger Cars at Different Low Ambient Temperatures and Their Evolution over Vehicle Legislation Categories,” J. of Atmospheric Environment, 43(15): p. 2419-2429, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrianov, D., Keynejad, F., Dingli, R., Voice, G. et al., “A Cold- Start Emissions Model of an Engine and Aftertreatment System for Optimisation Studies,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1274, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shahbakhti, M., Li, J., and Hedrick, J.K., “Early Model-based Verification of Automotive Control System Implementation,” 2012 American Control Conference (ACC), Montréal, Canada, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Asami, S., Cranmer, A., Shahbakhti, M., and Hedrick J.K., “Model- Based Control Via Balanced Realization For Automotive Cold Start Hydrocarbon Reduction,” 2011 ASME DSC Conference, Arlington, USA, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henry, C., Langenderfer, D., Yezerets, A., Ruth, M., et al., “Passive Catalytic Approach to Low Temperature NOx Emission Abatement,” US Department of Energy, Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference, October 3-6, Detroit, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ball, D., Zammit, M., Wuttke, J., and Buitrago, C., “Investigation of LEV-III Aftertreatment Designs,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 4(1):1-8, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):699-715, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakagawa, S., Minowa, T., Katogi, K., Higashiyama, K. et al., “A New Catalyzed Hydrocarbon Trap Control System for ULEV/SULEV Standard,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0567, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0567.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Waltner, A., Loose, G., Hirschmann, A., Mußmann, L. et al., “Development of Close-Coupled Catalyst Systems for European Driving Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 980663, 1998, doi:10.4271/980663.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Presti, M., Pace, L., Poggio, L., and Rossi, V., “Cold Start Thermal Management with Electrically Heated Catalyst: A Way to Lower Fuel Consumption,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0158, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24-0158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, D. and Heywood, J., “Effects of Secondary Air Injection During Cold Start of SI Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):182-196, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">zu Schweinsberg, A., Klenk, M., and Degen, A., “Engine- Independent Exhaust Gas Aftertreatment Using a Burner Heated Catalyst,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3401, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3401.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hepburn, J., Adamczyk, A., and Pawlowicz, R., “Gasoline Burner for Rapid Catalyst Light-off,” SAE Technical Paper 942072, 1994, doi:10.4271/942072.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lumsden, G. and Watson, H., “HAJI Operation in a Hydrogen-Only Mode for Emission Control at Cold Start,” SAE Technical Paper 950412, 1995, doi:10.4271/950412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saikalis, G., Byers, R., and Nogi, T., “Study on Air Assist Fuel Injector Atomization and Effects on Exhaust Emission Reduction,” SAE Technical Paper 930323, 1993, doi:10.4271/930323.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ohata, A., Ohashi, M., Nasu, M., and Inoue, T., “Model Based Air Fuel Ratio Control for Reducing Exhaust Gas Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 950075, 1995, doi:10.4271/950075.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hrovat, D., and Sun, J., “Models and control methodologies for IC engine idle speed control design,” Control Engineering Practice, 5(8): p.1093-1100, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., “The Effect of Spark Retard on Engine-out Hydrocarbon Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3867, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H., Mulla, S., Weigert, E., Camm, K. et al., “Cold Start Concept (CSC™): A Novel Catalyst for Cold Start Emission Control,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(2):372-381, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0535.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nunan, J., Lupescu, J., Denison, G., Ball, D. et al., “HC Traps for Gasoline and Ethanol Applications,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(2):430-449, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shaw II, B.T., “Modeling and Control of Automotive Cold Start Hydrocarbon Emissions,” Ph.D. Dissertation, U of California, Berkeley, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zavala, J.C., Sanketi, P.R., Wilcutts, M., Kaga, T., et al., “Simplified Models of Engine HC Emissions, Exhaust Temperature and Catalyst Temperature for Automotive Coldstart,” Fifth IFAC Symposium on Advances in Automotive Control, Seascape Resort, USA, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sanketi, P., Zavala, J.C., and Hedrick, J.K., “Automotive Engine Hybrid Modeling and Control for Reduction of Hydrocarbon Emission,” International Journal of Control, 79(05): p. 449-464, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keynejad, F., and Manzie, C., “Optimization of Cold Start Automotive Fuel Economy Using a Spark Timing Strategy,” 45th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, San Diego, USA, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hansen, A., Shahbakhti, M., and Hedrick, J.K., “Impact of Implementation Imprecision on Sliding Mode Controller Design of Automotive Cold Start Emissions,” 2012 ASME Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, USA, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edelberg, K., Shahbakhti, M., and Hedrick, J.K., “Incorporation of Implementation Imprecision in Automotive Control Design,” 2013 American Control Conference (ACC), Washington DC, USA, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrianov, D., Manzie, C., and Brear, M., “A Methodology for Minimising Emissions Constrained Cold Start Fuel Consumption,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0894, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01- 0894.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrianov, D.I., Brear, M.J., and Manzie, C., “A Physics- Based Integrated Model of a Spark Ignition Engine and a Three-Way Catalyst,” Combustion Science and Technology, 184(9): p. 1269- 1301, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cao, Y. and Li, L., “A Novel Closed Loop Control based on Ionization Current in Combustion Cycle at Cold Start in a GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1339, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1339.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keynejad, F., and Manzie, C., “Suboptimal Cold Start Strategies for Spark Ignition Engines,” IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 21(4): p.1295-1308, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cranmer, A., Shahbakhti, M., and Hedrick, J.K., “Grey-box Modeling Architectures for Rotational Dynamic Control in Automotive Engines,” 2012 American Control Conference (ACC), Montréal, Canada, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moore, B., “Principal Component Analysis in Linear Systems: Controllability, Observability, and Model Reduction,” IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control, 26(1): p. 17-32, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokotovic, P., O'Malley, R.E., and Sannuti, P., “Singular Perturbations and Order Reduction in Control Theory-an Overview” Automatica, 12(2): p. 123-132, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiu, Y., Anderson, B.D.O., “Singular Perturbation Approximation of Balanced Systems,” International Journal of Control, 50(4): p. 1379-1405, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sanketi, P.R., Zavala, J.C., Hedrick, J.K., Wilcutts M., et al., “A Simplified Catalytic Converter Model for Automotive Cold start Applications with Adaptive Parameter Fitting,” 8th Int. Symp. on Advanced Vehicle Control, Taiwan, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sanketi, P.R., “Coldstart Modeling and Optimal Control Design for Automotive SI Engines,” Ph.D. Dissertation, U of California, Berkeley, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salehi, R., Shahbakhti, M., and Hedrick, J.K., “Hybrid Switching Control of Automotive Coldstart Hydrocarbon Emission,” 2013 American Control Conference (ACC), Washington, USA, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
