<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100238</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">jmonecredbank</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Money, Credit and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00222879</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">15384616</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley (Variant)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26614933</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>House Price Booms, Current Account Deficits, and Low Interest Rates</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>FERRERO</surname>
                  <given-names>ANDREA</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>March-April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">47</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">S1</issue>
         <issue-title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Supplement 1</issue-title>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26614915</issue-id>
         <fpage>261</fpage>
         <lpage>293</lpage>

         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 The Ohio State University</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26614933"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Domestic factors, such as credit and preference shocks, can explain the negative correlation between house prices and the current account in the U.S. and several other countries before the recent crisis. These shocks, however, cannot account for the fall of world real interest rates observed in the data. Expansionary monetary policy shocks in the U.S., coupled with exchange rate pegs to the dollar in emerging economies, are crucial to understanding the evolution of the real interest rate. Yet, monetary policy factors play virtually no role for house prices and the current account.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>LITERATURE CITED</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Abraham, Jesse, Andrey Pavlov, and Susan Wachter. (2008) “Explaining the United States’ Uniquely Bad Housing Market.” Wharton Real Estate Review, 12, 24–41 .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Acharya, Viral, and Philip Schnabl. (2010) “Do Global Banks Spread Global Imbalances? The Case of Asset-Backed Commercial Paper during the Financial Crisis of 2007-09.” IMF Economic Review, 58, 37–73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bernanke, Ben. (2005) “The Global Saving Glut and the U.S. Current Account Deficit.” Remarks at The Homer Jones Lecture, St. Louis, MO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bernanke, Ben. (2010) “Monetary Policy and the Housing Bubble.” Speech at the Annual Meeting of the American Economic Association, Atlanta, GA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Boz, Emine, and Enrique Mendoza. (2014) “Financial Innovation, the Discovery of Risk, and the U.S. Credit Crisis.” Journal of Monetary Economics, 62, 1–22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Brown, Meta, Andrew Haugwout, Donghoon Lee, and Wilbert Van der Klaauw. (2013) “The Financial Crisis at the Kitchen Table: Trends in Household Debt and Credit.” Current Issues in Economics and Finance, 19, 1–10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bruno, Valentina, and Hyun Song Shin. (2014) “Cross-Border Banking and Global Liquidity.” Mimeo, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Caballero, Ricardo, Emannuel Farhi, and Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas. (2008a) “An Equilibrium Model of ‘Global Imbalances’ and Low Interest Rates.” American Economic Review, 98, 358–93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Caballero, Ricardo, Emannuel Farhi, and Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas. (2008b) “Financial Crash, Commodity Prices and Global Imbalances.” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Fall, 1–55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Campbell, Jeffrey, and Zvi Hercowitz. (2005) “The Role of Collateralized Household Debt in Macroeconomic Stabilization.” NBER Working Paper No. 11330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Clarida, Richard, Jordi Gali, and Mark Gertler. (2000) “Monetary Policy Rules and Macroeconomic Stability: Evidence and Some Theory.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 115, 147–80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Cortina, Antonio. (2009) “The Residential Boom and Its Consequences: A View from a Spanish Bank.” Presentation at the SUERF/Bank of Finland Conference: “HousingMarkets: A Shelter From the Storm or a Cause of the Storm?”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Davis, Morris, and Jonathan Heathcote. (2007) “The Price and Quantity of Residential Land in the United States.” Journal of Monetary Economics, 54, 2595–2620.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Davis, Morris, and Francois Ortalo-Magne. (2011) “Household Expenditures, Wages, Rents.” Review of Economic Dynamics, 14, 248–61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Diaz, Antonia, andMaria Jose Luengo-Prado. (2008) “On the User Cost and Homeownership.” Review of Economic Dynamics, 11, 584–613.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Dooley, Michael, David Folkerts-Landau, and Peter Garber. (2008) “Asia, Interest Rates, and the Dollar.” Deutsche Bank Global Markets Research, March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Duca, John, John Muellbauer, and Anthony Murphy. (2010) “Housing Markets and the Financial Crisis of 2007-2009: Lessons for the Future.” Journal of Financial Stability, 6, 203–17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Duca, John, John Muellbauer, and Anthony Murphy. (2011) “Shifting Credit Standards and the Boom and Bust in U.S. House Prices.” SERC Discussion Paper No. 76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Duca, John, John Muellbauer, and Anthony Murphy. (2012) “How Financial Innovations and Accelerators Drive Booms and Busts in U.S. Consumption.” Mimeo, FRB Dallas.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Dynan, Karen, Douglas Elmendorf, and Daniel Sichel. (2006) “Can Financial Innovation Help to Explain the Reduced Volatility of Economic Activity?” Journal of Monetary Economics, 53, 123–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Eggertsson, Gauti, and Paul Krugman. (2012) “Debt, Deleveraging, and the Liquidity Trap: A Fisher-Minsky-Koo Approach.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 127, 1469–1513.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">European Mortgage Federation. (2008) Hypostat:AReviewof Europe’s Mortgage andHousing Markets.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Favero, Carlo, Arie Gozluklu, and Haoxi Yang. (2013) “Demographics and the Behavior of Interest Rates.” Mimeo, Bocconi University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Favilukis, Jack, Sydney Ludvigson, David Kohn, and Stijn Van Nieuwerburgh. (2013) “International Capital Flows and House Prices: Theory and Evidence.” In Housing and the Financial Crisis, edited by Edward Glaeser and Todd Sinai, pp. 235–99. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Favilukis, Jack, Sydney Ludvigson, and Stijn Van Nieuwerburgh. (2011) “The Macroeconomic Effects of Housing Wealth, Housing Finance, and Limited Risk-Sharing in General Equilibrium.” Mimeo, London School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Ferrero, Andrea. (2010) “A Structural Decomposition of the U.S. Trade Balance: Productivity, Demographics and Fiscal Policy.” Journal of Monetary Economics, 57, 478–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Ferrero, Andrea, Mark Gertler, and Lars E.O. Svensson. (2010) “Current Account Dynamics andMonetary Policy.” In International Dimensions of Monetary Policy, edited by Jordi Galı and Mark Gertler, pp. 199–244. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Galı, Jordi, and Mark Gertler. (2007) “Macroeconomic Modeling for Monetary Policy Evaluation.” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 21, 25–46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Geanakoplos, John. (2010a) “Solving the Present Crisis and Managing the Leverage Cycle.” FRBNY Economic Policy Review, 16, 101–31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Geanakoplos, J. (2010b) “The Leverage Cycle.” In NBER Macroeconomics Annual 2009,edited by Daron Acemoglu,Kenneth Rogoff, andMichaelWoodford, pp. 1–65. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Gete, Pedro. (2013) “Housing Demand and Current Account Dynamics.” Mimeo, Georgetown University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Glaeser, Edward, Joshua Gottlieb, and Joseph Gyourko. (2013) “Can Cheap Credit Explain the Housing Boom?” In Housing and the Financial Crisis, edited by Edward Glaeser and Todd Sinai, pp. 301–59. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Greenspan, Alan. (2005) “Closing Remarks.” In The Greenspan Era: Lessons for the Future, pp. 549–51. Jackson Hole, WY: Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City Symposium.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Greenspan, Alan, and James Kennedy. (2008) “Sources and Uses of Equity Extracted from Homes.” Oxford Review of Economic Policy, 24, 120–44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Guerrieri, Veronica, and Guido Lorenzoni. (2012) “Credit Crises, Precautionary Savings and the Liquidity Trap.” Mimeo, University of Chicago Booth School of Business.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Hall, Robert (2010) “Why Does the Economy Fall to Pieces after a Financial Crisis?” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 24, 3–20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Haughwout, Andrew, Donghoon Lee, Joseph Tracy, andWilbert Van derKlaauw. (2011) “Real Estate Investors, the Leverage Cycle, and the Housing Market Crisis.” FRB New York Staff Report No. 514.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Iacoviello, Matteo. (2005) “House Prices, Borrowing Constraints, and Monetary Policy in the Business Cycle.” American Economic Review, 95, 739–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Iacoviello, Matteo, and Stefano Neri. (2010) “Housing Market Spillovers: Evidence from an Estimated DSGE Model.” American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics, 2, 125–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Justiniano, Alejandro, Giorgio Primiceri, and Andrea Tambalotti. (2013) “Household Leveraging and Deleveraging.” NBER Working Paper No. 18941.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Justiniano, Alejandro, Giorgio Primiceri, and Andrea Tambalotti. (2014a) “Credit Supply and the Housing Boom.” Mimeo, Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Justiniano, Alejandro, Giorgio Primiceri, and Andrea Tambalotti. (2014b) “The Effect of the Saving and Banking Glut on the U.S. Economy.” Journal of International Economics, 92, S52–S67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Kiyotaki, Nobuhiro, and John Moore. (1997) “Credit Cycles.” Journal of Political Economy, 105, 211–48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Kocherlakota, Narayana R. (2000) “Creating Business Cycles Through Credit Constraints.” Federal Reserve Bank of Minnesota Quarterly Review, 24, 2–10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Kuvshinov, Dmitry. (2010) “Recent Trends in the UK First-Time Buyer Mortgage Market.” Mimeo, Bank of England.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">McCarthy, Jonathan, and Richard Peach. (2010) “The Measurement of Rent Inflation.” FRB New York Staff Report No. 425.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">McCarthy, Yvonne, and Kieran McQuinn. (2013) “Credit Conditions in a Boom and Bust Property Market.” Central Bank of Ireland Research Technical Paper No. 8/RT/13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Mendoza, Enrique, Vincenzo Quadrini, and Jose-Victor Rios-Rull. (2009) “Financial Integration, Financial Development, and Global Imbalances.” Journal of Political Economy, 117, 371–416.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Mian, Atif, and Amir Sufi. (2011) “House Prices, Home Equity-Based Borrowing, and the U.S. Household Leverage Crisis.” American Economic Review, 101, 2132–56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Mian, Atif, Amir Sufi, and Francesco Trebbi. (2013) “The Political Economy of the Subprime Mortgage Credit Expansion.” Quarterly Journal of Political Science, 8, 373–408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Midrigan, Virgiliu, and Thomas Philippon. (2011) “Household Leverage and the Recession.” NBER Working Paper No. 16965.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Nakamura, Emi, and Jon. Steinsson. (2008) “Five Facts about Prices: A Reevaluation ofMenu Cost Models.” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 123, 1415–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Obstfeld, Maurice, and Kenneth Rogoff. (2007) “The Unsustainable U.S. Current Account DeficitRevisited.” In G7 Current Account Imbalances: Sustainability and Adjustment, edited by Richard Clarida, pp. 339–76. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Obstfeld, Maurice, and Kenneth Rogoff. (2010) “Global Imbalances and the Financial Crisis: Products of Common Causes.” In Asia and the Global Financial Crisis, pp. 131–72. San Francisco: Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco’s Center for Pacific Basin Studies Asia Economic Policy Conference.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Ortalo-Magne, Francois, and Sven Rady. (2004) “Housing Transactions and Macroeconomic Fluctuations: A Case Study of England and Wales.” Journal of Housing Economics, 13, 287–303.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Piazzesi, Monika, Martin Schneider, and Selale Tuzel. (2007) “Housing, Consumption and Asset Pricing.” Journal of Financial Economics, 83, 531–69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Punzi, Maria Teresa (2013) “Housing Market and Current Account Imbalances in the International Economy.” Review of International Economics, 21, 601–13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Rajan, Raghuram. (2010) Fault Lines. How Hidden Fractures Still Threaten the World Economy. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Reinhart, Carmen, and Kenneth Rogoff. (2009) This Time Is Different: Eight Centuries of Financial Folly. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Sa, Filipa, and Tomasz Wieladek. (2011) “Monetary Policy, Capital Inflows and the Housing Bubble.” FRB Dallas Globalization and Monetary Policy Institute Working Paper No. 80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Schmitt-Grohe, Stephanie, andMartin Uribe. (2003) “Closing Small Open Economy Models.” Journal of International Economics, 61, 163–85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Shiller, Robert. (2007) “Understanding Recent Trends in House Prices and Homeownership.” In Housing, Housing Finance, and Monetary Policy, pp. 89–123. Jackson Hole,WY: Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City Symposium.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Taylor, John. (1993) “Discretion versus Policy Rules in Practice.” Carnegie-Rochester Conference Series on Public Policy, 39, 195–214.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Taylor, John B. (2008) “The Financial Crisis and the Policy Responses: An Empirical Analysis of WhatWent Wrong.” A Festschrift in Honour of David Dodge, pp. 1–18. Bank of Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Williams, David. (2009) “House Prices and Financial Liberalisation in Australia.” Mimeo, University of Oxford.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Woodford, Michael. (2003) Interest and Prices: Foundations of a Theory of Monetary Policy. Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Left Panel: U.S. Current Account Balance % of GDP (Left Axis) and Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) Existing One-Family House Price Index Deflated by Headline Consumer Price Index (CPI) (Right Axis, 2001q1 = 100). Right Panel: Percentage Changes in Current Account % of GDP and in Real House Prices for Advanced and Emerging Economies between 2001 and 2006.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Top Panel: U.S. Short-Term Real Interest Rate (Nominal 1-Year T-Bill Yield Minus Expected Inflation from the Survey of Professional Forecasters). Bottom Panel: U.S. Long-Term Real Interest Rate at Different Maturities (Implied from Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>LTVs for First-Time Home Buyers.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Real House Prices in the Model (for Different Values of β) in Response to LTV Shocks (Marked Solid Line), and in the Data (Dashed Line).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Real House Prices in the Model in Response to LTV Shocks (Solid Line with Diamonds) and Preference Shocks (Solid Line with Stars), and in the Data (Dashed Line).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Simulated Path of Real House Prices (Top), Current Account in % of GDP (Center), and Real Interest Rate (Bottom), in the Baseline Scenario (Solid Line), and in the Data (Dashed Line).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 7.</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Nominal Interest Rate Predicted by a Taylor Rule with (Solid Line with Diamonds) and without (Solid Line with Stars) Smoothing, and in the Data (Dashed Line).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 8.</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Simulated Path of Real House Prices (Top), Current Account in % of GDP (Center), and Real Interest Rate (Bottom), in the Baseline Scenario (Solid Line) and in the Baseline Scenario Plus Monetary Policy Shocks (Dashed Line).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 9.</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Bilateral U.S. Trade Balance % of GDP by Area.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Fig. 10.</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Simulated Path of Real House Prices (Top), Current Account in % of GDP (Center), and Real Interest Rate (Bottom) in the Baseline Scenario Plus Monetary Policy Shocks under a Flexible Exchange Rate Regime (Dashed Line), a Pure Foreign Peg (Solid Line with Diamonds), and a Dirty Foreign Peg (Solid Line with Stars).</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
