<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275572</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reed Valve CFD Simulation of a 2-Stroke Engine Using a 2D Model Including the Complete Engine Geometry</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jajcevic</surname>
                  <given-names>Dalibor</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Graz University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Almbauer</surname>
                  <given-names>Raimund</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Graz University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schmidt</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Graz University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Glinsner</surname>
                  <given-names>Karl</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>BRP-Powertrain GmbH &amp; Co KG</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fitl</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>BRP-Powertrain GmbH &amp; Co KG</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275542</issue-id>
         <fpage>448</fpage>
         <lpage>461</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International and Copyright © 2010 SAE Japan</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275572"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>CFD has been widely used to predict the flow behavior inside 2-stroke engines over the past twenty years. Usually a mass flow profile or a simple 0D model is used for the inlet boundary condition, which replaces the complete intake geometry, such as reed valve, throttle, and air box geometries. For a CFD simulation which takes into account the exact reed valve geometry, a simulation of all above mentioned domains is required, as these domains are coupled together and thus interact. As the high speed of the engine affects the opening dynamic and closure of the reed valve, the transient data from the crank case volume and the section upstream the reed valve have an important influence on the reed petal dynamic and therewith on the sucked fresh air mass of the engine.</p>
            <p>This paper covers a methodology for the transient CFD simulation of the reed petals of a 2-stroke engine by using a 2D model. It is a mathematical model, which describes the displacement and the dynamic behavior of a reed petal, applying a Fluid-Structure Interaction (FSI). This bending beam model of the petal is coupled with the commercial CFD Code Fluent via a user defined function. The used coupling and the mesh moving strategy is presented and discussed in detail. The 3D engine domain includes the complete engine geometry. The main focus lies on the requirements of a reed valve simulation for a 2-cylinder 2-stroke engine. Finally, test bench results of the fired engine were used for the validation of the gas dynamic behavior inside the engine.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hinds, E.T. and Blair, G.P., “Unsteady Gas Flow Through Reed Valve Induction Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 780766, 1978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blair, G.P., Hinds, E.T., and Fleck, R., “Predicting the Performance Characteristics of Two-Cycles Engines Fitted with Reed Induction Valves,” SAE Technical Paper 790842, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fleck, R., Blair, G.P., and Houston, R.A.R., “An Improved Model for Predicting Reed Valve Behaviour in Two-Stroke Cycles Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 871654, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fleck, R., Cartwright, A., and Thornhill, D., “Mathematical Modelling of Reed Valve Behaviour in High Speed Two-Stroke Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 972738, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitianiec, W. and Bogusz, A., “Theoretical and Experimental Study of Gas Flow Through Reed Valve in a Two-Stroke Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 961802, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cunningham, G., Kee, R.J., and Boyall, J., “CFD Prediction of Crankcase Flow Regimes in a Crankcase Scavenged Two-Stroke Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 970361, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cunningham, G., Kee, R. J., Kenny, R. G., “Reed valve modelling in a computational fluid dynamics simulation of the two-stroke engine”, Journal of Automobile Engineering, pages 37-45, ISSN 0954-4070 (Print) 2041-2991 (Online), 1999</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baudille, R., Biancolini, M. E., “Dynamic analysis of a two stroke engine reed valve”, XXXI AIAS Congress, Parma-Italy, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baudille, R., Biancolini, M. E., Mottola, E., “Optimization of dynamic reed valve behaviour by material orientation”, XXXIV AIAS Congres, Milano-Italy, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angeletti, A., Biancolini, M., Costa, E., Urbinati, M., “Optimisation of Reed Valves Dynamics by Means of Fluid Structure Interaction Modelling”, 4th European Automotive Simulation Conference, Munich, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jajcevic, D., Almbauer, R.A., Schmidt, S.P., and Glinsner, K., “Symmetry and Time Delayed Boundary Condition for CFD Simulation and its Application in a Two-Cylinder Two-Stroke Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-32-0024, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ANSYS Fluent: “Fluent 6.3 User's Guide”; Fluent Inc, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ANSYS Fluent: “Gambit User's Guide”; Fluent Inc, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toro, E., “Riemann Solvers and Numerical Methods for Fluid Dynamics”; Springer, ISBN 3-540-61676-4, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng, Y., Strauss, S., Lucier, P., and Craft, T., “Predicting and Optimizing Two-Stroke Engine Performance Using Multidimensional CFD,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-32-0039, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ANSYS Fluent: “UDF Manual”; Fluent Inc, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagy, D., Almbauer, R.A., Lang, W., Burgstaller, A., “Valve lift measurement for the validation of a compressor simulation model”, Proceedings of the International Compressor Conference at Purdue, 2008, West Lafayette, USA, Paper 1274</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lang, W., Almbauer, R.A., Nagy, D., 2009, “Comparison of two different approaches to model the suction valve dynamics of a hermetic reciprocating compressor”, Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Compressors and Coolants, Papiernicka, Slovak</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jajcevic, D., Almbauer, R.A., Schmidt, S. P., Glinser, K., “Simulation Strategy and Analysis of a Two-Cylinder Two Stroke Engine Using CFD Code Fluent”, European Automotive Simulation Conference (EASC), 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jajcevic, D., Almbauer, R.A., Schmidt, S.P., and Glinsner, K., “Simulation of Scavenging Process, Internal Mixture Preparation, and Combustion of a Gasoline Direct Injection Two-Cylinder Two-Stroke Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-32-0046, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winkler, F., “Untersuchungen zur Reduktion von Spülverlusten bei kleinvolumigen Zweitaktmotoren”, PhD thesis, Graz University of Technology, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
