<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438458</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>THE IFS ANNUAL LECTURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Take-Up of Multiple Means-Tested Benefits by British Pensioners: Evidence from the Family Resources Survey</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>RUTH</given-names>
                  <surname>HANCOCK</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>STEPHEN</given-names>
                  <surname>PUDNEY</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>GERALDINE</given-names>
                  <surname>BARKER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>MONICA</given-names>
                  <surname>HERNANDEZ</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>HOLLY</given-names>
                  <surname>SUTHERLAND</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2004</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">25</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438454</issue-id>
         <fpage>279</fpage>
         <lpage>303</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2004</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438458"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Non-take-up of means-tested benefits among pensioners is of long-standing concern. It has assumed increased importance from October 2003 with the introduction of the new means-tested pension credit to which about half of pensioners are expected to be entitled. We use Family Resources Survey data from April 1997 to March 2000 to investigate patterns of pensioner take-up of income support (IS) (subsequently renamed the minimum income guarantee and now subsumed in pension credit), housing benefit (HB) and council tax benefit (CTB). Although 36 per cent of pensioners in our sample failed to claim their entitlements to at least one of these benefits, only 16 per cent failed to claim amounts worth more than 10 per cent of their disposable income. Generally, take-up is high where entitlement is high. But there are exceptions which may reflect the claims process and/or a greater degree of social stigma associated with IS than with HB or CTB.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1e290a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e297" publication-type="other">
The 'guarantee credit' element of the new pension credit is calculated in a similar manner, although the upper
capital limit has been abolished and notional income from capital is calculated at the rate of £1 for every £500
of capital above the lower threshold.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e310a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e317" publication-type="other">
Note that cases with incomes above the appropriate means-tested level can be, and are, correctly identified as
not entitled to benefit even if capital data are missing.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e327a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e334" publication-type="other">
Hancock and Barker (forthcoming) describe the process as applied to income and capital. For this paper,
recorded amounts of rent, council tax, HB and CTB were treated similarly.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e344a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e351" publication-type="other">
0f these, 13 cases were awaiting the outcome of a claim for CTB and not entitled to IS or HB, eight cases
were receiving HB and CTB and awaiting a claim for IS, six were receiving CTB, not entitled to HB and
awaiting a claim for IS, and five were entitled to but not receiving IS and were awaiting a CTB claim. Smaller
numbers fell into each of the other categories. None was awaiting a claim for all three benefits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e368a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e375" publication-type="other">
Cases receiving HB and/or CTB but not taking up entitlements to IS were examined closely for evidence that
they were incorrectly calculated to be entitled to IS due to measurement error in their income or capital. Of
such cases, 65 per cent were receiving maximum HB and/or CTB which is consistent with income and capital
low enough to qualify for IS. The remainder were receiving less than maximum HB and CTB. This could result
from measurement error in income or capital which would indicate that they might not be entitled to IS.
Alternatively, it could be the consequence of measurement error in rent or council tax, which would not in itself
shed doubt on their entitlement to IS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e401a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e408" publication-type="other">
Cases with zero or negative income are excluded. An alternative measure of the significance of non-take-up
would be to express unclaimed entitlements as a proportion of potential income, i.e. income as constructed here
plus unclaimed entitlements. This would avoid the need to exclude negative and zero incomes since the
denominator would always be strictly positive. However, this alternative would probably be harder to interpret.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e424a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e431" publication-type="other">
Since owner-occupiers are not eligible for HB. they are more likely than renters to be entitled to only one
benefit, that being CTB.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e441a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e448" publication-type="other">
The general picture and conclusions are very similar for a sample of all pensioner units (based on 1999-2000
FRS with no error correction and using POLIMOD), as shown in Figure B1 in Appendix B.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e458a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e465" publication-type="other">
Note that Figure 4 conditions take-up on other receipts rather than other entitlements, despite the endogeneity
of other receipts. The reason for conditioning in this way is to illustrate the pattern of partial take-up and to
highlight some anomalies in the combinations of benefits claimed. See the subsequent discussion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e478a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e485" publication-type="other">
We do not include any allowance for the benefits, such as spectacle vouchers, that are 'passported' via IS (see
Sutherland (2003b) for a discussion of what can and cannot be deduced from the FRS on the value of these
benefits).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e499a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e506" publication-type="other">
Note that these groups are not disjoint. For example, some of the individuals in the group (ISICTB; n=522)
will also appear as non-take-up cases in the groups (HBIIS.CTB ) and ( HBICTB ).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e516a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e523" publication-type="other">
The HBIIS group has a lower take-up rate, but is numerically negligible.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e530a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e537" publication-type="other">
There are some combinations of entitlement that are rare or impossible (for example, IS and HB but not
CTB). However, these cause no modelling difficulty, since the take-up model conditions on the entitlement
configuration. The consequence is simply that there are some empty cells in the joint distribution of the
exogenous explanatory variables.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e553a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e560" publication-type="other">
Since the information would have been provided to local authorities, which administer HB and CTB, the Data
Protection Act inhibits this process by placing restrictions on information sharing between local authorities and
the Department for Work and Pensions, which administers IS / MIG / pension credit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e573a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e580" publication-type="other">
These are arrived at by noting that (in a large sample) Ti = E(r) / [E(r)+E(e*(l-r))] and Ti = E(re*) / E(e*),
where e is the FRS simulated entitlement status, and then doing a little algebra.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d1e599a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e603" publication-type="other">
Altmann, R. (1981), 'Take-up of supplementary benefit by male pensioners', London School of
Economics, Taxation, Incentives and the Distribution of Income, Discussion Paper no. 25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e613a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e617" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. W., Fry, V. and Walker, I. (1988), 'Modelling the take-up of means-tested benefits:
the case of housing benefits in the United Kingdom', Economic Journal, Conference Papers,
vol. 98, pp. 58-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e630a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e634" publication-type="other">
Costigan, P., Finch, H., Jackson, B., Legard, R. and Ritchie, J. (1999), Overcoming Barriers: Older
People and Income Support, Research Report no. 100, London: Department of Social Security.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e644a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e648" publication-type="other">
Croden, N., Costigan, P. and Whitfield, G. (1999), Helping Pensioners: Evaluation of the Income
Support Pilots, Research Report no. 105, London: Department of Social Security.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e659a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e663" publication-type="other">
Curry, C. and O'Connell, A. (2003), The Pensions Landscape, London: Pensions Policy Institute.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e670a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e674" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions (2001), The Pension Credit: The Government's Proposals,
London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e684a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e688" publication-type="other">
— (2003a), The Pensioners ' Income Series 2001/2, London: DWP Pensions Analysts Division.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e695a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e699" publication-type="other">
— (2003b), State Pension: Summary of Statistics, March 2003, available at www.dwp.gov.uk/asd/
asdl/state_pension/SP_summ_stats_Mar03.asp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e709a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e713" publication-type="other">
— (2003c), Income-Related Benefits: Estimates of Take-Up in 2000/2001, London: DWP
Information and Analysis Directorate.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e723a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e727" publication-type="other">
— (2004), Income-Related Benefits: Estimates of Take-Up in 2001/2002, London: DWP
Information and Analysis Directorate.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e738a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e742" publication-type="other">
Duclos, J-Y. (1995), 'Modelling the take-up of state support', Journal of Public Economics, vol.
58, pp. 391-415.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e752a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e756" publication-type="other">
Fraker, T. and Moffitt, R. (1988), 'The effect of Food Stamps and labor supply: a bivariate
selection model", Journal of Public Economics, vol. 35, pp. 25-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e766a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e770" publication-type="other">
Fry, V. and Stark, G. (1987), 'The take-up of supplementary benefit: gaps in the "safety net"?',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 8, no. 4, pp. 1-14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e780a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e784" publication-type="other">
— and — (1993), The Take-Up of Means-Tested Benefits, 1984-90, London: Institute for Fiscal
Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e794a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e798" publication-type="other">
Hancock, R. M. and Barker, G. (forthcoming), 'The quality of social security benefit data in the
British Family Resources Survey: implications for investigating income support take-up by
pensioners', Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, Series A.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e811a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e815" publication-type="other">
Hosek, J. R. (1980), 'Determinants of family participation in the AFDC-unemployed fathers
program', Review of Economics and Statistics, vol. 62, pp. 466-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e826a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e830" publication-type="other">
House of Commons Work and Pensions Committee (2003), The Future of UK Pensions, Third
Report of Session 2002-03, vol. I: Report and Proceedings of the Committee, HC 92-1,
London: The Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e843a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e847" publication-type="other">
Keane, M. and Moffitt, R. (1998), 'A structural model of multiple welfare program participation
and labor supply', International Economic Review, vol. 39, pp. 553-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e857a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e861" publication-type="other">
Kim, M. and Mergoupis, T. (1997), 'The working poor and welfare recipiency: participation,
evidence and policy directions', Journal of Economic Issues, vol. 31, pp. 707-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e871a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e875" publication-type="other">
McConaghy, M., Hill, C., Kane, C., Lader, D., Costigan, P. and Thornby, M. (2003), Entitled but
Not Claiming? Pensioners, the Minimum Income Guarantee and Pension Credit, Department
for Work and Pensions, Research Report no. 197, Leeds: Corporate Document Services.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e888a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e892" publication-type="other">
Moffitt, R. (1983), 'An economic model of welfare stigma', American Economic Review, vol. 73,
pp. 1023-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e902a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e906" publication-type="other">
Pensions Policy Institute (2003), The Pensions Primer, London: PPL</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e914a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e918" publication-type="other">
Pudney, S. E., Hernandez, M. and Hancock, R. M. (2002), 'The welfare cost of means-testing:
pensioner participation in income support', paper presented at the Royal Economic Society,
April 2003, Warwick. University of Leicester, Discussion Paper in Economics no. 03/02.
Available at www.le.ac.uk/economics/research/RePEc/lec/leecon/econ03-2.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e934a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e938" publication-type="other">
—, — and — (2004), 'An econometric model of participation in multiple welfare programmes: the
role of information', University of Essex, Institute for Social and Economic Research, Working
Paper no 2004-15. Available at www.iser.essex.ac.uk/pubs/workpaps/pdf/2004-15.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e951a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e955" publication-type="other">
Redmond, G., Sutherland, H. and Wilson, M. (1998), The Arithmetic of Tax and Social Security
Reform: A User's Guide to Microsimulation Methods and Analysis, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e968a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e972" publication-type="other">
Riphahn, R. T. (2001), 'Rational poverty or poor rationality? The take-up of social assistance
benefits', Review of Income and Wealth, vol. 47, pp. 379-98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e982a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e986" publication-type="other">
Ritchie, J. (1988), Income Related Benefits: The Causes of Non Take-Up, London: Social and
Community Planning Research (SCPR).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e996a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1000" publication-type="other">
Sutherland, H. (2003a), The Take-Up of Income Support by Pensioners Using POLIMOD and the
Family Resources Survey 1999-2000, Research Note no. MU/RN/42, Cambridge:
Microsimulation Unit, University of Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1014a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1018" publication-type="other">
— (2003b), Take-Up of Income Support and Passported Benefits for Older People, Research Note
no. MU/RN/43, Cambridge: Microsimulation Unit, University of Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
