<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422559</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Impact of Ammonium Nitrate Species on Low Temperature NOx Conversion Over Cu/CHA SCR Catalyst</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Luo</surname>
                  <given-names>Jinyong</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tang</surname>
                  <given-names>Yadan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Joshi</surname>
                  <given-names>Saurabh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kamasamudram</surname>
                  <given-names>Krishna</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Currier</surname>
                  <given-names>Neal</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Yezerets</surname>
                  <given-names>Aleksey</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Cummins Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>October 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422530</issue-id>
         <fpage>1691</fpage>
         <lpage>1696</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422559"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Cu/CHA catalysts have been widely used in the industry, due to their desirable performance characteristics including the unmatched hydrothermal stability. While broadly recognized for their outstanding activity at or above 200°C, these catalysts may not show desired levels of NOx conversion at lower temperatures. To achieve high NOx conversions it is desirable to have NO₂/NOx close to 0.5 for fast SCR. However even under such optimal gas feed conditions, sustained use of Cu/CHA below 200°C leads to ammonium nitrate formation and accumulation, resulting in the inhibition of NOx conversion.</p>
            <p>In this contribution, the formation and decomposition of NH₄NO₃ on a commercial Cu/CHA catalyst have been investigated systematically. First, the impact of NH₄NO₃ self-inhibition on SCR activity as a function of temperature and NO₂/NOx ratios was investigated through reactor testing. Second, the formation of NH₄NO₃ was qualitatively measured through various adsorption and model reactions as well as its decomposition reactions by the temperature-programed desorption (TPD). In addition, the transient formation and accumulation of NH₄NO₃ under relevant process conditions were tracked by <italic>in situ</italic> DRIFTS spectroscopy to identify its formation and accumulation mechanisms. Last, a kinetic model was built to estimate the NH₄NO₃ inhibition impact on NOx conversion. This work provides insights into the limiting processes and SCR reactions at low temperatures that are important for addressing future low temperature NOx conversion needs.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmieg, S.J., Oh, S.H., Kim, C.H., Brown, D.B., et al., “Thermal Durability of Cu-CHA NH3-SCR Catalysts for Diesel NOx Reduction,” Catal. Today 184 (2012) 252.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamasamudram, K., Kumar, A., Luo, J., Currier, N. et al., "New Insights into the Unique Operation of Small Pore Cu-Zeolite SCR Catalyst: Overlapping NH3 Desorption and Oxidation Characteristics for Minimizing Undesired Products," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1542, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1542.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma, L., Cheng, Y., Cavataio, G., McCabe, R.W., et al., “Characterization of Commercial Cu-SSZ-13 and Cu-SAPO-34 Catalysts with Hydrothermal Treatment for NH3-SCR of NOx in Diesel Exhaust”, Chemical Engineering Journal 225 (2013) 323.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yezerets, A., et al., International MinNOx conference, https://www.iav.com/sites/default/files/veranstaltung/13/minnox_program_0.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colombo, M., Nova, I., Tronconi, E., “Detailed Kinetic Modelling of the NH3-NO/NO2 SCR Reactions onver a commercial Cu-Zeolite Catalyst for Diesel Exhausts after Treatment”, Catal. Today 197 (2012) 243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chigada, P., Watling, T., Cleeton, J., Gall, M. et al., "Experimental and Modelling Study of Cold Start Effects on a Cu-Zeolite NH3 Selective Catalytic Reduction Catalyst," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-2011, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koebel, M., Madia, G., Elsener, M., “Selective Catalytic Reduction of NO and NO2 at low temperature”, Catal. Today 73 (2002) 239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grossale, A., Nova, I., Tronconi, E. et al., “The chemistry of the NO/NO2-NH3 “fast” SCR reaction over Fe-ZSM5 investigated by transient reaction analysis”, J. Catal. 256 (2008) 312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nova, I., Ciardelli, C., Tronconi, E. et al, “NH 3-NO/NO 2 chemistry over V-based catalysts and its role in the mechanism of the fast SCR reaction” Catal. Today 114 (2006) 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luo, J., An, H., Kamasamudram, K., Currier, N. et al., "Impact of Accelerated Hydrothermal Aging on Structure and Performance of Cu-SSZ-13 SCR Catalysts," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(3):1181-1186, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhu, H., Kwak, J.H., Peden, C.H.F., et al., “In situ DRIFTS-MS studies on the oxidation of adsorbed NH3 by NOx over a Cu-SSZ-13 zeolite”, Catal. Today 205 (2013) 16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szailer, T., Kwak, J.H., Kim, D.H. et al, “Effects of Ba loading and calcination temperature on BaAl2O4 formation for BaO/Al2O3 NOx storage and reduction catalysts”, Catal. Today 114 (2006) 86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://webbook.nist.gov/cgi/cbook.cgi?ID=C6484522&amp;Mask=80#IR-Spec</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
