<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association (NTA)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26418803</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CANADA’S CARBON PRICE FLOOR</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Parry</surname>
                  <given-names>Ian W.H.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Fiscal Affairs Department, International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC, USA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Mylonas</surname>
                  <given-names>Victor</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Fiscal Affairs Department, International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC, USA</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December, 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>70</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26418793</issue-id>
         <fpage>879</fpage>
         <lpage>900</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26418803"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Canadian provinces are required to phase in a minimum price of CAN $50 per tonne on carbon dioxide emissions by 2022. This paper discusses the rationale for, and design of, the price floor requirement; its (provincial-level) environmental, fiscal, and economic welfare impacts; monitoring issues; and (national-level) industry incidence. The general conclusion is that the welfare costs and implementation issues are manageable, and pricing provides significant new revenues. A challenge is that the floor price by itself is well short of what will be needed by 2030 for Canada’s Paris Agreement pledge.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label> 
            <kwd>carbon price</kwd> 
            <kwd>price floor</kwd> 
            <kwd>Canada</kwd> 
            <kwd>welfare impacts</kwd> 
            <kwd>incidence</kwd> 
            <kwd>effective carbon price</kwd> 
            <kwd>competitiveness impacts</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ares, Elena, and Jeanne Delebarre, 2016. The Carbon Price Floor. Briefing paper No. CBP05927, House of Commons Library, London, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bagnoli, Philip, 2016. Canada’s Greenhouse Gas Emissions: Developments, Prospects and Reductions. Office of the Parliamentary Budget Officer, Ottawa, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bovenberg, Lans, and Ruud de Mooij, 1994. “Environmental Levies and Distortionary Taxation.” American Economic Review 84 (4), 1085–1089.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Calder, Jack, 2015. “Administration of a U.S. Carbon Tax.” In Parry, Ian, Adele Morris, and Roberton Williams III (eds.), Implementing a U.S. Carbon Tax: Challenges and Debates, 38–61. Routledge, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Delbeke, Jos, and Peter Vis (eds.), 2015. EU Climate Policy Explained. Routeledge, London, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EC (Environment Canada), 2017. C-Tables-IPCC-Sector-Provinces-Territories. Environment Canada, Government of Canada. http://donnees.ec.gc.ca/data/substances/monitor/nationaland-provincial-territorial-greenhouse-gas-emission-tables/C-Tables-IPCC-Sector-Provinces-Territories.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ECCC, 2017a. Technical Paper: Federal Carbon Pricing Backstop. Environment and Climate Change Canada. Gatineau QC, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ECCC, 2017b. National Inventory Report 1990–2015: Greenhouse Gas Sources and Sinks in Canada - Executive Summary. Environment and Climate Change Canada. Gatineau QC, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farid, Mai, Michael Keen, Michael Papaioannou, Ian Parry, Catherine Pattillo, Anna Ter-Martirosyan, and others, 2016. After Paris: Fiscal, Macroeconomic, and Financial Implications of Climate Change. Staff Discussion Note 16-01, International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fell, Harrison, Ian A. MacKenzie, and William A. Pizer, 2012. “Prices versus Quantities versus Bankable Quantities.” Resource and Energy Economics 34 (4), 607–623.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goulding, A.J. and Martin Atanasov, 2014. Power Prices in Context: Comparing Alberta Delivered Electricity Prices to Other Canadian Provinces on a Level Playing Field. London Economics International, Toronto, ON.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harberger, Arnold C., 1964. “The Measurement of Waste.” American Economic Review 54 (3), 58–76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harrison, Kathryn, 2013. “The Political Economy of British Columbia’s Carbon Tax.” OECD Environment Working Papers No. 63. Paris, France.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hepburn, Cameron, and Alexander Teytelboym, 2017. “Reforming the EU ETS – Where Are We Now?” In Parry, Ian, Karen Pittel, and Herman Vollebergh (eds.), Energy Tax and Regulatory Policy in Europe: Reform Priorities, 29–62. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IEA (International Energy Agency), 2016a. CO₂ Emissions from Fuel Combustion. International Energy Agency, Paris, France.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IEA (International Energy Agency), 2016b. World Energy Balances. International Energy Agency, Paris, France.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IMF (International Monetary Fund), 2017. World Economic Outlook Database. International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC. Available at: www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/weo/2017/01/weodata/index.aspx.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IPCC (Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change), 1996. Good Practice Guidance and Uncertainty Management in National Greenhouse Gas Inventories. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, Geneva Switzerland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krupnick, Alan J., Ian W.H. Parry, Margaret Walls, Tony Knowles, and Kristin Hayes, 2010. Toward a New National Energy Policy: Assessing the Options. Resources for the Future and National Energy Policy Institute, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Metcalf, Gilbert E., 2016. “A Conceptual Framework for Measuring the Effectiveness of Green Fiscal Reforms.” International Journal on Green Growth and Development 2 (2), 87–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Metcalf, Gilbert E., and David Weisbach, 2009. “The Design of a Carbon Tax.” Harvard Environmental Law Review 33 (3), 499–556.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murray, Brian C., and Nicholas Rivers, 2015. “British Columbia’s Revenue-Neutral Carbon Tax: A Review of the Latest ‘Grand Experiment’ in Environmental Policy.” Working Paper No. 15-04. Nicholas Institute, Duke University, Durham, NC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NEB (National Energy Board), 2016. Canada’s Energy Future 2016: Energy Supply and Demand Projections to 2040. Calgary, Alberta.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parry, Ian W.H., and Antonio M. Bento, 2000. “Tax Deductions, Environmental Policy, and the ‘Double Dividend’ Hypothesis.” Journal of Environmental Economics and Management 39 (1), 67–96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parry, Ian W.H., Baoping Shang, Philippe Wingender, Nate Vernon, and Tarun Narasimhan, 2016. “Climate Mitigation in China: Which Policies Are Most Effective?” Working Paper No. 16-148. International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parry, Ian W.H., Victor Mylonas, and Nate Vernon, 2017. “Reforming Energy Policy in India: Assessing the Options.” Working Paper No. 17-103. International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parry, Ian W.H., Chandara Veung, and Dirk Heine, 2014. “How Much Carbon Pricing Is in Countries’ Own Interests? The Critical Role of Co-Benefits.” Working Paper No. 14174. International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parry, Ian W.H., Dirk Heine, Shanjun Li, and Eliza Lis, 2014. Getting Energy Prices Right: From Principle to Practice. International Monetary Fund, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pederson, Thomas F., and Stewart Elgie, 2015. “A Template for the World: British Columbia’s Carbon Tax Shift.” In Milne, Janet E., Larry A. Kreiser, and Hope Ashiabor (eds.), Critical Issues in Environmental Taxation, 3–15. Edward Elgar, Northampton, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragan, Christopher, 2017. The Evolution of Canadian Climate Policy. World Resources Institute Webinar, April 13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sawyer, David, and Christopher Bataille, 2016. Taking Stock: Canada’s GHG Progress to 2030 and Opportunities for Collaborative Action. Policy Brief 1: GHG Progress to 2030. EnviroEconomics. Ottawa, ON.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Snoddon, Tracy, 2016. Carbon Copies: The Prospects for an Economy-wide Carbon Price in Canada. CD Howe Institute, Toronto, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stern, Nicholas, and Joseph Stiglitz, 2017. Report of the High-Level Commission on Carbon Pricing. Carbon Pricing Leadership Coalition. World Bank Group, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UK DECC (Department of Energy &amp; Climate Change), 2011. Planning our Electric Future: A White Paper for Secure, Affordable and Low‑Carbon Electricity. Department of Energy and Climate Change, London, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UNFCCC (United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change), 2016. INDCs as Communicated by Parties. United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, New York City, NY, http://www4.unfccc.int/submissions/indc/Submission%20Pages/submissions.aspx.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UNEP (UN Environment Programme), 2016. UN Environment Emissions Gap Report. UN Environment Programme, Nairobi, Kenya.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US EPA (Environmental Protection Agency), 2014. Inventory of U.S. Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Sinks: 1990–2012. US Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US IAWG (Interagency Working Group), 2016. Technical Support Document: Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866. Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">WBG (World Bank Group), 2016. State and Trends of Carbon Pricing 2016. World Bank Group, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weitzman, Martin L., 1974. “Prices versus Quantities.” Review of Economic Studies 41 (4), 477–491.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
