<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562340</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Knock Phenomena under Very Lean Conditions in Gasoline Powered SI-Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Doornbos</surname>
                  <given-names>Gerben</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chalmers University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hemdal</surname>
                  <given-names>Stina</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chalmers University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Denbratt</surname>
                  <given-names>Ingemar</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chalmers University of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Dahl</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Volvo Cars</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>February 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562337</issue-id>
         <fpage>39</fpage>
         <lpage>54</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562340"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Homogeneous lean operation is a well-known strategy for enhancing the thermal efficiency of SI-engines. At higher load points the efficiency is often compromised by the need to suppress knock. Experiments were performed to determine the knock characteristics of SI engines using homogeneous lean operation at λ values of up to 1.8 with various hardware configurations that are commonly used to increase the lean limit.</p> 
            <p>Changing λ altered the eigenfrequencies of the combustion chamber and the highest energy excitation mode. Increasing λ from 1.0 to 1.2 increased the knock tendency and led to an earlier knock onset. However, further increases in λ significantly reduced the knock tendency and retarded the knock onset. The knock signal energy increased for higher λ values and constant knock tendencies. The differences in knock characteristics between the various λ values became more pronounced upon raising the intake temperature from 40 °C to 90 °C. The trends in knock tendency and knock onset largely parallels that observed for engine out NOₓ emissions and thus the NOₓ concentration in the internal EGR. The increased knock signal energy under lean conditions is partly attributed to the change in eigenfrequencies in the combustion chamber.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>Knock</kwd> 
            <kwd>SI-engines</kwd> 
            <kwd>Lean combustion</kwd> 
            <kwd>High frequency ignition</kwd> 
            <kwd>Heated intake air</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">European Commission, Reducing CO2 emissions from passenger cars, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vafamehr, A.C., Sampson, O., and Koupaie, M.M., “The competing chemical and physical effects of transient fuel enrichment on heavy knock in an optical spark ignition engine,” Applied Energy 179:687-697, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals (McGraw-Hill, 1988).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayala, F., Gerty, M., and Heywood, J., “Effects of Combustion Phasing, Relative Air-Fuel Ratio, Compression Ratio, and Load on SI Engine Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0229, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Doornbos, G., Hemdal, S., Dahl, D., and Denbratt, I., “Transient Responses of Various Ammonia Formation Catalyst Configurations for Passive SCR in Lean- Burning Gasoline Engines under Various Real Engine Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0935, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0935.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Einewall, P., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., “Lean Burn Natural Gas Operation vs. Stoichiometric Operation with EGR and a Three Way Catalyst,” SAE Technical Paper 2005- 01-0250, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0250.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grandin, B., “Knock in Gasoline Engines,” Ph.D. thesis, Chalmers University of Technology, Göteborg, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ikeya, K., Takazawa, M., Yamada, T., Park, S. et al., “Thermal Efficiency Enhancement of a Gasoline Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(4):1579-1586, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunce, M. and Blaxill, H., “Sub-200 g/kWh BSFC on a Light Duty Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0709, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0709.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stokes, J., Lake, T., and Osborne, R., “A Gasoline Engine Concept for Improved Fuel Economy-The Lean Boost System,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2902, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-2902.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, Y. and Raine, R., “Engine Knock in an SI Engine with Hydrogen Supplementation under Stoichiometric and Lean Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):595-605, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McKenzie, J. and Cheng, W., “Ignition Delay Correlation for Engine Operating with Lean and with Rich Fuel-Air Mixtures,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0699, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0699.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Topinka, J., Gerty, M., Heywood, J., and Keck, J., “Knock Behavior of a Lean-Burn, H2 and CO Enhanced, SI Gasoline Engine Concept,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0975, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, X., Zhang, Y., Shen, T., and Khajorntraidet, C., “Spark Advance Self-Optimization with Knock Probability Threshold for Lean-Burn Operation Mode of SI Engine,” Energy 122:1-10, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konig, G. and Sheppard, C., “End Gas Autoignition and Knock in a Spark Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 902135, 1990, doi:10.4271/902135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Javed, T., Lee, C., AlAbbad, M., Djebbi, K. et al., “Ignition Studies of n-Heptane/Iso-Octane/Toluene Blends,” Combustion and Flame 171:223-233, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davidson, D.F., Gauthier, B.M., and Hanson, R.K., “Shock Tube Ignition Measurements of Iso-Octane/Air and Toluene/Air at High Pressures,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 30:1175-1182, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, H.-P.S., Vanderover, J., and Oehlschlaeger, M.A., “A Shock Tube Study of Iso-Octane Ignition at Elevated Pressures: The Influence of Diluent Gases,” Combustion and Flame 155:739-755, 2008, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mittal, V., Revier, B., and Heywood, J., “Phenomena that Determine Knock Onset in Spark-Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0007, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01- 0007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu, H. and Chen, Z., “End-Gas Autoignition and Detonation Development in a Closed Chamber,” Combustion and Flame 162:4102-4111, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Z., Liu, H., and Reitz, R.D., “Knocking Combustion in Spark Ignition Engines,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 61:78-112, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, Y., Wang, Y., and Raine, R., “Correlation between Cycle-by-Cycle Variation, Burning Rate, and Knock: A Statistical Study from PFI and DISI Engines,” Fuel 206:210- 218, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westin, F., Grandin, B., and Ångström, H., “The Influence of Residual Gases on Knock in Turbocharged SI-Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2840, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01- 2840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Doornbos, G., Hemdal, S., and Dahl, D., “Reduction of Fuel Consumption and Engine-Out NOx Emissions in a Lean Homogeneous GDI Combustion System, Utilizing Valve Timing and an Advanced Ignition System, 2015-04-14, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zschutschke, A., Neumann, J., Linse, D., and Hasse, C., “A Systematic Study on the Applicability and Limits of Detailed Chemistry Based NOx Models for Simulations of the Entire Engine Operating Map of Spark-Ignition Engines,” Applied Thermal Engineering 98:910-923, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burluka, A., Liu, K., Sheppard, C., Smallbone, A. et al., “The Influence of Simulated Residual and NO Concentrations on Knock Onset for PRFs and Gasolines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2998, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stenlåås, O., Gogan, A., Egnell, R., Sundén, B. et al., “The Influence of Nitric Oxide on the Occurrence of Autoignition in the End Gas of Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2699, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2699.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stenlåås, O., Einewall, P., Egnell, R., and Johansson, B., “Measurement of Knock and Ion Current in a Spark Ignition Engine with and without NO Addition to the Intake Air,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0639, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003- 01-0639.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Contino, F., Foucher, F., Dagaut, P., Lucchini, T. et al., “Experimental and Numerical Analysis of Nitric Oxide Effect on the Ignition of Iso-Octane in a Single Cylinder HCCI Engine,” Combustion and Flame 160:1476-1483, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gogan, A., Sundén, B., Montorsi, L., Ahmedand, S. et al., “Knock Modeling: An Integrated Tool for Detailed Chemistry and Engine Cycle Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3122, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Schock, H., and Attard, W., “A Review of Pre- Chamber Initiated Jet Ignition Combustion Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2263, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dale, J.D., Checkel, M.D., and Smy, P.R., “Application of High Energy Ignition Systems to Engines,” Progression Energy Combustion Science 23:379-398, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogink, R. and Babajimopoulos, A., “Investigating the Limits of Charge Motion and Combustion Duration in a High- Tumble Spark-Ignited Direct-Injection Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(4):2129-2141, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-2245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertsch, M., Schreer, K., Disch, C., Beck, K. et al., “Investigation of the Flow Velocity in the Spark Plug Gap of a Two-Stroke Gasoline Engine Using Laser-Doppler- Anemometry,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(1):34-41, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-32-0529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ward, M., “High-Energy Spark-Flow Coupling in an IC Engine for Ultra-Lean and High EGR Mixtures,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0548, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01- 0548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hampe, C., Kubach, H., Spicher, U., Rixecker, G. et al., “Investigations of Ignition Processes Using High Frequency Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1633, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1633.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pineda, D., Wolk, B., Chen, J., and Dibble, R., “Application of Corona Discharge Ignition in a Boosted Direct-Injection Single Cylinder Gasoline Engine: Effects on Combustion Phasing, Fuel Consumption, and Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(3):1970-1988, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-9045.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Morganti, K., Algunaibet, I., Sarathy, M. et al., “Knock Prediction Using a Simple Model for Ignition Delay,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0702, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016- 01-0702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McKenzie, J. and Cheng, W., “The Anatomy of Knock,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0704, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01- 0704.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burgdorf, K. and Karlström, A., “Using Multi-Rate Filter Banks to Detect Internal Combustion Engine Knock,” SAE Technical Paper 971670, 1997, doi:10.4271/971670.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burgdorf, K., “Engine Knock: Characteristics and Mechanisms,” Ph.D. thesis, Chalmers University of Technology, Göteborg.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borg, J., Saikalis, G., Oho, S., and Cheok, K., “Knock Signal Analysis Using the Discrete Wavelet Transform,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0226, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01- 0226.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dahl, D., “Gasoline Engine HCCI Combustion,” Ph.D. thesis, Chalmers University of Technology, Göteborg.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NASA, Glenn Research Center, February 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hickling, R., Feldmaier, D.A., Chen, F.H.K., and Morel, J.S., “Cavity Resonances in Engine Combustion Chambers and Some Applications,” The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America 73, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elmqvist, C., Lindström, F., Ångström, H., Grandin, B., et al., “Optimizing Engine Concepts by Using a Simple Model for Knock Prediction,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01- 3123, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brunt, M., Pond, C., and Biundo, J., “Gasoline Engine Knock Analysis Using Cylinder Pressure Data,” SAE Technical Paper 980896, 1998, doi:10.4271/980896.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, H., Feng, D., Mingzhang, P., JiaYing, P. et al., “Experimental Investigation on the Knocking Combustion Characteristics of n-Butanol Gasoline Blends in a DISI Engine,” Applied Energy 175:346-355, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Livengood, J.C. and Wu, P.C., “Correlation of Autoignition Phenomena in Internal Combustion Engines and Rapid Compression Engines,” Symposium (International) on Combustion 5:347-356, 1955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoepke, B., Jannsen, S., Kasseris, E., and Cheng, W., “EGR Effects on Boosted SI Engine Operation and Knock Integral Correlation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):547-559, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0707.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
