<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277696</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Use of Low-Pressure Direct-Injection for Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Light-Duty Engine Operation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Walker</surname>
                  <given-names>N. Ryan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dempsey</surname>
                  <given-names>Adam B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andrie</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1222</fpage>
         <lpage>1237</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277696"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI) has been shown to be capable of providing improved engine efficiencies coupled with the benefit of low emissions via in-cylinder fuel blending. Much of the previous body of work has studied the benefits of RCCI operation using high injection pressures (e.g., 500 bar or greater) with common rail injection (CRI) hardware. However, low-pressure fueling technology is capable of providing significant cost savings. Due to the broad market adoption of gasoline direct injection (GDI) fueling systems, a market-type prototype GDI injector was selected for this study. Single-cylinder light-duty engine experiments were undertaken to examine the performance and emissions characteristics of the RCCI combustion strategy with low-pressure GDI technology and compared against high injection pressure RCCI operation. Gasoline and diesel were used as the low-reactivity and high-reactivity fuels, respectively. GDI injection pressures range from 150 to 200 bar, while the CRI pressures range from 250 to 500 bar. Start of injection (SOI) timings ranged from −35° aTDC and −115° aTDC. The experimental results show comparable engine performance and emissions output, but with slight reductions in overall combustion efficiency when using low-pressure fueling with the stock re-entrant piston. CFD simulations were also performed to aid in visualization of the in-cylinder fuel distributions, which are controlling factors for RCCI combustion. By utilizing an optimized RCCI piston geometry, equivalent RCCI combustion performance can be achieved under low-pressure fueling, at moderate and high loads. The optimized geometry also allows for significant increases in thermal efficiency, with peak efficiencies over 47% observed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flynn, P., Durrett, R., Hunter, G., zur Loye, A. et al., “Diesel Combustion: An Integrated View Combining Laser Diagnostics, Chemical Kinetics, And Empirical Validation,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0509, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. M. and Siebers, D. L., “Soot Formation in Diesel Fuel Jets Near the Lift-Off Length”, International Journal of Engine Research, 7(2):103-130, 2006, doi: 10.1243/146808705X57793.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, X., Han, D., and Huang, Z., “Fuel Design and Management for the Control of Advanced Compression- Ignition Combustion Modes”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 37(6):741-783, 2011, doi: 10.1016/j.pecs.2011.03.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lü, X., Chen, W., Hou, Y., and Huang, Z., “Study on the Ignition, Combustion and Emissions of HCCI Combustion Engines Fueled With Primary Reference Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0155, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neely, G., Sasaki, S., Huang, Y., Leet, J. et al., “New Diesel Emission Control Strategy to Meet US Tier 2 Emissions Regulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1091, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-1091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L., “Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition”, PhD Dissertation in Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin- Madison, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamimoto, T. and Bae, M., “High Combustion Temperature for the Reduction of Particulate in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 880423, 1988, doi: 10.4271/880423.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Fuyuto, T., Nishikawa, K., Nakakita, K. et al., “Dual-Fuel PCI Combustion Controlled by In- Cylinder Stratification of Ignitability,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0028, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., Kaddatz, J. et al., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion in Light- and Heavy-Duty Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):360-374, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wissink, M. L., Lim, J. H., Splitter, D. A., Hanson, R. M., and Reitz, R. D., “Investigation of Injection Strategies to Improve High Efficiency RCCI Combustion with Diesel and Gasoline Direct Injection”, Paper ICEF2012-92107, American Society of Mechanical Engineers Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, Vancouver, B.C., Canada, September 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L., Hanson, R. M., Splitter, D. A., and Reitz, R. D., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI): A Pathway to Controlled High-Efficiency Clean Combustion”, International Journal of Engine Research, 12(Special):209-226, 2011, doi: 10.1177/1468087411401548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The MARTEC Group, Inc., “Variable Costs of Fuel Economy Technologies”, Prepared for the Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers, June 1, 2008; amended December 10, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaddatz, J., Andrie, M., Reitz, R., and Kokjohn, S., “Light-Duty Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Combustion Using a Cetane Improver,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1110, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., “Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Heavy-Duty Engine Operation at Mid-and High-Loads with Conventional and Alternative Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0363, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Kokjohn, S., Rein, K., Hanson, R. et al., “An Optical Investigation of Ignition Processes in Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):142-162, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0345.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Wissink, M. et al., “Injection Effects in Low Load RCCI Dual-Fuel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0047, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-24-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Reitz, R., Splitter, D., and Musculus, M., “Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Stratification for Controlling PCI Heat-Release Rates Using High-Speed Chemiluminescence Imaging and Fuel Tracer Fluorescence,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):248-269, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Wissink, M., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., “Effect of Compression Ratio and Piston Geometry on RCCI Load Limits and Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0383, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Curran, S., Wagner, R., Kokjohn, S. et al., “Piston Bowl Optimization for RCCI Combustion in a Light-Duty Multi-Cylinder Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):286-299, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, N. R., Dempsey, A. B., Andrie, M. J., and Reitz, R. D., “Experimental Study of Low-Pressure Fueling Under RCCI Engine Operation”, Paper ILASS2012-80, ILASS-Americas 24th Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, San Antonio, Texas, May 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, N. R., “Investigation of Low-Pressure Injection Effects on Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Combustion”, MS Thesis in Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D. A., “High Efficiency RCCI Combustion”, PhD Dissertation in Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klein, S. A. and Nellis, G. F., “Thermodynamics”, p. 870, Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DieselNet, “Emission Standard”, www.dieselnet.com, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. B., Walker, N. R., Splitter, D. A., Wissink, M. L., and Reitz, R. D., “Characterization of Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Using Premixed Hydrated Ethanol and Direct Injection Diesel in Heavy-Duty and Light-Duty Engines”, THIESEL 2012 Conference on Thermo and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, Valencia, Spain, September 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lyn, W. T., “Study of Burning Rate and Nature of Combustion in Diesel Engines”, Symposium (International) on Combustion, 9(1):1069-1082, 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Colban, W., Miles, P., Park, S. et al., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Dilution-Controlled Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):411-430, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-24-0043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Colban, W., Miles, P., Park, S. et al., “Sources of UHC Emissions from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1265-1289, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W. F., Ekoto, I. W., Kim, D., and Miles, P. C., “In-Cylinder PIV Measurements in an Optical Light-Duty Diesel at LTC Conditions”, THIESEL 2008 Conference on Thermo and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, Valencia, Spain, September 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A., O'Rourke, P. J., and Butler, T. D., “KIVA-II - A Computer Program for Chemically Reactive Flows with Sprays”, 1989, Los Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-11560-MS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A., “KIVA-3V: A Block-Structured KIVA Program for Engines with Vertical or Canted Valves”, 1997, Los Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-13313-MS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A., “KIVA-3V, Release 2, Improvements to KIVA-3V”, 1999, Los Alamos National Laboratory Report LA-UR-99-915.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale, J. C. and Reitz, R. D., “Modeling Spray Atomization with the Kelvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh-Taylor Hybrid Model”, Atomization and Sprays, 9(6):623-650, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abani, N., Munnannur, A., and Reitz, R. D., “Reduction of Numerical Parameter Dependencies in Diesel Spray Models”, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 130(3):032809, 2008, doi: 10.1115/1.2830867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke, P. and Amsden, A., “A Spray/Wall Interaction Submodel for the KIVA-3 Wall Film Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0271, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000- 01-0271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y. and Reitz, R. D., “The Application of a Multicomponent Droplet Vaporization Model to Gasoline Direct Injection Engines”, International Journal of Engine Research, 4(3):193-218, 2003, doi:10.1243/146808703322223388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, Z. and Reitz, R. D., “Turbulence Modeling of Internal Combustion Engines Using RNG k-e Models”, Combustion Science and Technology, 106(4-6):167-295, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
