<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465666</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465674</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Frog in the Pan: Continuous Information and Momentum</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Zhi</given-names>
                  <surname>Da</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Umit G.</given-names>
                  <surname>Gurun</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mitch</given-names>
                  <surname>Warachka</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2171</fpage>
         <lpage>2218</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465674"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We test a frog-in-the-pan (FIP) hypothesis that predicts investors are inattentive to information arriving continuously in small amounts. Intuitively, we hypothesize that a series of frequent gradual changes attracts less attention than infrequent dramatic changes. Consistent with the FIP hypothesis, we find that continuous information induces strong persistent return continuation that does not reverse in the long run. Momentum decreases monotonically from 5.94% for stocks with continuous information during their formation period to −2.07% for stocks with discrete information but similar cumulative formation-period returns. Higher media coverage coincides with discrete information and mitigates the stronger momentum following continuous information.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d64e238a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e245" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer and Teoh (2003), Sims (2003), Peng and Xiong (2006), as well as DellaVigna and Pollet (2007)
provide theoretical foundations that allow limited attention to influence asset prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e255a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e262" publication-type="other">
Rational explanations for momentum are offered by Johnson (2002) and Sagi and Seasholes (2007), while
behavioral explanations include Daniel, Hirshleifer, and Subrahmanyam (1998), among others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e272a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e279" publication-type="other">
Although daily returns measure information with error because of market frictions and behavioral biases, this
error is small relative to the large amount of cumulative information underlying extreme formation-period returns.
In addition, a modified version of ID based on analyst forecast revisions instead of returns yields similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e292a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e299" publication-type="other">
We utilize media coverage throughout the paper as a proxy for investor attention but acknowledge that media
coverage is not exogenous. For example, large firms are more likely to appear in the financial press. In unreported
tests, we address this endogeneity concern by orthogonalizing media coverage with respect to several stock
characteristics. The residual media coverage resulting from this regression was found to provide similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e316a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e323" publication-type="other">
ID is also a stronger predictor of momentum than return consistency. Within the subset of stocks with
consistent returns (return consistency dummy variable equals one), portfolio double-sorts confirm that continuous
information induces stronger momentum than discrete information.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e336a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e343" publication-type="other">
We obtain similar results if %pos and %neg are defined using market-adjusted daily returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e350a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e357" publication-type="other">
Morck, Yeung, and Yu (2000) estimate a similar measure to capture cross-sectional commonality in the re
within individual countries. In contrast, ID is estimated from a time series of returns for individual firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e367a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e374" publication-type="other">
George and Hwang (2004) also cast doubt on the link between short-term return continuation and long-term
return reversals.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e384a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e391" publication-type="other">
Gutierrez and Kelley (2008) report that return consistency cannot predict returns when this measure is constructed
using weekly instead of monthly returns.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e401a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e408" publication-type="other">
The proxies for active and passive attention are not necessarily orthogonal. For example, the amount of media
coverage per stock may decrease when the number of stocks increases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d64e419a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e426" publication-type="other">
The simulation exercise is not intended to match the empirical results in Panel A of Table 2 exactly due to the
simplistic assumptions underlying the illustrative model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d64e445a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e449" publication-type="other">
Amihud, Y. 2002. Illiquidity and stock returns: Cross-section and time series effects. Journal of Financial Markets
5:31-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e459a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e463" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., R. Hodrick, Y. Xing, and X. Zhang. 2006. The cross-section of volatility and expected returns. Journal
of Finance 61:259-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e473a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e477" publication-type="other">
Bae, K. and W. Wang. 2012. What's in a "China" name? A test of investor attention hypothesis. Financial
Management 41:429-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e487a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e491" publication-type="other">
Bali, T., N. Cakici, and R. Whitelaw. 2011. Maxing out: Stocks as lotteries and the cross-section of expected
returns. Journal of Financial Economics 99:427-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e502a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e506" publication-type="other">
Barber, B., and T. Odean. 2008. All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on the buying behavior of
individual and institutional investors. Review of Financial Studies 21:785-818.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e516a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e520" publication-type="other">
Ben-David, I., and D. Hirshleifer. 2012. Beyond the disposition effect: Do investors really like realizing gains
more than losses? Review of Financial Studies 25:2485-532.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e530a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e534" publication-type="other">
Bernard, V., and J. Thomas. 1990. Evidence that stock prices do not fully reflect the implications of current
earnings for future earnings. Journal of Accounting and Economics 13:305-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e544a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e548" publication-type="other">
Birru, J. 2012. Confusion of confusions: A test of the disposition effect and momentum. Working Paper, Ohio
State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e558a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e562" publication-type="other">
Brennan, M., N. Jegadeesh, and B. Swaminathan. 1993. Investment analysis and the adjustment of stock prices
to common information. Review of Financial Studies 6:799-824.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e572a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e576" publication-type="other">
Chan, W. 2003. Stock price reaction to news and no-news: Drift and reversal after headlines. Journal of Financial
Economics 70:223-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e587a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e591" publication-type="other">
Chordia, T., A. Goyal, and N. Jegadeesh. 2011. Buyers versus sellers: Who initiates trades and when? Working
Paper, Emory University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e601a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e605" publication-type="other">
Cohen, L., and A. Frazzini. 2008. Economic links and predictable returns. Journal of Finance 63:1977-2011.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e616" publication-type="other">
Cooper, M., R. Gutierrez, and A. Hameed. 2004. Market states and momentum. Journal of Finance
59:1345-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e626a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e630" publication-type="other">
Corwin, S., and J. Coughenour. 2008. Limited attention and the allocation of effort in securities trading. Journal
of Finance 63:303 l-b7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e644" publication-type="other">
Da, Z., J. Engelberg, and P. Gao. 2011. In search of attention. Journal of Finance 66:1461-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e651a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e655" publication-type="other">
Daniel, K., D. Hirshleifer, and A. Subrahmanyam. 1998. Investor psychology and security market under- and
overreactions. Journal of Finance 53:1839-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e666a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e670" publication-type="other">
Daniel, K., and S. Titman. 1999. Market efficiency in an irrational world. Financial Analyst Journal 55:28-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e677a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e681" publication-type="other">
DellaVigna, S., and J. Pollet. 2007. Demographics and industry returns. American Economic Review
97:1667-1702.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e691a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e695" publication-type="other">
Engelberg, J., and C. Parsons. 2011. The causal impact of media in financial markets. Journal of Finance 66:
67-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e705a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e709" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and K. French. 1993. Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial
Economics 33:3-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e719a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e723" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and J. MacBeth. 1973. Risk, return, and equilibrium: Empirical tests. Journal of Political Economy
81:607-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e733a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e737" publication-type="other">
Frazzini, A. 2006. The disposition effect and underreaction to news. Journal of Finance 61:2017^46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e745a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e749" publication-type="other">
Fu, F. 2009. Idiosyncratic risk and the cross-section of expected stock returns. Journal of Financial Economics
91:24-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e763" publication-type="other">
George, T., and C. Y. Hwang. 2004. The 52-week high and momentum investing. Journal of Finance 59:
2145-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e773a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e777" publication-type="other">
Gervais, S., R. Kaniel, and D. Mingelgrin. 2001. The high-volume return premium. Journal of Finance
56:877-919.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e787a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e791" publication-type="other">
Gino, F., and M. Bazerman. 2009. When misconduct goes unnoticed: The acceptability of gradual erosion in
others' unethical behavior. Journal of Experimental Social Psychology 45:708-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e801a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e805" publication-type="other">
Grinblatt, M., and B. Han. 2005. Prospect theory, mental accounting, and momentum. Journal of Financial
Economics 78:311-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e815a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e819" publication-type="other">
Grinblatt, M., and T. Moskowitz. 2004. Predicting stock price movements from past returns: The role of
consistency and tax-loss selling. Journal of Financial Economics 71:541-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e830a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e834" publication-type="other">
Gurun, U. G, and A. Butler. 2012. Don't believe the hype: Local media slant, local advertising, and firm value.
Journal of Finance 67:561-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e844a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e848" publication-type="other">
Gutierrez, R., and E. Kelley. 2008. The long-lasting momentum in weekly returns. Journal of Finance 63:
415-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e858a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e862" publication-type="other">
Hartzell, J., and L. Starks. 2003. Institutional investors and executive compensation. Journal of Finance 58:
2351-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e872a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e876" publication-type="other">
Harvey, C., and A. Siddique. 2000. Conditional skewness in asset pricing tests. Journal of Finance 55:1263-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e883a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e887" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D., S. Lim, and S. H. Teoh. 2009. Driven to distraction: Extraneous events and underreaction to
earnings news. Journal of Finance 64:2289-325.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e901" publication-type="other">
Hirshleifer, D., and S. H. Teoh. 2003. Limited attention, information disclosure, and financial reporting. Journal
of Accounting and Economics 36:337-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e912a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e916" publication-type="other">
Hong, H., T. Lim, and J. Stein. 2000. Bad news travels slowly: Size, analyst coverage, and the profitability of
momentum strategies. Journal of Finance 55:265-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e930" publication-type="other">
Hong, H., and J. Stein. 1999. A unified theory of underreaction, momentum trading, and overreaction in asset
markets. Journal of Finance 54:2143-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e940a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e944" publication-type="other">
Hou, K., and T. Moskowitz. 2005. Market frictions, price delay, and the cross-section of expected returns. Review
of Financial Studies 18:981-1020.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e958" publication-type="other">
Hou, K., L. Peng, and W. Xiong. 2009. A tale of two anomalies: The implication of investor attention for price
and earnings momentum. Working Paper, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e972" publication-type="other">
Jegadeesh, N., and S. Titman. 1993. Returns to buying winners and selling losers: Implications for stock market
efficiency. Journal of Finance 48:65-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e986" publication-type="other">
Johnson, T. 2002. Rational momentum effects. Journal of Finance 57:585-608.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e994a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e998" publication-type="other">
Lee, C., and M. Ready. 1991. Inferring trade direction from intradaily data. Journal of Finance 46:733-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1005a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1009" publication-type="other">
Lee, C., and B. Swaminathan. 2000. Price momentum and trading volume. Journal of Finance 55:2017-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1016a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1020" publication-type="other">
Lesmond, D., J. Ogden, and C. Trzcinka. 1999. A new estimate of transaction costs. Review of Financial Studies
12:1113-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1030a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1034" publication-type="other">
Livnat, J., and R. Mendenhall. 2006. Comparing the post-earnings announcement drift for surprises calculated
from analyst and time series forecasts. Journal of Accounting Research 44:177-205.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1044a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1048" publication-type="other">
Morck, R., B. Yeung, and W. Yu. 2000. The information content of stock markets: Why do emerging markets
have synchronous stock price movements? Journal of Financial Economics 58:215-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1058a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1062" publication-type="other">
O'Brien, P., and R. Bhushan. 1990. Analyst following and institutional ownership. Journal of Accounting
Research 28:55-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1073a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1077" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and R. Stambaugh. 2003. Liquidity risk and stock returns. Journal of Political Economy 111:642-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1084a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1088" publication-type="other">
Peng, L., and W. Xiong. 2006. Limited attention, overconfidence and category learning. Journal of Financial
Economics 80:563-602.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1098a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1102" publication-type="other">
Peress, J. 2009. Media coverage and investors' attention to earnings announcements. Working Paper, INSEAD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1109a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1113" publication-type="other">
Sagi, J., and M. Seasholes. 2007. Firm-specific attributes and the cross-section of momentum. Journal of Financial
Economics 84:389-434.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1123a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1127" publication-type="other">
Sims, C. 2003. Implications of rational inattention. Journal of Monetary Economics 50:665-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1134a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1138" publication-type="other">
Tetlock, P. 2007. Giving content to investor sentiment: The role of media in the stock market. Journal of Finance
62:1139-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1149a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1153" publication-type="other">
. 2011. All the news that's fit to reprint: Do investors react to stale information? Review of Financial
Studies 24:1481-512.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d64e1163a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1167" publication-type="other">
Zhang, F. 2006. Information uncertainty and stock returns. Journal of Finance 61:105-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


