<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26296356</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Center for Army Analysis “Revolutionary War” Wargame</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Engelmann</surname>
                  <given-names>Karsten</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Karsten Engelmann is a senior operations research analyst with the Center for Army Analysis. His current assignment is the development and execution of strategic and operational wargames, political military games, and table top exercises. His focus area is analysis in support of Army and war-fighting leadership. Throughout his career, starting in 1990, Dr. Engelmann has employed wargaming/pol-mil gaming techniques to examine a wide range of issues related to counterinsurgency, logistics, economics, alliance warfare, humanitarian affairs, and a wide range of operational issues such as missile defense, chemical warfare, and armored warfare. His commercial wargames include ancient historical, current-day insurgency, and future situations. He is married to Ms. Kaarin Engelmann, has no children but does have a mischievous dog named Kiska, is an avid traveler, historian, and wargamer. He is a long-time member of MORS.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Erdman</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Major Robert Erdman was commissioned at the University of Oregon in June 2000 as an Armor officer. He has served as a Mobile Gun System Platoon leader, Reconnaissance Platoon leader, assistant operations officer, Squadron Logistics Officer, and troop commander before becoming a Functional Area 49 (FA49), operations research and systems analyst. Major Erdman received a master’s degree in operations research from the Naval Postgraduate School in June 2010. Since then, he has served as the Enlisted Strength forecaster for the Army G1, FA49 Proponent Action Officer, military analyst for the Center for Army Analysis, and the senior analyst for Special Operations Joint Task Force—Afghanistan. Major Erdman has deployed to both Afghanistan and Iraq during his career and is married to Malissa Erdman and has two children, Karli and Michael.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>March 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>50</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26296346</issue-id>
         <fpage>26</fpage>
         <lpage>33</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2016, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26296356"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joes, Anthony James. 2010. Victorious Insurgencies: Four Rebellions that Shaped Our World, University Press of Kentucky.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Quinlivan, James T. 2002. Burden of Victory, The Rand Corporation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">US Army. 2012. ADP 5-0: The Operations Process. Army Doctrine Publication. Headquarters, Department of the Army.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
