<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816549</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Optimal Taxation 2</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Should We Be Taxed Out of Our Homes?</article-title>
            <subtitle>The Optimal Taxation of Housing Consumption</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Albouy</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Findeisen</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>24</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816549"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Optimal tax theory suggests that it is more efficient to tax housing as a consumption good than other forms of consumption as it is a complement to leisure and is produced more intensively from land, an inelastic factor, than other goods. This tax rate appears to be at least 50 percent higher than other forms of consumption, justifying high rates of property taxation, particularly in areas with inelastic housing supply. It may be efficient to offer a lump sum transfer to households who choose to live close to high-paying jobs, justifying infra-marginal subsidies to housing units in some high-price areas. Proximity to amenities may also influence optimal tax rates depending on whether they are substitutes or complements to labor supply or housing consumption.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Albouy, David, 2009. “The Unequal Geographic Burden of Federal Taxation.” Journal of Political Economy. 2009: 635-667.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Albouy, David, Gabriel Ehlrich, and Yingyi Liu 2015. “Housing Demand and Expenditures: How Rising Rents affect Behavior and Costs-of-Living.” Mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Albouy, David and Andrew Hanson. 2014, “Are Houses Too Big or In the Wrong Place? Taxes Benefits to Housing and Inefficiencies in Location and Consumption.” NBER Tax Policy and the Economy, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Albouy, David and Byran Stuart 2015. “Urban Population and Amenities.” NBER Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Aura, Saku and Thomas Davidoff (2012) “An Analysis of Constrained Property Taxes in a Simple Optimal Tax Model” CESifo Economic Studies</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Barnett, William A. 1979. “The Joint Allocation of Leisure and Goods Expenditures.” Econometrica 47: 539-563</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Becker, Gary S. 1965. “A Theory of the Allocation of Time.” Economic Journal 75: 493-517.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Boskin, Michael J. 1985. “Efficiency Aspects of the Differential Tax Treatment of Market and Household Economic Activity.” Journal of Public Economics 4: 1-25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Bruce, Donald and Douglas Holtz-Eakin, 1999. “Fundamental Tax Reform and Residential Housing” Journal of Housing Economics, 8(4): 249-271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Brueckner, Jan and Hyun-A Kim. 2003. “Urban Sprawl and the Property Tax.” International Tax and Public Finance, 10(1): 5-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Burman, Leonard and Marvin Phaup, 2012. “Tax Expenditures, the Size and Efficiency of Government, and Implications for Budget Reform” Tax Policy and the Economy 26, 93-124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Cremer, Jacques and Firouz Gahvari 1998 “On Optimal Taxation of Housing.” Journal of Urban Economics, 43: 315-335.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Corlett, W.J. D.C. Hague, 1953. “Complementarity and the Excess Burden of Taxation” Review of Economic Studies, 21(1), 21-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dasgupta, Partha and Joseph E. Stiglitz, (1971) “Differential Taxation, Public Goods, and Economic Efficiency” Review of Economic Studies 38: 151-174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Deskins, John, and William Fox, 2008. “Measuring Behavioral Responses to the Property Tax” In Challenging the Conventional Wisdom on the Property Tax, R. Bahl,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Evans, Alan W. 2012. “Optimal Tax Theory and the Taxation of Housing in the U.S. and the U.K.” Journal of Property Research 29(4): 368-378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">George, Henry 1879. Progress and Poverty.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Gervais, Martin. 2002. “Housing Taxation and Capital Accumulation.” Journal of Monetary Economics 49: 1461-1489.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Glaeser, Edward, 2011. “Rethinking the Federal Bias Toward Homeownership” Cityscape: A Journal of Policy Development and Research, 13 (2), 5-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Glaeser, Edward and Jesse Shapiro, 2003.“The Benefits of the Home Mortgage Interest Deduction.” Tax Policy and the Economy 17, 37-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Green, Richard K. and Andrew Reshovsky. 1999. “Using Tax Policy to Subsidize Homeownership” in A. Stager, Ed., Public Spending and Incentives for Community Development Federal Reserve Bank of Boston-Aspen Institute</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Gyourko, Joseph and Todd Sinai, 2003. “The Spatial Distribution of Housing-Related Ordinary Income Tax Benefits” Real Estate Economics 31(4), 527-575.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Iorwerth, Aled ab, and John Whalley. 2002. “Efficiency Considerations and the Exemption of Food from Sales and Value Added Taxes.” Canadian Journal of Economics. 35: 166-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Jacob, Brian A. 2012 “The Effects of Housing Assistance on Labor Supply: Evidence from a Voucher Lottery.”</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Kaplow, Louis, 2008 The Theory of Taxation and Public Economics. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Kleven, Henrik J., Wolfram F. Richter, and Peter Birch Sorensen 2000 “Optimal Taxation with Household Production.” Oxford Economic Papers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Mieskowski, Peter, 1972. “The Property Tax: An Excise Tax or a Profits Tax?” Journal of Public Economics, 1(1): 73-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">O’Sullivan, Arthur, Terri Sexton, and Steven Sheffrin, 1995. “Property Taxes, Mobility, and Home Ownership” Journal of Urban Economics, 37(1): 107-129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Piggott, John and John Whalley 1996. “The Tax Unit and Household Production.” Journal of Political Economy. 104(2): 398-418.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Poterba, James M, 1984. “Tax Subsidies to Owner-Occupied Housing: An Asset Market Approach.” Quarterly Journal of Economics 99 (4): 729-752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Poterba, James, 1992.“Taxation and Housing: Old Questions, New Answers.” American Economic Review 82(2): 237-242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Poterba, James, and Todd Sinai, 2008a. “Revenue Costs and Incentive Effects of the Mortgage Interest Deduction for Owner-Occupied Housing” National Tax Journal, 64(2): 531-564.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Poterba, James and Todd Sinai, 2008b.“Tax Expenditures for Owner-Occupied Housing: Deductions for Property Taxes and Mortgage Interest and the Exclusion of Imputed Rental Income,” American Economic Review, 96(2): 84-89</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Rosen, Harvey, 1985 “Housing Subsidies” in Auerbach, A. and M. Feldstein (eds.) Handbook of Public Economics. Elsevier Science.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Sandmo, Agnar “Tax Distortions and Household Production.” Oxford Economic Papers, New Series, 42(1): 78-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Shan, Hui, 2010. “Property Taxes and Elderly Mobility” Journal of Urban Economics, 67(2): 194-205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Turnbull, Geoffrey K. 1996. Urban Consumer Theory. Avebury</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">West, Sarah E. and Roberton Williams III. 2007. “Optimal Taxation and Cross-Price Elasticities on Labor Supply: Estimates of the Optimal Gas Tax.” Journal of Public Economics. 91: 593-617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Wildasin, David E. (1985) “Income Taxes and Urban Spatial Structure” Journal of Urban Economics 18: 313-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Zodrow, George, 2001. “The Property Tax as a Capital Tax: A Room with Three Views” National Tax Journal, 54(1): 139-156.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>TIME USE AT HOME, IN VEHICLES, OUTSIDE THE HOME, AND IN THE WORKPLACE</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>LABOR FORCE PARTICIPATION, WORK HOURS, AND LOCAL CHARACTERISTICS</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
