<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816589</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Avoiding Taxes (Accounting)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Corporate Governance on Tax Avoidance</article-title>
            <subtitle>Evidence from Governance Reform</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kerr</surname>
                  <given-names>Jon N.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Price</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Román</surname>
                  <given-names>Francisco J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>50</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816589"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Recent tax research explores the relation between the strength of corporate governance and tax avoidance. Desai and Dharmapala (2006) find strong evidence that firms using high-powered equity incentives engage in less tax avoidance. Subsequent research on whether governance curbs tax avoidance is mixed. Seidman and Stomberg (2011) argue that this result is attributable to the tax benefits of stock options. Armstrong et al. (2015) find limited evidence of a relation between equity incentives and tax avoidance in the extremes of the distribution. In this paper, we re-examine the issue and present new evidence by focusing on Mexican firms, which radically transformed their systems of governance following governance reform in 2000. Using a broad measure of governance generally unaffected by equity incentives, we show that tax avoidance decreases significantly following the implementation of the governance reform. This suggests there is a causal link between the strength of governance systems and tax evasion. We also show that firms with higher reported governance engage in less tax avoidance. Overall, our results contribute to this growing literature by documenting that improved governance does appear to curb tax avoidance.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Anton, A. 2005. Average effective tax rates in México. Economía Mexicana, Centro de Investigación y Docéncias Económicas 14 (2), 185-215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Armstrong, C., J. Blouin, A. Jagolinzer, D. Larcker. 2015. Corporate governance, incentives, and tax avoidance. Journal of Accounting and Economics 60, 1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bergman, M., V. Carreón and F. Hernández. 2005. Evasión fiscal del impuesto sobre la renta de personas morales. Unpublished working paper. Centro de Investigación y Docéncias Económicas (México).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Blaylock, B. 2016. Is tax avoidance associated with economically significant rent extraction among U.S. firms? Contemporary Accounting Research Vol. 20, 1–30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chen, S., X. Chen, Q. Cheng, and T. Shevlin. 2010. Are family firms more tax aggressive than non-family firms? Journal of Financial Economics 95, 41–61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Desai, M., and D. Dharmapala. 2006. Corporate tax avoidance and high-powered incentives.Journal of Financial Economics 79 (1), 145-179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Desai, M., A. Dyck, and L. Zingales. 2007. Theft and taxes. Journal of Financial Economics 84, 591–623.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Desai, M., and D. Dharmapala. 2008. Tax and corporate governance: An economic approach.Tax and Corporate Governance, W. Schön (ed.), Springer, 13-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Código de Mejores Prácticas Corporativas, 1999. Bolsa Mexicana de Valores. México.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Código de Mejores Prácticas Corporativas, 2014. Consejo Coordinador Empresarial. April 14.Mexico.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Congreso de la Union. 2001. “Ley de Sociedades de Inversión”, Diario Oficial de la Federación, June 4. México. http://www.diputados.gob.mx/LeyesBiblio/pdf/69_130614.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Congreso de la Union. 2003. “Disposiciones de Carácter General Aplicables a las Emisoras de Valores y a Otros Participantes del Mercado de Valores”, Diario Oficial de la Federación, March 19. México.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Congreso de la Union. 2005. “Nueva Ley del Mercado de Valores (NLMV)”, Diario Oficial de la Federación, December 30. México.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Congreso de la Union. 2007. “Ley del Impuesto Empresarial a Tasa Única”, Diario Oficial de la Federación, October 1. México.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Congreso de la Union. 2007. “Ley de Impuestos a los Depósitos en Efectivo”, Diario Oficial de la Federación, October 1. México.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Gallemore, J. and E. Labro. 2015. The Importance of the Internal Information Environment for Tax Avoidance. Journal of Accounting and Economics 60, 149-167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Gompers, P., J. Ishii, and A. Metrick.2003. Corporate governance and equity prices. Quarterly Journal of Economics 116, 229-259.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Lemmon, M., and K. Lins. 2003. Ownership structure, corporate governance, and firm value: evidence from the East Asian financial crisis. Journal of Finance 58, 1445-1468. 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Macias, A. and F. J. Román. 2014. Economic consequences of corporate governance reform in an emerging market: Evidence from México. Trimestre Económico 322 (2), 357-412.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Minnick, K., and T.J. Noga. 2010. Do Corporate Governance Characteristics Influence Tax Management? Journal of Corporate Finance, 16 (5), 703-718.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Price, R., F. J. Román, and B. Rountree.2011. The impact of governance reform on performance and transparency. Journal of Financial Economics 99 (1), 76-96.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Rego, S.O., and R. Wilson. 2012. Equity risk incentives and corporate tax aggressiveness.Journal of Accounting Research 50, 775–810.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Robinson, J.R., Y. Xue, and M.H. Zhang. 2012. Tax planning and financial expertise in the audit committee. Unpublished working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Rodriguez A., and C. Ruiz. 2013. Contribución efectiva al impuesto sobre la renta en personas morales del régimen general. Economia: Teoría y Práctica 38, 9-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Rubin, R. and L. Hoffman. 2016. U.S. sets tougher rules on tax deals. Wall Street Journal, April 5, p.1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Ruiz Alvarez, J.C. 2014. El impuesto a los depósitos en efectivo (IDE): un incentivo a la informalidad? Unpublished working paper. Instituto Tecnológico Autónoma de México.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Samaniego, R., E. Martinez, A. Mitsuko, V. Mendoza, and F. Zorrila. 2006. Medición de la evasión fiscal en México. Unpublished working paper. Centro de Economía Aplicada y Políticas Públicas. Instituto Tecnológico Autónoma de México.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Seidman, J., and B. Stomberg. 2011. Why are option compensation and tax sheltering negatively related? Unpublished working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>APPENDIX A</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Variable Definitions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Chronolgy of Mexico’s Implementations Tax and Corporate Governance Reforms under the Study’s Examination</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>ETRSpr over Time</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Current ETRSpr over Time</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Sample Construction</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Governance Reform and Tax Avoidance</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Governance Reform Indicator and Tax Avoidance</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Post-Governance Reform Period Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Post-Governance Reform Correlation Matrix</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Governance Index and Tax Avoidance</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Lag Governance Index and Tax Avoidance</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Governance Index and Cash Tax Payments</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Tax Reform and Tax Avoidance</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>The Effect of Governance and Tax Reforms on Tax Avoidance</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Tax Avoidance and Firm Value</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
