<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278029</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Experimental and Modeling Study of Ash Impact on DPF Backpressure and Regeneration Behaviors</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Liu</surname>
                  <given-names>Yi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Emission Solutions</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Su</surname>
                  <given-names>Changsheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Emission Solutions</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Clerc</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Emission Solutions</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Harinath</surname>
                  <given-names>Arvind</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Emission Solutions</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rogoski</surname>
                  <given-names>Leigh</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Cummins Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1313</fpage>
         <lpage>1321</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278029"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>One field-returned DPF loaded with a high amount of ash is examined using experimental and modeling approaches. The ash-related design factors are collected by coupling the inspection results from terahertz spectroscopy with a calibrated DPF model. The obtained ash packing density, ash layer permeability and ash distribution profile are then used in the simulation to assess the ash impact on DPF backpressure and regeneration behaviors. The following features have been observed during the simulation:</p>
            <p>1. The ash packing density, ash layer permeability and ash distribution profile should be collected at the same time to ensure the accurate prediction of ash impact on DPF backpressure. Missing one ash property could mislead the measurement of the other two parameters and thus affects the DPF backpressure estimation.</p>
            <p>2. The ash buildup would gradually increase the frequency for the backpressure-based active soot regeneration. However, the accumulated ash reduces the energy density during the regeneration event as well as adsorbing exotherm, lowering the thermal cracking risk.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A.G., Kostoglou, M., Lorentzou, S., Vlachos, N., “Aspects of multifunctional diesel particulate filters and their efficient simulation,” Catalysis Today 188(2013) 2-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McGeehan, J., Yeh, S., Rutherford, J., Couch, M. et al., “Analysis of DPF Incombustible Materials from Volvo Trucks Using DPF-SCRUrea With API CJ-4 and API CI-4 PLUS Oils,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):762-780, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1781.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, K., Martirosyan, K.S., Luss, D., “Temperature gradients within a soot layer during DPF regeneration,” Chemical Engineering Science 66 (2011) 2968-2973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bissett, E.J., “Mathematical model of the thermal regeneration of a wallflow monolith diesel particulate filter,” Chemical Engineering Science 39 (1984) 1233-1244.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schejbal, M., Stepanek, J., Marek, M., Koci, P., Kubicek, M., “Modelling of soot oxidation by NO2 in various types of diesel particulate filters,” Fuel 89(2010) 2365-2375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tighe, C.J., Twigg, M.V., Hayhurst, A.N., Dennis, J.S., “The kinetics of oxidation of diesel soots by NO2,” Combustion and Flame 159 (2012) 77-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sappok, A., Santiago, M., Vianna, T., and Wong, V., “Characteristics and Effects of Ash Accumulation on Diesel Particulate Filter Performance: Rapidly Aged and Field Aged Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01- 1086, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nuszkowski, J., Thompson, G., Moles, N., Chiaramonte, M. et al., “Pressure Drop and Cleaning of In-Use Ash Loaded Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3256, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006- 01-3256.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, K., Lynskey, M., Corrigan, E., Hickman, D. et al., “Real World Study of Diesel Particulate Filter Ash Accumulation in Heavy- Duty Diesel Trucks,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3257, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3257.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sappok, A., Rodriguez, R., and Wong, V., “Characteristics and Effects of Lubricant Additive Chemistry on Ash Properties Impacting Diesel Particulate Filter Service Life,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):705-722, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1213.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cordiner, S., Mulone, V., Nobile, M., and Rocco, V., “Diesel Engine Biofuelling: Effects of Ash on the Behavior of the Diesel Particulate Filter,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-24-0165, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-24- 0165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MECA, “Diesel Particulate Filter Maintenance: Current Practices and Experience,” Manufacturers of Emission Controls Association, Washington, D.C., 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, B., Kang, H., Son, G., and Hwang, C., “Thermal Aging Behavior of SiC Substrate in the Presence of Ash Materials and Alkali Metals,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1939, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sappok, A., Wang, Y., Wang, R., Kamp, C. et al., “Theoretical and Experimental Analysis of Ash Accumulation and Mobility in Ceramic Exhaust Particulate Filters and Potential for Improved Ash Management,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(2):511-524, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1517.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishizawa, T., Yamane, H., Satoh, H., Sekiguchi, K. et al., “Investigation into Ash Loading and Its Relationship to DPF Regeneration Method,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 2(2):164-175, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2882.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harris, T., Kozlov, A., Ayyappan, P., and Combs, J., “Engine Test Protocol for Accelerated Ash Loading of a Diesel Particulate Filter,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0607, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dittler, A., “Ash Transport in Diesel Particle Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1732, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1732.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Youngquist, A., Nguyen, K., Bunting, B., and Toops, T., “Development of an Accelerated Ash Loading Protocol for Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2496, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morcos, M., Ayyappan, P., and Harris, T., “Characterization of DPF Ash for Development of DPF Regeneration Control and Ash Cleaning Requirements,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1248, doi:10.4271/2011- 01-1248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gaiser, G. and Mucha, P., “Prediction of Pressure Drop in Diesel Particulate Filters Considering Ash Deposit and Partial Regenerations,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0158, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., Wong, V., Sappok, A., and Munnis, S., “The Sensitivity of DPF Performance to the Spatial Distribution of Ash Inside DPF Inlet Channels,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-011584, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013- 01-1584.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zandhuis, J., Finney, C., Toops, T., Partridge, W. et al., “Nondestructive X-ray Inspection of Thermal Damage, Soot and Ash Distributions in Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0289, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strzelec, A., Bilheux, H., Finney, C., Daw, C. et al., “Neutron Imaging of Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-2735, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2735.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Foley, R., Naber, J., Johnson, J., and Rogoski, L., “Development of the Methodology for Quantifying the 3D PM Distribution in a Catalyzed Particulate Filter with a Terahertz Wave Scanner,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1573, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1573.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, K., Martirosyan, K.S., Luss, D., “Hot zone formation during regeneration of diesel particulate filters,” AICHE Journal 57 (2011) 497- 506.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A., Kostoglou, M., Housiada, P., Vlachos, N. et al., “Multichannel Simulation of Soot Oxidation in Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0839, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003- 01-0839.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A., Kostoglou, M., Skaperdas, E., Papaioannou, E. et al., “Fundamental Studies of Diesel Particulate Filters: Transient Loading, Regeneration and Aging,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1016, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Charbonnel, S. and Opris, C., “Fundamental Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) Pressure Drop Model,” SAE Technical Paper 200901-1271, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huynh, C., Johnson, J., Yang, S., Bagley, S. et al., “A One-Dimensional Computational Model for Studying the Filtration and Regeneration Characteristics of a Catalyzed Wall-Flow Diesel Particulate Filter,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0841, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0841.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yezerets, A., Currier, N.W., Kim, D.H., Eadler, H.A., Epling, W.S., Peden, C.H.F., “Differential kinetic analysis of diesel particulate matter (soot) oxidation by oxygen using a step-response technique,” Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 61 (2005) 120-129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bird, R.B., Stewart, W.E., Lightfoot, E.N., “Transport phenomena,” 2nd ed.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Y., Chen, W., Henrichsen, M., and Harinath, A., “Analysis of Packaging Impact on Emission Catalyst Design,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1560, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1560.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, N., Rutland, C., Foster, D., Narayanaswamy, K. et al., “Investigation into Different DPF Regeneration Strategies Based on Fuel Economy Using Integrated System Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1275, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ogyu, K., Oya, T., Kasuga, T., and Ohno, K., “Study on Filter Substrate Structure for Lower Backpressure and Higher Regeneration Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-011526, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1526.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tan, J., Opris, C., Baumgard, K., and Johnson, J., “A Study of the Regeneration Process in Diesel Particulate Traps Using a Copper Fuel Additive,” SAE Technical Paper 960136, 1996, doi:10.4271/960136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
