<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169010</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>PHEV Cold Start Emissions Management</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Chambon</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Deter</surname>
                  <given-names>Dean</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Tennessee</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Irick</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Tennessee</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Smith</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>July 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169008</issue-id>
         <fpage>252</fpage>
         <lpage>260</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169010"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Plug-in hybrid electric vehicles (PHEV) operate predominantly as electric vehicles (EV) with intermittent assist from the engine. As a consequence, the engine can be subjected to multiple cold start events. These cold start events have a significant impact on tailpipe emissions due to degraded catalyst performance and starting the engine under less than ideal conditions. On current conventional vehicles, the first cold start of the engine dictates whether or not the vehicle will pass federal emissions tests. PHEV operation compounds this problem due to infrequent, multiple engine cold starts.</p>
            <p>ORNL, in collaboration with the University of Tennessee, developed an Engine-In-the-Loop (EIL) test platform to investigate cold start emissions on a 2.0l Gasoline Turbocharged Direct Injection (GTDI) Ecotec engine coupled to a virtual series hybrid electric vehicle. The end-goal of this project is to demonstrate the benefits of coordinating engine and powertrain supervisory control strategies to minimize cold start emissions.</p>
            <p>First, this paper provides a summary of the results obtained by optimizing engine cold start strategies on their own within the context of a PHEV application where the engine can be motored up to speed and supplemented with the electric machine. These specific operating modes open up new engine calibration opportunities. This study investigated the effect of different cranking injection, post-start load, idle speed and spark timing strategies.</p>
            <p>The paper then reports on the second phase of the project which focuses on the coordination of engine control strategies and hybrid energy management strategies. Stand-alone optimization of each component's algorithms does not guarantee that the resulting hybrid powertrain will operate efficiently. Therefore cold start strategies have to be controlled and optimized as a system to minimize tailpipe emissions. Comparison results of different coordination algorithms are presented to demonstrate the benefit of system coordination and optimization.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morita, K., Sonoda, Y., Kawase, T., and Suzuki, H., “Emission Reduction of a Stoichiometric Gasoline Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3687, 2005: doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Landenfeld, T., Kufferath, A., and Gerhardt, J., “Gasoline Direct Injection - SULEV Emission Concept,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0041, 2004: doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0041.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, D., Lohse-Busch, H., and Irick, D., “A Preliminary Investigation into the Mitigation of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle Tailpipe Emissions Through Supervisory Control Methods,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):996-1011, 2010: doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brdarski, A., Kern, J., Woldring, D., Yilmaz, H. et al., “SI Engine Hardware and Software Design for High Power, Low Emission Applications,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):189-195, 2009: doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yu, C., Park, K., Han, S., and Kim, W., “Development of Theta II 2.4L GDI Engine for High Power &amp; Low Emission,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1486, 2009: doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1486.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reiche, D., Wooldridge, S., Moilanen, P., and Davis, G., “Experimental Optimization of the Cold Start for the EcoBoost Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1491, 2009: doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1491.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
