<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007195</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Ice accretion on circular cylinder in relation to its diameter</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Virk</surname>
                  <given-names>Muhammad S</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Arctic Technology Research Team, Institute of Industrial Technology, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>February 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007189</issue-id>
         <fpage>55</fpage>
         <lpage>61</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© SAGE Publications Ltd, 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007195"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>Numerical study of atmospheric ice accretion on circular cylinder is carried out to understand the relation between cylinder diameter and resultant ice accretion. To validate the numerical model, results are compared with the experimental data and a good agreement is found. Numerical study shows that change in cylinder diameter significantly affects the air and droplet behavior that results a change in ice growth along cylinder. A detailed parametric study is carried out for different droplet sizes and cylindrical diameters. Results show a decrease in droplet collision efficiency and ice growth with the increase in cylinder diameter.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label>
            <kwd>Atmospheric ice</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>circular cylinder</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>diameter</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>droplet size</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ackely SF and Templeton MK (1979) Computer Modelling of Atmospheric Ice Accretion. Hanover, NH: Cold Regions Research and Engineering Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boutanios Z (1999) An Eulerian 3D analysis of water droplets impingement on a Convair-580 nose and cockpit geometry. Master’s Thesis, Concordia University, Montréal, QC, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Clift R, Grace JR and Weber ME (1978) Bubbles, Drops and Particles. New York: Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FENSAP Ice User Manual, Release 1.0.0 (2010) Newmerical Technologies International, Canada.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Finstad J, Lozowski EP and Gates EM (1988) A computational investigation of water droplet trajectories. Journal of Atmospheric and Oceanic Technology 5: 160–170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fu P, Farzaneh M and Bouchard G (2006) Two dimensional modelling of the ice accretion process on transmission line wires and conductors. Cold Regions Science and Technology 46: 132–146.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lozowski EP and Oleskiw MM (1983) Computer Modelling of Time Dependant Rime Icing in the Atmosphere. Hanover, NH: Cold Regions Research and Engineering Laboratory.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lozowski EP, Finstad KJ and Gates EM (1985) Comments on calculation of the impingement of cloud droplets on a cylinder by finite element method. Journal of Atmospheric Science 42(3): 306–307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lozowski EP, Stallabrass JR and Hearty FP (1983) The icing of an unheated, non-rotating cylinder, part I: A simulation model. Journal of Climate and Applied Meteorology 22: 2053–2062.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McComber P (1983) Numerical simulation of ice accretion on cables. In: First international workshop on atmospheric icing on structures, Hanover, NH, 1–3 June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McComber P, Martin R and Morin G (1983) Estimation of combined ice and wind loads on overhead transmission lines. In:First international workshop on atmospheric icing on structures, Hanover, NH, 1–3 June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Makkonen L (2000) Models for the growth of rime, glaze, icicles and wet snow on structures. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society A: Mathematical Physical and Engineering Sciences 358(1776): 2913–2939.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Makkonen L, Laakso T and Marjaniemi M (2001) Modelling and prevention of ice accretion on wind turbines. Wind Engineering 25(1): 3–21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Özgen S and Canıbek M (2009) Ice accretion simulation on multi-element airfoils using extended Messinger model. Heat Mass Transfer 45: 305–322.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shin J (1994) Prediction of ice shapes and their effect on airfoil drag. Journal of Aircraft 31(2): 263–270.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shin J and Bind TH (1992) Experimental and computational ice shapes and resulting drag increase for a NACA 0012 airfoil (NASA Technical Memorandum). In: 5th symposium on numerical and physical aspects of aerodynamic flows, Long Beach, CA, 13–16 January, vol. 105743. Cleveland, OH: NASA Lewis Research Center. Available at: http://ntrs.nasa.gov/archive/nasa/casi.ntrs.nasa.gov/19920019431.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skelton PLI and Poots G (1991) Snow accretion on overhead line conductors of finite torsional stiffness. Cold Regions Science and Technology 19: 301–316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith BW and Barker CP (1982) Icing of cables. In: First international workshop on atmospheric icing on structures, Hanover, NH, 1–3 June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Virk M (2011) Numerical study of atmospheric ice accretion on various geometric cross sections. Wind Engineering 35(5): 607–614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Virk MS (2013) Atmospheric ice accretion on circular over-head powerline conductors installed in tandem arrangement. International Journal of Computational Multiphase Flow 5(1): 73–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Virk MS, Mughal UN and Polanco G (2015) Atmospheric ice accretion on non rotating vertical circular cylinder. World Journal of Engineering and Technology 3: 284–289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Virk SM, Homola MC and Nicklasson PJ (2010a) Effect of rime ice accretion on aerodynamic characteristics of wind turbine blade profiles. Wind Engineering 34(2): 207–218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Virk SM, Homola MC, Wallenius T, et al. (2010b) Effect of atmospheric temperature and droplet size variation on ice accretion of wind turbine blades. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 98: 724–729.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner T, Peil U and Borri C (2009) Numerical investigation of conductor bundle icing. In: EACWE 5, Florence, 19–23 July.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
