<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465645</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465649</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Frictions in Shadow Banking: Evidence from the Lending Behavior of Money Market Mutual Funds</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Sergey</given-names>
                  <surname>Chernenko</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Adi</given-names>
                  <surname>Sunderam</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1717</fpage>
         <lpage>1750</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465649"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We document frictions in money market mutual fund lending that lead to the transmission of distress across borrowers. Using novel security-level holdings data, we show that funds exposed to Eurozone banks suffered large outflows in mid-2011. These outflows had significant spillovers: non-European issuers relying on such funds raised less short-term debt financing. Issuer characteristics do not explain the results: holding fixed the issuer, funds with higher Eurozone exposure cut lending more. Due to credit market frictions, funds with low Eurozone exposure provided substitute financing only to issuers they had pre-existing relationships with, even though issuers are large, highly rated firms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d36e226a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e233" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Volcker (2010), Yellen (2011), Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission (2011), Acharya and
Richardson (2009), Becker and Ivashina (Forthcoming), Duffie (2010), and Kacperczyk and Schnabl (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e243a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e250" publication-type="other">
Theoretical work includes Bernanke and Blinder (1988), Bernanke and Gertler (1989), and Holmstrom and
Tirole (1997). Recent empirical work includes Gan (2007), who studies the effects of the Japanese real estate
bust, Khwaja and Mian (2008), who study the aftermath of Pakistani nuclear tests in 1998, Paravisini (2008),
who studies a government lending program in Argentina, Iyer and Peydro (2011), who study a major bank failure
in India, and Chava and Purnanandam (2011) and Schnabl (2012), who study how banks transmitted distress
after the Russian default in 1998.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e273a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e280" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Bernanke (1983), Rajan (1992), and Petersen and Rajan (1994).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e287a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e294" publication-type="other">
We will refer to prime money market mutual funds simply as MMMFs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e302a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e309" publication-type="other">
As of June 1, 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e316a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e323" publication-type="other">
Recent papers on MMMFs include Christoffersen (2001 ), Christoffersen and Musto (2002), Baba, McCauley, and
Ramaswamy (2009), McCabe (2010), Adrian, Kimbrough, and Marchioni (2011), Duygan-Bump et al. (2013),
Kacperczyk and Schnabl (2013), Strahan and Tanyeri (Forthcoming), and Schmidt, Timmermann, and Weimers
(2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e339a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e346" publication-type="other">
See Bloomberg's European Crisis Timeline for more information: www.bloomberg.com/news/2011-11-07/
europe-timeline-maastricht-to-papandreou.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e356a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e363" publication-type="other">
Based on data from the Investment Company Institute (ICI), covering the 1984-2011 period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e370a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e377" publication-type="other">
Schmidt, Timmermann, and Wermers (2013) document that this relationship is reversed during the financial
crisis, showing that higher-yielding MMMFs suffered higher outflows following the Lehman default. We show
a similar result for the post-period, June-August 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e390a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e397" publication-type="other">
These statements were not sufficient to stem investor redemptions. The first statement was made on June 24th,
2011; the fund nonetheless suffered $10 billion (18% of June 2011 assets) of outflows in July 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e408a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e415" publication-type="other">
Despite the fact that only a relatively small number of issuers raise financing from MMMFs, there is anecdotal
evidence that the approved issuer lists are both restrictive and slow to change. For instance, Reich and Tang publish
their list on their Web site. On their November 15, 2011 list, the oldest that we have access to, there are over 150
issuers that are in our N-MFP data but are not preapproved by Reich and Tang. Of these, 48 are nonfinancials,
including such highly rated (P-l) issuers as Honda, Cargill, Automatic Data Processing, Merck, Google, Texas
Instruments, Cisco, Philip Morris International, eBay, Medtronic, Honeywell International, Target, and Campbell
Soup. Reich and Tang's list is also quite stable over time. On November 15, 2011, it had 164 approved issuers.
By December 27, 2012, over a year later, only 34 issuers were removed and 22 were added. Out of the removed
issuers, 16 were downgraded by Moody's to second tier, and nine were subsidiaries whose parents remain on the
list.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e450a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e459" publication-type="other">
Funds report their category (e.g., prime, government, municipal) in item 10 of form N-MFP. We manually
examine all funds that ever report their category as prime to check for reporting errors. We manually identify
internal funds by looking up their profiles and by searching for them in the CRSP Mutual Fund database, which
does not cover internal funds. Variable annuities are identified in item 9 of form N-MFP. We also exclude two
funds that hold only cash during the whole sample period and seven prime muni funds, which we define as
prime funds that consistently invest more than 75% of their assets in municipal securities. Some of these funds
explicitly state that their investment objectives include "sustainability and social responsibility factors."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e485a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e492" publication-type="other">
After applying our screens, aggregate assets of prime MMMFs are very close to the ICI numbers: $1,655 versus
$1,660 billion as of May 31, 2011. Before applying our screens, aggregate assets of prime MMMFs are larger
in N-MFP data than in ICI data. As of May 31, 2011, aggregate assets of prime MMMFs reporting on form
N-MFP are $1,875 billion, while they are $1,660 billion according to the ICI. Most of the difference is due to
the inclusion of internal funds in N-MFP data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e511a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e518" publication-type="other">
Form N-MFP provides us with issuer name, security CUSIP, if available, and issuer CIK if security CUSIP is
not available. Because a given issuer can have multiple issuer CUSIPs and because some instruments, such as
repurchase agreements and certificates of deposit, do not have CUSIPs, we use a number of other datasets—the
CUSIP master file, FISD, S&amp;P Ratings iQuery, the SEC's list of all CIKs matched with entity names, and datasets
of Fitch, Moody's, and S&amp;P credit ratings publicly available per Rule 17g-2—to link each security to the ultimate
parent of the issuer. For example, our algorithm attributes all of the following to BNP Paribas: CDs issued by
its Chicago, New York, and San Francisco branches (which have their own issuer CUSIPs), commercial paper
issued by BNP Paribas Finance, and repurchase agreements entered into by BNP Paribas Securities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e547a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e554" publication-type="other">
Furthermore, municipal issuers are generally small (the median municipal issuer borrows just $35 million from
prime MMMFs), are missing from the CUSIP master file most of the time, and have the most variation across
funds in the spelling of a given issuer's name.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e567a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e574" publication-type="other">
For example, three Morgan Stanley funds experience the largest inflows in our sample, with each fund more than
doubling in size. These apparent inflows are due to a one-time sweep of the cash balances of Morgan Stanley
Smith Barney clients into Morgan Stanley MMMFs in April 2011. Because this decision was made by Morgan
Stanley with investors having relatively little say in the matter, these fund flows are unlikely to be informative
about the general performance-flow relationship. Rather than make subjective judgements about such outliers,
we winsorize fund flows at the 5th and 95th percentiles. We obtain similar results when we winsorize at the 1st
and 99th percentiles.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e601a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e610" publication-type="other">
For reference, Kacperczyk and Schnabl (2013) estimate that in the pre-crisis period a 10 basis point increase
in yield is associated with a 7% increase in fund assets on an annualized basis. Thus, the performance-flow
relationship was nearly twice as strong per basis point during March-May 2011 as it was during August 2007-
August 2008. This is consistent with the conjecture of Rajan (2006), who suggested that risk-taking incentives
in financial intermediaries may increase as nominal yields fall.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e629a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e636" publication-type="other">
Similarly, we find that fund flows are more sensitive to exposures to banks in Greece, Ireland, Italy, Spain, and
Portugal, which not surprisingly were in significantly weaker financial condition, than to banks in other Eurozone
countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e649a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e656" publication-type="other">
Fitch Ratings, for example, has been producing monthly reports discussing changes in the exposure of MMMFs
to Eurozone banks.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e666a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e673" publication-type="other">
One may also wonder why MMMFs could not stem these outflows by reducing their exposures to Eurozone
banks. One answer is that secondary markets for large CDs and commercial paper are not very liquid (Covitz
and Downing 2007), so MMMFs trying to sell their Eurozone bank exposures would potentially have to do so
at significant discounts. A second answer is that risk taking by funds is persistent. In unreported results available
upon request, we find that the cross-sectional rank of funds by yield, a measure of risk, is highly persistent
over time. We also find that outflows around Lehman's bankruptcy, a proxy for risk taking before the crisis, are
strongly correlated with risk taking in the pre-period, both in the form of exposure to Eurozone banks and in
the form of lending through repo backed by highly distressed structured finance collateral. (See, for example,
Fitch Ratings (2012) on the risks of MMMFs lending against highly distressed structured finance collateral.) Our
results on persistence in risk taking are consistent with Fahlenbrach, Prilmeier, and Stulz (2012), who show that
a commercial bank's performance during the 1998 crisis predicts its performance during the recent crisis, though
their evidence shows persistence over a longer period than ours. In contrast, Strahan and Tanyeri (Forthcoming)
find that money funds that took on more risk leading up to Lehman's default did not invest in riskier assets in
the fall of 2008 after they were guaranteed by the government. This may be because funds feared the negative
stigma associated with actually using government guarantee.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e724a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e731" publication-type="other">
Note, however, that the results in Table 3 suggest investors were not withdrawing from all funds that generally
invest in riskier assets, only from those with large exposures to Eurozone banks. Also, in Table 4, it is not the
case that riskier issuers, as proxied for by pre-period yield, experience larger declines in outstandings during the
post-period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e747a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e754" publication-type="other">
Indeed, most of the effect in panel A is driven by exit. When we restrict our analysis of A Outstanding if to
fund-issuer pairs that are not exited in the post-period, the coefficient on Fund Euro share is negative, but not
statistically significant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e768a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e775" publication-type="other">
See, for example, reports by Fitch Ratings: U.S. Money Fund Exposure and European Banks: Seeking a
New Equilibrium from February 23, 2012 and U.S. Money Fund Exposure and European Banks: A Partial
Disengagement from March 22, 2012.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e788a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e795" publication-type="other">
We thank an anonymous referee for suggesting this</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e802a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e809" publication-type="other">
We are assuming that a typical loan is renewed once every 1-3 years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e816a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e823" publication-type="other">
In contrast to form N-MFP, which is filed by each individual fund, multiple funds can file on a single form N-Q,
N-CSRS, or N-CSR. Therefore, we make sure to use only that portion of each filing that covers the particular
fund in question.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e836a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e843" publication-type="other">
The negative coefficient on strong relationship in Columns 4—5 captures mean reversion in portfolio share that
is not picked up by the linear effect of lagged portfolio share.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e853a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e860" publication-type="other">
Because we are looking at the subset of all issuer types, namely, non-European financials and nonfinancials
and ABCP, the positive constant term indicates that on average funds are shifting their portfolios towards these
issuers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e874a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e881" publication-type="other">
Similar arguments apply to ABCP programs, which almost always have liquidity backstops from their sponsors
(Acharya, Schnabl, and Suarez 2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e891a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e898" publication-type="other">
Reporting of outstanding CP is voluntary, so not all nonfinancial issuers consistently report it.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e905a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e912" publication-type="other">
As with the evidence in Table 4, our analysis here is at the issuer level and could therefore be partially driven
by a broad withdrawal of MMMF financing from risky borrowers, in addition to the transmission of distress
suggested by the spillovers we identify in Tables 5 and 8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e925a1310">
            <label>32</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e932" publication-type="other">
We may also simply lack the power to detect real effects in our small sample of nonfinancial firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e939a1310">
            <label>33</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e946" publication-type="other">
See for example the unofficial transcript of the SEC roundtable on MMMFs and systemic risk
www.sec.gov/spotlight/mmf-risk/mmf-risk-transcript-051011.htm. Indeed, during the episode we study, both
U.S. domiciled banks and U.S. branches of foreign banks saw withdrawals of large time deposits, one of the
main instruments purchased by MMMFs and institutional investors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e962a1310">
            <label>34</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e969" publication-type="other">
Based on data from the Investment Company Institute, over the 2008-2012 period the correlation between weekly
flows into institutional prime and institutional government MMMFs was —0.34. Substitution between prime and
government MMMFs is particularly strong during crisis times. For example, the correlation between prime and
government flows was —0.89 during the second half of 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e986a1310">
            <label>35</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e993" publication-type="other">
Other similar proposals include Ricks (2011 ab), who calls for regulations similar to those governing commercial
banks for any issuer of short-term "money-like" claims; Gorton and Metrick (2010), who call for insurance of
money market funds to guarantee their investors payment and eliminate incentives to run; and McCabe, Cipriani,
Holscher, and Martin (2012), who call for a small fraction of each investor's recent balances to be set aside to
cover any losses if a fund has to be liquidated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e1021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1025" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V. V., and M. Richardson. 2009. Causes of the financial crisis. Critical Review 21:195-210.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1032a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1036" publication-type="other">
Acharya, V. V., P. Schnabl, and G Suarez. 2013. Securitization without risk transfer. Journal of Financial
Economics 107:515-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1046a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1050" publication-type="other">
Adrian, T., K. Kimbrough, and D. Marchioni. 2011. The federal reserve's commercial paper funding facility.
Federal Reserve Bank of New York Economic Policy Review 17:25-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1060a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1064" publication-type="other">
Aiyar, S. 2012. From financial crisis to great recession: The role of globalized banks. American Economic
Review 102:225-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1079" publication-type="other">
Almeida, H., M. Campello, B. Laranjeira, and S. Weisbenner. 2012. Corporate debt maturity and the real effects
of the 2007 credit crisis. Critical Finance Review 1:3-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1093" publication-type="other">
Angrist, J. D., and J.-S. Pischke. 2009. Mostly harmless econometrics: An empiricist's companion. Princeton:
Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1107" publication-type="other">
Aragon, G O., and P. E. Strahan. 2012. Hedge funds as liquidity providers: Evidence from the Lehman bankruptcy.
Journal of Financial Economics 103:570-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1121" publication-type="other">
Baba, N., R. McCauley, and S. Ramaswamy. 2009. US dollar money market funds and non-US banks. BIS
Quarterly Review March:65-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1131a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1135" publication-type="other">
Becker, B., and V. Ivashina. Forthcoming. Reaching for yield in the bond market. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1142a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1146" publication-type="other">
Ben-David, I., F. Franzoni, and R. Moussawi. 2013. Hedge fund stock trading in the financial crisis of 2007-2009.
Review of Financial Studies 25:1-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1157a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1161" publication-type="other">
Benmelech, E. 2009. Asset salability and debt maturity: Evidence from 19th century American railroads. Review
of Financial Studies 22:1545-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1175" publication-type="other">
Berglöf, E., and E.-L. von Thadden. 1994. Short-term interests vs. long-term interests: Capital structure with
multiple investors. Quarterly Journal of Economics 87:1055-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1189" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B. S. 1983. Nonmonetary effects of the financial crisis in the propagation of the great depression.
American Economic Review 73:257-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1203" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B. S., and A. Blinder. 1988. Credit, money, and aggregate demand. American Economic Review
78:435-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1217" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B. S., and M. Gertler. 1989. Agency costs, net worth, and business fluctuations. American Economic
Review 79:14-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1227a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1231" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., E. Duflo, and S. Mullainathan. 2004. How much should we trust differences-in-differences
estimates? Quarterly Journal of Economics 119:249-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1242a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1246" publication-type="other">
Bharath, S., S. Dahiya, A. Saunders, and A. Srinivasan. 2007. So what do I get? The bank's view of lending
relationships. Journal of Financial Economics 85:368—419.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1260" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., X. Freixas, L. Gambacorta, and P. E. Mistrulli. 2013. Relationship and transaction lending in a crisis.
Working Paper, BIS.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1270a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1274" publication-type="other">
Bolton, P., and D. S. Scharfstein. 1996. Optimal debt structure and the number of creditors. Journal of Political
Economy 104:1-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1284a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1288" publication-type="other">
Boyson, N., J. Helwege, and J. Jindra. 2013. Does hedge fund trading disrupt the stock market? Working
Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1298a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1302" publication-type="other">
Calomiris, C., and G Gorton. 1991. The origin of banking panics: Models, facts, and bank regu-
lation. Financial Markets and Financial Crises, ed. R. G Hubbard, 109-74. University of Chicago
Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1319" publication-type="other">
Calomiris, C. W., and J. R. Mason. 2003. Fundamentals, panics, and bank distress during the depression. American
Economic Review 93:1615—47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1330a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1334" publication-type="other">
Cameron, A. C., J. B. Gelbach, and D. L. Miller. 2008. Bootstrap-based improvements for inference with clustered
errors. Review of Economics and Statistics 90:414—27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1344a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1348" publication-type="other">
Chava, S., and A. Purnanandam. 2011. The effect of banking crisis on bank-dependent borrowers. Journal of
Financial Economics 99:116-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1358a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1362" publication-type="other">
Chevalier, J., and G Ellison. 1997. Risk taking by mutual funds as a response to incentives. Journal of Political
Economy 105:1167-200.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1372a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1376" publication-type="other">
Chodorow-Reich, G 2013. The employment effects of credit market disruptions: Firm-level evidence from the
2008-09 financial crisis. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1386a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1390" publication-type="other">
Christoffersen, S. E. K. 2001. Why do money fund managers voluntarily waive their fees? Journal of Finance
56:1117-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1404" publication-type="other">
Christoffersen, S. E. K., and D. K. Musto. 2002. Demand curves and the pricing of money management. Review
of Financial Studies 15:1499-524.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1415a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1419" publication-type="other">
Coval, J., and E. Stafford. 2007. Asset fire sales (and purchases) in equity markets. Journal of Financial Economics
86:479-512.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1429a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1433" publication-type="other">
Covitz, D., and C. Downing. 2007. Liquidity or credit risk? The determinants of very short-term corporate yield
spreads. The Journal of Finance 62:2302-28.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1443a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1447" publication-type="other">
De Haas, R., and N. Van Horen. 2012. International shock transmission after the Lehman Brothers collapse:
Evidence from syndicated lending. American Economic Review 102:231-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1457a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1461" publication-type="other">
Donald, S. G, and K. Lang. 2007. Inference with difference-in-differences and other panel data. Review of
Economics and Statistics 89:221-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1471a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1475" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D. 2010. Presidential address: Asset price dynamics with slow-moving capital. Journal of Finance
65:1237-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1485a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1489" publication-type="other">
Duygan-Bump, B., P. M. Parkinson, E. S. Rosengren, G A. Suarez, and P. S. Willen. 2013. How effective were
the federal reserve emergency liquidity facilities? Evidence from the asset-backed commercial paper money
market mutual fund liquidity facility. Journal of Finance 68:715-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1503a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1507" publication-type="other">
Economist. 2011. Chest pains: Europe's sovereign-debt crisis is constricting the flow of money to its banks.
Economist August 27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1517a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1521" publication-type="other">
Fahlenbrach, R., R. Prilmeier, and R. Stulz. 2012. This time is the same: Using bank performance in 1998 to
explain bank performance during the recent financial crisis. Journal of Finance 67:2139-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1531a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1535" publication-type="other">
Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission. 2011. The financial crisis inquiry report.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1542a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1546" publication-type="other">
Fitch Ratings. 2012. Repos: A deep dive in the collateral pool. Research note.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1553a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1557" publication-type="other">
Gan, J. 2007. The real effects of asset market bubbles: Loan- and firm-level evidence of a lending channel.
Review of Financial Studies 20:1941-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1567a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1571" publication-type="other">
Gatev, E., and P. E. Strahan. 2006. Banks' advantage in hedging liquidity risk: Theory and evidence from the
commercial paper market. Journal of Finance 61:867-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1582a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1586" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G 2009. The subprime panic. European Financial Management 15:10-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1593a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1597" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and A. Metrick. 2010. Regulating the shadow banking system. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity
2010:261-312.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1611" publication-type="other">
Greenwood, R., and D. Thesmar. 2011. Stock price fragility. Journal of Financial Economics
102:471-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1625" publication-type="other">
Hanson, S. G, and A. Sunderam. 2013. Are there too many safe securities? Securitization and the incentives for
information production. Journal of Financial Economics 108:565-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1635a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1639" publication-type="other">
Hart, O., and J. Moore. 1994. A theory of debt based on the inalienability of human capital. Quarterly Journal
of Economics 109:841-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1649a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1653" publication-type="other">
Holmstrom, B., and J. Tirole. 1997. Financial intermediation, loanable funds, and the real sector. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 112:665-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1668" publication-type="other">
Ivashina, V., and D. Scharfstein. 2010. Bank lending during the financial crisis of 2008. Journal of Financial
Economics 97:319-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1678a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1682" publication-type="other">
Iyer, R., and J.-L. Peydro. 2011. Interbank contagion at work: Evidence from a natural experiment. Review of
Financial Studies 24:1337-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1692a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1696" publication-type="other">
Kacperczyk, M., and P. Schnabl. 2013. How safe are money market funds. Quarterly Journal of Economics
128:1073-122.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1706a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1710" publication-type="other">
Khwaja, A. I., and A. Mian. 2008. Tracing the impact of bank liquidity shocks: Evidence from an emerging
market. American Economic Review 98:1413-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1720a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1724" publication-type="other">
Kloek, T. 1981. OLS estimation in a model where a microvariable is explained by aggregates and
contemporaneous disturbances are equicorrelated. Econometrica 49:205-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1734a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1738" publication-type="other">
Lou, D. 2012. A flow-based explanation for return predictability. Review of Financial Studies 25:3457-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1746a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1750" publication-type="other">
Manconi, A., M. Massa, and A. Yasuda. 2012. The role of institutional investors in propagating the crisis of
2007-2008. Journal of Financial Economics 104:491-518.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1760a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1764" publication-type="other">
McCabe, P. E. 2010. The cross section of money market fund risks and financial crises. Federal Reserve Board,
Finance and Economics Discussion Series working paper 2010-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1774a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1778" publication-type="other">
McCabe, P. E., M. Cipriani, M. Holscher, and A. Martin. 2012. The minimum balance at risk: A proposal to
mitigate the systemic risks posed by money market funds. Federal Reserve Bank of New York Staff Report.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1788a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1792" publication-type="other">
Moulton, B. R. 1990. An illustration of a pitfall in estimating the effects of aggregate variables on micro units.
Review of Economics and Statistics 72:334-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1802a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1806" publication-type="other">
Paravisini, D. 2008. Local bank financial constraints and firm access to external finance. Journal of Finance
63:2161-93.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1816a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1820" publication-type="other">
Peek, J., and E. S. Rosengren. 1997. The international transmission of financial shocks: The case of Japan.
American Economic Review 87:495-505.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1831a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1835" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M. A., and R. G Rajan. 1994. The benefits of lending relationships: Evidence from small business data.
Journal of Finance 49:3-37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1845a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1849" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R. 1992. Insiders and outsiders: The choice between informed and arm's-length debt. Journal of Finance
47:1367^00.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1859a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1863" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R. G 2006. Has finance made the world riskier? European Financial Management 12:499-533.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1870a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1874" publication-type="other">
Ricks, M. 201 la. Regulating money creation after the crisis. Harvard Business Law Review 1:75-144.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1885" publication-type="other">
. 2011b. Shadow banking and financial regulation. Columbia Law and Economics Working Paper 370.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1892a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1896" publication-type="other">
Schmidt, L., A. Timmermann, and R. Weimers. 2013. Runs on money market funds. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1904a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1908" publication-type="other">
Schnabl, P. 2012. The international transmission of bank liquidity shocks: Evidence form an emerging market.
Journal of Finance 67:897-932.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1918a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1922" publication-type="other">
Squam Lake Group. 2011. Reforming money market funds. Proposal.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1929a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1933" publication-type="other">
Strahan, P. E., and B. Tanyeri. Forthcoming. Once burned, twice shy: Money market fund responses to a systemic
liquidity shock. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1943a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1947" publication-type="other">
Volcker, P. 2010. How to reform our financial system. New York Times, January 31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e1954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1958" publication-type="other">
Yellen, J. L. 2011. Assessing potential financial imbalances in an era of accommodative monetary policy. Speech
at the 2011 International Conference: Real and Financial Linkage and Monetary Policy, Bank of Japan, Tokyo,
Japan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


