<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308343</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of an Improved NOₓ Reaction Mechanism for Low Temperature Diesel Combustion Modeling</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yoshikawa</surname>
                  <given-names>Takeshi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Engine Research Center, University of Wisconsin - Madison</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>1105</fpage>
         <lpage>1117</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308343"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The development of a new Nitric Oxide (NOₓ) reaction mechanism has been conducted by adding species, including hydrogen cyanide (HCN) and the CH radical to a reduced chemistry diesel combustion model. The additional chemical reactions were added to the ERC’s reduced 12-step NOₓ mechanism, which consists of N, NO, N₂O, and NO₂. The new NOₓ mechanism was implemented into the KIVA/ERC-CHEMKIN code and was found to be able to predict the experimentally observed trend that the amount of engine-out NOₓ decreases as engine load is increased, which is not reproduced by the current reduced NOₓ mechanism. HCN and CH were found to be species that bridge CₓH<sub>y</sub>products and N radicals via the reaction CH+N₂→HCN+N under high equivalence ratio conditions, and Zeldovich NO formation is suppressed by the formation of HCN, a species in the Fenimore NO formation pathway. The additional species and reactions were also found to influence the prediction of engine-out soot emissions. Predictions with the new NOₓ mechanism and the ERC 2-step soot model showed a reduced amount of soot compared to the standard 12-step NOₓ and 2-step soot models. Acetylene (C₂H₂), which is considered to be a precursor of soot in the 2-step soot model, serves as a CH radical precursor as well, and soot and CH radicals compete with C₂H₂ in fuel rich regions. It is concluded that the new NOₓ reaction mechanism is able to predict NOₓ emissions more accurately for fuel-rich, high-load diesel engine operating conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeldovich, Y. B., "The oxidation of nitrogen in ombustion and explosions," Acta Physicochim, SSR 21:577, 1946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fenimore, C. P., "Studies of fuel-nitrogen in rich lame gases," Proceeding of Combustion Institute, 17:661, 1979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warnatz, J., Maas, and U., Dibble, R. W., ombustion: Physical and Chemical Fundamentals, odeling and Simulation, Experiments, Pollutant ormation, 4th ed., Spinger, Berlin, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eberius, H., Just, T., Kelm, S., Warnatz, J., and owak, U., "Konversion von brennstoffgebundenem tickstoff am Beispiel von dotierten Propan-Luft- lammen," VDI-Berichte, 645:626, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiedenhoefer, J. F., and Reitz, R. D., "A ultidimensional Radiation Model for Diesel Engine imulation with Comparison to Experiment," umerical Heat Transfer, Part A, 44, pp. 665-682, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guo, H., and Smallwood, G. J., "The interaction etween soot and NO formation in a laminar xisymmetric coflow ethylene/air diffusion flame," ombustion and Flame, 149, pp. 225-233, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, Y., "Diesel combustion optimization and missions reduction using adaptive injection trategies (AIS) with improved numerical models," h.D. Thesis, University of Wisconsin – Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smith, G. P., Golden, D. M., Frenklach, M., Moriarty, . W., Eiteneer, B., Goldenberg, M., Bowman, C. T., anson, R. K., Song, S., Gardinder, Jr. W. C., issianski, VV., and Qin, Z., ttp://www.me.berkeley.edu/gri_mech/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kong, S. C., Sun, Y., and Reitz, R. D., "Modeling iesel Spray Flame Liftoff, Sooting Tendency, and Ox Emissions Using Detailed Chemistry With henomenological Soot Model," Journal of ngineering for Gas Turbines and Power, Vol. 129, p. 245-251, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., Kadota, T., and Arai, M., "Development and Use of a spray Combustion odeling to Predict Diesel Engine Efficiency and ollutant Emissions, Part 1: Combustion Modeling," ulletin of the JSME, Vol. 26, No. 214, pp. 569-575, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagle, J. and Strickland-Constable, R. F., "Oxidation f carbon between 1000-2000􅘙C,” Proceedings of he 5th Carbon Conference, Vol.1, pp. 154-164, 1962, ergamon, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patterson, M. A., Kong, S. C., Hampson, G. J., and eitz, R. D., “Modeling the Effects of Fuel Injection haracteristics on Diesel Engine Soot and NOx missions,” SAE Paper 940523, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lutz, A. E., Kee, R. J., and Miller, J. A., "SENKIN: A ORTRAN Program for Predicting Homogeneous as Phase Chemical Kinetics with Sensitivity nalyses," Sandia Report, SAND 87-8248, UC-4, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patel, A., and Reitz, R. D., "Development and alidation of a Reduced Reaction Mechanism for CCI Engine Simulations," SAE Paper No. 2004-01- 0558, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Singh, S., "Experimental Investigation of ombustion and Validation of Advanced ombustion," PhD Thesis, University of Wisconsin – adison, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brakora, J. L., "Development and Validation of a educed Reaction Mechanism for Biodiesel-Fueled ngine Simulations," Master’s Thesis, University of isconsin – Madison, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">"XSENKPLOT: An Interactive Postprocessor for umerical Simulations of Chemical Kinetics," ttp://www.nist.gov/cstl/div836/xsenkplot.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sutton, J. A., Williams, B. A., and Fleming, J. W., “Laser-induced fluorescence measurements of NCN n low-pressure CH4/O1/N2 flames and its role in rompt NO formation,” Combustion and Flame,” 2007, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2007.09.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moskaleva, L. V., Lin, M. C., “The spin-conserved eaction CH+N2H+NCN: A major pathway to rompt NO studied by quantum/statistical theory alculations and kinetic modeling of rate constant,” roceedings of the Combustion Institute, Vol. 1, 28, p. 2393-2401, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kweon, C. B., and Foster, D. E. "Detailed Chemical omposition and Particle Size Assessment of Diesel ngine Exhaust," SAE Paper No. 2002-01-2670, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cheng, A. S., Upatnieks, A., and Mueller, C. J., "Investigation of the impact of biodiesel fuelling on Ox emissions using an optical direct injection diesel ngine," Int. J. Engine Res., Vol. 7, pp. 297-318, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environment Protection Agency, “A Comprehensive nalysis of Biodiesel Impacts on Exhaust missions,” EPA420-P-02-001, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
