<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007194</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Computational fluid dynamics simulation and full-scale experimental model inter-comparison of the wind flow around a university campus</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Dhunny</surname>
                  <given-names>AZ</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Toja-Silva</surname>
                  <given-names>F</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Peralta</surname>
                  <given-names>C</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a3">
                  <sup>3</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lollchund</surname>
                  <given-names>MR</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Rughooputh</surname>
                  <given-names>SDDV</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>Department of Physics, Faculty of Science, University of Mauritius, Reduit, Mauritius</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>CIEMAT, Madrid, Spain</aff>
            <aff id="a3">
               <sup>3</sup>Fraunhofer IWES, Oldenburg, Germany</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>February 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007189</issue-id>
         <fpage>43</fpage>
         <lpage>54</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© SAGE Publications Ltd, 2017</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007194"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>In this article, results obtained from two computational fluid dynamics solvers, WindSim and OpenFOAM, have been compared for the wind flow around the University of Mauritius’ campus for different wind directions, and a reference incident wind speed at diverse height above ground level. A grid resolution study is performed for both software and the mean differences of the two solvers with multiple turbulence models (standard k-ε, k-ε with Yap correction, and renormalization group k-ε) are analyzed with onsite measured data. The article concludes that the best results for the computational fluid dynamics simulation of the wind flow around buildings are obtained using OpenFOAM with <italic>k-ε</italic> turbulence model including Yap correction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label>
            <kwd>Urban region</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>computational fluid dynamics simulations around buildings</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>OpenFOAM</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>WindSim</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AWS (1997) Wind resource assessment handbook: Fundamentals for conducting a successful monitoring program. Report prepared for National Renewable Energy Laboratory. NREL Subcontract no. TAT-5-15283-01, April. Albany, NY: AWS Scientific, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baik JJ, Kang YS and Kim JJ (2007) Modeling reactive pollutant dispersion in an urban street canyon. Atmospheric Environment 41: 934–949.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartzis JG, Vlachogiannis D and Sfetsos A (2004) Thematic area 5: Best practice advice for environmental flows. QNET-CFD Network Newsletter 2: 34–39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blocken B and Carmeliet J (2002) Spatial and temporal distribution of driving rain on a low-rise building. Wind and Structures (5): 441–462.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blocken B and Carmeliet J (2004a) A review of wind-driven rain research in building science. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 92(13): 1079–1130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blocken B and Carmeliet J (2004b) Pedestrian wind environment around buildings: Literature review and practical examples. Journal of Thermal Envelope and Building Science 28(2): 107–159.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blocken B, Carmeliet J and Stathopoulos T (2007) CFD evaluation of wind speed conditions in passages between parallel buildings—effect of wall-function roughness modifications for the atmospheric boundary layer flow. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 95(9–11): 941–962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blocken B, Carmeliet J, Moonen P, et al. (2008) Numerical study on the existence of the Venturi effect in passages between perpendicular buildings. Journal of Engineering Mechanics-ASCE 134(12): 1021–1028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Britter R and Hanna S (2003) Flow and dispersion in urban areas. Annual Review of Fluid Mechanics 35: 469–496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Britter R and Schatzmann M (2007) Background and Justification Document to Support the Model Evaluation Guidance and Protocol, 3-00-018312-4 COST Office, Brussels, Belgium Cost Action 732.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferziger JH and Peric M (2002) Computational Methods for Fluid Dynamics (3rd edn). Springer Berlin Heidelberg.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Franke J, Hellsten A, Schlünzen H, et al. (2007) Best practice guideline for the CFD simulation of flows in the urban environment. COST Action 732, 1 May. Brussels: COST Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gagliano A, Nocera F, Patania F, et al. (2013) Assessment of micro-wind turbines performance in the urban environments: An aided methodology through geographical information systems. International Journal of Energy and Environmental Engineering 4: 43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GSI (2015) “Google Satellite Map,” Google Earth.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson T, Summers DM and Wilson CB (1986) Validation of a computer simulation of wind flow over a building model. Building and Environment 21: 97–111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Houda S, Zemmouri N, Hasseine A, et al. (2012) A CFD model for simulating urban flow in complex morphological street network. The Online Journal of Science and Technology 2(1): 1–10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalmikov A, Dupont G, Dykes K, et al. (2010) Wind power resource assessment in complex urban environments: MIT campus case study using CFD analysis. In: AWEA 2010 WINDPOWER conference, Dallas, TX, USA, 23–26 May 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kang YS, Baik JJ and Kim JJ (2008) Further studies of flow and reactive pollutant dispersion in a street canyon with bottom heating. Atmospheric Environment 42: 4964–4975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumar P, Fennell P and Britter R (2008) Effect of wind direction and speed on the dispersion of nucleation and accumulation mode particles in an urban street canyon. Science of the Total Environment 402: 82–94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Launder BE and Spalding DB (1974) The numerical computation of turbulent flows. Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics and Engineering 3: 269–289.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li XX, Liu CH, Leung D, et al. (2006) Recent progress in CFD modelling of wind field and pollutant transport in street canyons. Atmospheric Environment 40: 5640–5658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McNabola A, Broderick BM and Gill LW (2009) A numerical investigation of the impact of low boundary walls on pedestrian exposure to air pollutants in urban street canyons. Science of the Total Environment 407: 760–769.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meissner C (2010) WindSim Getting Started (5th edn). Tønsberg, Norway: WindSim AS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OpenFOAM (2015) Available at: http://www.openfoam.com/ (accessed 22 July 2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parente A, Gorlé C, Van Beeck J, et al. (2011) A comprehensive modelling approach for the neutral atmospheric boundary layer: Consistent inflow conditions, wall function and turbulence model. Boundary-Layer Meteorology 140: 411–428.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richards PJ and Hoxey RP (1993) Appropriate boundary conditions for computational wind engineering models using the k-ε turbulence model. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 46–47: 145–153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roache PJ (1998) Verification of codes and calculations. AIAA Journal 36: 696–702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sabatino SD, Buccolieri R, Pulvirenti B, et al. (2007) Simulations of pollutant dispersion within idealized urban-type geometries with CFD and integral models. Atmospheric Environment 41: 8316–8329.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sabatino SD, Buccolieri R, Pulvirenti B, et al. (2008) Flow and pollutant dispersion in street canyons using FLUENT and ADMS-Urban. Environmental Modeling &amp; Assessment 13: 369–381.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schatzmann M and Leitl B (2011) Issues with validation of urban flow and dispersion CFD models. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 99(4): 169–186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Solazzo E, Vardoulakis S and Cai X (2007) Evaluation of traffic-producing turbulence schemes within operating schemes within operational street pollution models using road side measurements. Atmospheric Environment 41: 5357–5370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stathopoulos T and Baskaran A (1996) Computer simulation of wind environmental conditions around buildings. Engineering Structures 18(11): 876–885.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toja-Silva F, Colmenar-Santos A and Castro-Gil M (2013) Urban wind energy exploitation systems: Behavior under multidirectional flow conditions—opportunities and challenges. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 24: 364–378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toja-Silva F, Peralta C, Lopez-Garcia O, et al. (2015a) On roof geometry for urban wind energy exploitation in high-rise buildings. Computation 3(2): 299–325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toja-Silva F, Peralta C, Lopez-Garcia O, et al. (2015b) Roof region dependent wind potential assessment with different RANS turbulence models. Journal of Wind Engineering and Industrial Aerodynamics 142: 258–271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Hooff T and Blocken B (2010) On the effect of wind direction and urban surroundings on natural ventilation of a large semi-enclosed stadium. Computers &amp; Fluids 39(7): 1146–1155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vardoulakis S, Fisher BEA, Pericleous K, et al. (2003) Modelling air quality in street canyons: A review. Atmospheric Environment 37: 155–182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wesseling P. (2001) Principles of Computational Fluid Dynamics. New York: Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yakhot V, Orszag SA, Thangam S, et al. (1992) Development of turbulence models for shear flows by a double expansion technique. Physics of Fluids A-Fluid Dynamics 4(7): 1510–1520.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yap CJ (1987) Turbulent heat and momentum transfer in recirculating and impinging flows. PhD Thesis, Faculty of Technology, University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
