<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Multi-Science Publishing Company</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i40151497</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">43749873</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Continuous Variable Speed Wind Turbine: Transmission Concept and Robust Control</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Moshe</given-names>
                  <surname>Idan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
                  <surname>Lior</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>151</fpage>
         <lpage>167</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/43749873"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper presents the theory and design of a novel hybrid mechanical-electrical variable speed wind turbine transmission, and discusses a robust control solution for optimal power output of the wind turbine equipped with such a transmission. The novel, planetary differential transmission would be driven by the variable speed rotor and controlled by a control system to ensure a constant speed of the main generator at a wide range of wind speed variations. Analysis shows that this would lead to an increase in the wind turbine energy output, estimated to be in the range of 15% to 20%, compared to a wind turbine with the same rotor and a fixed transmission. Using robust control design techniques, a single controller is synthesized for efficient operation over the entire anticipated wind speed range. The control system automatically varies the rotor speed to optimize its power output for slow wind speed variation and attenuates high frequency wind gust effects to reduce the resulting fatigue damage. Overall, the new concept provides a cost effective solution for variable speed wind turbine operation. The improved system performance is demonstrated using the results of a numerically simulated dynamic model of the proposed system.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d15e235a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e239" publication-type="other">
Balas, G. J., Doyle, J. C., Glover, K., Packard, A., and Smith, R. 1993. Analysis and
Synthesis Toolbox User's Guide. Mathworks Inc., Natick., Mass.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e249a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e253" publication-type="other">
Bedford, L.A.W., Simpson, PB., and Stevenson, W.G. 1985. The Orkeny 60 meter
Horizontal Axis Wind Turbine Generator - A Progress Report. Proceeding of the 7-th
BWEA Conference, MEP.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e266a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e270" publication-type="other">
Carlson, O., Grauers, A., Stevenson, J., and Larsson, A. 1994. A Comparison
Between Electrical Systems for Variable Speed Operation of Wind Turbines. Pages 500-
505 of: Proceeding ofEWEC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e283a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e287" publication-type="other">
Dijkstra, Sj., Bongers, P. M. M., and van Baars, G. E. 1994. Control of Wind Turbine
Systems to Reduce Vibrations and Fatigue Loading. Pages 425-429 of: Proceeding of
EWEC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e305" publication-type="other">
Divalentin, E. 1986. The Application of Broad Range Variable Speed for Wind Turbine
Enhancement. Proceeding ofEWEC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e319" publication-type="other">
Doyle, J. C., Packard, A., and Zhou, K. 1991. Review of LFTs, LMIs and μ. Pages 1227-
1232 of: IEEE Conference on Decision and Control, vol. 2. Brighton, England: IEEE.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e333" publication-type="other">
Freris, L. L. 1990. Wind Energy Conversion Systems. Prentice Hall. Pages 176-207.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e340a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e344" publication-type="other">
Henderson, G. M. 1992 (Aug.). Power Generating System. US Patent No. 5,140,170.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e351a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e355" publication-type="other">
Idan, M., Lior, D., and Shaviv, G.E. 1998 (Mar.). A Novel Variable Speed Wind Turbine
Concept and Control. Tech. rept. TAE818. Faculty of Aerospace Engineering, Technion
- Israel Institute of Technology.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e368a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e372" publication-type="other">
Idan, M., and Shaviv, G.E. 1996. Robust Control Design Strategy with Parameter
Dominated Uncertainty. AIAA Journal of Guidance, Control and Dynamics 19(3), 605-611.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e383a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e387" publication-type="other">
Miller, R. H. (Principal Investigator), Dugundji, J., Matrinez-Sanchez, M.,
Gohard, J., Chung, S., and Humes, T. 1978 (Sept.). Wind Energy Conversion, Volume
II - Aerodynamics of Horizontal Axis Wind Turbines. Tech. rept. ASRL TR-184-8.
(Aeroelastic and Structures Research Laboratory, Department of Aeronautics and
Astronautics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e406a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e410" publication-type="other">
Novak, P., Ekelund, T., Jovik, I., and Schmidtbauer, B. 1995. Modeling and Control
of Variable-Speed Wind-Turbine Drive-System Dynamics. IEEE Control Systems, 15(4),
28-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e423a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e427" publication-type="other">
Pierik, J. T. G., Veltman, A. T., De Haan, S. W. H., Smith, G. A., Infield, D. G., and
Simmons, A. D. 1994. A New Class of Converters for Variable Speed Wind Turbines.
Pages 534-540 of: Proceeding ofEWEC.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e440a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e444" publication-type="other">
Smith, G. A., and Nigim, K. A. 1981. Wind Energy Recovery by Static Scherbius
Induction Generator. IEE Proceedings, 128(6), 317-324.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e454a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e458" publication-type="other">
Twidell, J.W., Gauld, R., Ferni, D., and Burton, A. 1995. Recommissioning and
Operating the LSI 3MW Burgar Hill, Orkney, Wind Turbine Using Novel Crack Repair, p
279-284, Proc 17th BWEA Conference, MEP.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e471a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e475" publication-type="other">
Zhou, K., Doyle, J. C., and Glover, K. 1996. Robust and Optimal Control. Prentice
Hall. Chap. 8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


