<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169094</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Study of Potential Fuel Economy Technologies to Achieve CAFE 2025 Regulations using Fleet Simulation Modeling Software</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Porter</surname>
                  <given-names>Bernie</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Blaxill</surname>
                  <given-names>Hugh</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jariri</surname>
                  <given-names>Noor</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>MAHLE Powertrain LLC</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>July 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169081</issue-id>
         <fpage>352</fpage>
         <lpage>362</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169094"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The 2025 Corporate Average Fleet Economy (CAFE) fuel economy regulations are a significant challenge to the automotive industry. These regulations require dramatic increases in vehicle fleet fuel economy. This paper will identify and analyze a portfolio of technologies that have the potential to achieve the 2025 CAFE fuel economy targets, focusing on powertrain enhancements. The study uses a MAHLE Powertrain developed fleet modeling tool and a range of vehicle technologies and powertrain data taken from MAHLE's global research and development activities. Powertrain technologies considered include extreme engine downsizing, dilute combustion, friction reduction, hybridization, diesel and alternative fuels. The vehicle technologies analyzed include vehicle light weighting, reduced rolling resistance, advanced transmissions and improved aerodynamics.</p>
            <p>The results of this study suggest that in order to meet CAFE 2025 fleet fuel economy regulations, a combination of advanced powertrain, drivetrain and vehicle technology changes will be required.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brooke, L., “Mapping the Road to 54.5 MPG,” Automotive Engineering International, 24-31, Oct. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Federal Register, “2017 and Later Model Year Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards,” Vol. 77, No. 199, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ford Motor Company, “Vehicle Specifications,” http://www.ford.com, Aug. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blaxill, H., Reader, S., Mackay, S., Lerch, B. et al., “Development of a Friction Optimized Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1052, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1052.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lumsden, G., OudeNijeweme, D., Fraser, N., and Blaxill, H., “Development of a Turbocharged Direct Injection Downsizing Demonstrator Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1420-1432, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blaxill H; “Downsizing and Electrification”, Presentation at the UK National Automotive Conference 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Toulson, E., Huisjen, A., Chen, X. et al., “Spark Ignition and Pre-Chamber Turbulent Jet Ignition Combustion Visualization,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0823, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0823.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A., Blaxill, H., and Irlam, G., “Exhaust Gas Recirculation for Improved Part and Full Load Fuel Economy in a Turbocharged Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0047, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mahr, Dr B “Potential for EGR in Gasoline Engines” MAHLE Press Presentation 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor J “Application of EGR to the MAHLE Downsized Engine” Customer Presentation</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A. and Blaxill, H., “Lean Boost and External Exhaust Gas Recirculation for High Load Controlled Auto-Ignition,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3744, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3744.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bassett, M., Hall, J., OudeNijeweme, D., Darkes, D. et al., “The Development of a Dedicated Range Extender Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1002, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bishop, J., Nedungadi, A., Ostrowski, G., Surampudi, B. et al., “An Engine Start/Stop System for Improved Fuel Economy,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1777, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-1777.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“SAE Meeting: Vehicle Lightweighting Technology,” Volkswagen Group of America, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laxman, S., Iyengar, R., and Morgans, S., “Achieving Light-Weight Design of Automotive Bodies with Advanced High Strength Steels via Structural Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0795, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caffrey, C., Bolon, K., Harris, H., Kolwich, G. et al., “Cost- Effectiveness of a Lightweight Design for 2017-2020: An Assessment of a Midsize Crossover Utility Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0656, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0656.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guillou, M. and Bradley, C., “Fuel Consumption Testing to Verify the Effect of Tire Rolling Resistance on Fuel Economy,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0763, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0763.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
