<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jeducfina</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50000843</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Education Finance</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>University of Illinois Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00989495</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19446470</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">39</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i23597599</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23597603</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Public and Private Incentives for Investment in Higher Education: Are They Sufficient, Especially for Black Males?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Elizabeth N.</given-names>
                  <surname>Appiah</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>47</fpage>
         <lpage>72</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2013 Board of Directors of the Journal of Education Finance, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23597603"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The institutional costs of higher education have been rising. With diminishing public support per student, tuition and fees private costs have also been rising. But so have the real earnings of college graduates. Are there still sufficient incentives on efficiency grounds for additional public investment in higher education? And in particular, given that recent studies reveal that the costs to society of the inadequate education by black males (i.e., costs of reduced tax revenue as a result of lack of marketable job skills as well as their reliance on public assistance) are enormous, are there incentives for public support and/or other policy insights that would help address the problem? This paper estimates nationwide private and social rates of return computed by the 'full method' by degree for each race and sex, and then repeats this for a specific campus based on tracer study data. It controls for 'ability', and breaks these rates down by field of study. Mincer returns at the campus level are also computed. Private rates of return are the rates that discount the stream of net increments to earnings after taxes over the lifecycle attributable to education back to their present value and equate them to the private investment costs to students and their families. Therefore the private rates of return are the returns relevant to individual students and their families. Social rates of return are the rates that discount the stream of net earnings differential before taxes over the lifecycle back to their present value and set the result back to the total institutional and foregone earnings costs. These social rates are relevant to decisions by government about development policies. The article finds that both the private and social rates of return for black males are much lower than they are for whites or for black females at the bachelor's level and in each field. Higher 'ability' raises these rates, but its effect on the rates of return is only about 2—3 percentage points, and is not much different for other races and sexes. The larger propensity of black males to choose low net return fields is a major source of the insufficient economic incentives, and additional counseling of other policy approaches may be needed to help reduce the large social costs incurred from the inadequate education of this group.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d29e153a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e157" publication-type="other">
Arias, O., K. Hallock, and W. Sosa-Escudero. Individual heterogeneity in the returns to schooling:
Instrumental variables quantile regression using twins data, http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/
papers.cfm?abstract_id=238898 (accessed January 15, 2010).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e170a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e174" publication-type="other">
Arias, O., and W. W. McMahon. 2001. Dynamic rates of return to education in the United States.
Economics of Education Review 20 (2): 121-138.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e184a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e188" publication-type="other">
Ashenfelter, O. and A. Krueger. 1994. Estimates of the economic return to schooling from a new
sample of twins. American Economic Review, 84(5): 1157-1173.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e198a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e202" publication-type="other">
Ashenfelter, O and D. Zimmerman. 1997. Estimates of the returns to schooling from sibling data:
Fathers, sons, and brothers. The Review of Economics and Statistics 79:1-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e217" publication-type="other">
Ashenfelter, O. and C. Rouse. 1999. Schooling, intelligence, and income in America: Cracks in the
bell curve. National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER) Working Paper, No. 6902. http://
www.nber.org/papers/w6902. (accessed January 15, 2010).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e230a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e234" publication-type="other">
Averette, S. and S. Dalessandro. 2001. Racial and gender differences in the returns to 2-year and
4-year degrees. Education Economics 9(3): 281-292.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e244a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e248" publication-type="other">
Becker, G. S. 1957. The economics of discrimination. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e255a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e259" publication-type="other">
Behrman, j. R. and M. R. Rosenzweig. 1999. "Ability" bias in schooling returns and twins: A test
and new estimates. Economics of Education Review 18(2): 159-167.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e269a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e273" publication-type="other">
Bourne, C. and A. Dass. 2003. Private and social rates of return to higher education in science and
technology in a Caribbean economy. Education Economics 11(1): 1-10.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e283a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e287" publication-type="other">
Boarini, R., J. O. Martins, H. Strauss, C. de la Maisonneuve, and G. Nicoletti. 2008. Investment in
tertiary education: Main Determinants and implications for policy. CESifo Economic Studies,
54(2): 277-312.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e301a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e305" publication-type="other">
Cameron, S. and C. Taber 2000. Borrowing constraints and the returns to schooling. NBER Working
Paper No. 7761,1-55. http://www.nber.org/papers/w7761/ (accessed May 8, 2012).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e315a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e319" publication-type="other">
Card, D. 1999. The causal effect of education on earnings. In handbook of labor economics, Vol. 3.
ed. O. Ashenfelter and D. Card, 1801-1863, Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e329a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e333" publication-type="other">
Carnoy, M. As higher education expands, is it contributing to greater inequality? Journal of the
National Institute of Economic and Social Research, National Institute Economic Review No.
215, 1: R34-R47. http://ner.sagepub.com/ (accessed March 4, 2011).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e346a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e350" publication-type="other">
Carnoy, M. 1996. Race gender, and the role of education in earnings inequality: An introduction.
Economics of Education Review 15(3): 207-212.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e360a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e364" publication-type="other">
Choy, S. P. and M. Premo. 1995. Student Financing of Graduate and First-Professional Education
1992-93. U.S. Department of Education Office of Educational Research and Improvement,
NCES 96-235:1-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e377a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e381" publication-type="other">
Cohn, E. 1997. The rate of return to schooling in Canada. Journal of Education Finance 23(2):
193-206.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e392a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e396" publication-type="other">
Conrad, C. A. 2005. Changes in the labor market status of black women, 1960-2000. In African
Americans in the U.S. economy, ed. C. A. Conrad, J. Whitehead, P. Mason, and J. Stewart, 157-
162. USA: Rowman and Littlefield Publishers, Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e409a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e413" publication-type="other">
Cooper, S. T. and E. Cohn. 1997. Internal rates of return to college education in the United States
by sex and race. Journal of Education Finance 23:101-133.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e423a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e427" publication-type="other">
Davies S. and N. Guppy. 1997. Field of study, college selectivity and student inequalities in higher
education. Social Forces 75(4): 1417-1438.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e437a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e441" publication-type="other">
Gerald, D. E., and W. J. Hussar. 1998 and 2009. Projections of education statistics to2008; 2009.
National Center for Education Statistics, NCES 98-016 &amp; NCES 1999-038. Washington, DC:
U.S. Department of Education.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e454a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e458" publication-type="other">
Grogger, J., and E. Eide. 1995. Changes in college skills and the rise of the college wage premium.
Journal of Human Resources 30: 280-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e468a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e472" publication-type="other">
Hiñes, F., L. Tweeten, and M. Redfern. 1970. Social and private rates of return to investment in
schooling by race—sex groups and regions. The Journal of Human Resources 3: 318-340.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e483a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e487" publication-type="other">
JBHE. Holding a four-year college degree brings blacks close to economic parity with whites.
The Journal of Blacks in Higher Education, http://www.jbhe.com/news_views/47_four-year_
collegedegrees.html (accessed April 21, 2012).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e500a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e504" publication-type="other">
Kimmel, J. 1994. Rural wages and returns to education: Differences between whites, black and
American Indians. Economics of Education Review 16 (1): 81-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e514a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e518" publication-type="other">
Levin, H. M., C. Belfield, R Muennig, and C. Rouse. 2007. The public returns to public educational
investments in African American males. Economics of Education Review 26 (6): 699-708.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e532" publication-type="other">
Levin, H. M (chair) 2007. The social costs of inadequate education. In The price we pay: Economic
and social consequences of inadequate education, ed. C. Belfield and H. M. Levin, Washington
DC: Brookings Institution Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e545a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e549" publication-type="other">
Mason, P. L. 2005. Persistent racial discrimination in the labor market. In African Americans in
the U.S. economy, ed. C. A. Conrad, J. Whitehead, P. Mason, and J. Stewart, 141-151. USA:
Rowman and Littlefield Publishers, Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e562a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e566" publication-type="other">
McMahon, W. W. 2009. Appendix A: "Ability bias" in higher learning, greater good: The private and
social benefits of higher education, Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e577a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e581" publication-type="other">
Mincer, J. 1974. Schooling, experience, and earnings. New York: Columbia University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e588a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e592" publication-type="other">
National Center for Education Statistics (NCES), 1987-88 and 1997-98. Average graduate and
first-professional tuition and required fees in institutions of higher education, table 313. The
Condition of Education (1998). U.S. Department of Education, Office of Education Research
and Improvement.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e608a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e612" publication-type="other">
Niemi Jr., A. W. 1975. Racial differences in returns to educational investment in the South. The
American Journal of Economics and Sociology 34(1): 87-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e622a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e626" publication-type="other">
Pager, D. and H. Shepherd. 2008. The sociology of discrimination: Racial discrimination in
employment, housing, credit, and consumer markets. Annu. Rev. Sociol, 34:181-209.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e636a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e640" publication-type="other">
Psacharopoulos, G., and H. Patrinos. 2004. Returns to investment in education: A further update.
Education Economics 12(2): 111-134.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e654" publication-type="other">
Stokes, A., and S. Wright. 2008. Measuring the social rate of return in public sector labor markets.
Journal of Business and Economic Research 6(5): 1-16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e665a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e669" publication-type="other">
Suh, S. 2000. Women's perspectives of work-place discrimination: Impacts of racial group, gender,
and class. In Prismatic metropolis: Inequality in Los Angeles, ed. L. D. Bob, M. L. Oliver, J. H.
Johnson Jr., and A. Valenzuela Jr. New York: Russell Sage Foundation Twice as many black
women earn college degrees as black men study reveals. In Jet, 1997. Johnson Publishing Co,
91(18): 22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e688a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e692" publication-type="other">
U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis. Gross domestic product: Implicit price deflator, 2005=100,
seasonally adjusted. U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Economic Analysis Website.
http://www.stls.frb.org/fred/data/gdp/gdpdef/ (accessed August 16, 2011).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e705a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e709" publication-type="other">
U.S. Census Bureau. 1993, 1997, and 2008. Current Population Survey 1993, 1997, and PINC-04.
Educational Attainment— People 18 Years Old and Over, by Total Money Earnings in 2008,
Work Experience in 2008 Age, Race, Hispanic Origin, and Sex. U.S. Census Bureau website.
Department of Commerce, Washington, DC. http://www.census.gov/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e725a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e729" publication-type="other">
UI Office for Planning and Budgeting. Current Funds Revenue by Source, University of llinois at
Urbana-Champaign and University of Illinois at Central Administration 1988-1989. Urbana,
Illinois.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e742a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e746" publication-type="other">
UI Office for Planning and Budgeting. Current Funds Expenditures and Transfers at the University
of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign and University of Illinois at Central Administration 1988-
1989. Urbana, Illinois.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e759a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e763" publication-type="other">
UI Office for Planning and Budgeting. 1998. Unit Cost Study for the University of Illinois, 1988.
Prepared in 1998 by the University Office for Planning and Budgeting. Urbana, Illinois.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e774a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e778" publication-type="other">
UI Office for Planning and Budgeting. Tracer study for the University of Illinois 1988 Graduates
in 1993 and 1997. Prepared by the University of Illinois Office for Planning and Budgeting.
Urbana, Illinois.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e791a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e795" publication-type="other">
UI Office of Admissions &amp; Records. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Student Guide
Timetable, 1988-1993. Produced for the Office of Admissions &amp; Records by the Office of
Publications &amp; Marketing. Urbana, Illinois.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e808a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e812" publication-type="other">
UI Office of Admissions and Records. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Students'
Records, 1984-1988. Urbana, Illinois.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e822a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e826" publication-type="other">
Vedder, R. 2009. Not all degrees are equal. The New York Times, June 39,2009, The New York Times
Co. http://roomfordebate.blogs.nytimes.com/2009/06/30/what-is-a-masters-degree-worth/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e836a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e840" publication-type="other">
Welch, F. 1973. Black-white differences in returns to schooling. Am. Econ. Rev. 63:893-907.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e847a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e851" publication-type="other">
Weston, L. P. 2009. Degrees that don't pay off. New York Times, June 39,2009, The New York Times
Co. http://roomfordebate.blogs.nytimes.com/2009/06/30/what-is-a-masters-degree-worth/.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e862a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e866" publication-type="other">
Wolfe, B. and R. Haveman. Accounting for the social and non-market benefits of education, http://
www.oecd.org/dataoecd/5/19/1825109.pdf(accessed May 10, 2012).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e876a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e880" publication-type="other">
Yong, Y. K, T. M. Heng, S. M. Thangavelu, and J. Wong. 2007. Premium on fields of study: The
returns to higher education in Singapore. Working paper no. 2007/3. MOM website: http://
www.mom.gov.sg/mrsd/publication (accessed May 12, 2012).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


