<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466863</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466867</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Learning About CEO Ability and Stock Return Volatility</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Yihui</given-names>
                  <surname>Pan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Tracy Yue</given-names>
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michael S.</given-names>
                  <surname>Weisbach</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1623</fpage>
         <lpage>1666</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466867"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Consistent with predictions from a stylized Bayesian learning model stock return volatility declines with CEO tenure in a convex manner, even for CEOs whose appointments occur for exogenous reasons. The decline is faster when there is higher uncertainty about the CEO's ability when there is more transparency about the firm's prospects, and when CEO ability is more important in value creation. We quantify the importance of uncertainty about CEO ability relative to the firm's fundamental cash flow uncertainty in contributing to stock return volatility, highlighting the importance of management in creating value.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d926031e248a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e255" publication-type="other">
In addition, several studies apply the learning framework to understand managerial incentives in the money
management industry (e.g., Berk and Green 2004; Chung et al. 2012; and Lim, Sensoy, and Weisbach 2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e265a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e272" publication-type="other">
We can also obtain a result similar to Equation (6) in a two-state continuous time Bayesian learning model,
in which CEO ability is assumed to be high with probability 7rt and low with probability (1 -7rt). With this
distributional assumption, an equation comparable to Equation (6) holds exactly. We focus on the case in which
ability is distributed normally because the posterior variance is characterized by the formula presented in Equation
(5) and is a monotonie function of time, which provides cleaner guidance for the empirical analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e291a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e298" publication-type="other">
The model presented here assumes that CEO ability a is constant over time so that the uncertainty about it 8f
converges to zero. If CEO ability changes over time, then the uncertainty about it converges to a stationary level
above zero (e.g., Holmström 1999). In this case, the stock return volatility will always be above the level of
fundamental volatility.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e314a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e321" publication-type="other">
The model in Pastor and Veronesi (2003) endogenizes the discount rate. In that model, learning affects the firm's
idiosyncratic risk, but not its systematic risk and the expected rate of return. Our simpler model with constant
discount rate cannot speak to this point. However, we do provide empirical evidence suggesting that systematic
risk does not change with CEO tenure in a similar way to idiosyncratic risk.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e338a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e345" publication-type="other">
This fraction is consistent with those reported in other studies such as Parrino (1997), Murphy and Zabojnik
(2007), and Cremers and Grinstein (Forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e355a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e362" publication-type="other">
See Warner, Watts, and Wrack (1988) or Weisbach (1988) for more detail. Schwartz-Ziv and Weisbach (2013)
use private data on board meetings to document details of specific cases in which CEOs are forced out of their
jobs, but for which one could never tell so using publicly available information.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e375a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e382" publication-type="other">
We thank Edward Fee, Charles Hadlock, and Joshua Pierce for kindly providing us with the classification of
illness, death related, and outright forced turnovers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e392a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e399" publication-type="other">
The total number of turnovers in our sample period is 1,873 (see Panel A of Table 1). However, there are 171
turnovers with insufficient pre-turnover performance or volatility data, and thus are excluded from the analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e409a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e416" publication-type="other">
The small number of outright forced turnovers is consistent with the institutional evidence that firings of CEOs
are relatively rare events. Using an interview-based approach, Vancil 1987, 82-83) estimates that only 10% of
CEOs during 1960 to 1984 left involuntarily.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e429a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e436" publication-type="other">
We use both the information from Capital IQ and news searches to identify the key announcement dates for
the 875 CEO turnovers since 2001 in our sample. These sources provide 700 departure announcements and 851
appointment announcements. In a number of cases, the incoming CEO is the earliest CEO that we can identify
in the firm's history, which is why there are fewer departure announcements than appointment announcements.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e453a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e460" publication-type="other">
All the CEOs in our sample have at least three years of tenure. Thus, the decrease in stock volatility is not driven
by CEOs in high-volatility firms being fired quickly. We have also estimated these equations including CEOs
with tenure shorter than thirty-six months, and the results are similar to those reported in Table 2. For example,
the coefficient estimate on Tenure is -0.593 (p-value &lt;0.001) and that on Tenure2 is 0.137 (p-value &lt;0.001)
using the specification of Model (3) of Table 2, Panel B.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e479a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e488" publication-type="other">
In the polynomial specification with option-implied volatility or idiosyncratic volatility as the dependent variable,
the fitted value of volatility (ignoring the controls) is not necessarily monotonically declining with tenure in the
third year. This is likely due to the noise from an imperfect measurement process. The spline specification reported
in Panel A of Table 2 yields a convex and monotonie decline of volatility over a CEO's first three years in office.
Therefore, in an unreported robustness check, we put restrictions on the coefficient estimation in the polynomial
specification, so that volatility monotonically changes with Tenure throughout the first three years. The estimates
from the constrained polynomial specification confirm that there is a convex and monotonie decline of volatility
over CEO tenure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e517a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e524" publication-type="other">
The estimated volatility of dividend growth rate ranges from 0.23 to 0.28, depending on the definition of dividend-
paying firm and the time period that we use for the estimation of a.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e534a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e541" publication-type="other">
The estimated high importance of the CEO is consistent with Bennedsen, Pérez-Gonzâlez, and Wolfenzon
(2013), who find that a ten-day hospital stay of the CEO reduces firm profitability by 4%.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e551a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e558" publication-type="other">
Note that this exercise is different from that in Section 4.3 (Table 4) where we control for the direct impact of
post-turnover actions on the level of volatility rather than the impact of the information content of these actions
on the volatility-tenure slope.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e571a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e578" publication-type="other">
News related to capital expenditures mainly come from the category "Business Expansion" in Capital IQ (e.g.,
opening a new store or a new office). The M&amp;A announcements come from SDC Platinum.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d926031e589a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d926031e596" publication-type="other">
A detailed definition is at http://mba.tuck.dartmouth.edu/pages/faculty/ken.french/data_library.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d926031e612a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e616" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., R. J. Hodrick, Y. Xing, and X. Zhang. 2006. The cross-section of volatility and expected returns. Journal
of Finance 61:259-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e626a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e630" publication-type="other">
Bennedsen, M., F. Pérez-Gonzâlez, K. Nielsen, and D. Wolfenzon. 2007. Inside the family firm: The role of
families in succession decisions and performance. Quarterly Journal of Economics 122:647-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e644" publication-type="other">
Bennedsen, M., F. Pérez-Gonzâlez, and D. Wolfenzon. 2013. Estimating the value of the boss: Evidence from
CEO hospitalization events. Working Paper, Stanford University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e658" publication-type="other">
Berk, J., and R. Green. 2004. Mutual fund flows and performance in rational markets. Journal of Political
Economy 112:1269-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e669a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e673" publication-type="other">
Bertrand, M., and A. Schoar. 2003. Managing with style: The effect of managers on firm policies. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 118:1169-1208.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e687" publication-type="other">
Boot, A. W. A. 1992. Why hang on to losers? Divestitures and takeovers. Journal of Finance 47:1401-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e694a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e698" publication-type="other">
Bushman, R., Z. Dai, and X. Wang. 2010. Risk and CEO turnover. Journal of Financial Economics 96:381-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e705a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e709" publication-type="other">
Chung, J., B. A. Sensoy, L. H. Stern, and M. S. Weisbach. 2012. Pay for performance from future fund flows:
The case of private equity. Review of Financial Studies 25:3259-3304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e719a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e723" publication-type="other">
Clayton, M., J. Hartzell, and J. Rosenberg. 2005. The impact of CEO turnover on equity volatility. Journal of
Business 78:1779-1808.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e733a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e737" publication-type="other">
Cox, D. R. 1972. Regression models and life tables (with discussion). Journal of the Royal Statistical Society,
Series B, 34:187-220.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e748a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e752" publication-type="other">
Cremers, M., and Y. Grinstein. Forthcoming. Does the Market for CEO Talent Explain Controversial CEO Pay
Practices? Review of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e762a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e766" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. F., and K. R. French. 1993. Common risk factors in the returns on stocks and bonds. Journal of Financial
Economics 33:3-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e776a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e780" publication-type="other">
Fee, C. E., C. J. Hadlock, and J. R. Pierce. 2013. Managers with and without style: Evidence using exogenous
variation. Review of Financial Studies 26:567-601.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e790a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e794" publication-type="other">
Friedman, J. H. 1991. Multivariate adaptive regression splines. Annals of Statistics 19:1-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e801a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e805" publication-type="other">
Gibbons, R., and K. J. Murphy. 1992. Optimal incentive contracts in the presence of career concerns: Theory
and evidence. Journal of Political Economy 100:468-505.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e815a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e819" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E. 2005. Trends in corporate governance. Journal of Finance 60:2351-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e827a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e831" publication-type="other">
Hermalin, B. E., and M. S. Weisbach. 1998. Endogenously chosen boards of directors and their monitoring of
the CEO. American Economic Review 88:96-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e841a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e845" publication-type="other">
. 2012. Information disclosure and corporate governance. Journal of Finance 67:195-233.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e852a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e856" publication-type="other">
Holmström, B. 1999. Managerial incentive problems: A dynamic perspective. Review of Economic Studies
66:169-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e866a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e870" publication-type="other">
Johnson, B. W., R. Magee, N. Nagarajan, and H. Newman. 1985. An analysis of the stock price reaction to
sudden executive death: Implications for the management labor market. Journal of Accounting and Economics
7:151-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e883a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e887" publication-type="other">
Karpoff, J. M., A. Koester, D. S. Lee, and G S. Martin. 2014. An analysis of database challenges in financial
misconduct research. Working Paper, University of Washington.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e901" publication-type="other">
Kanodia, C., R. Bushman, and J. Dickhaut. 1989. Escalation errors and the sunk cost effect: An explanation
based on reputation and information asymmetries. Journal of Accounting Research 21:59-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e912a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e916" publication-type="other">
Li, M., Y. Lu, and G Phillips. 2014. CEOs and the product market: When are powerful CEOs beneficial? Working
Paper, University of Southern California.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e926a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e930" publication-type="other">
Lim, J., B. A. Sensoy, and M. S. Weisbach. 2015. Indirect incentives of hedge fund managers. Working Paper,
Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e940a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e944" publication-type="other">
Naveen, L. 2006. Organizational complexity and succession planning. Journal of Financial and Quantitative
Analysis 41:661—83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e954a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e958" publication-type="other">
Milbourn, T. 2003. CEO reputation and stock-based compensation. Journal of Financial Economics 68:233-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e965a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e969" publication-type="other">
Murphy, K. J., and J. Zabojnfk. 2007. Managerial capital and the market for CEOs. Working Paper, University
of Southern California.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e979a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e983" publication-type="other">
Murphy, K. J., and J. L. Zimmerman. 1993. Financial performance surrounding CEO turnover. Journal of
Accounting and Economics 16:273-315.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e994a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e998" publication-type="other">
Pan, Y., T. Y. Wang, and M. S. Weisbach. 2014. CEO investment cycles. Working Paper, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1005a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1009" publication-type="other">
Parrino, R. 1997. CEO turnover and outside succession: A cross-sectional analysis. Journal of Financial
Economics 46:165-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1019a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1023" publication-type="other">
Pastor, L., and P. Veronesi. 2009. Learning in financial markets. Annual Review of Financial Economics
1:361-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1033a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1037" publication-type="other">
. 2003. Stock valuation and learning about profitability. Journal of Finance 58:1749-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1044a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1048" publication-type="other">
Schwartz-Ziv, M., and M. S. Weisbach. 2013. What do boards really do? Evidence from minutes of board
meetings. Journal of Financial Economics 108:349-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1058a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1062" publication-type="other">
Taylor, L. 2013. CEO wage dynamics: Estimates from a learning model. Journal of Financial Economics
108:79-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1073a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1077" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Why are CEOs rarely fired? Evidence from structural estimation. Journal of Finance 65:2051-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1084a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1088" publication-type="other">
Timmermann, A. G 1993. How learning in financial markets generates excess volatility and predictability in
stock returns. Quarterly Journal of Economics 108:1135-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1098a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1102" publication-type="other">
Vancil, R. 1987. Passing the baton: Managing the process of CEO succession. Boston: Harvard Business School
Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1112a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1116" publication-type="other">
Warner, J., R. L. Watts, and K. H. Wruck. 1988. Stock prices and top-management changes. Journal of Financial
Economics 20:461-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1126a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1130" publication-type="other">
Weisbach, M. S. 1995. CEO turnover and the firm's investment decisions. Journal of Financial Economics
37:155-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d926031e1140a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d926031e1144" publication-type="other">
. 1988. Outside directors and CEO turnover. Journal of Financial Economics 20:431-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


