<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440108</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Value of Teachers' Pensions in England and Wales</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
                  <surname>Disney</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Carl</given-names>
                  <surname>Emmerson</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Gemma</given-names>
                  <surname>Tetlow</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">31</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440103</issue-id>
         <fpage>121</fpage>
         <lpage>150</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2010</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440108"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The paper examines in detail the value of pension provision to teachers in the public sector in England and Wales, comparing pension accrual under both the pre- and the post-2007 schemes. We find that, at the median, pension accruals under the old scheme rules were worth 14.7 per cent of current salary to members, while if the new scheme rules were applied to all current members this would fall to 11.2 per cent. We find that this reduction in generosity is more than sufficient to offset the increase in generosity implied by rising life expectancies over the last quarter of a century. In addition, we show how the estimates depend on both the shape of the underlying age–earnings profile and the headline pay award. We find that the value of the new scheme rules to Teachers' Pension Scheme (TPS) members is similar to the value of the defined contribution pension offered to civil servants, but worth more than a simple, example, private sector defined contribution scheme.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d43e248a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e255" publication-type="other">
Submitted February 2009.
The authors are grateful to the Office of Manpower Economics for funding for this project as well as to
the Economic and Social Research Council for co-funding through the ESRC Centre for the
Microeconomic Analysis of Public Policy at IFS (RES-544-28-5001) and for funding the project 'Pension
Wealth, Early Retirement and Job Mobility', reference RES-000-23-1149, from which this research draws
much. The authors also thank Paul Johnson, David Miner, Steve Palmer and Grant Whitfield for useful
advice and assistance, the Office for National Statistics for allowing the authors to access the ASHE/NES
data and Richard Howe of the Department for Children, Schools and Families for supplying information
from the Database of Teacher Records. Responsibility for the interpretation of the data, and any
remaining errors, remains the authors' alone.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e290a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e297" publication-type="other">
Data from the Office for National Statistics suggest that in 2007 around three-quarters (76.5 per cent)
of public sector employees and one-sixth (17.0 per cent) of private sector employees were members of an
occupational DB plan. See Bozio and Johnson (2008, table 8.3) for more details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e310a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e317" publication-type="other">
See 'Cameron hints at phasing out public sector pensions', Financial Times, 26 November 2008
(http://www.ft.eom/cms/s/0/cb9bc356-bcl0-lldd-80e9-0000779fdl8c.html). For the latest official
estimates, see HM Treasury (2009, box 6.B, p. 49). For a discussion of both official and alternative
estimates, see, for example, Chote, Emmerson and Tetlow (2008, section 3.3), Hawksworth (2006),
Record (2006 and 2008) and Watson Wyatt (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e336a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e343" publication-type="other">
This is often referred to as a 'normal retirement age', but it is the age at which an individual stops
contributing to the pension plan, which is not necessarily the age of retirement. It is also not the state
pension age, which is the age from which the state retirement pension is payable regardless of when, or
whether, the individual retired.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e360a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e369" publication-type="other">
Sources: House of Commons Hansard Written Answers, 25 Oct. 2005 column 314W
(http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200506/cmhansrd/vo051025/text/51025w30.htm), 11 Nov.
2005 column 776W (http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200506/cmhansrd/vo0511U/text/
51111w04.htm) and 25 June 2007 column 389W (http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200607/
cmhansrd/cm070625/text/70625w0089.htm); evidence to the Treasury Select Committee by the then
Chancellor of the Exchequer, Gordon Brown, on 8 Dec. 2005 (http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/
cm200506/cmselect/cmtreasy/739/5120807.htm). For a discussion, see, for example, Bozio and Johnson
(2008, section 8.4) and Pensions Policy Institute (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e398a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e405" publication-type="other">
For analysis of the impact of teachers' pay on teacher retention in the UK, see Dolton and van der
Klaauw (1995 and 1999). For analysis of the impact of teacher quality on pupil outcomes, see, for
example, Flanushek et al. (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e418a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e425" publication-type="other">
he method we use to value pension accrual in this paper most closely resembles what actuaries refer
to as the Current Unit Method.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e435a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e442" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Hewitt Bacon &amp; Woodrow Ltd (2007) and Watson Wyatt (2008a).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e449a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e456" publication-type="other">
In the public pension context, see, for example, Watson Wyatt (2007 and 2008a).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e463a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e470" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Watson Wyatt (2008a, appendix A).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e478a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e485" publication-type="other">
Prior to 1 January 2007, while full-time teachers were automatically enrolled, part-time teachers had
to make an active decision to join the TPS. Under the Pensions Bill 2007-08 (http://
services.parliament.uk/bills/2007-08/pensions.html), which received Royal Assent on 26 November 2008,
the majority of employees aged between 22 and the state pension age are to be automatically enrolled into
a private pension arrangement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e504a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e511" publication-type="other">
Source: Teachers' Pension Scheme, 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e518a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e525" publication-type="other">
Under the new rules, the annual pension is reduced by £1 for every £12 taken in lump sum. Someone
choosing to take a lump sum worth 3/80ths under the new arrangements will find their pension reduced to
l/60th less (3/80)x( 1/12), which is equal to (13/12)x( 1/80) - i.e. greater than l/80th.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e538a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e545" publication-type="other">
Prior to April 1997, ill-health retirement could be claimed as long as an individual was unable to
teach for the foreseeable future. This changed from April 1997 so that an individual now needs to prove
that they are permanently unable to teach. Around twice as many teachers in England received an ill-
health pension in the years immediately before this reform than did immediately after this reform (see
Bowers and Mclver (2000, figure 1) and HM Treasury (2000, annex E)). From November 1997, local
education authorities (LEAs) were made to finance part of the additional cost of retirements prior to age
60. This change was associated with the number of teachers taking early retirement falling by four-fifths
(see Smithers and Robinson (2000, chart 7.1)). Actuarially reduced pensions were introduced from 31
March 2001. The findings of the latest official actuarial review of the TPS - which includes estimates
based on both the old and the new scheme rules — can be found in Government Actuary's Department
(2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e583a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e590" publication-type="other">
We limit our sample to the years 1996 to 2006 because prior to 1996 it is not possible to identify
accurately (and therefore exclude from our sample) those teachers who were employed outside the public
sector.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e603a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e610" publication-type="other">
Disney, Emmerson and Tetlow (2009b, appendix B) provide descriptive statistics of the distribution
of hourly pay of teachers in the ASHE/NES revalued to 2006 prices, in the aggregate and also broken
down by sex and school sector. In addition, figure 3.2 of that paper provides a comparison of the average
year-on-year increases with the pay awards from the School Teachers' Review Body.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e627a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e634" publication-type="other">
See Dolton and Chung (2004) and Dolton (2005).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e641a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e648" publication-type="other">
We also experimented with controlling for region of employment but the results were not sensitive to
the inclusion of this.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e658a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e665" publication-type="other">
This is because both 0.0292 / (2X0.0007) and 0.0299 / (2x0.0007) are approximately equal to 21, and,
since the regressor is age less 30, this implies a turning point in log earnings with respect to age around
age 51.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e678a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e685" publication-type="other">
Full results from the regressions with complete age dummies and with just a linear age term are
available from the authors on request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e695a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e702" publication-type="other">
Cohort life expectancy by age and sex is taken from the latest (2006) UK projections from the
Government Actuary's Department (http://www.gad.gov.uk/Demography Data/Life Tables/Period_and
cohort_eol.html).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e715a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e722" publication-type="other">
in the period 2002-05, life expectancy at age 65 among men in social class II was 18.0 years
compared with 16.6 years overall, and for women in social class II life expectancy was 21.0 years
compared with 19.4 years overall. These data are taken from an update to Donkin, Goldblatt and Lynch
(2002).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e739a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e746" publication-type="other">
See Disney, Emmerson and Tetlow (2009b, figure 3.4 and surrounding text) for more details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e753a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e760" publication-type="other">
If all pension plan members experience zero or positive real earnings growth each year, the
assumption will be equivalent to the measure of 'final salary' that would actually be used by the plan.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e770a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e777" publication-type="other">
Estimates broken down by school sector are available on request.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e784a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e791" publication-type="other">
The official estimates use the AA corporate bond rate, which for 31 March 2008 was 2'/2 per cent.
Source: HM Treasury, 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e801a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e808" publication-type="other">
A rate of 314 per cent is recommended by the Treasury for discounting the future costs and benefits
of potential public sector projects - see HM Treasury (2006, annex 6) - and up to 2005 was also the rate
that was used by GAD to assess unfunded public sector pension liabilities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e821a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e828" publication-type="other">
Disney, Emmerson and Tetlow (2009b, appendix A) present sensitivity analysis of these figures to
the assumed discount rate.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e839a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e846" publication-type="other">
Precise details of the core employer contribution for members of different ages in the Civil Service
Partnership pension accounts are provided in Disney, Emmerson and Tetlow (2009b, table B.6).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e856a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e863" publication-type="other">
This is not the same as the amount the employer put in (i.e. 10 per cent) for a number of reasons:
first, adverse selection in the annuities market, which means that those who purchase annuities have, on
average, longer life expectancies than other members of their cohort; second, even if the gross investment
return were the same as the discount rate, the value of pension accrual would still be lower than the
employer contribution due to administrative costs, and profits, of those providing the pension; third, we
have assumed a certain date of death. In reality, members of DC pensions are likely to be uncertain about
their true life expectancy and, if they are risk averse, they may value the insurance against living a long
time that is provided by annuity income and therefore still prefer to receive a pension accrual worth 7.1
per cent rather than a larger immediate increase in salary.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e895a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e902" publication-type="other">
These profiles are taken from Disney, Emmerson and Tetlow (2009a).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d43e918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e922" publication-type="other">
Bowers, T. and Mclver, M. (2000), III Health Retirement and Absenteeism amongst Teachers,
Research Report no. 235, London: Department for Education and Employment
(http://www.dcsf.gov.uk/research/data/uploadfiles/RR235.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e935a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e941" publication-type="other">
Bozio, A. and Johnson, P. (2008), 'Public sector pay and pensions', in R. Chote, C.
Emmerson, D. Miles and J. Shaw (eds), The IFS Green Budget: January 2008,
Commentary no. 104, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/
publications/4112).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e957a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e961" publication-type="other">
Cabinet Office (2000), Winning the Generation Game: Improving Opportunities for People
Aged 50-65 in Work and Community Activity, Cabinet Office Performance and Innovation
Unit report, April (http://www.cabinetoffice.gov.uk/media/cabinetoffice/strategy/assets/
generation.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e977a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e981" publication-type="other">
Chote, R., Emmerson, C. and Tetlow, G. (2008), 'The fiscal rules and policy framework', in
R. Chote, C. Emmerson, D. Miles and J. Shaw (eds), The IFS Green Budget: January
2008, Commentary no. 104, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/
publications/4112).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e998a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1002" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions (2002), Simplicity, Security and Choice: Working and
Saving for Retirement, Cm. 5677, London: The Stationery Office (http://
www. dwp. gov.uk/ docs/gp.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1015a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1019" publication-type="other">
— (2003), Simplicity, Security and Choice: Working and Saving for Retirement — Action on
Occupational Pensions, Cm. 5835, London: The Stationery Office (http://
www.dwp.gov.uk/docs/simplicity-security-and-choice.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1032a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1036" publication-type="other">
Disney, R., Emmerson, C. and Tetlow, G. (2009a), 'What is a public sector pension worth?',
Economic Journal, vol. 119, pp. F517-35 (DOI: 10.111 l/j,1468-0297.2009.02320.x).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1046a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1050" publication-type="other">
—, — and — (2009b), 'The value of teachers' pensions', Institute for Fiscal Studies, Working
Paper no. 09/07 (http://www.ifs.org.uk/publications/4452).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1060a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1064" publication-type="other">
Dolton, P. (2005), The Labour Market for Teachers: A Policy Perspective, London: Office of
Manpower Economics (http://www.ome.uk.com/STRB_Research_Documents.aspx).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1074a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1078" publication-type="other">
— and Chung, T-P. (2004), 'The rate of return to teaching: how does it compare to other
graduate jobs?', National Institute Economic Review, no. 190, October, pp. 89-103
(http://ner.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/190/1/89).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1092a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1096" publication-type="other">
— and van der Klaauw, W. (1995), 'Leaving teaching in the UK: a duration analysis',
Economic Journal, vol. 105, pp. 431^14 (http://www.jstor.org/stable/2235502).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1106a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1110" publication-type="other">
— and — (1999), 'The turnover of teachers: a competing risks explanation', Review of
Economics and Statistics, vol. 81, pp. 543-50 (http://www.mitpressjournals.org/doi/abs/
10.1162/003465399558292).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1123a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1127" publication-type="other">
Donkin, A., Goldblatt, P. and Lynch, K. (2002), 'Inequalities in life expectancy by social
class, 1972-1999', Health Statistics Quarterly, 15, Autumn 2002, pp. 5-14; updated to
2005 in News Release, 24 October 2007 (http://www.statistics.gov.uk/statbase/
Product.asp?vlnk=8460).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1143a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1147" publication-type="other">
Government Actuary's Department (2006), The Teachers' Pension Scheme (England and
Wales) Actuarial Review as at 31 March 2004 (http://www.teachernet.gov.uk/_doc/
10670/TPS%20Actuarial%20Valuation%20Report%20November%202006.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1160a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1164" publication-type="other">
Hanushek, E. A., Kain, J. F., O'Brien, D. M. and Rivkin, S. G. (2005), 'The market for
teacher quality', National Bureau of Economic Research, Working Paper no. 11154
(http://papers.nber.org/papers/wl 1154).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1177a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1181" publication-type="other">
Hawksworth, J. (2006), Public Service Pension Liabilities and the Fiscal Rides, London:
PriceWaterhouseCoopers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1192a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1196" publication-type="other">
Flewitt Bacon &amp; Woodrow Ltd (2007), Principal Civil Service Pension Scheme: Analysis of
Scheme Experience between 1 April 2003 and 31 March 2007, London
(http://www.civilservice.gov.uk/Assets/Analysis%20of%20scheme%20experience%20
2007_tcm6-3873.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1212a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1216" publication-type="other">
FIM Treasury (2000), Review of III Health Retirement in the Public Sector, London: HMT
(http://archive.treasury.gov.uk/pdf/2000/ill_healthl 10700.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1226a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1230" publication-type="other">
— (2006), Green Book, London: HMT (http://www.hm-treasury.gov.uk/data_greenbook_
index.htm).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1240a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1244" publication-type="other">
— (2008), Public Expenditure System: Guidance on Managing the Change in Discount Rates
for Pension Liabilities, London: HMT.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1254a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1258" publication-type="other">
— (2009), Long-Term Public Finance Report: An Analysis of Fiscal Sustainability, London:
HMT (http://www.hm-treasury.gov.uk/prebud_pbr09_longtermfinances.htm).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1268a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1272" publication-type="other">
Pensions Policy Institute (2005), Public Sector Pension Reform: What Happened?, Briefing
Note no. 25, London: PPI (http://www.pensionspolicyinstitute.org.uk/
uploadeddocuments/PPI_Briefing_Note_25.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1286a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1290" publication-type="other">
Peters, M., Hutchings, M., Edwards, G., Minty, S., Seeds, K. and Smart, S. (2008),
Behavioural Impact of Changes in the Teachers Pension Scheme, Research Report no.
DCSF-RR024, London: Department for Children, Schools and Families (http://
www.dcsf.gov.uk/rsgateway/DB/RRP/u015010/index.shtml).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1306a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1310" publication-type="other">
Record, N. (2006), Sir Humphrey's Legacy: Facing up to the Cost of Public Sector Pensions,
London: Institute of Economic Affairs (http://www.iea.org.uk/record.jsp?type=book&amp;ID=
390).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1323a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1327" publication-type="other">
— (2008), Sir Humphrey's Legacy: An Update, London: Institute of Economic Affairs (http://
www.iea.org.uk/files/upld-release 136pdf7.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1337a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1341" publication-type="other">
Smithers, A. and Robinson, P. (2000), Attracting Teachers: Past Patterns, Present Policies,
Future Prospects, Liverpool: Carmichael Press (http://www.buckingham.ac.uk/education/
research/ceer/pdfs/attractingteachers.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1354a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1358" publication-type="other">
Teachers' Pension Scheme (2007), Teachers ' Pension Scheme (England and Wales) Resource
Accounts 2006-07, London: The Stationery Office (http://www.official-
documents.gov.uk/document/hc0607/hc08/0872/0872.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1371a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1375" publication-type="other">
Watson Wyatt (2006), 'Unfunded public sector pension liabilities now close to £1,000
billion', Press Release, 8 March (http://www.watsonwyatt.com/news/press.asp?ID=
15784).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1389a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1393" publication-type="other">
— (2007), Comparative Valuation of the Armed Forces ' Pension Schemes 2006 (http://
www.ome.uk.com/AFPRB_Research_Reports.aspx).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1403a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1407" publication-type="other">
— (2008a), Report on the Comparison of the Pension Schemes of the Senior Civil Service,
Judiciary and Senior Military (http://www.ome.uk.com/SSRB_Research_Papers.aspx).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1417a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1421" publication-type="other">
— (2008b), Pension Plan Design Survey: 2008 Report, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1428a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1432" publication-type="other">
Wooldridge, J. (2002), Introductory Econometrics: A Modern Approach, Cincinnati, OH:
South-Western College Publishing.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
