<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">windengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017550</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Wind Engineering</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Sage Publications, Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0309524X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2048402X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90007083</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Failure Prognostic Schemes and Database Design of a Software Tool for Efficient Management of Wind Turbine Maintenance</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Sinha</surname>
                  <given-names>Yashwant</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Steel</surname>
                  <given-names>John A</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>School of Engineering, Robert Gordon University, Garthdee, Aberdeen AB10 7GJ, UK</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e90007075</issue-id>
         <fpage>453</fpage>
         <lpage>477</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90007083"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Wind Turbines require numerous and varied types of maintenance activities throughout their lifespan, the frequency of which increases with years in operation. At present the proportion of maintenance cost to the total cost for wind turbines is significant particularly for offshore wind turbines (OWT) where this ratio is ~35%. If this ratio is to be reduced in-spite of adverse operating conditions, pre-mature component failures and absence of reliability database for wind turbine components, there is a need to design unconventional maintenance scheme preferably by including novel failure prediction methodologies. Several researchers have advocated the use of Artificial Neural Networks (ANN), Bayesian Network Theory (BNT) and other statistical methods to predict failure so as to plan efficient maintenance of wind turbines, however novelty and randomness of failures, nature and number of parameters involved in statistical calculations and absence of required amount of fundamental work required for such advanced analysis have continued to maintain the high cost of maintenance. This work builds upon the benefits of condition monitoring to design methods to predict generic failures in wind turbine components and exhibits how such prediction methods can assist in cutting the maintenance cost of wind turbines. This study proposes using a dedicated tool to assist with failure prediction and planning and execution of wind turbine maintenance. The design and development of such an all-inclusive tool will assist in performing administrative works, inventory control, financial calculations and service management apart from failure prediction in wind turbine components. Its database will contain reference to standard management practices, regulatory provisions, staff details and their skillsets, service call register, troubleshooting manuals, installation guide, service history, details of customers and clients etc. that would cater to multiple avenues of wind turbine maintenance. In order to build such a software package, a robust design of its database is crucial. This work lists prerequisites for choosing a physical database and identifies the benefits of relational database software in controlling large amounts of data of various formats that are stored in such physical databases. Such a database would be an invaluable resource for reliability studies, an area of interest for both academic researchers and the industry that are identifying avenues to economise wind turbine operations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>wind turbines</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>failure prediction</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>condition based maintenance</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>artificial neural network</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>Bayesian network</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>maintenance tool</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>database</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>offshore wind turbines</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>efficient maintenance</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>reliability database</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y. Study of Technology of Feature Extraction of Gearbox Fault, Taiyuan, North University of China, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li. S., Jiang, D. and Zhao, M. Experimental Investigation and Analysis for Gearbox Fault, IEEE, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caselitz, P. and Giebhardt, J. Rotor Condition Monitoring for Improved Operational Safety of Offshore Wind Energy Converters, Institute of Solar Energy Suly Technology, Kassel.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elforjani, M. and Mba, D. Detecting Natural Crack Initiation and Growth in Slow Speed Shaft with the Acoustic Emission Technology, Engineering Failure Analysis, Vol. 16, pp. 2121–2129, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dongxiang, J., Liangyou, H., Qian, H. and Yongshan, D. Condition Monitoring and Fault Diagnosis Techniques for Wind Turbine, Power System and Clean Energy, Vol. 23, pp. 40–44, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat, Y., Choqueuse, V. and Benbouzid and M. E. H. Wind Turbine Condition Monitoring and Fault Diagnosis Using Generator Current Amplitude Demodulation, IEEE International Energy Conference, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, R., Lapworth, J., Hall, L. and Richardson, Z. Transformer Lifetime Performance: Managing the Risks, “3<sup>rd</sup> IEEE International Conference on Reliability of Transmission and Distribution Networks, London, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wilson, A., Heywood, R. and Richardson, Z. The Life time of Power Transformer, Insucon, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heathcote, J. and P Transformer Book, 13<sup>th</sup> Edition, Elsevier, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dongxiang, J., Liangyou, H., Qian, H. and Yongshan, D. Condition Monitoring and Fault Diagnosis Techniques for Wind Turbine, Power System and Clean Energy, Vol. 23, pp. 40–44, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guo, H. and Wu, B. Fault Diagnosis of Wind Turbine Power Electronic Equipment based on SOM Neural Network, Sixth International Conference on Natural Computation (ICNC), 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ye, X., Veeramachaneni, K., Yan, Y. and Osadiw, L. A. Unsupervised Learning and Fusion for Failure Detection in Wind Turbines, 12<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Information Fusion, ISIF, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Becker, E. and Posta, P. Keeping the Blade Turning: Condition Monitoring of Wind Turbine Gears, Vol. 7(2), pp. 48–51, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Editorial, Managing the Wind - Reducing kilowatt-hour Costs with Condition Monitoring, Refocus, Vol. 6(3), pp. 253–261, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrawus, J. A. Maintenance Optimisation for Wind Turbines, PhD Thesis, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UK, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ding, H., Heywood, R., Lapworth, J. and Ryder, S. Why Transformers Fail, Euro TechCon, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, S., Li, W. and Wang, C. The Intelligent Fault Diagnosis of Wind Turbine Gearbox Based on Artificial Neural Network, International Conference on Condition Monitoring and Diagnosis, Beijing, China, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leite, A., Borges, C. and Falcao, D. Probabilistic Wind farm Generation Model for Reliability Studies applied to Brazilians Sites, IEEE Transaction on Power Systems, Vol. 21, 1493–15016, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karki, R. and Billinton, R. Cost Effective Wind Utilisation for Reliable Power Supply, IEEE – Energy Conversion, Vol. 19(2), pp. 435–440, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sinha, Y. and Steel, J. A. A Progressive study into offshore wind farm maintenance optimisation using risk based failure analysis, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, Vol. 42, pp 735–742, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walford, C. Wind Turbine Reliability, Understanding and Minimising Wind Turbine Operation and Maintenance Costs, Sandia National Laboratories, Report No. SAND2006– 1100, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Renewables Global Status Report, 2011 (Available: http://www.ren21.net/Portals/97/documents/GSR/REN21_GSR2011.pdf) (Accessed: 13/08/2012).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tavner, P. Offshore Wind Turbines – Reliability, Availability and Maintenance, IET Renewable Energy Series, 1<sup>st</sup> Ed, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">www.amariner.net/cblog/index.php?/archives/17-unknown.html (Assessed: 8/7/2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koch, H. R. Connecting Large Offshore Wind Farms to the Transmission Network, T&amp;D Conference New Orleans, IEEE, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moskalenko, N. and Orths, A. Study of Wake Effect for Offshore Wind Farm Planning, Motor Electric Power System, Poland, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Electricity Generation Costs, Department of Energy &amp; Climate Change, October 2012, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez, I., Gracia, M., Morant, F., Correcher, A. and Quiles, E. Application of Latent Nestling Methods using Coloured Petri Nets for the Diagnosis in the WT Subsets, IEEE Int. conference of Emerging Technologies and Factory Automation, pp. 767–73, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guo, H. and Wu, B. Fault Diagnosis of WT Power Electronic Equipment based on SOM Neural Network, Sixth International Conference on Natural Computation (ICNC), 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>[30]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benbouzid, M. A. Review of Induction Motors Signature Analysis as a Medium for Fault Detection, IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 47 (5), pp. 984–993, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>[31]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cusido, J., Romeral, L., Ortega, J., Rosero, J. and Espinosa, A. Fault Detection in Induction Machines using Power Spectral Density in Wavelet Decomposition, IEEE Transaction on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 55 (2), pp. 633–643, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>[32]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stack, J. R., Harley, R. G. and Habetler, T. G. An Amplitude Modulation Detector for Fault Diagnosis in rolling Element Bearings, IEEE Transaction on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 51(5), 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>[33]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat, Y., Choqueuse, V., Benbouzid, M. E. H. and Charoentier, J. F. Bearing Fault Detection in DFIG Based WT Using the First Intrinsic Mode Function, XIX International Conference on Electrical Machines – ICEM, Rome, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>[34]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elforjani, M. and Mba, D. Detecting Natural Crack Initiation and Growth in Slow Speed Shaft with the Acoustic Emission Technology, Engineering Failure Analysis, Vol. 16, pp. 2121–2129, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>[35]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Ahmar, E., Benbouzid, M. E. H. and Amirat, Y. DFIG-Based Wind Turbine Fault Diagnosis Using A Specific Discrete Wavelet Transform, In Proceedings of Icem’08, Vilamoura, Portugal, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>[36]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Becker, E. and Posta, P. Keeping the Blade Turning: Condition Monitoring of Wind Turbine Gears, Vol. 7(2), pp. 48–51, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>[37]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Editorial, Managing the Wind: Reducing kilowatt-hour Costs with Condition Monitoring, Refocus, Vol. 6 (3), pp. 253–261, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>[38]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat, Y., Choqueuse, V., Benbouzid, M. E. H. and Charoentier, J. F. Bearing Fault Detection in DFIG Based Wind Turbine Using the First Intrinsic Mode Function, XIX International Conference on Electrical Machines – ICEM, Rome, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>[39]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sinha, Y., Steel, J. A., Andrawus, J. A. and Gibson K, A SMART Software Package for Maintenance Optimisation of Offshore Wind Turbines, Wind Engineering, Vol. 37 (6), pp. 569–577, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>[40]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Palma, J., Hijes, F. C. G., Martinez, M. C. and Careles, L.G. Scheduling of Maintenance Work: A Constraint based Approach, Expert Systems with Applications, Vol. 37, pp. 2963–2973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>[41]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zaher, A. S. and McArthur, S. D. J, A multi agent fault detection system for Wind Turbine defect recognition and diagnosis, IEEE, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>[42]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li P, He Q, Kong F, A New Method of Feature Extraction for Gearbox Vibration Signals, 3rd International Congress on Image and Signal Processing, IEEE, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>[43]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Igarshi, T. and Hamada, H. Studies on the Vibration and Sound of Defective Roller Bearings, First Report: Vibration of Ball Bearing with one Defect, Bull JSME, Vol. 25 (204), pp. 1791–1798, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>[44]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ribrant, J. Reliability Performance and Maintenance - A Survey of Failures in Wind Power Systems, Master Thesis, KTH, Stockholm, Sweden, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>[45]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ben-Daya, M. S. and Duffuaa, A. R. Handbook of Maintenance Management and Engineering, Springer, London, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>[46]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neale M, Condition Monitoring Manual, HMSO, UK (Available: http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=j2mN2aIs2YIC&amp;pg=PA467&amp;lpg=PA467&amp;dq=Neale+M.,+Condition+Monitoring+Manual,+HMSO,+UK&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=Qqz9l0KTVA&amp;sig=3mBJe F7tW10J6uekghmzCzVXBjI&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=t6MgUaOtI82Thge_pIHYAQ&amp;ved=0CDIQ6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;q=Neale%20M.%2C%20Condition%20Monitoring%20Manual%2C%20HMSO%2C%20UK&amp;f=false) (Assessed – 10/1/2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>[47]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hameed, Z., Hong, Y S, Choa Y M, Ahn S H, and Song C K, Condition Monitoring and Fault Detection of Wind Turbines and Related Algorithms: A Review, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Review, Vol. 13, pp. 1–39, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>[48]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tandon N Makra B C, Vibration and Acoustic Monitoring Techniques for the Detection of Defects in Rolling Elements Bearings – A Review, Shock and Vibration Digest, Vol. 24 (3), pp. 3–11, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>[49]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshioka T, Takeda M, Classification of Rolling Contact Fatigue Initiation using Acoustic Emission Technique, Lubrication Engineering, Vol. 51(1), 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>[50]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tan C C, Application of Acoustic Emission to the Detection of Bearing Failures, Proceedings Tribology Conference, Brisbane, 110–114, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>[51]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morfiadakis E, Papadopouls K and Philippidis T P, Assessment of the Strain Gauge Technique for Measurement of Wind Turbine Blade Loads, Wind Energy, Vol. 3(1), pp. 35–65, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>[52]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giebel G, Oilver G, Malcom M, Kaj B, Common Access to Wind Turbine Data for Condition Monitoring, RISO International Symposium on Material Science, Denmark, pp. 157–164, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>[53]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morando I E, Measuring Shock Pulses is Ideal for Bearing Condition Monitoring, Pulp and Paper, Vol. 62(12), 96–98, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>[54]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tandon N and Nakra B C, Comparison of Vibration and Acoustic Measurement Techniques for the Condition Monitoring of Rolling Element Bearings, Tribology International, Vol. 25(3), 205–212, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>[55]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deshpande V S and Modak J P, Application of RCM for Safety Considerations in a Steel Plant, Reliability Engineering and System Safety, Vol. 3 (78), pp 325–334, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>[56]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Endrenyl J, McCauley J and Singh C, The Present Status of Maintenance Strategies and the Impact of Maintenance on Reliability, IEEE Transaction Power System, Vol. 16 (4), 638–646, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>[57]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verbruggen T W, Wind Turbine Operation and Maintenance based on Condition Monitoring, WT-O, Final Report, ECN-C-03-047, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>[58]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leske S and Kitaljevich D, Managing Gearbox Failure, Dewek, Dewek Magazine, No. 29, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>[59]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schoen R R, Lin B K, Habetler T G, Schlag J H and Farag S, An Unsupervised On-line System for Induction Motor Fault Detection using Stator Current Monitoring, IEEE Transaction on Industry Applications, Vol 31 (6), pp.1280–1286, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>[60]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sep D C and Lee J J, Damage Detection of CFRP Laminates using Electrical Resistance Measurement and Neural Network, Composite Structures, Vol. 47, pp. 525–530, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>[61]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zaher A S and McArthur S D J, A Multi-Agent Fault Detection System for Wind Turbines Defect Recognition and Diagnosis, International Proceedings IEEE Lausanne POWERTECH 2007, pp. 22–27, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>[62]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sorensen B F, Lading L, Sendrup P, McGugan M, Debel C P and Kristensen O J D, Fundamentals for Remote Structural Health Monitoring of Wind Turbines Blades – A Pre-project, RISO-R-1336(EN), 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>[63]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dale S L, Dolan and Lehn P W, Real Time Wind Turbine Emulator Suitable for Power Quality and Dynamic Control Studies, International Proceedings of International Conference on Power Systems Transients, Montreal, Canada, pp 1–6, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>[64]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fantidis J G, Potolias C, and Bandekas D. V, Wind Turbine Blade Non-destructive Testing with a Transportable Radiography System, Science and Technology of Nuclear Installations, ID 347320, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>[65]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dolinski L and Krawczuk M, Damage Detection in Wind Turbine Blades by Vibration based Methods, 7<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Modern Practice in Stress and Vibration Analysis, Journal of Physics, Conference Series 181 012086, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>[66]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Ahmar E, Benbouzid M E H and Amirat Y, DFIG-Based Wind Turbine Fault Diagnosis Using A Specific Discrete Wavelet Transform, In Proceedings of ICEM’08, Vilamoura, Portugal, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>[67]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Choqueuse V, Benbouzid M E H, Wind Turbine Condition Monitoring And Fault Diagnosis Using Generator Current Amplitude Demodulation, IEEE International Energy Conference, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>[68]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Benbouzid M and Al-Ahmar E A, A Brief Status On Condition Monitoring And Fault Diagnosis In Wind Energy Conversion Systems, Renewable &amp; Sustainable Energy Reviews, Vol. 3 (9), pp. 2629–2636, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>[69]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Holland C, Modern Condition Monitoring Methods – Advantages On-board, Underhall, 2008 (Available: http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=condition+monitoring+techniques+pdf&amp;source=web&amp;cd=2&amp;cad=rja&amp;ved=0CEQQFjAB&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2F www.uhfg.se%2Fhtml%2FMarinpresentationer%2FLR%2520Chris%2520Holland.pdf&amp;ei=Q88wUO4Kpo7QBeL5gOgM&amp;usg=AFQjCNFuX5QOf3ZlIKTHHiRS bXclR4BM9Q) (Last Accessed on 19/08/2012).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>[70]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nilsson J and Bertling L, Maintenance Management of Wind Power Systems using Condition Monitoring Systems - Life Cycle Cost Analysis for Two Case Studies, IEEE Transaction on Energy Conversion, Vol. 22(1), 223–229, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <label>[71]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benbouzid M A, Review of Induction Motors Signature Analysis as a Medium for Fault Detection, IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 47 (5), pp. 984–993, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <label>[72]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cusido J, Romeral L., Ortega J, Rosero J and Espinosa A, Fault Detection in Induction Machines using Power Spectral Density in Wavelet Decomposition, IEEE Transaction on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 55 (2), pp. 633–643, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <label>[73]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stack J R, Harley R G, and Habetler T G, An Amplitude Modulation Detector for Fault Diagnosis in Rolling Element Bearings, IEEE Transaction on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 51(5), 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <label>[74]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez I, Gracia M, Morant F, Correcher A. and Quiles E, Application of Latent Nestling Methods using Coloured Petri Nets for the Diagnosis in the Wind Turbine Subsets, IEEE International Conference of Emerging Technologies and Factory Automation, pp. 767–73, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <label>[75]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Echavarria E, Tomiyama T, Huberts H and Van Bussel G, Fault Diagnosis System for an Offshore Wind Turbine using Quantitative Physics, EWEC 2008, Brussels, Belgium, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <label>[76]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xingjia Y, Guangkun Shan and Donghai, Study on Variable Pitch System Characteristics of Big Wind Turbine, Energy Saving, Environment Protection and Sustainable Development in the Manufacturing Industry, International Technology and Innovation Conference, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <label>[77]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranchin T, Furevik B, Stette M, et al, Obtaining Data for Wind Farm Development and Management: The EO-WINDFARM Project.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <label>[78]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Choqueuse V, Benbouzid M E H and Charoentier J F, Bearing Fault Detection in DFIG Based Wind Turbine Using the First Intrinsic Mode Function, XIX International Conference on Electrical Machines – ICEM, Rome, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <label>[79]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sainz E, Liombart A and Guerrero J J, Robust filtering for the characterization of wind turbines: Improving its operation and maintenance, Energy Conversion and Management, Vol. 50, 2136–2147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <label>[80]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tana C K and Irvinga P, A Comparative Experimental Study on the Diagnostic and Prognostic Capabilities of Acoustic Emission, Vibration and Spectrometric Oil Analysis for Spur Gears, Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing, Vol. 21, pp. 208–33, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <label>[81]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei X and Liu L, Fault Detection of Large Scale Wind Turbine Systems, 5<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Computer Science and Education, Hefei, China, IEEE pp. 1299–1304, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <label>[82]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu B, Li Y, Wu X and Yang Z, A Review of Recent Advances in Wind Turbine Condition Monitoring and Fault Diagnosis, IEEE, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <label>[83]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson K E and Fleming P A, Development, Implementation and Testing of Fault Detection Strategies on the National Wind Technology Centre’s Controls Advanced Research Turbines, Mechatronics, Vol. 21, pp. 728–736, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <label>[84]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Application of Condition Monitoring Systems in Wind Energy Converters, EWEC 97, Dublin, Ireland, pp. 597–582, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <label>[85]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.gl-garradhassan.com/assets/downloads/20100129-EWEC2010_full_ paper_(SUBMITTED).pdf (Last Assessed: 26/01/2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <label>[86]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Ahmar E, Benbouzid M E H and Amirat Y, DFIG-Based WT Fault Diagnosis Using A Specific Discrete Wavelet Transform, In Proceedings Of ICEM ’08, Vilamoura, Portugal, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <label>[87]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Choqueuse V and Benbouzid M E H, Wind Turbine Condition Monitoring And Fault Diagnosis Using Generator Current Amplitude Demodulation, IEEE International Energy Conference, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref88">
            <label>[88]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Benbouzid M and Al-Ahmar E A, A Brief Status On Condition Monitoring And Fault Diagnosis In Wind Energy Conversion Systems, Renewable &amp; Sustainable Energy Reviews, Vol. 3(9), pp. 2629–2636, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref89">
            <label>[89]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodriguez I, Gracia M, Morant F, Correcher A and Quiles E, Application of Latent Nestling Methods using Coloured Petri Nets for the Diagnosis in the WT Subsets, IEEE Int. conference of Emerging Technologies and Factory Automation, pp. 767–73, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref90">
            <label>[90]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guo H and Wu B, Fault Diagnosis of WT Power Electronic Equipment based on SOM Neural Network, Sixth International Conference on Natural Computation (ICNC), 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref91">
            <label>[91]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benbouzid M A, Review of Induction Motors Signature Analysis as a Medium for Fault Detection, IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 47(5), pp. 984–993, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref92">
            <label>[92]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cusido J, Romeral L, Ortega J, Rosero J and Espinosa A, Fault Detection in Induction Machines using Power Spectral Density in Wavelet Decomposition, IEEE Transaction on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 55(2), pp. 633–643, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref93">
            <label>[93]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stack J R, Harley R G, and Habetler T G, An Amplitude Modulation Detector for Fault Diagnosis in rolling Element Bearings, IEEE Transaction on Industrial Electronics, Vol. 51(5), 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref94">
            <label>[94]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Choqueuse V, Benbouzid M E H, and Charoentier J F, Bearing Fault Detection in DFIG Based WT Using the First Intrinsic Mode Function, XIX International Conference on Electrical Machines – ICEM, Rome, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref95">
            <label>[95]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Ahmar E, Benbouzid M E H and Amirat Y, DFIG-Based Wind Turbine Fault Diagnosis Using A Specific Discrete Wavelet Transform, In Proceedings Of Icem’08, Vilamoura, Portugal, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref96">
            <label>[96]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Choqueuse V, and Benbouzid M E H, Wind Turbine Condition Monitoring And Fault Diagnosis Using Generator Current Amplitude Demodulation, IEEE International Energy Conference, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref97">
            <label>[97]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amirat Y, Benbouzid M and Al-Ahmar E A, A Brief Status On Condition Monitoring And Fault Diagnosis In Wind Energy Conversion Systems, Renewable &amp; Sustainable Energy Reviews, Vol. 3 (9), pp 2629–2636, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref98">
            <label>[98]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">British Standards, Glossary of terms used in terotechnology, British Standards BS 3811:1993, Published 15<sup>th</sup> December 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref99">
            <label>[99]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.quora.com/What-are-some-real-life-applications-of-Bayesian-Belief-Networks (Accessed: 24/01/2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref100">
            <label>[100]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://faculty.washington.edu/tamre/BayesTheorem.pdf (Accessed: 11/11/2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref101">
            <label>[101]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/business-english/relationaldatabase?q=relational+database (Accessed: 9/06/2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref102">
            <label>[102]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.cs.cityu.edu.hk/~helena/cs34622000B/Normalization.pdf (Accessed: 6/06/2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref103">
            <label>[103]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.cs.utexas.edu/~cannata/dbms/Class%20Notes/06%20Normalization.pdf (Accessed 9/6/2014).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>

