<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25829964</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25829969</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE IMPACT OF FOREIGN DIRECT INVESTMENT ON DOMESTIC CAPITAL FORMATION IN A DEVELOPING COUNTRY: NIGERIA / LES EFFETS DES INVESTISSEMENTS DIRECTS ETRANGERS SUR LA FORMATION NATIONALE DU CAPITAL DANS UN PAYS EN VOIE DE DEVELOPPEMENT: L'EXPERIENCE DU NIGERIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gladson I.</given-names>
                  <surname>Nwanna</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1986</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>265</fpage>
         <lpage>278</lpage>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25829969"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>On pense que les investissements directs étrangers apportent de nombreux effets favorables de nature économique aux pays d'accueil. En ce qui concerne les pays en voie de développement qui sont caractérisés structurellement par une insuffisante accumulation de capital, le flux d'investissements directs est très souvent bien accepté. D'autre part, on remarque que ces investissements donnent lieu à des effets négatifs mais toutefois le phénomène continue. Le but fondamental de cet article est d'évaluer sur le plan empirique l'effet des investissements étrangers directs de nature privée sur l'investissement national au Nigéria de 1960 à 1980. En particulier on essayera: 1) de déterminer les effets quantitatifs et leur direction à court et à long terme et 2) de répondre à la question de savoir si ces investissements ont eu un effet complémentaire, neutre ou négatif (de substitution) sur la formation interne de capital. Dans ce contexte, l'article conclut que les investissements directs étrangers ont eu un effet de substitution à court terme et un effet complémentaire à long terme. Une unité de capital étranger donnait lieu à court terme à une réduction de l'investissement interne de 0,90 et à long terme à un augmentation de 3,7 unités. Une certaine partie des effets négatifs s'expliquait par le fait que les investissements étrangers stimulaient les importations. Ce phénomène était clairement démontré par une augmentation sans précédent de la consommation des biens importés à partir à peu près du 1975. D'autre part, les effets positifs à long terme s'expliquaient probablement par la présence d'un effet multiplicateur des fonds investis. Même si on tient compte des limites de cet article (disponibilité des données, période analysée, modèle utilisé et techniques d'analyse, etc.) il arrive à la conclusion que les investissements étrangers directs ne sont pas structurellement « destructeurs ». Ils sont et resteront une source importante de capital destinée à la croissance de l'ensemble des pays en voie de développement, y compris le Nigéria. Ils continueront à donner lieu à des effets positifs de premier ou de deuxième degré. De ces investissements il faut toutefois reconnaître non seulement les effets positifs mais aussi les effets négatifs. Pour la prochaine recherche et pour une meilleure action directe des pouvoirs publics il faudra tenir compte non seulement des différents effets temporels des investissements mais aussi de la variabilité des résultats d'un pays à l'autre.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d1e117a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e124" publication-type="other">
E.F. Denison, « The Contribution of Capital to Economic Growth », American Economic Review, Papers
and Proceedings, (May 1980), pp. 220-224</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e133" publication-type="other">
N.N. Behram, « Promoting Free World Economic Development
Through Direct Investment», American Economic Review, 50 (May 1980), p. 271</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e142" publication-type="other">
H.B. Chenery and A. Strout,
« Foreign Assistance and Economic Development», American Economic Review 56 (September 1966),
pp. 679-733</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e155" publication-type="other">
T. Balough and P.O. Streeten, « Domestic vs Foreign Investment», Bulletin, Oxford University
Institute of Statistics, 22 (1960), p. 224</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e164" publication-type="other">
M.C. Kemp, « Foreign Investment and National Advantage », Economic
Record, Vol. XXXVIII (March 1962).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e174a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e181" publication-type="other">
Raymond Vernon, Sovereignty at Bay, The Multinational Spread of U.S. Enterprises (New York: Basic
Books, Inc. 1971), pp. 172-178</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e190" publication-type="other">
Michael I. Obaden, « Impact of Direct Foreign Investment: A case study from
Nigeria », Intereconomics (Jan, Feb. 1980), pp. 39-42</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e199" publication-type="other">
Isaiah Litvak and Christopher Maule, (eds.) Foreign
Investment: The Experience of Host Countries (New York: Praeger Publishers, 1970), p. 240.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e209a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e216" publication-type="other">
M.W. Kelly, Foreign Investment Evaluation Practices of U.S. Multinational Corporations. (Michigan: UMI
Research Press, 1981), p. 8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e226a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e233" publication-type="other">
Richard Caves and Grant Reuber, Capital Transfers and
Economic Policy: Canada 1952-1962. (Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1971).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e244a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e251" publication-type="other">
R. Eisner and R. Strotz, « The Determinants of Business Investment», in D.B. Suits et al., Impact of Monetary
Policy (Englewcod Cliffs, 1963), pp. 60-338</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e260" publication-type="other">
E. Kuh, « Theory and Institutions in the Study of Investment Beha-
viour », American Economic Review, (May 1963) pp. 260-268</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e269" publication-type="other">
Dale W. Jorgenson, « The Theory of Investment
Behavior», in ed. Robert Ferber, Determinants of Investment Behavior, A Conference of the National Bureau
Committee for Economic Research (New York: Columbia University Press, 1967)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e282" publication-type="other">
D.W. Jorgenson, « Capital
Theory and Investment Behavior», American Economic Review Proc, 53 (May 1963), pp. 147-259</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e291" publication-type="other">
D.W. Jor-
genson and CO. Sierbert, « A Comparison of Alternative Theories of Corporate Investment Behavior», Ameri-
can Economic Review, Vol. 58 (Sept. 1968), pp. 681-712.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e304a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e311" publication-type="other">
Arthur S. Goldberg, Impact Multipliers and Dynamic Properties of the Klein-Goldberg Model. (Amsterdam:
1959) p. 20.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e321a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e328" publication-type="other">
Jan Kmenta, Elements of Econometrics (New York: Macmillan Publishing Co., Inc., 1971), pp. 531-585</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e334" publication-type="other">
Michael D. Intrilligator, Econometric Models, Techniques and Applications (Englewood, New Jersey: Prentice-
Hall, Inc., 1978), pp. 230-402</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e343" publication-type="other">
C.E.V. Lesser, Econometric Techniques and Problems (London: Charles Griffin
and Company Ltd., 1966), pp. 37-59.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e353a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e360" publication-type="other">
R. Mikesell, ed., U.S. Private and Government Investment Abroad (Eugene, Ore: University of Oregon
Press, 1962). pp. 140-150</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e369" publication-type="other">
Hollis Chenery and Alan Strout, « Foreign Assistance and Economic Develop-
ment », American Economic Review, 56 (September 1966)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e378" publication-type="other">
Paul Rosenstein-Rodan, « International Aids for
Underdeveloped Countries », Review of Economics and Statistics, 43 (May 1961).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e388a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e395" publication-type="other">
J. Behrman, National Interests and the Multinational Enterprise. (Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall, Inc.,
1970). pp. 13-45.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d1e405a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e412" publication-type="other">
Keith Griffin, « Foreign Capital, Domestic Savings and Economic Development», Bulletin, Oxford Universi-
ty, Institute of Economics and Statistics, 32 (May 1970)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e421" publication-type="other">
Gustav Papanek, « The Effect of Aid and Other
Resource Transfers on Savings and Growth in Less Developed Countries », Economic Journal, 82 (September
1972).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>Bibliography</title>
        <ref id="d1e443a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e447" publication-type="other">
Addy, P. (Ed.) Private Foreign Investment and Developing World. New York: Praeger Publishers 1971.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e454a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e458" publication-type="other">
Areskoug, Kaj. Private Foreign Investment and Capital Formation in Developing Countries », Economic Deve-
lopment and Cultural Change, Vol. 24 (October 1975).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e468a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e472" publication-type="other">
Balough T. and Streeten, P.P. « Domestic Vs. Foreign Investment», Bulletin of Oxford University Institute of
Statistics, 22, 1960.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e482a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e486" publication-type="other">
Behran, N.N. « Promoting Free World Economic Development Through Direct Investment», American Econo-
mic Review, 50 (May 1960).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e497a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e501" publication-type="other">
Behrman, J. National Interests and The Multinational Enterprise Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey: Prentice Hall
Inc., 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e511a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e515" publication-type="other">
Boatwright, B.D. and Renton, G.A. « An Analysis of U.K. Inflows and Outflow of Foreign Direct Investment»,
Review of Economics and Statistics, 57 (1975).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e525a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e529" publication-type="other">
Branson, William H. Macroeconomic Theory and Policy (2nd Ed.), New York: Harper and Row Publishers,
1979.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e539a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e543" publication-type="other">
Caves, Richard and Reuber, Grant. Capital Transfers and Economic Policy: Canada 1951-1962. Cambridge:
Harvard University Press, 1971.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e553a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e557" publication-type="other">
Chenery, Hollis B. and Strout, Alan M. « Foreign Assistance and Economic Development», American Econo-
mic Review, 56 (September 1966).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e567a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e571" publication-type="other">
Denison, E.F. « The Contribution of Capital to Economic Growth », American Economic Review: Papers and
Proceedings, (May 1980).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e582a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e586" publication-type="other">
Domar, E.D. « The Effect of Foreign Investment on the Balance of Payments », American Economic Review,
XL (December 1950).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e596a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e600" publication-type="other">
Dunning, J.H. Studies in International Investment London: George Allen and Unwin, Ltd. 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e611" publication-type="other">
Eisner, R. and Strotz, R. « The Determinants of Business Investments », in Suits, D.B. et al; Importance of
Monetary Policy. Englewood Cliffs. 1968.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e621a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e625" publication-type="other">
Fair, C. « The Estimation of Simultaneous Equation Model with Lagged Endogenous Variables and First Order
Serially Correlated Errors », Econometrica, Vol. 38, No. 3 (May 1970).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e635a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e639" publication-type="other">
Goldberg, Arthur S. Impact Multipliers and Dynamic Properties of the Klein-Goldberger Model. Amsterdam:
1959.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e649a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e653" publication-type="other">
Griffin, Keith, « Foreign Capital, Domestic Savings and Economic Development», Bulletin, Oxford University,
Institute of Economics and Statistics, 32 (May 1970).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e668" publication-type="other">
Grubel, Herbert G. International Economics. Homewood, Illinois: Richard Irwin, Inc., 1977.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e675a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e679" publication-type="other">
Intrilligator, Michael D. Econometric Models, Techniques, and Applications. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey:
Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1978.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e689a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e693" publication-type="other">
lyanda, Olukunle. « Impact of Foreign Direct Investment in Manufacturing on the Nigeria Economy », Unpubli-
shed Ph. d. Dissertation, New York University, New York, 1975.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e703a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e707" publication-type="other">
Jorgenson, Dale. « The Theory of Investment Behavior», in Ferber, Robert, ed., Determinants of Investment
Behavior., A Conference of the National Bureau Committee for Economic Research. New York: Columbia
University Press, 1967.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e720a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e724" publication-type="other">
Jorgenson, D.W. « Capital Theory and Investment Behavior», American Economic Review, Proc, 53 (May
1963).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e734a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e738" publication-type="other">
Jorgenson, D.W. and Siebert, CO. « A Comparison of Alternative Theories of Corporate Investment Beha-
vior », American Economic Review, Vol. 58 (Sept. 1968).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e749a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e753" publication-type="other">
Kelly, M.W. Foreign Investment Evaluation Practices of U.S. Multinational Corporations, Michigan: UMI Re-
search Press, 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e763a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e767" publication-type="other">
Kemp, M.C. « Foreign Investment and National Advantage », Economic Records, Vol. XXXIX (March 1929).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e774a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e778" publication-type="other">
Kindleberger, Charles P. (Ed.) The international Corporations. Cambridge, Mass., The M.l.T. Press, 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e785a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e789" publication-type="other">
Kuh, E. « Theory and Institution in the Study of Investment Behavior», American Economic Review, (May
1963).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e799a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e803" publication-type="other">
Kmenta, Jan. Elements of Econometrics. New York: MacMillan Publishing Company, Inc., 1971.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e810a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e814" publication-type="other">
Kwack, S.Y. « A Model of U.S. Direct Investment Abroad: A Neoclassical Approach », Western Economic
Journal, 10 (Dec. 1972).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e825a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e829" publication-type="other">
Lall, Sanjaya. « Less Developed Countries and Private Foreign Direct Investment: A Review Article », World
Development, Vol. 2, No. 4 and 5 (1974).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e839a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e843" publication-type="other">
Lall, Sanjaya. « Transfer Pricing by Multinational Firms », Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, 35
(1973).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e853a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e857" publication-type="other">
Lesser, E.V. Econometric Techniques and Problems (2nd Impression), London: Charles Griffin and Company
Limited, 1969.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e871" publication-type="other">
Litvak, Isaiah and Maule, Christopher (Eds.). Foreign Investment: The Experience of Host Countries. New York:
Praeger Publishers, 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e885" publication-type="other">
Lubitz, Raymond, « The United States Direct Investment in Canada and Canadian Capital Formation, 1950-
1962 », in Caves, R. and Reuber, G (1971).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e895a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e899" publication-type="other">
MacDougall, G.D.A. « The Benefits and Costs of Private Investment From Abroad: A Theoretical Approach »,
Bulletin of Oxford University Institute of Statistics, 22 (August 1960).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e910a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e914" publication-type="other">
Mikesell, R. (Ed.), U.S. Private and Government Investment Abroad. Eugene, Ore.: University of Oregon Press,
1962.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e928" publication-type="other">
Obadan, Michael I. « Impact of Foreign Investment: A Case Study From Nigeria », Intereconomics, January/
February (1980).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e942" publication-type="other">
Papanel, Gustav F. « The Effect of Aid and Other Resource Transfers on Savings and Growth in Less Develo-
ped Countries », Journal of Political Economy, Vol. 81, (1973).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e952a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e956" publication-type="other">
Rodan, Rosenstein. « International Aids for Underdeveloped Countries », Review of Economics and Statistics,
43 (May 1961).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e970" publication-type="other">
Schatz, Sayre. Nigerian Capitalism, Berkeley: University Press, 1977.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e977a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e981" publication-type="other">
Singer, Hans. « The Distribution of Gains Between Investing and Borrowing Countries », Reprinted in American
Economic Review, XL (May 1950).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e992a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e996" publication-type="other">
Tims, Wouter (Chief of Mission and Co-ordinating Author), Nigeria; Options for Long Term Development Re-
port of Mission Sent to Nigeria by the World Bank, Baltimore: John Hopkins University Press, 1974.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1006a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1010" publication-type="other">
Van Loo, Frances. « The Effect of Foreign Direct Investment on Investment in Canada », Review of Economics
and Statistics, 59 (4), (Nov. 1977).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1020a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1024" publication-type="other">
Vernon, Raymond. Sovereignty at Bay. The Multinational Spread of U.S. Enterprises. New York: Basic Books,
Inc., 1971.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1e1034a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1038" publication-type="other">
Weiskopf, Thomas E. « The Impact of Foreign Capital Inflow on Domestic Savings in Underdeveloped Coun-
tries », Journal of International Economics, 2 (Feb. 1972).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


