<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278211</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Use of Detailed Kinetics and Advanced Chemistry-Solution Techniques in CFD to Investigate Dual-Fuel Engine Concepts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Puduppakkam</surname>
                  <given-names>Karthik V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Reaction Design</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Liang</surname>
                  <given-names>Long</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Reaction Design</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Naik</surname>
                  <given-names>Chitralkumar V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Reaction Design</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Meeks</surname>
                  <given-names>Ellen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Reaction Design</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kokjohn</surname>
                  <given-names>Sage L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin–Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin–Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1127</fpage>
         <lpage>1149</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278211"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A multi-component fuel model is used to represent gasoline in computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations of a dual-fuel engine that combines premixed gasoline injection with diesel direct injection. The simulations employ detailed-kinetics mechanisms for both the gasoline and diesel surrogate fuels, through use of an advanced and efficient chemistry solver. The objective of this work is to elucidate kinetics effects of dual-fuel usage in Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) combustion. The model is applied to simulate recent experiments on highly efficient RCCI engines. These engine experiments used a dual-fuel RCCI strategy with port-fuel-injection of gasoline and early-cycle, multiple injections of diesel fuel with a conventional diesel injector [ 1 ]. The experiments showed that the US 2010 heavy-duty NO ₓ and soot emissions regulations were easily met without aftertreatment, while achieving greater than 50% net indicated thermal efficiency. However, as with other low-temperature combustion strategies, CO and unburnt hydrocarbon emissions must be controlled. Homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI) engine experiments were also earlier performed and simulated using a less detailed primary-reference-fuel (PRF) mechanism and single-component surrogates [ 1 ]. The present work introduces a more accurate multi-component representation of the gasoline and a more detailed kinetics mechanism for both the gasoline and diesel surrogates. The simulation results show accurate representation of combustion phasing and better predictions of unburned hydrocarbons and CO emissions as an outcome of using the detailed kinetics. The model demonstrates that the most-reactive surrogate component, n-heptane (component in both diesel and gasoline) ignites first, and the other, slower gasoline-surrogate components follow. The model also shows that the slowest gasoline surrogate component, toluene, is found disproportionately in the unburned hydrocarbon (UHC) emissions. Overall, the predicted UHC emissions can be broadly classified into three groups: surrogate-fuel species make up 37 wt%, large hydrocarbon intermediates that form from the surrogate fuels form 42 wt%, and small C ₁ -C ₄ hydrocarbons form 21 wt%. Of the surrogate fuels present, toluene has the largest concentration. Analysis of uncertainties in IVC temperature input on emissions predictions has also been performed. As the combustion phasing is retarded, the UHC and CO emissions increase for the base case and the uncertainties in temperature have a more dominant effect on emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L., Hanson, R.M., Splitter, D.A. and Reitz, R.D., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y. and Reitz, R. D., “A reduced chemical kinetic model for IC engine combustion simulations with primary reference fuels,” Combustion and Flame 155: 713-738, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golovitchev, V. I., Montorsi, L., Rinaldini, C. A., and Rosetti, A., “CFD Combustion and Emission Formation Modeling for a HSDI Diesel Engine Using Detailed Chemistry,” ASME Paper ICEF 2006-1506, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pitz, W.J., Cernansky, N.P., Dryer, F.L., Egolfopoulos, F.N., et al., “Development of an Experimental Database and Chemical Kinetic Models for Surrogate Gasoline Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0175, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0175.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrell, J.T., Cernansky, N.P., Dryer, F.L., Hergart, C.A., Law, C.K., McDavid, R.M., Mueller, C.J., Patel, A.K. and Pitsch, H., “Development of an Experimental Database and Kinetic Models for Surrogate Diesel Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0201, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colket, M., Edwards, T., Williams, S., Cernansky, N. P., Miller, D. L., Egolfopoulos, F., Lindstedt, P., Seshadri, K., Dryer, F. L., Law, C. K., Friend, D., Lenhert, D. B., Pitsch, H., Sarofim, A., Smooke, M., and Tsang, W., “Development of an Experimental Database and Kinetic Models for Surrogate Jet Fuels,” in 45th AIAA Aerospace Sciences Meeting, 2007-0770. Reno, NV: AIAA, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C.V., Puduppakkam, K.V., Wang, C., Kottalam, J., Liang, L., Hodgson, D. and Meeks, E., “Applying Detailed Kinetics to Realistic Engine Simulation: the Surrogate Blend Optimizer and Mechanism Reduction Strategies,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):241-259, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0541.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“The Model Fuels Consortium,” &lt;http://www.modelfuelsconsortium.com&gt; Reaction Design</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reaction Workbench 15101: Reaction Design, San Diego, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ghosh, P., Hickey, K. J., and Jaffe, S. B., “Development of a Detailed Gasoline Composition-Based Octane Model,” Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Research, 45: 337-345, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G.T., Risberg, P. and Ångström, H-E., “A Method of Defining Ignition Quality of Fuels in HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1816, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1816.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunting, B.G., Eaton, S., Naik, C.V., Puduppakkam, K., Chou, C.P. and Meeks, E., “A Comparison of HCCI Ignition Characteristics of Gasoline Fuels Using a Single-Zone Kinetic Model with a Five Component Surrogate Fuel” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2399, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-2399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CHEMKIN-PRO 15101: Reaction Design, San Diego, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C.V., Puduppakkam, K. and Meeks, E., “Modeling the Detailed Chemical Kinetics of NOx Sensitization for the Oxidation of a Model fuel for Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):556-566, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1084.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puduppakkam, K.V., Naik, C.V., Wang, C. and Meeks, E., “Validation Studies of a Detailed Kinetics Mechanism for Diesel and Gasoline Surrogate Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0545, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0545.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C. V., Puduppakkam, K. V., and Meeks, E., “An Improved Core Reaction Mechanism for Saturated C0-C4 Fuels,” To be presented at the Proceedings of the ASME Turbo Expo 2011: Power for Land, Sea, and Air, GT2011-46705, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Skjøth-Rasmussen, M. S., Glarborg, P., Østberg, M., Johannessen, J. T., Livbjerg, H., Jensen, A. D., and Christensen, T. S., “Formation of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons and soot in fuel-rich oxidation of methane in a laminar flow reactor,” Combustion and Flame, 136: 91-128, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klotz, S. D., Brezinsky, K., and Glassman, I., “Modeling the combustion of toluene-butane blends,” 27th Symposium (International) on Combustion, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Held, T. J., Marchese, A. J., and Dryer, F. L., “A semiempirical reaction mechanism for n-heptane oxidation and pyrolysis,” Combustion Science and Technology, 123: 107-146, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, H.-P. S., Steinberg, J., Vanderover, J., and Oehlschlaeger, M. A., “A Shock Tube Study of the Ignition of n-Heptane, n-Decane, n-Dodecane, and n-Tetradecane at Elevated Pressures,” Energy &amp; Fuels 23: 2482-2489, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ciezki, H. K. and Adomeit, G., “Shock-Tube investigation of self-ignition of n-heptane-air mixtures under engine relevant conditions,” Combustion and Flame, 93: 421-433, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garner, S., Sivaramakrishnan, R., and Brezinsky, K., “The high-pressure pyrolysis of saturated and unsaturated C7 hydrocarbons,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 32 461-467, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gauthier, B. M., Davidson, D. F., and Hanson, R. K., “Shock tube determination of ignition delay times in fullblend and surrogate fuel mixtures,” Combustion and Flame, 139: 300-311, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vasudevan, V., Davidson, D. F., and Hanson, R. K., “Shock tube measurements of toluene ignition times and OH concentration time histories,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 30: 1155-1163, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shen, H.-P. S., Vanderover, J., and Oehlschlaeger, M. A., “A shock tube study of the auto-ignition of toluene/air mixtures at high pressures,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 32: 165-172, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dagaut, P., Pengloan, G., and Ristori, A., “Oxidation, Ignition and Combustion of Toluene: Experimental and Detailed Chemical Kinetic Modeling,” Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics, 4: 1846-1845, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yahyaoui, M., Djebarli-Chaumeix, N., Dagaut, P., Paillard, C.-E., and Gail, S., “Experimental and modelling study of gasoline surrogate mixtures oxidation in jet stirred reactor and shock tube,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 31: 385-391, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vanhove, G., Ribaucour, M., and Minetti, R., “On the influence of the position of the double bond on the lowtemperature chemistry of hexenes,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 30: 1055-1072, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haylett, D. R., Lappas, P. P., Davidson, D. F., and Hanson, R. K., “Application of an aerosol shock tube to the measurement of diesel ignition delay times,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 32: 477-484, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fieweger, K., Blumenthal, R., and Adomeit, G., “Selfignition of S.I. engine model fuels: A shock tube investigation at high pressure,” Combustion and Flame, 109: 599-619, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Griffiths, J. F., Halford-Maw, P. A., and Mohamed, C., “Spontaneous ignition delays as a diagnostic of the propensity of alkanes to cause engine knock” Combustion and Flame, 111: 327-337, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Callahan, C. V., Held, T. J., Dryer, F. L., Minetti, R., Ribaucour, M., and Sochet, L. R., “Experimental data and kinetic modeling of primary reference fuel mixtures,” 26th Symposium (International) on Combustion, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cancino, L. R., Fikri, M., Oliveira, A. A. M., and Schulz, C., “Autoignition of gasoline surrogate mixtures at intermediate temperatures and high pressures: Experimental and numerical approaches,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 32: 501-508, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka, S., Ayala, G., Keck, J. C., and Heywood, J. B., “Two-stage ignition in HCCI combustion and HCCI control by fuels and additives,” Combustion and Flame, 132: 219-239, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, T. and Law, C. K., “A directed relation graph method for mechanism reduction,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 30: 1333-1341, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, T. and Law, C. K., “Linear time reduction of large kinetic mechanisms with directed relation graph: n-heptane and iso-octane,” Combustion and Flame, 144: 24-36, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pepiot-Desjardins, P. and Pitsch, H., “An efficient errorpropagation- based reduction method for large chemical kinetic mechanisms,” Combustion and Flame, 154: 67-81, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Stevens, J. G., and Farrell, J. T., “A dynamic adaptive chemistry scheme for reactive flow computations,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 32: 527-534, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ahmed, S. S., Mauss, F., Moreac, G., and Zeuch, T., “A Comprehensive and Compact n-Heptane Oxidation Model Derived Using Chemical Lumping,” Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 9: 1107-1126, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pepiot-Desjardins and P. P. H., “An automatic chemical lumping method for the reduction of large chemical kinetic mechanisms” Combustion Theory and Modelling 12: 1089-1108, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, T. and Law, C. K., “Strategies for Mechanism Reduction for Large Hydrocarbons: n-Heptane,” Combustion and Flame, 154: 153-163, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FORTÉ 40101: Reaction Design, San Diego, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abani, N., Kokjohn, S., Park, S.W., Bergin, M., Munnannur, A., Ning, W., Sun, Y. and Reitz, R.D., “An Improved Spray Model for Reducing Numerical Parameter Dependencies in Diesel Engine CFD Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-02-0970, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beale, J. C. and Reitz, R. D., “Modeling spray atomization with the Kelvin-Helmholtz/Rayleigh-Taylor hybrid model,” Atomization and Sprays, 9: 623-650, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., Ge, H-W. and Reitz, R.D., “Validation of Mesh- and Timestep-Independent Spray Models for Multi- Dimensional Engine CFD Simulation,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):277-302, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0626.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Munnannur, A. and Reitz, R. D., “A Comprehensive Collision Model for Multi-Dimensional Engine Spray Computations,” Atomization and Sprays, 19: 597-619, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y. and Reitz, R. D., “A vaporization model for discrete multi-component fuel sprays,” International Journal of Multiphase Flow, 35: 101-117, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Naik, C.V., Puduppakkam, K.V., Wang, C., Modak, A., Meeks, E., Ge, H-W., Reitz, R.D. and Rutland, C.J., “Efficient Simulation of Diesel Engine Combustion Using Realistic Chemical Kinetics in CFD,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0178, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Stevens, J. G., and Farrell, J. T., “A dynamic multi-zone partitioning scheme for solving detailed chemical kinetics in reactive flow computations,” Combustion Science and Technology, 181: 1345-1371, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V.Y., Curran, S.J., Barone, T.L., Lewis, S.A., Storey, J.M., Cho, K., Wagner, R.M. and Parks, J.E., “Emission Characteristics of a Diesel Engine Operating with In-Cylinder Gasoline and Diesel Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):946-955, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
