<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816504</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Business Size and Organizational Form (Corporate)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Subchapter S Election and Bank Risk Taking</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yamashita</surname>
                  <given-names>Takashi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>38</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816504"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Subchapter S corporations are flow-through entities that avoid double taxation of corporate profit and dividends. Given the features of pass-through taxation, S-corporation owners face incentives to pay out a higher proportion of income as dividends and not to accumulate retained earnings as equity, leading to higher leverage of the bank’s balance sheet. Consequently, electing the S-corporation status not only increases the after-tax income of owners but also changes the riskiness of investment, which may influence the risk-taking appetite of bank owners. The Small Business Job Protection Act of 1996 for the first time allowed financial institutions to elect the Subchapter S corporation status. Taking advantage of this change as a quasi-natural experiment, this paper examines how banks that elect the S-corporation status evolve vis-à-vis other corporate banks that remain C corporations. Using longitudinal data that cover the universe of all commercial banks and savings institutions insured by the FDIC, I estimate changes in bank growth, composition of income sources, and portfolio compositions after the conversion using the difference-in-differences method. Between 1997 and 1999, banks that elect the S corporation status become more leveraged. In response, they grow less aggressively in revenues and total assets while relying more heavily on interest income rather than more volatile fee incomes. With respect to portfolio compositions, S-corporation banks exhibit a higher loan-to-assets ratio and generally safer compositions of assets and liabilities. I also find strong negative relationship among S-corporation banks between the past leverage ratio and growth rates and portfolio compositions suggesting higher leverage leads to slower growth and safer asset compositions. In sum, S-corporation banks operate more conservatively and rely on traditional banking and maintain safer asset portfolios as the balance sheets become highly leveraged. The results indicate the importance of risk considerations in evaluating the effects of taxes on corporate capital structure.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Berger, Allen N., Thomas Kick, and Klaus Schaeck, “Executive Board Composition and Bank Risk Taking,” Journal of Corporate Finance, 28: October 2014, 48-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bouwman, Christa H. and Ulrike Malmendier, “Does a Bank’s History Affect Its Risk-Taking?” American Economic Review: Papers &amp; Proceedings, 105 (5): May 2015, 321-325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Carroll, Robert and Gerald Parente, “The Flow-Through Business Sector and Tax Reform: The Economic Footprint of the Flow-through Sector and the Potential Impact of Tax Reform,” Ernst &amp; Young, April 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Cullen, Julie Berry, and Roger H. Gordon, “Taxes and Entrepreneurial Risk-Taking: Theory and Evidence for the U.S.” Journal of Public Economics, 91 (7-8): August 2007, 1479-1505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Cummins, Jason G., Kevin A. Hassett, and R. Glenn Hubbard, “A Reconsideration of Investment Behavior Using Tax Reforms as Natural Experiments,” Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 2: 1994, 1-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Craig, Steven G. and Polly T. Hardee, “Subchapter S, An Entrepreneurial Survival Strategy for Small Banks,” The Journal of Entrepreneurial Finance, 7 (3): Fall 2002, 53-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Cyree, Ken B., Scott E. Hein, and Timothy W. Koch, “Avoiding Double Taxation: The Case of Commercial Banks,” Unpublished Manuscript, Texas Tech University, July 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Denis, David J., and Atulya Sarlin, “Taxes and the Relative Valuation of S Corporations and C Corporations,” Journal of Applied Finance, Fall/Winter 2002, 5-14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Depken II, Craig A., Harris Hollands, and Steve Swidler, “Do Tax Benefits Conferred to Sub-S Banks Affect Their Deposit or Loan Rates?” Finance Research Letters, 7 (4): December 2010, 238-245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Faccio, Mara, and Jin Xu, “Taxes and Capital Structure,” Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, 50 (3): June 2015, 277-300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Gilbert, R. Alton, and David C. Wheelock, “Measuring Commercial Bank Profitability: Proceed with Caution,” Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis Review, November/December 2007, 515-532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Gilbert, R. Alton, Andrew P. Meyer, and James W. Fuchs, “The Future of Community Banks: Lessons from Banks that Thrived during the Recent Financial Crisis,” Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis Review, March/April 2013, 115-143.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Gollier, Christian, and John W. Pratt, “Risk Vulnerability and the Tempering Effect of Background Risk,” Econometrica, 64 (5): September 1996, 1109-1123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Graham, John R. “Taxes and Corporate Finance: A Review,” The Review of Financial Studies, 16 (4): Winter 2003, 1075-1129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Harvey, James, and Jane Padget, “Subchapter S - A New Tool for Enhancing the Value of Community Banks,” Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City Financial Industry Perspective, December 2000, 17-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Hemmelgarn, Thomas, and Daniel Teichmann, “Tax Reforms and the Capital Structure of Banks,” International Tax and Public Finance, 21 (4): August 2014, 645-693.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Hodder, Leslie, Mary Lea McAnally, and Connie D. Weaver, “The Influence of Tax and Nontax Factors on Banks’ Choice of Organizational Form,” The Accounting Review, 78 (1): January 2003, 297-325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">International Monetary Fund, Global Financial Stability Report - Risk Taking, Liquidity, and Shadow Banking: Curbing Excess While Promoting Growth, Washington DC, October 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Kashyap, Anil K., and Jeremy C. Stein, “What Do a Million Observations on Banks Say about the Transmission of Monetary Policy?” American Economic Review, 90 (3): 407-428, June 2000,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Lang, Larry, Eli Ofek, and René M. Stulz. “Leverage, Investment, and Firm Growth,” Journal of Financial Economics, 40 (1): July 1996: 3-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Lin, Leming, and Mark J. Flannery, “Do Personal Taxes Affect Capital Structure? Evidence from the 2003 Tax Cut,” Journal of Financial Economics, 109 (2): August 2013, 549-565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Mackie-Mason, Jeffrey K. and Roger H. Gordon, “How Much Do Taxes Discourage Incorporation?” Journal of Finance 52 (2): June 1997, 477-505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Mehran, Hamid, and Michael Suher, “The Impact of Tax Law Changes on Bank Dividend Policy, Sell-Offs, Organizational Form, and Industry Structure,” Federal Reserve Bank of New York Staff Report No. 369, April 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Saunders, Anthony, Elizabeth Strock, and Nickolas G. Travlos, “Ownership Structure, Deregulation, and Bank Risk Taking,” The Journal of Finance, 45 (2): June 1990, 643-654.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Slemrod, Joel, “Income Creation or Income Shifting? Behavioral Responses to the Tax Reform Act of 1986,” American Economic Review, 85 (2): May 1995, 175-180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Stiroh, Keven J., “Diversification in Banking: Is Noninterest Income the Answer?” Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, 36 (5): October 2004, 853-882.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">United States General Accounting Office (GAO), Banking Taxation: Implications of Proposed Revisions Governing S-Corporations on Community Banks, Report to Congressional Committees GAO/GGD-00-159, June 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Yagan, Danny, “Capital Tax Reform and the Real Economy: The Effects of the 2003 Dividend Tax Cut,” American Economic Review, 105 (12): December 2015, 3531-3563.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Probability of Electing the S-Corporation Status, 1997-2000</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Summary Statistics of Analysis Sample by Type of Banks, 1997</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Difference-in-Differences Regressions with Publicly Traded Banks as Control</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Difference-in-Differences Regressions with Privately Held Banks as Control</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Leverage Ratio and Portfolio Compositions, 1999-2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>C-Corporation and S-Corporation Banks by Asset Decile, 2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Tax Rates and Return on S-Corporation Conversion, 1996-2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
