<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794466</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Tax Planning Consequences</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Are Multinational Companies “Fooled” by Their Own Tax Planning?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>De Simone</surname>
                  <given-names>Lisa</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Klassen</surname>
                  <given-names>Kenneth J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Seidman</surname>
                  <given-names>Jeri K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>32</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794466"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Badertscher, B., N. Shroff, and H.D. White, 2013. Externalities of public firm pressure: Evidence from private firms’ investment decisions. Journal of Financial Economics. 109: 682-706.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bem, D.J., 1965. An experimental analysis of self-persuasion. Journal of Experimental Social Psychology. 1: 199–218.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Blouin, J., L. Krull, and L. Robinson, 2014. The location, composition, and investment implications of permanently reinvested earnings. University of Pennsylvania, University of Oregon and Dartmouth College working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Blouin, J., L. Robinson, and J. Seidman, 2016. Conflicting transfer pricing incentives and the role of coordination. Contemporary Accounting Research, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Buettner, T., M. Overesch, and G. Wamser, 2014. Anti profit-shifting rules and foreign direct investment. CESifo Working paper No. 4710.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Chen, C., B. Hepfer, P. Quinn, and R. Wilson, 2017. The effect of income shifting on the information environment: Evidence from two-stage least squares and SFAS 131. University of Illinois, Texas A&amp;M University, University of Washington and University of Illinois working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Cook, Jr., P., 1955. Decentralization and the transfer-pricing problem. Journal of Business 28: 87-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Daniel, K., D. Hirschleifer, and A. Subrahmanyam. 1998. Investor psychology and security market under- and overreactions. Journal of Finance. 53(6): 1839-1885.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Dean, J., 1955. Decentralization and intra-company pricing. Harvard Business Review 33: 65-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">De Simone, L., 2016. Does a common set of accounting standards affect tax-motivated income shifting for multinational firms? Journal of Accounting and Economics 61: 135-165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">De Simone, L., K. Klassen, and J. Seidman, 2017. Unprofitable affiliates and income shifting behavior. The Accounting Review 92: 113-136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Dharmapala, D., and N. Riedel, 2013. “Earnings shocks and tax-motivated income-shifting: Evidence from European multinationals,” Journal of Public Economics 97(1): 95-107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Donohoe, M.P., G.A. McGill, and E. Outslay, 2012. Through a glass darkly: What can we learn about a U.S. multinational coporation’s international operations from its financial statement disclosure? National Tax Journal 65(4): 961-984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Dyreng, S., and B. Lindsey, 2009. Using financial accounting data to examine the effect of foreign operations located in tax havens and other countries on U.S. multinational firms’ tax rates. Journal of Accounting Research 47: 1283-1316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">EY, 2013. Navigating the Choppy Waters of International Tax: 2013 Global Transfer Pricing Survey. Available at tinyurl.com/l47jp5n</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Erickson, M., M. Hanlon, and E. Maydew, 2004. How much will firms pay for earnings that do not exist? Evidence of taxes paid on allegedly fraudulent earnings. The Accounting Review 79: 387-408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Gallemore, J., and E. Labro, 2015. The importance of the internal information environment for tax avoidance. Journal of Accounting and Economics 60: 149-167.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Halperin, R., and B. Srinidhi, 1987. The effect of the U.S. income tax regulations’ transfer pricing rules on allocative efficiency. The Accounting Review 62: 686-706.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Halperin, R., and B. Srinidhi, 1991. U.S. income tax transfer-pricing rules and resource allocation: the case of decentralized multinational firms. The Accounting Review 66: 141-157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Hanlon, M., and S. Heitzman, 2010. A review of tax research. Journal of Accounting and Economics 50: 127-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Hiemann, M. and S. Reichelstein, 2012. Transfer pricing in multinational corporations: An integrated management- and tax perspective. in Schön, W., and K. Konrad, Eds. Fundamentals of International Transfer Pricing in Law and Economics. Berlin: Springer</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Hines, J. R. and E. M. Rice, 1994. Fiscal paradise: foreign tax havens and American business.The Quarterly Journal of Economics 109: 149-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Hirshleifer, J., 1956. On the economics of transfer pricing. Journal of Business 29: 172-184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Hirshleifer, J., 1957. Economics of the divisionalized firm. Journal of Business 30: 96-108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Huizinga, H., and L. Laeven, 2008. International profit shifting within multinationals: A multicountry perspective. Journal of Public Economics 92: 1164-1182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Huizinga, H., L. Laeven, and G. Nicodeme. 2008. Capital structure and internal debt shifting.Journal of Financial Economics 88: 80-118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Klassen, K., M. Lang, and M. Wolfson, 1993. Geographic income shifting by multinational corporations in response to tax rate changes. Journal of Accounting Research 31: 141-173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Klassen, K., and S. Laplante, 2012. “Are U.S. multinational corporations becoming more aggressive income shifters?” Journal of Accounting Research 50(5): 1245–1285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Klassen, K., P. Lisowsky, and D. Mescall, 2017. Transfer pricing: Strategies, practices and tax minimization. Contemporary Accounting Research 34: 455-493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Malmendier, U. and G. Tate, 2005. CEO overconfidence and corporate investment. Journal of Finance 60: 2661–2700.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Markle, K., 2016. A comparison of the tax-motivated income shifting of multinationals in territorial and worldwide countries. Contemporary Accounting Research 33: 7-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Markle, K., L.F. Mills, and B. Williams, 2017. Implicit corporate taxes and income shifting.University of Texas, Austin working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">McNichols, M., and S. Stubben, 2008. Does earnings management affect firms’ investment decisions? The Accounting Review 83: 1571-1603.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Samuelson, L., 1982. The multinational firm with arm’s length transfer price limits. Journal of International Economics 31: 365-374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Sansing, R. 2014. International transfer pricing. Foundations and Trends in Accounting 9: 1-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Springsteel, I. 1999. Separate but unequal. CFO Magazine 15: 89–91, August 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Shroff, N., R. Verdi, and G. Yu. 2015. Information environment and the investment decisions of multinational corporations. The Accounting Review 89: 759-790.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Weiner, B., 1985. An attribution theory of achievement motivation and emotion. Psychological Review 92: 548-573.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Affiliate-Year Sample Selection to Estimate G</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Description of Affiliate-Year Sample Used to Estimate G</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Results of Estimating G</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Firm-year Sample Selection to Test Hypothesis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Compustat Firm-Year Sample Used to Test Hypothesis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Correlations of Variables Used in Hypothesis Test</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Determinants of Investment</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
