<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90023233</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>International Tax Policy, Reform and Innovation</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CROSS-COUNTRY EVIDENCE ON THE PRELIMINARY EFFECTS OF PATENT BOX REGIMES ON PATENT ACTIVITY AND OWNERSHIP</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bradley</surname>
                  <given-names>Sebastien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Department of Economics, LeBow College of Business, Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Dauchy</surname>
                  <given-names>Estelle</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>New Economic School, Moscow, Russia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Robinson</surname>
                  <given-names>Leslie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Tuck School of Business at Dartmouth, Hanover, NH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>108</volume>
         <issue-id>e90023147</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>30</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90023233"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper takes a first step at evaluating whether patent box regimes achieve their primary stated objectives: namely, stimulating domestic innovation and containing (or retaining) mobile patent income in order to limit base erosion. To do this, we estimate whether these policies increase the attractiveness of a country as a location for patenting domestic innovations or as a location for patent <italic>ownership</italic>. Furthermore, we examine the extent to which patent box regimes influence the prevalence of cross-border relationships between patent owners and inventors on new patent applications, with a particular focus on ownership involving tax havens—an outcome commonly viewed as a consequence of tax planning. We find that despite their lack of nexus requirements, patent box regimes appear to have been relatively successful at achieving their first objective—increasing new patent applications by an average of 3 percent for every percentage point reduction in the tax rate on patent income. We find no evidence of any significant impact of these regimes on deterring outward attribution of patent ownership, nor on attracting ownership of foreign inventions, at least in the short period since they were put in place. Increased patent activity hence appears to be focused on inventions involving co-located domestic inventors and owners.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>patent box</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>tax policy</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>innovation</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>base erosion</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Böhm, Tobias, Tom Karkinsky, Bodo Knoll, and Nadine Riedel, 2015. “Corporate Taxes and Strategic Patent Location within Multinational Firms.” Working Paper, March.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dauchy, Estelle, 2013. “The Efficiency Cost of Asset Taxation in the U.S. after Accounting for Intangible Assets.” NES-CEFIR Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dischinger, Matthias, and Nadine Riedel, 2011. “Corporate Taxes and the Location of Intangible Assets within Multinational Firms.” Journal of Public Economics 95, 691-707.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ernst, Christof, Katharina Richter, and Nadine Riedel, 2014. “Corporate Taxation and the Quality of Research and Development.” International Tax and Public Finance, 21. (ED)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ernst, Christof and Christoph Spengel, 2011. “Taxation, R&amp;D Tax Incentives, and Patent Applications in Europe.” ZEW Discussion Paper No. 11-024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evers, Lisa, Helen Miller, and Christoph Spengel, 2014. “Intellectual Property Box Regimes: Effective Tax Rates and Tax Policy Considerations” International Tax and Public Finance, June. (ED)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Graetz, Michael and Rachael Doud, 2013. “Technological Innovation, International Competition, and the Challenges of International Income Taxation.” Columbia Law Review, 113, 347-445.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Griffith, Rachel, Helen Miller, and Martin O’Connell, 2014. “Ownership of Intellectual Property and Corporate Taxation.” Journal of Public Economics 112, 12-23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grubert, Harry, 2003. “Intangible Income, Intercompany Transactions, Income Shifting and the Choice of Location.” National Tax Journal 56(1), 221-242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hines, James R., Jr., 1998. “International Taxation and Corporate R&amp;D: Evidence and Implications.” Borderline Case: International Tax Policy, Corporate Research and Development, and Investment. James Poterba ed.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hines, James R. Jr., 2010. “Treasure Islands.” Journal of Economic Perspectives, 24(2), 103-126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karkinsky, Tom and Nadine Riedel, 2012. “Corporate Taxation and the Choice of Patent Location Within Multinational Firms.” Journal of International Economics, 88, 176-185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kleinbard, E., 2012. “Stateless Income’s Challenge to Tax Policy, Part 2.” Tax Notes International, 12 (Nov), 671-687.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merrill, Peter R. and James R. Shanahan, Jr., 2012. “Is It Time for the United States to Consider the Patent Box?” Tax Notes, March 26, 1665-1675.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, 1996. “Fiscal Measures to Promote R&amp;D and Innovation.” OCDE/GD(96)165. Paris: OECD.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, Walter G., 2008. “International Patent Protection: 1960–2005.” Research Policy, 37, 761-766.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Quick, P.D., Day, T.L., 2006. “Management of IP: Intercompany Transfers, Offshore Planning and Recent Developments Regarding Cost-Sharing.” The Licensing Journal 1, 14–21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back> 
</article>
