<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284846</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Assessment of Advanced SGS Models for LES Analysis of ICE Wall-Bounded Flows - Part I</article-title>
            <subtitle>Basic Test Case</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Catellani</surname>
                  <given-names>Cristian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bianchi</surname>
                  <given-names>Gian Marco</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Falfari</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefania</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cazzoli</surname>
                  <given-names>Giulio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Forte</surname>
                  <given-names>Claudio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Bologna</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>657</fpage>
         <lpage>673</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284846"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Large Eddy Simulation (LES) represents nowadays one of the most promising techniques for the evaluation of the dynamics and evolution of turbulent structures characterizing internal combustion engines (ICE). In the present paper, subdivided into two parts, the capabilities of the open-source CFD code<italic>OpenFOAM</italic>® v2.3.0 are assessed in order to evaluate its suitability for engine cold flow LES analyses. Firstly, the code dissipative attitude is evaluated through an inviscid vortex convection test to ensure that the levels of numerical dissipation are compatible with LES needs. Quality and completeness estimators for LES simulations are then proposed. In particular the Pope M parameter is used as a LES completeness indicator while the LSR parameter provides useful insights far calibrating the grid density. Other parameters such as the two-grid<italic>LES<sub>IQk</sub>
               </italic>index are also discussed. Then advanced SGS models such as the dynamic WALE and the Sigma models are compared with models traditionally used for LES simulations of ICE wall-bounded flows, i.e. the dynamic Smagorinsky and the WALE models. The proposed SGS models have been implemented in the open-source CFD code<italic>OpenFOAM</italic>®, extending its standard capabilities. Validation of the implemented models has been performed using two different test cases: the Dellenback abrupt expansion, which is presented in part I, and the Thobois stationary flow bench, presented in part II. The results have been evaluated through comparison with experimental data and the completeness of the LES simulations has been assessed using the aforementioned quality estimators.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thobois, L., Rymer, G., Soulères, T., and Poinsot, T., "Large-Eddy Simulation in IC Engine Geometries," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01- 1854, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1854.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thobois L., Rymer G., Souleres T., Poinsot T., and Van Den Heuvel B. . Large-eddy simulation for the prediction of aerodynamics in ic engines. International Journal of Vehicle Design, 39(4):368-382, January 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusiani, F., Forte, C., and Bianchi, G., "Assessment of a Numerical Methodology for Large Eddy Simulation of ICE Wall Bounded Non-Reactive Flows," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4145, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusiani, F. and Bianchi, G., "LES Simulation of ICE Non-Reactive Flows in Fixed Grids," SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0959, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piscaglia F., Montorfano A., Onorati A., and Brusiani F.. Boundary conditions and sgs models for les of wall-bounded separated flows: An application to engine-like geometries. Oil Gas Sci. Technol. - Rev. IFP Energies nouvelles, 69(1):11-27, January 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keskinen, J., Vuorinen, V., and Larmi, M., "Large Eddy Simulation of Flow over a Valve in a Simplified Cylinder Geometry," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0843, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keskinen, J., Vuorinen, V., Kaario, O., and Larmi, M., "Large Eddy Simulation of the Intake Flow in a Realistic Single Cylinder Configuration," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0137, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0137.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huijnen V., Olbricht C., Sadiki A., Somers L. M., Baert R. S., Janicka J., and de Goey L. P.. Study of turbulent flow structures of a practical steady engine head flow using large-eddy simulations. Journal of Fluids Engineering, 128(6):1181-1191, April 2006. ISSN 0098-2202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moureau, V., Barton, I., Angelberger, C., and Poinsot, T., "Towards Large Eddy Simulation in Internal-Combustion Engines: Simulation of a Compressed Tumble Flow," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1995, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, K. and Haworth, D., "Development and Assessment of POD for Analysis of Turbulent Flow in Piston Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0830, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0830.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benoit Enaux, Victor Granet, Olivier Vermorel, Corine Lacour, Ludovic Thobois, Vincent Dugu, and Thierry Poinsot. Large eddy simulation of a motored single-cylinder piston engine: Numerical strategies and validation. SAE, 86(2):153-177-, 2011. ISSN 1386-6184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haworth D.C. and Jansen K.. Large-eddy simulation on unstructured deforming meshes: towards reciprocating ic engines. Computers &amp; Fluids, 29(5):493-524, June 2000. ISSN 0045-7930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haworth, D. C. Large-eddy simulation of in-cylinder flows. Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology - Rev. IFP, 54(2):175-185, 1999. doi: 10.2516/ogst:1999012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thobois, L., Lauvergne, R., and Poinsot, T., "Using LES to Investigate Reacting Flow Physics in Engine Design Process," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0166, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richard S., Colin O., Vermorel O., Benkenida A., Angelberger C., and Veynante D.. Towards large eddy simulation of combustion in spark ignition engines. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 31(2):3059 - 3066, 2007. ISSN 1540-7489. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.proci.2006.07.086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vermorel O., Richard S., Colin O., Angelberger C., Benkenida A., and Veynante D.. Towards the understanding of cyclic variability in a spark ignited engine using multi-cycle {LES}. Combustion and Flame, 156(8):1525 - 1541, 2009. ISSN 0010-2180. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.combustflame.2009.04.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stephen B Pope. Ten questions concerning the large-eddy simulation of turbulent flows. New Journal of Physics, 6(1):35, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Celik IB, Cehreli ZN, and Yavuz I. Index of resolution quality for large eddy simulations. Journal of Fluids Engineering, 127(5):949-, 2005. ISSN 00982202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Francesca di Mare, Robert Knappstein, and Michael Baumann. Application of les-quality criteria to internal combustion engine flows. Computers &amp; Fluids, 89(0):200 - 213, 2014. ISSN 0045-7930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brusiani, F., Bianchi, G., Baritaud, T., and d’Espinosa, A., "Using LES for Predicting High Performance Car Airbox Flow," SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 2(1):1050-1064, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Charles Hirsch, editor. Numerical Computation of Internal and External Flows: Fundamentals of Numerical Discretization. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., New York, NY, USA, 1988. ISBN 0-471-91762-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nicoud F. and Ducros F.. Subgrid-scale stress modelling based on the square of the velocity gradient tensor. Flow, Turbulence and Combustion, 62(3): 183-200, 1999. ISSN 1386-6184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abraham, P., Liu, K., Haworth, D., Reuss, D., and Sick, V. Evaluating large-eddy simulation (les) and high-speed particle image velocimetry (piv) with phase-invariant proper orthogonal decomposition (pod). Oil Gas Sci. Technol. - Rev. IFP Energies nouvelles, 69(1):41-59, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Plengsaard, C. and Rutland, C., "Improved Engine Wall Models for Large Eddy Simulation (LES)," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1097, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1097.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Misdariis, A., Robert, A., Vermorel, O., Richard, S., and Poinsot, T. Numerical methods and turbulence modeling for les of piston engines: Impact on flow motion and combustion. Oil Gas Sci. Technol. - Rev. IFP Energies nouvelles, 69(1):83-105, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BayaToda H., Truffin K., and Nicoud F.. Is the dynamic procedure appropriate for all sgs models? In Poceedings of ECCOMAS CFD 2010. ECCOMAS, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baya Toda H., Cabrit O., Balarac G., Bose S., Lee J., Choi H., and Nicoud F.. A subgrid-scale model based on singular values for les in complex geometries. In Poceedings of Summer Program 2010. Center for Turbulence Research, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weller H. G., Tabor G., Jasak H., and Fureby C.. A tensorial approach to computational continuum mechanics using object-oriented techniques. Comput. Phys., 12(6):620-631, 1998. ISSN 0894-1866.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">OpenFOAM Foundation. OpenFOAM-2.3.0 Programmer’s Guide. OpenFOAM Foundation, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dellenback P. A., Metzger D. E., and Neitzel G. P.. Measurements in turbulent swirling flow through an abrupt axisymmetric expansion. AIAA Journal, 26(6):669-681, June 1988. ISSN 0001-1452. doi: 10.2514/3.9952.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Germano Massimo, Piomelli Ugo, Moin Parviz, and Cabot William H.. A dynamic subgrid scale eddy viscosity model. Physics of Fluids A: Fluid Dynamics (1989-1993), 3(7):1760-1765, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lilly D. K.. A proposed modification of the germano subgrid-scale closure method. Physics of Fluids, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vreman A. W.. An eddy-viscosity subgrid-scale model for turbulent shear flow: Algebraic theory and applications. Physics of Fluids (1994-present), 16(10):3670-3681, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jukka-Pekka Keskinen, Ville Vuorinen, Ossi Kaario, Martti Larmi. Effects of mesh deformation on the quality of large eddy simulations. In Fluid Dynamics and Co-located Conferences, pages -. American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, June 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SB Pope. Turbulent flows. Cambridge University Press, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Durbin Paul and Pettersson Reif B.A.. Statistical theory and modeling for turbulent flows. Wiley, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferziger J.H. and Peric M.. Computational Methods for Fluid Dynamics. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yee H. C., Vinokur M., and Djomehri M. J.. Entropy splitting and numerical dissipation. J. Comput. Phys., 162(1):33-81, July 2000. ISSN 0021-9991. doi: 10.1006/jcph.2000.6517.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parthib, R. Rao and Laura, A. Schaefer. Numerical stability of explicit off-lattice boltzmann schemes: A comparative study. Journal of Computational Physics, 285(0):251-264, March 2015. ISSN 0021-9991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vuorinen V., Keskinen J.-P., Duwig C., and Boersma B.J.. On the implementation of low-dissipative runge-kutta projection methods for time dependent flows using openfoam. Computers &amp; Fluids, 93(0):153- 163, April 2014. ISSN 0045-7930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moureau V., Lartigue G., Sommerer Y., Angelberger C., Colin O., and Poinsot T.. Numerical methods for unsteady compressible multicomponent reacting flows on fixed and moving grids. Journal of Computational Physics, 202(2):710-736, January 2005. ISSN 0021- 9991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John, B. Heywood. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. Mcgraw-Hill, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">John, L. Lumley. Engines: An Introduction. Cambridge University Press, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuo, Tang-Wei, Yang, Xiaofeng, Gopalakrishnan, Venkatesh, and Chen, Zhaohui. Large eddy simulation (les) for ic engine flows. Oil Gas Sci. Technol. - Rev. IFP Energies nouvelles, 69(1):61-81, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B. and Ghandhi, J., "High Resolution Scalar Dissipation and Turbulence Length Scale Measurements in an Internal Combustion Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):65-83, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01- 0185.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heim, D. and Ghandhi, J., "A Detailed Study of In-Cylinder Flow and Turbulence using PIV," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1642-1668, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1287.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schlter J. U., Pitsch H., and Moin P.. Large-eddy simulation inflow conditions for coupling with reynoldsaveraged flow solvers. AIAA Journal, 42(3):478-484, March 2004. ISSN 0001-1452. doi: 10.2514/1.3488.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ardalan Javadi and Hakan Nilsson. Les and des of strongly swirling turbulent flow through a suddenly expanding circular pipe. Computers &amp; Fluids, 107: 301-313, 2015. ISSN 0045-7930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piscaglia, F., Montorfano, A., and Onorati, A., "A Scale Adaptive Filtering Technique for Turbulence Modeling of Unsteady Flows in IC Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(2):426-436, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01- 0395.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walter Gyllenram and Hkan Nilsson. Design and validation of a scaleadaptive filtering technique for lrn turbulence modeling of unsteady flow. Journal of Fluid Engineering, Volume 130:10, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
