<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284922</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Prechamber Hot Jet Ignition of Ultra-Lean H₂/Air Mixtures</article-title>
            <subtitle>Effect of Supersonic Jets and Combustion Instability</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Biswas</surname>
                  <given-names>Sayan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Qiao</surname>
                  <given-names>Li</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Purdue University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>September 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284904</issue-id>
         <fpage>1584</fpage>
         <lpage>1592</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284922"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>An experiment has been developed to investigate the ignition characteristics of ultra-lean premixed H₂/air mixtures by a supersonic hot jet. The hot jet is generated by combustion of a stoichiometric mixture in a small prechamber. The apparatus adopted a dual-chamber design in which a small-volume (1% of the main chamber by volume) prechamber was installed within a large-volume main chamber. A small orifice (nozzle) connects the two chambers. Spark initiated combustion inside the prechamber causes a pressure rise and pushes the gases though the nozzle, resulting in a hot jet that would ignite the lean mixture in the main chamber. Simultaneous high-speed Schlieren photography and OH* Chemiluminescence were applied to visualize the jet penetration and the ignition processes inside the main chamber. Hot Wire Pyrometry (HWP) was used to measure temperature distribution of the transient hot jet. A novel velocity measurement technique based on Schlieren PIV (SPIV) has also been developed to characterize the local flow field. Three nozzle geometries (straight, convergent and converging-diverging) have been studied to understand their effect on ignition probability and characteristics. The results show that a supersonic jet by using a converging-diverging nozzle can ignite leaner mixtures than the jet produced by a straight nozzle of the same throat area (e.g., the ignition limit is reduced to<italic>ϕ</italic>= 0.22, from 0.35). Additionally, infrared imaging and OH* Chemiluminescence indicated diamond shock structures in the supersonic jets and a high-temperature zone downstream the shocks. This high-temperature zone is likely the reason why the main-chamber flammability limit can be further reduced. Lastly, combustion instability becomes noticeable near the lean-limit conditions for all three types of nozzles, which affect the structural integrity of the combustion chamber. Two instable frequency modes, natural frequency of the combustor at 180 Hz and a higher mode at 2400 Hz were observed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kartay E. "Recent advances in production of hydrogen from biomass". Energy Convers Manag 2011;52(4):1778 e 89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zuttel A, Remhof A, Borgschulte A, Friedrichs O. “Hydrogen: the future energy carrier”. Philos Trans R Soc A 2010;368:3329 e 42.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schindler J, Grube T, Stolten D. “National strategies and programs”. In: 18th World hydrogen energy conference 2010 WHEC 2010, Essen, Germany; 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Korakianitis, T., Namasivayam, A.M., Crookes, R.J., “Natural- Gas Fueled Spark-Ignition (SI) and Compression-Ignition (CI) Engine Performance and Emissions”, Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 37 (1), Elsevier Ltd: 89-112, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2010.04.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, New York: McGraw-Hill Inc, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klausmeyer, U., Beyer, M., “Enhancement of The Safety of Flameproof Containments by Clarifying The Flame Transmission Phenomena”, International Symposium on Hazardous, Prevention and Mitigation of Industrial Explosions, p. 7.41-7.52, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, M. P., Mcmillin, B.K., Palmer, J.L., Hanson, R.K., “Planar Fluorescence Imaging of a Transverse Jet in a Supersonic Crossflow”, Journal of Propulsion and Power 8 (4), 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murase, E., Ono, S., Hanada, K., Oppenheim, A.K., “Initiation of Combustion in Lean Mixtures by Flame Jets”, Combustion Science and Technology 113 (1): 167-77, 1996, doi:10.1080/00102209608935492.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dobski, T. J.R., Wawrzyniak, J., “The Analysis of The Process of Combustion of Natural Gases of High Molar Fraction Nitrogen in Reciprocating Gas Engines”, 7th Dessau Gas Engine Conference. Dessau, Germany, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Phillips, H., “A Nondimensional Parameter Characterizing Mixing Processes in a Model of Thermal Gas Ignition”, Combustion and Flame 19: p. 181-86, 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, D. Y., Ghoniem, A. F., Oppenheim, A. K., “Experimental and Theoretical Study of Combustion and Jet Ignition”, NASA CR-168139 (DOE/NASA/0131-1), pp. 1-130, March, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yamaguchi, S., Ohiwa, N., Hasegawa, T., “Ignition and Burning Process in a Divided Chamber Bomb”, Combustion and Flame 59(2): p. 177- 187, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Djebaili, N., Lisbet, R., Dupre, G., Paillard, C., “Ignition of a Combustible Mixture by a Hot Unsteady Gas Jet”, Combustion Science and Technology 104 (4-6): 273-85, 1995, doi:10.1080/00102209508907724.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elhsnawi, M., Teodorczyk, A., “Studies of Mixing and Ignition in Hydrogen-Oxygen Mixture with Hot Inert Gas Injection”, Proceedings of the European Combustion Meeting, Warsaw University of Technology ITC, Nowowiejska 21/25, 00-665 Warszawa, Poland, p. 4-9, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sadanandan, R., Schiebl, R.A., Markus, D., Maas, U., “2D Mixture Fraction Studies in a Hot-Jet Ignition Configuration Using NO-LIF and Correlation Analysis”, Flow, Turbulence and Combustion 86 (1): 45-62, 2010, doi:10.1007/s10494-010-9285-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sadanandan, R., Stöhr, M., Meier, W., “Simultaneous OH-PLIF and PIV Measurements in a Gas Turbine Model Combustor”, Applied Physics B 90 (3-4): 609-18, 2008. doi:10.1007/s00340-007-2928-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Fraser, N., Parsons, P., and Toulson, E., "A Turbulent Jet Ignition Pre-Chamber Combustion System for Large Fuel Economy Improvements in a Modern Vehicle Powertrain," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):20-37, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Huisjen, A., Chen, X., Squibb, C. et al., "Visualization of Propane and Natural Gas Spark Ignition and Turbulent Jet Ignition Combustion," SAE Int. J. Engines 5(4):1821-1835, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-32-0002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gentz Gerald, Thelen Bryce, Gholamisheeri Masumeh, Litke Paul, "A study of the influence of orifice diameter on a turbulent jet ignition system through combustion visualization and performance characterization in a rapid compression machine", Applied Thermal Engineering 81 (2015) 399-411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lieuwen Timothy., Yang V., Combustion Instabilities in Gas Turbine Engines, Progress in Astronautics and Aeronautics, AIAA, September 30, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lieuwen Timothy, Unsteady Combustor Physics, Cambridge University Press, 1 edition, August 27, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, A., Tunestal, P., and Johansson, B., "Applicability of Ionization Current Sensing Technique with Plasma Jet Ignition Using Pre-Chamber Spark Plug in a Heavy Duty Natural Gas Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1632, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1632.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, A., Tunestål, P., and Johansson, B., "CFD Simulations of Pre- Chamber Jets' Mixing Characteristics in a Heavy Duty Natural Gas Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1890, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015- 01-1890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
