<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308320</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Work-Based Window Method for Calculating In-Use Brake-Specific NOx Emissions of Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shade</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Carder</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Thompson</surname>
                  <given-names>Gregory J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gautam</surname>
                  <given-names>Mridul</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>West Virginia University</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>778</fpage>
         <lpage>793</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308320"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A work-based window method has been developed to calculate in-use brake-specific oxides of nitrogen (NOx) emissions for all engine speeds and engine loads. During an in-use test, engine speed and engine torque are read from the engine’s electronic control unit, and along with time, are used to determine instantaneous engine power. Instantaneous work is calculated using this power and the time differential in the data collection. Work is then summed until the target amount of work is accumulated. The emissions levels are then calculated for that window of work. It was determined that a work window equal to the theoretical Federal Test Procedure (FTP) cycle work best provides a means of comparison to the FTP certification standard. Also, a failure criterion has been established based on the average amount of power generated in the work window and the amount of time required to achieve the target work window to determine if a particular work window is valid.</p>
            <p>Data collected during Phase IV of West Virginia University’s in-use testing program were used to show that the work window method produces in-use brake-specific NOx values similar to the 30 second Not-To-Exceed (NTE) window method, which was applicable at the time of testing, and the continuous NTE window method over different highway and urban test routes for a variety of engine configurations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Code of Federal Regulations, Title 40, Part 86, ubpart N – Emission Regulations for New Otto- ycle and Diesel Heavy-Duty Engines; Gaseous nd Particulate Exhaust Test Procedures, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Code of Federal Regulations, Title 40, Part 1065 – ngine Testing Procedures, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shimpi, S., “US Engine Manufacturer Views on In- se Testing,” JRC Transport and Emissions onference, Milan, Italy, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“DieselNet: Diesel Emissions Online,” ttp://www.dieselnet.com, Ecopoint, Inc., 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Consent Decree, United States of America v. aterpillar, Inc., Civil Action 98-02544, 1998</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Consent Decree, United States of America v. ummins Engine Company, Inc., Civil Action 98- 02546, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Consent Decree, United States of America v. Detroit iesel Corporation, Civil Action 98-02548, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Consent Decree, United States of America v. Mack rucks, Inc. and Renault Vehicules Industriels, s. a., ivil Action 98-02543, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Consent Decree, United States of America v. avistar International Transportation Corporation, ivil Action 98-02545, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Consent Decree, United States of America v. Volvo ruck Corporation, Civil Action 98-02547, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Horiba MEXA-720 NOx Instruction Manual,” Horiba, td., Japan, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gautam, M., W. C. Riddle, G. J. Thompson, D. K. arder, N. N. Clark, and D. W. Lyons, “Measurement of Brake-Specific NOx Emissions sing Zirconia Sensors for In-Use, On-Board, eavy-Duty Vehicle Applications,” SAE Technical aper 2002-01-1755, Warrendale, PA, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“HORIBA Engine Measurement Division: BE-140 AD – Five-Gas Bench,” ttp://www.emd.horiba.com/engmeas/be140ad/index .htm, Horiba, Ltd., Ann Arbor, MI, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gautam, M., N. N. Clark, G. J. Thompson, D. K. arder, and D. W. Lyons, “Evaluation of Mobile onitoring Technologies for Heavy-Duty Diesel- owered Vehicle Emissions,” Phase I Report, ttp://www.epa.gov/compliance/resources/cases/civi /caa/diesel/phasei.pdf, Submitted to the Settling eavy-Duty Diesel Engine Manufacturers by West irginia University, Morgantown, WV, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heinein, N. A. and D. J. Patterson, “Emissions and ombustion Engines,” Ann Arbor Science ublishers, Inc., 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Pond Technical Sales – Dieterich Standard, Inc. – lowmeters,” ttp://www.pondtechnicalsales.com/products_dieteri h.htm, Pond Technical Sales, Inc., 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Dearborn Protocol Adapters let You interconnect erial communication networks and PC computers sing CAN (canbus), GMLAN, GMU,” ttp://www.dgtech.com/product/dpa/dpa.php#DPA4, earborn Group, Inc., 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice: Joint AE/TMC Electronic Data Interchange Between icrocomputer Systems In Heavy-Duty Vehicle pplications,” SAE J1587, Warrendale, PA, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Surface Vehicle Recommended Practice: ecommended Practice for Serial Control and ommunications Vehicle Network – Part 81 – etwork Management,” SAE J1939-81, Warrendale, A, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolyard, J. D., “Evaluation of an Air-to-Fuel Ratio erived Exhaust Flow Rate for In-Use Emissions esting,” M. S. Thesis, ttp://kitkat.wvu.edu:8080/files/4302/Bolyard_Jason_hesis.pdf, Department of Mechanical and erospace Engineering, West Virginia University, organtown, WV, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Data Link Monitor lets You validate in-vehicle etwork interfaces using CAN (canbus), GMLAN, 1587, J1708, J1850 GM (Class 2), GMLAN, GMU,” ttp://www.dgtech.com/product/dlm/dlm.php, earborn Group, Inc., 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gautam, M., N. N. Clark, G. J. Thompson, D. K. arder, and D. W. Lyons, “Development of In-Use rocedures for Heavy-Duty Diesel Powered Vehicle missions,” Phase II Report, ttp://www.epa.gov/compliance/resources/cases/civi /caa/diesel/phaseii.pdf, Submitted to the Settling eavy-Duty Diesel Engine Manufacturers by West irginia University, Morgantown, WV, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">United States Environmental Protection Agency, ffice of Transportation and Air Quality, “In-Use esting Program for Heavy-Duty Diesel Engines and ehicles,” Technical Support Document, EPA420-R- 05-006, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spears, M., “NTE for Nonroad Diesel Engines,” US PA Presentation, Calibrations Standards Task orce Meeting, Ann Arbor, MI, Jul 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Draft Regulatory Impact Analysis – Chapter 4 ‘Technologies and Test Procedures for Low- mission Engines’,” ttp://www.epa.gov/otaq/cleanernonroad/ 03008e.pdf, United States Environmental rotection Agency, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
