<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26649165</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Influence of Engine Speed and Injection Phasing on Lean Combustion for Different Dilution Rates in an Optically Accessible Wall-Guided Spark Ignition Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Irimescu</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Merola</surname>
                  <given-names>Simona Silvia</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Martinez</surname>
                  <given-names>Santiago</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26649117</issue-id>
         <fpage>1343</fpage>
         <lpage>1370</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26649165"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Alternative combustion control in the form of lean operation offers significant advantages such as high efficiency and “clean” fuel oxidation. Maximum dilution rates are limited by increasing instability that can ultimately lead to partial burning or even misfires. A compromise needs to be reached between high tumble-turbulence levels that “speed-up” combustion and the inherent stochastic nature of this fluid motion. The present study is focused on gaining improved insight into combustion characteristics through thermodynamic analysis and flame imaging, in a wall-guided direct injection spark ignition engine with optical accessibility. Engine speed values were investigated in the range of 1000 to 2000 rpm, with commercial gasoline fueling, in wide open throttle conditions; mixture strength ranged from stoichiometric, down to the equivalence ratios that allowed acceptable cycle-by-cycle variations; and all cases featured spark timing close to the point of maximum brake torque. The effect of injection phasing was also scrutinized, with three different settings of start of injection during the intake stroke. For the “leanest” cases, fuel delivery timing exerted a significant influence on combustion stability; overall performance was comparable for all three settings. These results were further detailed with the evaluation of macro- and micro-characteristics of the flame front, as well as flame intensity that was correlated to the evolution of bulk oxidation and locally rich regions caused by fuel impingement. Natural flame emission spectroscopy revealed that indeed, the nature of the two flame types was related to “normally,” premixed combustion-related propagating fronts in the first case, while for the latter, “soot production” was the driving mechanism. The experimental results were also correlated to simulations of characteristic length within the reaction zone, using a quasi-dimensional approach. Both types of data confirmed a reduction of the characteristic length at high dilution rates, in line with results obtained on burner flames at high pressure.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Castilla Alvarez, C.E., Elias Couto, G., Ruckert Roso, V., Braga Thiriet, A. et al., “A Review of Prechamber Ignition Systems as Lean Combustion Technology for SI Engines,” Appl. Therm. Eng. 128:107-120, 2018, doi:10.1016/j. applthermaleng.2017.08.118.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Fontana, G. and Galloni, E., “Experimental Analysis of a Spark-Ignition Engine Using Exhaust Gas Recycle at WOT Operation,” Appl. Energy 87:2187-2193, 2010, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2009.11.022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Alger, T., Gukelberger, R., and Gingrich, J., “Impact of EGR Quality on the Total Inert Dilution Ratio,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):796-806, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0713.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Wallner, T., Lohse-Busch, H., and Shidore, N., “Operating Strategy for a Hydrogen Engine for Improved Drive-Cycle Efficiency and Emissions Behavior,” Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 34(10):4617-4625, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2008.07.099.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Park, C., Lee, S., Kim, C., and Choi, Y., “A Comparative Study of Lean Burn and Exhaust Gas Recirculation in an HCNG-Fueled Heavy-Duty Engine,” Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 42(41):26094-26101, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2017.08.170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Sjoberg, M. and Zeng, W., “Combined Effects of Fuel and Dilution Type on Efficiency Gains of Lean Well-Mixed DISI Engine Operation with Enhanced Ignition and Intake Heating for Enabling Mixed-Mode Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):750-767, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0689.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Watson, H., Mehrani, P., and Brear, M., “The Always Lean Burn Spark Ignition (ALSI) Engine - Its Performance and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0932, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Wagner, R., Drallmeier, J., and Daw, C., “Prior-Cycle Effects in Lean Spark Ignition Combustion - Fuel/Air Charge Considerations,” SAE Technical Paper 981047, 1998, doi:10.4271/981047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Hanabusa, H., Kondo, T., Hashimoto, K., and Furutani, M., “Study on Cyclic Variations of Laminar Flame Speed in Homogeneous Lean Charge Spark Ignition Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-2173, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016- 01-2173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Kolodziej, C., Pamminger, M., Sevik, J., Wallner, T. et al., “Effects of Fuel Laminar Flame Speed Compared to Engine Tumble Ratio, Ignition Energy, and Injection Strategy on Lean and EGR Dilute Spark Ignition Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 10(1):82-94, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0671.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Peterson, B., Reuss, D.L., and Sick, V., “On the Ignition and Flame Development in a Spray-Guided Direct-Injection Spark-Ignition Engine,” Combust. Flame 161(1):240-255, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2013.08.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Myung, C.L. and Park, S., “Exhaust Nanoparticle Emissions from Internal Combustion Engines: A Review,” Int. J. Automot. Technol. 13(1):9-22, 2012, doi:10.1007/s12239−012−0002−y.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Uberall, A., Otte, R., Eilts, P., and Krahl, J., “A Literature Research about Particle Emissions from Engines with Direct Gasoline Injection and the Potential to Reduce These Emissions,” Fuel 147:203-207, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. fuel.2015.01.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Bertsch, M., Weidenlener, A., Dornhofer, J., Koch, T. et al., “Effect of Implementing Large-Scale Charge Motion, Reducing Hydraulic Flow of the Injector and Increasing Injection Pressure on Particle Emissions of a GDI Engine at WOT and Boosted Operation,” Int. J. Engine Res. 18(5-6):467-489, 2016, doi:10.1177/1468087416670248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Song, J., Kim, T., Jang, J., and Park, S., “Effects of the Injection Strategy on the Mixture Formation and Combustion Characteristics in a DISI (Direct Injection Spark Ignition) Optical Engine,” Energy 93:1758-1768, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2015.10.058.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Gu, X., Shiono, H., Nakaya, S., and Tsue, M., “Ignition Performance of Pulsed Microwave-Assisted Sparks in Lean Methane/Air Mixture,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1898, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1898.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Bresler, M., Attard, W., and Reese, R., “Investigation of Alternative Ignition System Impact on External EGR Dilution Tolerance in a Turbocharged Homogeneous Direct Injected Spark Ignited Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 8(4):1967- 1976, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-9043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Poggiani, C., Cimarello, A., Battistoni, M., Grimaldi, C. et al., “Optical Investigations on a Multiple Spark Ignition System for Lean Engine Operation,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0711, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0711.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Xie, K., Yu, S., Yu, X., Bryden, G. et al., “Investigation of Multi-Pole Spark Ignition under Lean Conditions and with EGR,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0679, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0679.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Tang, Q., Liu, H., Li, M., Yao, M. et al., “Study on Ignition and Flame Development in Gasoline Partially Premixed Combustion Using Multiple Optical Diagnostics,” Combust. Flame 177:98-108, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2016.12.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Aleiferis, P., Taylor, A., Whitelaw, J., Ishii, K. et al., “Cyclic Variations of Initial Flame Kernel Growth in a Honda VTEC-E Lean-Burn Spark-Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1207, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000- 01-1207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Jung, D., Sasaki, K., and Iida, N., “Effects of Increased Spark Discharge Energy and Enhanced In-Cylinder Turbulence Level on Lean Limits and Cycle-to-Cycle Variations of Combustion,” Appl. Energy 205:1467-1477, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2017.08.043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Mostafijur Rahman, K., Kawahara, N., Matsunaga, D., Tomita, E. et al., “Local Fuel Concentration Measurement through Spark-Induced Breakdown Spectroscopy in a Direct-Injection Hydrogen Spark-Ignition Engine,” Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 41(32):14283-14292, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. ijhydene.2016.05.280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Merola, S.S., Di Iorio, S., Irimescu, A., Sementa, P. et al., “Spectroscopic Characterization of Energy Transfer and Thermal Conditions of the Flame Kernel in a Spark Ignition Engine Fueled with Methane and Hydrogen,” Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 42(18):13276-13288, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. ijhydene.2017.03.219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Truffin, K., Angelberger, C., Richard, S., and Pera, C., “Using Large-Eddy Simulation and Multivariate Analysis to Understand the Sources of Combustion Cyclic Variability in a Spark-Ignition Engine,” Combust. Flame 162(12):4371-4390, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2015.07.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Sforza, L., Lucchini, T., Onorati, A., Zhu, X. et al., “Modeling Ignition and Premixed Combustion Including Flame Stretch Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0553, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0553.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Bowditch, F., “A New Tool for Combustion Research a Quartz Piston Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 610002, 1961, doi:10.4271/610002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Merola, S.S., Marchitto, L., Tornatore, C., Valentino, G. et al., “Optical Characterization of Combustion Processes in a DISI Engine Equipped with Plasma-Assisted Ignition System,” Appl. Therm. Eng. 69(1-2):177-187, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2014.04.046.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Irimescu, A., Marchitto, L., Merola, S.S., Tornatore, C. et al., “Evaluation of Different Methods for Combined Thermodynamic and Optical Analysis of Combustion in Spark Ignition Engines,” Energy Convers. Manag. 87:914-927, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2014.07.037.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Martinez, S., Irimescu, A., Merola, S.S., Lacava, P. et al., “Flame Front Propagation in an Optical GDI Engine under Stoichiometric and Lean Burn Conditions,” Energies 10:1337, 2017, doi:10.3390/en10091337.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Iaccarino, S., Breda, S., D’Adamo, A., Fontanesi, S. et al., “Numerical Simulation and Flame Analysis of Combustion and Knock in a DISI Optically Accessible Research Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 10(2):576-592, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0555.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Soika, A., Dinkelacker, F., and Leipertz, A., “Pressure Influence on the Flame Front Curvature of Turbulent Premixed Flames: Comparison between Experiment and Theory,” Combust. Flame 132(3):451-462, 2003, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(02)00490-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Bradley, D., Gaskell, P.H., Sedaghat, A., and Gu, X.J., “Generation of PDFS for Flame Curvature and for Flame Stretch Rate in Premixed Turbulent Combustion,” Combust. Flame 135(4):503-523, 2003, doi:10.1016/S0010- 2180(03)00181-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Merola, S.S., Irimescu, A., Marchitto, L., Tornatore, C. et al., “Effect of Injection Timing on Combustion and Soot Formation in a Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine Fueled with Butanol,” Int. J. Engine Res. 18(5-6):490-504, 2017, doi:10.1177/1468087416671017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals (New York: McGraw Hill, 1988).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Irimescu, A., Tornatore, C., Marchitto, L., and Merola, S.S., “Compression Ratio and Blow-By Rates Estimation Based on Motored Pressure Trace Analysis for an Optical Spark Ignition Engine,” Appl. Therm. Eng. 61(2):101-109, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2013.07.036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Irimescu, A., Merola, S.S., and Valentino, G., “Application of an Entrainment Turbulent Combustion Model with Validation Based on the Distribution of Chemical Species in an Optical,” Appl. Energy 162:908-923, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2015.10.136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Merola, S.S., Irimescu, A., Tornatore, C., and Valentino, G., “Effect of the Fuel-Injection Strategy on Flame-Front Evolution in an Optical Wall-Guided DISI Engine with Gasoline and Butanol Fueling,” J. Energy Eng. 142(2):E4015004, 2015, doi:10.1061/(ASCE)EY.1943- 7897.0000301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <label>39.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Gaydon, A.G., The Spectroscopy of Flames (London: Chapman and Hall, 1957).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <label>40.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Crosley, D.R. and Lengel, R.K., “Relative Transition Probabilities and the Electronic Transition Moment in the A-X System of OH,” J. Quant. Spectrosc. Radiat. Transf. 15(7-8):579-591, 1975, doi:10.1016/0022- 4073(75)90026-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <label>41.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Merola, S., Marchitto, L., Tornatore, C., Valentino, G. et al., “UV-Visible Optical Characterization of the Early Combustion Stage in a DISI Engine Fuelled with Butanol- Gasoline Blend,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(4):1953-1969, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2638.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <label>42.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Hayashida, K., Amagai, K., Satoh, K., and Arai, M., “Experimental Analysis of Soot Formation in Sooting Diffusion Flame by Using Laser-Induced Emissions,” J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power 128(2):241-246, 2006, doi:10.1115/1.2056536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <label>43.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Stewart, S.M., “Spectral Peaks and Wien’s Displacement Law,” J. Thermophys. Heat Transf. 26(4):689-692, 2012, doi:10.2514/1.T3789.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <label>44.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Zhang, Z.M. and Wang, X.J., “Unified Wien’s Displacement Law in Terms of Logarithmic Frequency or Wavelength Scale,” J. Thermophys. Heat Transf. 24(1):222-224, 2010, doi:10.2514/1.45992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <label>45.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Bohm, H., Hesse, D., Jander, H., Luers, B. et al., “The Influence of Pressure and Temperature on Soot Formation in Premixed Flames,” Symposium (International) on Combustion 22(1):403-411, 1989, doi:10.1016/S0082- 0784(89)80047-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <label>46.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Li, T., Yin, T., and Wang, B., “Anatomy of the Cooled EGR Effects on Soot Emission Reduction in Boosted Spark-Ignited Direct-Injection Engines,” Appl. Energy 190:43-56, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.12.105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <label>47.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Kang, K.Y. and Baek, J.H., “Turbulence Characteristics of Tumble Flow in a Four-Valve Engine,” Exp. Therm. Fluid. Sci. 18:231-243, 1998, doi:10.1016/S0894- 1777(98)10023-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <label>48.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Matalon, M. and Francesco, C., “The “Turbulent Flame Speed” of Wrinkled Premixed Flames,” Comptes RendusMecanique 340(11-12):845-858, 2012, doi:10.1016/j. crme.2012.10.031.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <label>49.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Fragner, R., Halter, F., Mazellier, N., Chauveau, C. et al., “Investigation of Pressure Effects on the Small Scale Wrinkling of Turbulent Premixed Bunsen Flames,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 35(2):1527-1535, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. proci.2014.06.036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <label>50.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Ranga Dinesh, K.K.J., Shalaby, H., Luo, K.H., van Oijen, J.A., et al., "Heat Release Rate Variations in High Hydrogen Content Premixed Syngas Flames at Elevated Pressures: Effect of Equivalence Ratio," Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 42(10):7029-7044, 2017, doi:10.1016/j. ijhydene.2016.11.205.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <label>51.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Kayes, D. and Hochgreb, S., “Mechanisms of Particulate Matter Formation in Spark-Ignition Engines. 1. Effects of Engine Operating Conditions,” Environ. Sci. Technol. 33:3957-3967, 1999, doi:10.1021/es9810991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <label>52.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Matsumoto, A., Zheng, Y., Xie, X., Lai, M. et al., “Interactions of Multi-Hole DI Sprays with Charge Motion and their Implications to Flexible Valve-Trained Engine Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1883, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1883.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <label>53.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Yu, H., Liang, X., Shu, G., Sun, X. et al., “Experimental Investigation on Wall Film Ratio of Diesel, Butanol/Diesel, DME/Diesel and Gasoline/Diesel Blended Fuels during the Spray Wall Impingement Process,” Fuel Process. Technol. 156:9-18, 2017, doi:10.1016/j.fuproc.2016.09.029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <label>54.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Beavis,N.J., Ibrahim, S.S., and Malalasekera, W., “ImpingementCharacteristics of an Early Injection Gasoline Direct Injection Engine: A Numerical Study,” Int. J. Engine Res. 18(4):378-393, 2017, doi:10.1177/1468087416663325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <label>55.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Beretta, G.P., Rashidi, M., and Keck, J.C., “Turbulent Flame Propagation and Combustion in Spark Ignition Engines,” Combust. Flame 52:217-245, 1983, doi:10.1016/0010- 2180(83)90135-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <label>56.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Irimescu, A., Merola, S.S., Tornatore, C., and Valentino, G., “Development of a Semi-Empirical Convective Heat Transfer Correlation Based on Thermodynamic and Optical Measurements in a Spark Ignition Engine,” Appl. Energy 157:777-788, 2015, doi:10.1016/j. apenergy.2015.02.050.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <label>57.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Irimescu, A., Di Iorio, S., Merola, S., Sementa, P. et al., “On the Entrainment Velocity and Characteristic Length Scales Used for Quasi-Dimensional Turbulent Combustion Modeling in Spark Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-24-0002, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-24-0002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <label>58.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Irimescu, A., Di Iorio, S., Merola, S., Sementa, P. et al., “Correlation between Simulated Volume Fraction Burned Using a Quasi-Dimensional Model and Flame Area Measured in an Optically Accessible SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-01-0545, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01-0545.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <label>59.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Mann, K., Ting, D., and Henshaw, P., “A Semi-Empirical Model of Spark-Ignited Turbulent Flame Growth,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0201, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000- 01-0201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <label>60.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Breda, S., D’Adamo, A., Fontanesi, S., Del Pecchia, M. et al., “CFD Optimization of N-Butanol Mixture Preparation and Combustion in an Research GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2017-24-0063, 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <label>61.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Kosmadakis, G.M., Rakopoulos, D.C., and Rakopoulos, C.D., “Methane/Hydrogen Fueling a Spark-Ignition Engine for Studying NO, CO and HC Emissions with a Research CFD Code,” Fuel 185:903-915, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. fuel.2016.08.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <label>62.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Zeng, W., Sjoberg, M., Reuss, D.L., and Hu, Z., “The Role of Spray-Enhanced Swirl Flow for Combustion Stabilization in a Stratified-Charge DISI Engine,” Combust. Flame 168:166-185, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2016.03.015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <label>63.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Merola, S.S., Irimescu, A., Di Iorio, S., and Vaglieco, B.M., “Effect of Fuel Injection Strategy on the Carbonaceous Structure Formation and Nanoparticle Emission in a DISI Engine Fuelled with Butanol,” Energies 10:832, 2017, doi:10.3390/en10070832.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <label>64.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Breda, S., D’Adamo, A., Fontanesi, S., D’Orrico, F. et al., “Numerical Simulation of Gasoline and N-Butanol Combustion in an Optically Accessible Research Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 10(1):32-55, 2017, doi:10.4271/2017-01- 0546.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <label>65.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Lucchini, T., D’Errico, G., Onorati, A., Bonandrini, G. et al., “Development of a CFD Approach to Model Fuel-Air Mixing in Gasoline Direct-Injection Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0146, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0146.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <label>66.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Lucchini, T., D’ Errico, G., Onorati, A., Bonandrini, G. et al., “Development and Application of a Computational Fluid Dynamics Methodology to Predict Fuel-Air Mixing and Sources of Soot Formation in Gasoline Direct Injection Engines,” Int. J. Engine Res. 15(5):581-596, 2014, doi:10.1177/1468087413500297.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <label>67.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Irimescu, A., “Working Fluid Properties Variation during Combustion in Premixed Charge Hydrogen Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1646, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01- 1646.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <label>68.</label> 
            <mixed-citation id="c68">Irimescu, A., “Comparison of Combustion Characteristics and Heat Loss for Gasoline and Methane Fueling of a Spark Ignition Engine,” Proc. Rom. Acad. Ser. A 14(2):161- 168, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Schematic representation of the experimental setup. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Engine specifications. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Operating conditions. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Sketch of the image processing steps for the analysis of the premixed flame morphology. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Typical histogram representative of the curvature frequency distribution and related Gaussian fitting curve. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Sketch of the image processing steps for the analysis of fuel deposit flames. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Bottom field of view of the combustion chamber, with the locations selected for spectroscopic investigations. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Overall engine performance indicators for the three engine speed values, with two different air-fuel ratios. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>In-cylinder pressure (top), rate of heat release (middle), and volume fraction burned (bottom) traces for stoichiometric fueling; spark timing is marked with a vertical line. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>In-cylinder pressure (top), rate of heat release (middle), and volume fraction burned (bottom) for lean fueling; spark timing is marked with vertical lines (if visible). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Exhaust gas emissions at different engine speed settings; CO and HC data feature opaque filling, while opacity and NOₓ are shown with gradient filling. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Flame images recorded during the cycle closest to the average pressure trace, with stoichiometric fueling. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Flame area (lines with symbols) and VFB (single lines) for the three engine speed settings; the curves correspond to the cycle closest to the average pressure trace. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Schematic illustration of the location for the two categories of diffusive flames. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Selected images of diffusive flames during late combustion, for the three engine speed settings and two air-fuel ratios. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Occurrence maps of diffusive flames associated with oxidation of liquid fuel films and fresh charge returning from the top-land region, in the 60-70 CAD ASOS crank angle range. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Diffusive flame area estimated as percentage with respect to the piston cross section; data are referred to the late combustion phase (from 60 to 70 CAD ASOS). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>UV-visible emission spectra detected during late combustion in two locations (Loc.2 and Loc.7) of the measurement region for the stoichiometric case at 1000 rpm. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Soot evolution evaluated through spectroscopic investigations in two locations (Loc.2 and Loc.7) of the measurement region for the stoichiometric case at 1000 and 2000 rpm. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Overall thermodynamic parameters for different air-fuel ratios, at 1000 rpm and start of injection 300 CAD BTDC. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>In-cylinder pressure (top), rate of heat release (middle), and volume fraction burned (bottom) traces, for different air-fuel ratios, at 1000 rpm and start of injection 300 CAD BTDC; spark timing is marked with vertical lines (if visible). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Spark arc and displacement of premixed flames and circularity (evaluated through the Heywood factor) at two instances during combustion. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Average value (top) and mean of the Gaussian distribution (bottom) of curvature for two instances during combustion. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Exhaust gas emissions for different air-fuel ratios. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 23</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>Distribution of occurrence with regard to the size of localized diffusive flames for three air-fuel ratio settings and 1000 rpm, with SOI 300. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 24</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>Normalized size of diffusive flames and their displacement along the x- and y-axis for the investigated air-fuel ratios, at 1000 rpm. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 25</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>Simulated (solid lines) and measured (double lines) in-cylinder pressure traces (top) and residual values (bottom) for 1000 rpm at three different equivalence ratios; spark timing is also shown with vertical lines. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 26</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>Optimized calibration coefficients for the investigated air-fuel ratio range; linear correlations are also shown. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 27</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>Simulated (diamond symbols) and measured (round symbols) flame front curvature for different air-fuel ratios, at the CAD corresponding to 30% flame area. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 28</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>Overall thermodynamic parameters and initial combustion duration at different injection phasing, for 1000 rpm and relative air-fuel ratio of 1.6. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 29</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>In-cylinder pressure (top), rate of heat release (middle), and volume fraction burned (bottom) traces for 1000 rpm, relative air-fuel ratio 1.6; spark timing is marked with a vertical line (if visible). © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 30</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>Displacement of premixed flames and circularity (evaluated through the Heywood factor) during the cycles closest to the average pressure traces, for the three injection settings. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 31</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>Exhaust gas emissions for different start of injection settings, at 1000 rpm and relative air-fuel ratio of 1.6. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 32</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>Selected images recorded during late combustion for the three SOIs with lambda 1.6. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 33</label>
         <caption id="ca-35">
            <p>Diffusive flames area and displacement along the x- and y-axis, for the three SOIs, at 1000 rpm and lambda 1.6. Areas were normalized with respect to SOI_300. © SAE International</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
