<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Wiley</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26604804</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Original Articles</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Decomposing Inequality Changes</article-title>
            <subtitle>Allowing for Leisure in the Evaluation of Tax and Transfer Policy Effects</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Creedy</surname>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hérault</surname>
                  <given-names>Nicolas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">36</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26604802</issue-id>
         <fpage>157</fpage>
         <lpage>180</lpage>

         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26604804"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In this paper, we present two alternative methods of accounting for changes in leisure time in decomposing the inequality effects of tax and transfer policy changes. Three components are identified: tax policy, labour supply responses to tax policy changes and other population effects. The methods are used to decompose inequality changes in Australia between 2001 and 2006. Inequality is first defined in non-welfarist terms as a function of disposable income: the independent judge places no value on leisure. Then, this is modified to allow for evaluations using a weighted geometric mean of disposable income and leisure. This is seen to modify the evaluation of changes in important ways. The results are found to differ from those obtained using a ‘welfarist’ evaluation in terms of money metric utility, where separate labour supply effects cannot be isolated.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Aaberge, R. and Colombino, U. (2008), ‘Designing optimal taxes with a microeconometric model of household labour supply’, Centre for Household Income, Labour and Demographic Economics, Working Paper no. 06/2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Banks, J. and Johnson, P. (1994), ‘Equivalence scale relativities revisited’, Economic Journal, vol. 104, pp. 883–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Bargain, O. (2012a), ‘The distributional effects of tax-benefit policies under New Labour: a decomposition approach’, Oxford Bulletin of Economics and Statistics, vol. 74, pp. 856–74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bargain, O. (2012b), ‘Decomposition analysis of distributive policies using behavioural simulations’, International Tax and Public Finance, vol. 19, pp. 708–31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Bargain, O. and Callan, T. (2010), ‘Analysing the effects of tax-benefit reforms on income distribution: a decomposition approach’, Journal of Economic Inequality, vol. 8, pp. 1–21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Blackorby, C., Laisney, F. and Schmachtenberg, R. (1993), ‘Reference-price-independent welfare prescriptions’, Journal of Public Economics, vol. 50, pp. 63–76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Blundell, R. and Shephard, A. (2009), ‘Employment, hours of work and the optimal taxation of low income families’, Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS), Working Paper no. 08/01.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Chantreuil, F. and Trannoy, A. (2013), ‘Inequality decomposition values: the trade-off between marginality and consistency’, Journal of Economic Inequality, vol. 11, pp. 83–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Creedy, J. and Kalb, G. (2006), Labour Supply and Microsimulation: The Evaluation of Tax Policy Reforms, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Creedy, J., and Sleeman, C. (2005), ‘Adult equivalence scales, inequality and poverty’, New Zealand Economic Papers, vol. 39, pp. 51–83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Creedy, J., Hérault, N. and Kalb, G. (2011), ‘Measuring welfare changes in behavioural microsimulation modelling: accounting for the random utility component’, Journal of Applied Economics, vol. 14, pp. 5–34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Creedy, J., Kalb, G. and Scutella, R. (2006), ‘Income distribution in discrete hours behavioural microsimulation models: an illustration’, Journal of Economic Inequality, vol. 4, pp. 57–76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Creedy, J., Duncan, A. S., Harris, M. and Scutella, R. (2002), Microsimulation Modelling of Taxation and The Labour Market: The Melbourne Institute Tax and Transfer Simulator, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Decoster, A. and Haan, P. (2010), ‘Empirical welfare analysis in random utility models of labour supply’, Institute for the Study of Labour (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 5301.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Deutsch, J., Fl¨uckiger, Y. and Silber, J. (2006), ‘The concept of Shapley decomposition and the study of occupational segregation’, Bar-Ilan University, unpublished paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">DiNardo, J., Fortin, N.M. and Lemieux, T. (1996), ‘Labor market institutions and the distribution of wages, 1973–1992: a semi-parametric approach’, Econometrica, vol. 64, pp. 1001–44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Donaldson, D. (1992), ‘On the aggregation of money measures of well-being in applied welfare economics’, Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics, vol. 17, pp. 88–102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Duncan, A. S. and Weeks, M. (1998), ‘Simulating transitions using discrete choice models’, Proceedings of the American Statistical Association, vol. 106, pp. 151–56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Ericson, P. and Flood, L. (2009), ‘A microsimulation approach to an optimal Swedish income tax’, Institute for the Study of Labour (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 4379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gunatilaka, R. and Chotikapanich, D. (2006), ‘Inequality trends and determinants in Sri Lanka 1980–2002: a Shapley approach to decomposition’, Monash University Department of Econometrics and Business Statistics, Working Paper no. 6/06.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Hyslop, D. andMaré, D. (2005), ‘Understanding New Zealand’s Changing Income Distribution, 1983–1998: a semi-parametric analysis’, Economica, vol. 72, pp. 469–95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Jenkins, S. P. and Cowell, F. A. (1994), ‘Parametric equivalence scales and scale relativities’, Economic Journal, vol. 104, pp. 891–900.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Kaplow, L. and Shavell, S. (2001), ‘Any non-welfarist method of policy assessment violates the Pareto Principle’, Journal of Political Economy, vol. 109, pp. 281–86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Kolenikov, S. and Shorrocks, A. (2005), ‘A decomposition analysis of regional poverty in Russia’, Review of Development Economics, vol. 9, pp. 25–46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Lambert, P. (2013), ‘Mini-symposium on the Shapley value’, Journal of Economic Inequality, vol. 11, pp. 79–82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Pattanaik, P. K., Reddy, S. G. and Zu, Y. (2007), ‘On procedures for measuring deprivation and living standars of societies in a multi-attribute framework’, Georgia State University Andrew Young School of Policy Studies, Working Paper no. 08–02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Pignataro, G. (2010), ‘Mearuring equality of opportunity by Shapley value’, Economics Bulletin, vol. 30, pp. 786–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Seth, S. (2013), ‘A class of distribution and association sensitive multidimensional welfare indices’, Journal of Economic Inequality, vol. 11, pp. 133–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Shapley, L. S. (1953), ‘A value for N-person games’, in H. W. Kuhn and A. W. Tucker (eds), Annals ofMathematical Studies, volume 28, pp. 307–17, Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Shorrocks, A. F. (2011), ‘Decomposition procedures for distributional analysis: a unified framework based on the Shapley value’, Journal of Economic Inequality, vol. 11, pp. 99–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Shorrocks, A. F. and Kolenikov, S. (2001), ‘Poverty trends in Russia during the transition’, unpublished manuscript.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Stiglitz, J. E., Sen, A. and Fitoussi, J.-P. (2010), Mis-measuring our Lives: Why GDP Doesn’t Add Up, New York: The New Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Decomposition into behavioural, population and tax policy effects</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Income tax schedules 2000/01 and 2005/06</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Population size (000s) in 2000/01 and 2005/06</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Baseline disposable income measures and total changes 2000/01 to 2005/06</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Average effects as per cent of baseline: disposable income measures</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Baseline for welfare metric and total changes 2000/01 to 2005/06: α = 0.7</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Average effects as per cent of baseline: welfare metric with α = 0.7</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Baseline money metric measures and changes 2000/01 to 2005/06</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Average effects as per cent of baseline: money metric measure</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
