<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169114</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Energy Reallocation Model for Estimation of Equivalent Greenhouse Gas Emissions of Various Charging Behaviors of Plugin Hybrid Electric Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hamza</surname>
                  <given-names>Karim</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Laberteaux</surname>
                  <given-names>Ken</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Toyota Research Institute-North America</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>May 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169099</issue-id>
         <fpage>139</fpage>
         <lpage>147</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169114"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This work presents a modeling approach for estimation of the equivalent greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions of plugin hybrid electric vehicles (PHEVs) for real driving patterns and charging behaviors. In general, modeling of the equivalent GHG for a trip made by a PHEV not only depends on the trip trace in question, but also on the electric range of the vehicle and energy consumption in previous trips since the last charging event. This can significantly increase the necessary computational burden of estimating the GHG emissions using numerical simulation tools, which are already computationally-expensive. The proposed approach allows a trip numerical simulation starting with a fully charged battery to be re-used for GHG estimation of a trip that starts with any initial state of charge by re-allocating the appropriate amount electric energy to an equivalent gas consumption. Thus, the proposed approach allows modeling of many charging behaviors with minimal additional computational effort beyond one numerical simulation for each drive trace. Validation of the proposed approach is established through comparative simulations using 1012 trip traces, where the error in estimated fuel consumption was less than 3% in most simulations. The full set of trip traces in California Household Travel Survey (CHTS) were then analyzed for the two PHEV models (with short and long electric range), for different charging behaviors and grid conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jenn, A., Azevedo I. and Ferriera P.. The impact of federal incentives on the adoption of hybrid electric vehicles in the United States. Energy Economics, Vol. 40, 2013, pp. 936-942</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Electric Drive Transportation Association: http://www.electricdrive.org/index.php?ht=d/sp/i/20952/pid/20952. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paul B., Kockelman K. and Musti S.. Evolution of the Light-Duty Vehicle Fleet Anticipating Adoption of Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles and Greenhouse Gas Emissions Across the U.S. Fleet. Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board, No. 2252, Transportation Research Board of the National Academies, Washington, D.C., 2011, pp. 107-117</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barton, J. H.R.6 Energy Policy Act of 2005: http://thomas.loc.gov/cgibin/bdquery/z?d109:H.R.6. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">California Environmental Protection Agency Air Resources Board: Clean Vehicle Rebate Project: http://www.arb.ca.gov/msprog/aqip/cvrp. htm. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diamond D. The impact of government incentives for hybrid-electric vehicles: Evidence from US states. Energy Policy, Vol. 37, 2009, pp. 972-983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Congressional Budget Office. Effects of Federal Tax Credits for the Purchase of Electric Vehicles: http://www.cbo.gov/publication/43576. Accessed December 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elgowainy, A., Zhou Y., Vyas A. D., Mahalik M., Santini D. and Wang M.. Impacts of Charging Choices for Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles in 2030 Scenario. Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board, No. 2287, Transportation Research Board of the National Academies, Washington, D.C., 2012, pp. 9-17</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, W., Choi D. and Sunwoo M.. Modelling and simulation of vehicle electric power system. Journal of Power Sources, Vol. 109, 2002, pp. 58-66</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Granovskii, M., Dincer I. and Rosen M.. Economic and environmental comparison of conventional, hybrid, electric and hydrogen fuel cell vehicles. Journal of Power Sources, Vol. 159, 2006, pp. 1186-1193</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Samaras, C. and Meisterling K.. Life Cycle Assessment of Greenhouse Gas Emissions from Plug-in Hybrid Vehicles: Implications for Policy. Environmental Science and Technology, Vol 42, No. 9, 2008, pp. 3170-3176</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bradley, T. and Frank A.. Design, demonstrations and sustainability impact assessments for plug-in hybrid electric vehicles. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, Vol. 13, 2009, pp. 115-128</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiau, C., Samaras C., Hauffe R. and Michalek J.. Impact of battery weight and charging patterns on the economic and environmental benefits of plug-in hybrid vehicles. Energy Policy, Vol. 37, 2009, pp. 2653-2663</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elgowainy, A., Han J., Poch L., Wang M., Vyas A., Mahalik M. and Rousseau A. Weel-to-wheels Analysis of Energy use and Greenhouse Gas Emissions of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles. Argonne National Lab, Report: ANL/ESD/10-1, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Axsen, J., Kurani K., McCarthy R. and Yang C.. Plug-in hybrid vehicle GHG impacts in California: Integrating consumer-informed recharge profiles with an electricity-dispatch model. Energy Policy, Vol. 39, 2011, pp. 1617-1629</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kelly, J., McDonald J. and Keoleian G.. Time-dependent plug-in hybrid electric vehicle charging based on national driving patterns and demographics. Applied Energy, Vol. 94, 2012, pp. 395-405</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Traut, E., Hendrickson C., Klampfl E., Liu Y. and Michalek J.. Optimal design and allocation of electrified vehicles and dedicated charging infrastructure for minimum lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions and cost. Energy Policy, Vol. 51, 2012, pp. 524-534</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raykin, L., Roorda M. and MacLean H.. Impacts of driving patterns on tank-to-wheel energy use of plug-in hybrid electric vehicles. Transportation Research Part D, Vol. 17, 2012, pp. 243-250</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neubauer, J. Brooker A. and Wood E.. Sensitivity of plug-in hybrid electric vehicle economics to drive patterns, electric range, energy management, and charge strategies. Journal of Power Sources, Vol. 236, 2013, pp. 357-364</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karabasoglu, O. and Michalek J.. Influence of driving patterns on life cycle cost and emissions of hybrid and plug-in electric vehicle power trains. Energy Policy, Vol. 60, 2013, pp. 445-461</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laberteaux, K. and Hamza K.. A Study of Greenhouse Gas Emissions Reduction Opportunity in Light-Duty Vehicles by Analyzing Real Driving Patterns, Transportation Research Part D - in review</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">California Household Travel Survey: http://www.nrel.gov/transportation/secure_transportation_data.html. Accessed July 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Renewable Energy Laboratory. Future Automotive Systems Technology Simulator: FASTSim http://www.nrel.gov/transportation/fastsim.html. Accessed August 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Microsoft. Windows Azure Platform: http://www.microsoft.com/windowsazure/. Accessed September 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, M., Wu Y. and Elgowainy A.. Operating Manual for GREET 1.7, Argonne National Lab, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environmental Protection Agency. Greenhouse Gas equivalencies calculator: http://www.epa.gov/cleanenergy/energy-resources/calculator.html. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davies, J. and Kurani K.. Recharging Behavior of Households’ Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles Observed Variation in Use of Conversions of 5-kW-h Blended Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicle. Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board, No. 2191, Transportation Research Board of the National Academies, Washington, D.C., 2010, pp. 75-83</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The EV Project: http://avt.inl.gov/pdf/EVProj/VoltHomeAwayL1L2DayNightCharging.pdf. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Environmental protection agency. Dynamometer Drive Cycles: http://www.epa.gov/nvfel/testing/dynamometer.htm. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Energy Information Administration: http://www.eia.gov/tools/faqs/faq. cfm?id=427&amp;t=3. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">California Energy Commission: http://energyalmanac.ca.gov/electricity/total_system_power.html. Accessed June 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
