<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830199</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830204</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>EXTERNAL DEBT, AND DEBT-FOR-EQUITY SWAPS: A PROSPECTIVE ANALYSIS FOR PERU / DETTE EXTERIEURE, CROISSANCE ET CONVERSION DE LA DETTE EN CAPITAL: UNE ANALYSE PROSPECTIVE POUR LE PEROU</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gerardo M. Gonzales</given-names>
                  <surname>Arrieta</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>369</fpage>
         <lpage>390</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830204"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper is concerned with the issue of structuring and implementing a successful, beneficial debt-for-equity swap programme in Peru. To begin with, it is claimed that a need for a revised management of the debt problem arises from the fact that the recurrent strategy based on adjustment policies and rescheduling negotiations has proved to be costly and futile. Thus, within a developmental perspective, new initiatives have to be pursued so as to contribute to the management of medium-and long-term commercial bank debt and to properly deal with its impact on economic growth. Debt-for-equity swap appear rather appealing to simultaneously tackle both aspects. The implementation of a debt-for-equity conversion programme has a number of potential benefits to the debtor countries but it may also give rise to a number of pitfalls. The paper provides a brief, but comprehensive, review of such elements inherent in debt-for-equity swaps. Furthermore, based on the experience of other heavily indebted developing countries which keep conversion programmes underway, the paper highlights some issues and proposals for further consideration as a contribution to policy practice towards developing a debt-for-equity conversion programme in Peru suitable to the country's needs and current circumstances. The paper concludes that a debt-for-equity swap programme in Peru may become a useful, successful instrument provided that: (a) it be carefully shaped as suggested, so as to maximise its potential benefits and mitigate its inherent pitfalls; (b) it be launched on a relatively flexible, simple basis with the possibility to monitor its scope so as to ensure an adequate accomplishment of its targets; (c) both a stable, non-recessionary scenario and the availability of sound investment opportunities prevail in the Peruvian economy; and (d) it be implemented within the framework of an overall, growth-oriented debt strategy in order to provide relief on other quantitatively important categories of total external debt, for which a debt-for-equity conversion programme is not applicable or sufficient. Cet article analyse les différents aspects de la mise en oeuvre et de la gestion d'un programme fructueux et nécessaire de conversion de la dette extérieure en capital au Pérou. Il faut toute de suite reconnaître que le besoin urgent d'une nouvelle approche au problème de la dette extérieure découle du fait que les stratégies jusqu'ici suivies basées sur l'ajustement des paiements courants et sur les accords de restructuration de la dette ont enregistrés des résultats négligeables et couteux. Dans le contexte d'une stratégie de développement, de nouvelles initiatives doivent être envisagées pour contribuer à la gestion de la dette commerciale à moyen et à long terme et pour influencer positivement son impact sur la croissance économique. Les projets de conversion de la dette en capital semblent pouvoir faire face de façon avantageuse à tous les deux aspects sous-mentionnés. La mise en place d'un programme de conversion de la dette en capital présente de nombreux aspects positifs sur le plan de potentialités pour les pays endettés: ces avantages doivent toutefois être comparés avec les nombreuses conséquences négatives. Cet article met en lumière même si de façon extrêmement syntéthique, l'ensemble de ces aspects qui sont liés aux programmes de conversion de la dette extérieure. En se basant sur l'expérience des pays en voie de développement largement endettés qui ont acceptés des programmes de conversion de la dette on cherche à analyser les problèmes sousjacents et à avancer des solutions pour améliorer le schéma. Ces aspects sont analysés tout spécialement dans le cas du programme de la conversion en capital de la dette du Pérou pour le rendre plus adéquat aux besoins et à la situation du pays. L'article conclut en mettant en relief que le programme de conversion peut être un instrument utile et efficace à certaines conditions qui peuvent être résumées de la façon suivante: 1) le programme doit être soigneusement étudié et appliqué pour maximiser les bénéfices potentiels et pour en minimiser les caractéristiques négatives; 2) le programme doit être envisagé de façon flexible et souple toujours avec la possibilité de contrôler ses objectifs et de se rendre compte si ces objectifs peuvent être atteints; 3) la présence dans l'économie pérouvienne de perspectives macroéconomiques stables et non-inflationistes ainsi que d'opportunités valables d'investissements; 4) une stratégie de la dette extérieure axée sur la croissance de l'économie du Pérou pour réduire le poids des autres importantes catégories de la dette pour lesquelles on ne peut pas envisager des programmes de conversion en capital.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d29e107a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e114" publication-type="other">
Banco Central de Reserva del Peru, Analisis de largo plazo del sector externo de la economfa peruana
1975-1986, Lima, June 1987, p. 58.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e124a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e131" publication-type="other">
Direct, short-term working capital debt by Peruvian banks totals a bit over US$900 million ("Global debt:
the equity solution", Euromoney, Special supplement, January 1988, p. 110).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e141a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e148" publication-type="other">
Michael Blackwell and Simon Nocera, "Debt/equity swaps", IMF Working Paper
(Washington, D.C.) No. Wp/88/15, February 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e157" publication-type="other">
Juan Carlos Echeverry, "Mecanismos de transformation de
deuda externa. La experiencia latinoamericana", Ensayos sobre Polftica Economica (Bogota), N° 11, June 1987,
pp. 135-157</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e169" publication-type="other">
Eugenio Lahera, "La convprsion de la deuda externa vista desde America Latina", Ftevista
de la CEPAL (Santiago de Chile), N° 32, August, 1987, pp. 105-125.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e179a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e186" publication-type="other">
Joel Bergsman and Wayne Edisis, "Debt-
equity swaps and foreign direct investment in Latin America", International Finance Corporation/Foreign Invest-
ment Advisory Service (Washington, D.C), August 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e198" publication-type="other">
M. Blackwell and S. Nocera, op. c/'f.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e204" publication-type="other">
J.C. Echeverry,
op. cit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e214" publication-type="other">
Juan Andres Fontaine, "Los mecanismos de conversion de deuda en Chile", paper presented at the
Mesa redonda sobre mercados de capital internacionales, Oxford, England, February 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e223" publication-type="other">
E. Lahera, op. cit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e229" publication-type="other">
Miguel Rodriguez Mendoza, "Debt-equity swaps: the Latin American experience", paper presented at the
UNCTC/SELA Workshop on Debt-Equity Swaps, Caracas, April 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e238" publication-type="other">
Padej Sukachevin, "Statistical issues of
debt conversion", IMF Working Paper (Washington, D.C), No WP/88/28, March 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e247" publication-type="other">
David Suratgar, "Debt-
equity conversions", paper presented at the UNCTC/SELA Workshop on Debt-Equity Swaps, Caracas, April 1988.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e258a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e265" publication-type="other">
Andrew
C. Quale, "Structuring a debt/equity conversion programme: issues to consider", paper presented at the
UNCTC/SELA Workshop on Debt-Equity Swaps, Caracas, April 1988</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e277" publication-type="other">
David L. Roberts and Eli M. Remolona,
"Debt swaps: a technique in developing country finance", in Finance for developing countries: alternative sources
of finance debt swaps, New York and London, Group of Thirty, 1987, pp. 15-40.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e290a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e297" publication-type="other">
Roberts and Remolona, op. cit.,
pp. 28-32.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e307a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e314" publication-type="other">
Bergsman and Edisis, op. cit, pp. 7-8.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e320" publication-type="other">
Rodriguez Mendoza, op. cit., pp. 17-19.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e327a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e334" publication-type="other">
notes 5</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e340" publication-type="other">
7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e347a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e354" publication-type="other">
Bergsman and
Edisis, op. cit, p. 4 of Annex 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e364a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e371" publication-type="other">
Fontaine, op. cit, pp. 28-29.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e379a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e386" publication-type="other">
Jeffrey Sachs and Harry Huizinga, "U.S. commercial banks and the developing-country debt crisis",
Brookings Papers on Economic Activity (Washington, D.C), N° 2, 1987, p. 563.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e396a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e403" publication-type="other">
Suratgar,
op. cit, pp. 40-41.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e413a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e420" publication-type="other">
Bergsman and Edisis, op. cit., pp. 13-14.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e427a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e434" publication-type="other">
Bergsman and Edisis, op. cit, p. 11.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e441a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e448" publication-type="other">
"Global debt: the equity solution", Euromoney, Special supplement, January 1988, p. 34.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d29e455a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e462" publication-type="other">
Wolfgang Spieles, "Debt-equity only swaps
and the heavily indebted countries", Intereconomics (Hamburg), vol. 22, N° 3, May-June 1987, pp. 120-124.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


