<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25829625</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25829628</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>QUELQUES CONSIDERATIONS SUR LA POLITIQUE DES TAUX D'INTERET DANS LES PAYS EN VOIE DE DEVELOPPEMENT / SOME COMMENTS ON INTEREST RATE POLICY IN THE DEVELOPING COUNTRIES</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Paolo</given-names>
                  <surname>Mottura</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1977</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>129</fpage>
         <lpage>149</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25829628"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The author analyses primarily the interest rate policy in these countries and observes that, save for rare exceptions, the governments of the less developed countries have adopted a liberal policy of providing monetary incentives for investment through the application of reduced interest rates, and, in any case, by keeping the levels of interest rates generally low. A cheap money policy of this kind is normally justified by the fact that: 1. the financing of investments in infrastructures requires a low capital cost, given their scanty and delayed productivity; 2. the financing of investment in agriculture must be facilitated in the same way, because of the scanty productivity of this investment (above all if it is medium-long term), and the great social and economic importance of agricultural production (employment issues, facilitations for the export of agricultural products, etc); 3. the financing of industrial investments must also be aided by low cost capital, as it is considered that this accelerates development. The author however raises considerable doubts as to whether this policy of indiscriminate financial incentives achieves the desired effects and he also maintains that it has adverse effects. Above all, the generalisation of financial concessions tends to transform the economy into a system essentially subsidised by the public administration. The very concept of providing incentives is by its nature selective, and indiscriminate application turns the incentive into a subsidy. Moreover there is sound reason to believe that the low level of interest rates has negative effects on the supply of capital: family savings are, in fact, discouraged, and company self-financing is inadequately utilised. The result is that the supply of capital must, to a large extent, be supplemented, to balance the demand, by government capital, which is usually obtained by applying growing fiscal pressure and by increasing foreign indebtedness. As far as capital demand is concerned, there is reason to believe that the low cost of capital tends to favour a mix of productive factors characterised by a high capital intensity. This may have undesirable repercussions both on the employment prospects for less skilled manpower, and on the equilibrium of the balance of payments (imports of sophisticated technologies and capital goods). Another consideration is the possibility that the system of financial incentives has the effect of altering the allocation of funds. In fact, the existing financial infrastructures tend to grant credit indiscriminately if the resulting insolvencies are borne by the government budget, or they tend to severely ration credit if they are called upon to bear the risk of insolvency (the low interest rate does not remunerate the risks typical of investiment in the countries in question). The author concludes that, in order to obviate such serious drawbacks, the level of interest rates must be raised, while at the same time maintaining a very selective and suitably managed system of financial concessions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>fre</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


