<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562344</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Lean Burn Combustion of Iso-Octane in a Rapid Compression Machine Using Dual Mode Turbulent Jet Ignition System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Vedula</surname>
                  <given-names>Ravi Teja</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan State University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Gentz</surname>
                  <given-names>Gerald</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Stuecken</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan State University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Toulson</surname>
                  <given-names>Elisa</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan State University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Schock</surname>
                  <given-names>Harold</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Michigan State University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>2</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>February 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562337</issue-id>
         <fpage>95</fpage>
         <lpage>108</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562344"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Turbulent jet ignition (TJI) is a pre-chamber initiated combustion technology that has been demonstrated to provide low temperature, faster burn rate combustion of lean and intake charge diluted air-fuel mixtures. Dual mode turbulent jet ignition (DM-TJI) is a novel concept wherein a separate air supply is provided for the pre-chamber apart from the conventional auxiliary fuel as supplied for TJI systems. The current study aims to extend the lean flammability limit of a gasoline-fueled engine using DM-TJI. Ignition delay time and combustion behavior of ultra-lean iso-octane/air mixture (Lambda ≅ 3.0) was studied using a TJI-based optically accessible rapid compression machine. High-speed fuel spray recordings in the pre-chamber were obtained using borescope imaging setup. Images of the reacting turbulent jet and subsequent combustion in the main chamber were captured using a visible color camera. The focus of the current study was to investigate (i) the effect of auxiliary fuel injection timing in TJI mode and (ii) the influence of having pre-chamber air injection in DM-TJI mode, on jet propagation and combustion behavior in the main chamber. Combustion behavior was analyzed by visually inspecting the particulates present in the chamber. Including an auxiliary air injection pulse during the auxiliary fuel injection event enhanced the combustion burn rates and mitigated particulate formation. Also, fuel injection timing and air injection pressure showed some differences in flame propagation and more noticeable differences in the particulate content.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>Air injection</kwd> 
            <kwd>Turbulent Jet Ignition</kwd> 
            <kwd>Pre-chamber borescope imaging</kwd> 
            <kwd>Mie-scattering fuel spray</kwd> 
            <kwd>Autoignition</kwd> 
            <kwd>Rapid compression machine</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellies, B., Schenk, C., and Dekraker, P., “Benchmarking and Hardware-in-the-Loop Operation of a 2014 MAZDA SkyActiv 2.0L 13:1 Compression Ratio Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-1007, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-1007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsuo, S., Ikeda, E., Ito, Y., and Nishiura, H., “The New Toyota Inline 4 Cylinder 1.8L ESTEC 2ZR-FXE Gasoline Engine for Hybrid Car,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0684, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0684.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, K., Hwang, I., Lee, H., Park, H. et al., “Development of New High-Efficiency Kappa 1.6L GDI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0667, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0667.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):1258-1275, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reese, R., “Progress (and Challenges) along the Path to 2025,” in Engine Research Center 2015 Symposium, University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 6(2):699-715, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0538.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Schock, H., and Attard, W., “A Review of Pre- Chamber Initiated Jet Ignition Combustion Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2263, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alkidas, A.C., “Combustion Advancements in Gasoline Engines,” Energy Conversion and Management 48(11):2751- 2761, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2007.07.027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Epping, K., Aceves, S., Bechtold, R., and Dec, J., “The Potential of HCCI Combustion for High Efficiency and Low Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1923, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ghorbanpour, M. and Rasekhi, R., “A Parametric Investigation of HCCI Combustion to Reduce Emissions and Improve Efficiency Using a CFD Model Approach,” Fuel 106:157-165, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2012.12.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saxena, S., Shah, N., Bedoya, I., and Phadke, A., “Understanding Optimal Engine Operating Strategies for Gasoline-Fueled HCCI Engines Using Crank-Angle Resolved Exergy Analysis,” Applied Energy 114:155-163, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.09.056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion—The Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel Injection,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0752, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasan, A.O., Abu-Jrai, A., Ala’a, H., Tsolakis, A. et al., “HC, CO and NOx Emissions Reduction Efficiency of a Prototype Catalyst in Gasoline Bi-Mode SI/HCCI Engine,” Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering 4(2):2410-2416, 2016, doi:10.1016/j.jece.2016.04.015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tunestål, P., “Optimal Control of HCCI,” Optimization and Optimal Control in Automotive Systems, Springer International Publishing, 2014, 291-300, ISBN: 978-3-319- 05371-4 (Online).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Loeper, P., Ra, Y., Adams, C., Foster, D. et al., “Experimental Investigation of Light-Medium Load Operating Sensitivity in a Gasoline Compression Ignition (GCI) Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0896, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0896.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S.L., Hanson, R.M., Splitter, D.A., and Reitz, R.D., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI): A Pathway to Controlled High-Efficiency Clean Combustion,” International Journal of Engine Research 12(3):209-226, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411401548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Olesky, L.M., Lavoie, G.A., Assanis, D.N., and Wooldridge, M.S., “The Effects of Diluent Composition on the Rates of HCCI and Spark Assisted Compression Ignition Combustion,” Applied Energy 124:186-198, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2014.03.015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dainton, L., “Nikolai Nikolaevich Semenov, 16 April 1896- 25 September 1986,” Biographical Memoirs of Fellows of the Royal Society 36:527-546, 1990, doi:10.1098/rsbm.1990.0042.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oppenheim, A.K., “Combustion in Piston Engines: Technology, Evolution, Diagnosis and Control,” (Springer- Verlag, Berlin Heidelberg, Germany, 2004), ISBN: 978-3-662- 06297-5 (Online).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gussak, L., Turkish, M., and Siegla, D., “High Chemical Activity of Incomplete Combustion Products and a Method of Prechamber Torch Ignition for Avalanche Activation of Combustion in Internal Combustion Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 750890, 1975, doi:10.4271/750890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Latsch, R., “The Swirl-Chamber Spark Plug: A Means of Faster, More Uniform Energy Conversion in the Spark- Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 840455, 1984, doi:10.4271/840455.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, M. and Reader, G.T., “Energy Efficiency Analyses of Active Flow Aftertreatment Systems for Lean Burn Internal Combustion Engines,” Energy Conversion and Management 45(15):2473-2493, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2003.11.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W. and Blaxill, H., “A Lean Burn Gasoline Fueled Pre-Chamber Jet Ignition Combustion System Achieving High Efficiency and Low NOx at Part Load,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1146, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1146.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Biswas, S. and Qiao, L., “Prechamber Hot Jet Ignition of Ultra-Lean H2/Air Mixtures: Effect of Supersonic Jets and Combustion Instability,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(3):1584-1592, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Attard, W., Fraser, N., Parsons, P., and Toulson, E., “A Turbulent Jet Ignition Pre-Chamber Combustion System for Large Fuel Economy Improvements in a Modern Vehicle Powertrain,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):20-37, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1457.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bunce, M., Blaxill, H., Kulatilaka, W., and Jiang, N., “The Effects of Turbulent Jet Characteristics on Engine Performance Using a Pre-Chamber Combustor,” SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1195, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1195.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szwaja, S., Jamrozik, A., and Tutak, W., “A Two-Stage Combustion System for Burning Lean Gasoline Mixtures in a Stationary Spark Ignited Engine,” Applied Energy 105:271- 281, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2012.12.080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schock, H., Zhu, G., Toulson, E., and Stuecken, T.R., “Internal Combustion Engine,” U.S. Patent 4/086,168, May 29, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kukkadapu, G., Kumar, K., Sung, C.J., Mehl, M. et al., “Experimental and Surrogate Modeling Study of Gasoline Ignition in a Rapid Compression Machine,” Combustion and Flame 159(10):3066-3078, 2012, doi:10.1016/j. combustflame.2012.05.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mittal, G., Burke, S.M., Davies, V.A., Parajuli, B. et al., “Autoignition of Ethanol in a Rapid Compression Machine,” Combustion and Flame 161(5):1164-1171, 2014, doi:10.1016/j. combustflame.2013.11.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sung, C.-J. and Curran, H.J., “Using Rapid Compression Machines for Chemical Kinetics Studies,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 44:1-18, 2014, doi:10.1016/j. pecs.2014.04.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gentz, G. and Toulson, E., “Experimental Studies of a Liquid Propane Auxiliary Fueled Turbulent Jet Igniter in a Rapid Compression Machine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 9(2):777-785, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gholamisheeri, M., Thelen, B.C., Gentz, G., Wichman, I.S. et al., “Rapid Compression Machine Study of a Premixed, Variable Inlet Density and Flow Rate, Confined Turbulent Jet,” Combustion and Flame 169:321-332, 2016, doi:10.1016/j. combustflame.2016.05.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vedula, R.T., Song, R., Stuecken, T., Zhu, G.G. et al., “Thermal Efficiency of a Dual-Mode Turbulent Jet Ignition Engine under Lean and near-Stoichiometric Operation,” International Journal of Engine Research 18:1055-1066, 2017, doi:10.1177/1468087417699979.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, C., Toulson, E., Edwards, T., and Lee, T., “Application of a Novel Charge Preparation Approach to Testing the Autoignition Characteristics of JP-8 and Camelina Hydroprocessed Renewable Jet Fuel in a Rapid Compression Machine,” Combustion and Flame 159(9):2780-2788, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2012.03.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miller, D., Narayan, R., Berglund, K., Lira, C. et al., Novel Biofuel Formulations for Enhanced Vehicle Performance, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI, Technical Report, Aug. 30, 2013, doi:10.2172/1236141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiaki, T., Takahashi, K., Tsuji, T., Hongo, M. et al., “Vapor- Liquid Equilibria of 1-Propanol or 2-Propanol with 2, 2, 4- Trimethylpentane at 101.3 kPa,” Journal of Chemical &amp; Engineering Data 39:602-604, 1994, doi:10.1021/je00015a047.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van Basshuysen, R. and Schäfer, F., Internal Combustion Engine Handbook-Basics, Components, Systems and Perspectives, (Warrendale, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc., 2004), 345, ISBN: 0-7680-1139-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, K., Kim, D., Jung, Y., and Bae, C., “Spray and Combustion Characteristics of Gasoline and Diesel in a Direct Injection Compression Ignition Engine,” Fuel 109:616-626, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.02.060.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka, S., Ayala, F., and Keck, J.C., “A Reduced Chemical Kinetic Model for HCCI Combustion of Primary Reference Fuels in a Rapid Compression Machine,” Combustion and Flame 133(4):467-481, 2003, doi:10.1016/s0010-2180(03)00057-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiera, D., Riley, M., and Hampson, G.J., “Mechanism for High Velocity Turbulent Jet Combustion from Passive Prechamber Spark Plug,” presented at ASME 2012 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, USA, Sept. 23, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walton, S.M., He, X., Zigler, B.T., Wooldridge, M.S. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Iso-Octane Ignition Phenomena,” Combustion and Flame 150(3):246-262, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2006.07.016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huang, S., Deng, P., Huang, R., Wang, Z. et al., “Visualization Research on Spray Atomization, Evaporation and Combustion Processes of Ethanol-Diesel Blend under LTC Conditions,” Energy Conversion and Management 106:911-920, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.enconman.2015.10.028.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serras-Pereira, J., Aleiferis, P., Richardson, D., and Wallace, S., “Characteristics of Ethanol, Butanol, Iso-Octane and Gasoline Sprays and Combustion from a Multi-Hole Injector in a DISI Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):893- 909, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1591.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, (New York, McGraw-Hill, 1988), Vol. 930, ISBN-13: 978- 0070286375.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
