<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186480</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44437118</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PART I</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject>Production</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Data on Machinability and Wear of Cast Iron</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Thomas H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Wickenden</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1928</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>181</fpage>
         <lpage>189</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44437118"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>THE hardness or chemical composition of an iron is, by itself, no indication of the wearing property and machinability of the iron. Irons containing a large amount of free ferrite have been found to wear rapidly, whereas others having considerable pear lite or sorbite in their structure show good wearing properties. The presence in cylinder-blocks of excess-carbide spots or of phosphides of high phosphorus-content is deleterious, because such spots wear in relief and the material ultimately breaks put, acting as an abrasive that scores the surfaces. Causes of wear in cylinder-blocks are discussed, and nickel, or nickel and chromium, intelligently added to the iron is suggested as a means of obtaining the correct microstructure for a combination of good wearing properties and machinability. Since greater hardness is the result of a harder matrix rather than of an increase in the number of carbide spots, it has been found to be a good index of the improved resistance to wear, and to overcome the difficulty due to the hammering of the valves into their seats. Analyses of cylinder-blocks, pistons, clutch plates, brake drums, cams, and forming-dies, in which nickel and chromium have been used, are given, and the improvements secured in the performance of these parts are described. The discussion treats largely of the relationship between hardness, lubrication, finish and wear. Wear is stated to be much more dependent upon lubrication than upon quality of the iron. The use of nickel in iron is stated to improve the tightness and homogeneity of the metal. Various methods of testing iron for machinability are outlined.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d393e233a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d393e240" publication-type="other">
An Investigation on the Wearing and Anti-Frictional
Qualities of Cast Iron, by J. E. Hurst;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d393e249" publication-type="other">
The Iron and Steel In-
stitute Carnegie Scholarship Memoirs. 1918, p. 59 ;</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d393e258" publication-type="other">
The
Wear of Cast-Iron Cylinders and Liners, The Iron Age, June 22,
1916, p. 1492.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d393e271a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d393e278" publication-type="other">
Nickel and
Nickel-Chromium in Cast Iron, Transac-
tions of the American Foundrymen's As-
sociation, vol. XXXIII, p. 424.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d393e294a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d393e301" publication-type="other">
Transactions, vol. 20, part 2, p. 103.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


