<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica, Centre for Financial Assistance to African Countries</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23027199</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE STRUCTURE OF THE INFORMAL CREDIT MARKET IN NIGERIA: LESSONS FROM AWKA TOWN OF ANAMBRA STATE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Aforka C.</given-names>
                  <surname>Ibe</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1990</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23027197</issue-id>
         <fpage>5</fpage>
         <lpage>14</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23027199"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This study is aimed at providing some insights into the structure of the informal credit market in Nigeria. The approach adopted involved selecting a segment of the market and then examining its structure while noting any features that local values and traditions may have conditioned. By discounting these peculiar social influences on the market, a representative social background for the credit market in Nigeria is constructed which thus permits a generalisation of the findings for Nigeria. On the basis of this, it is established that the associations are the major suppliers of fund in the market and that these associations can easily be nurtured into co-operative thrift and lending associations so that their financial intermediation role can be improved and directed towards national development. Cet article essaie de fournir des précisions dans la structure du marché informel du crédit au Nigéria. L'approche suivi consiste à selectionner un segment de ce marché pour ensuite examiner sa structure dans le but de mettre en lumière comment les traditions et le système de valeurs existant ont pu conditionner ses caractéristiques. Tenant compte de ces influences sociales, on a pris en consideration un ensemble social représentatif pour le marché du crédit au Nigéria qui permette de généraliser le phénomène à l'ensemble du pays. Sur la base de cette généralisation, on peut conclure que les associations sont la source la plus importante de fonds sur le marché et qu'elles peuvent facilement alimenter les associations coopératives d'épargne et de prêts. Le rôle financier de ces associations peut être amélioré et dirigé vers des objectifs de développement national.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
