<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275430</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Cycle-by-Cycle Analysis, Knock Modeling and Spark-Advance Setting of a “Downsized” Spark-Ignition Turbocharged Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bozza</surname>
                  <given-names>F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DIME – Università di Napoli “Federico II”</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siano</surname>
                  <given-names>D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori – CNR – Napoli</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Torella</surname>
                  <given-names>E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ELASIS SCpA, Napoli</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>381</fpage>
         <lpage>389</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275430"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Recently, a tendency is consolidating to produce low displacement turbocharged spark-ignition engines. This design philosophy, known as “engine downsizing”, allows to reduce mechanical and pumping losses at low load as a consequence of the higher operating Brake Mean Effective Pressure (<italic>BMEP</italic>). The presence of the turbocharger allows to restore the maximum power output of the larger displacement engine. Additional advantages are a higher low-speed torque and hence a better drivability and fun-to-drive. Of course, at high loads, the spark-advance must be carefully controlled to avoid the knock occurrence and this determines a substantial penalization of the fuel consumption. The knowledge of the knock-limited spark timing is hence a key point in order to reduce the fuel consumption drop at high loads.</p>
            <p>In a previous study [1], a combined procedure for the quasi-dimensional modeling of both combustion and knock phenomena was developed and applied to a 1D thermodynamic engine model in order to find the knock-limited spark-advance at wide-open-throttle (<italic>WOT</italic>) conditions, for different engine speeds. In the present paper, indeed, the previous analysis is extended to include the cycle-by-cycle variations effects. Cyclic dispersion is characterized through the introduction of a random variation on a number of parameters controlling the rate of heat release (air/fuel ratio, initial flame kernel duration and radius, EGR rate, turbulence intensity). The intensity of the random variation is specified in order to realize an Indicated Mean Effective Pressure (<italic>IMEP</italic>) coefficient of variation similar to the experimentally observed one.</p>
            <p>A kinetic scheme is then solved within the unburned gas zone, characterized by different thermodynamic conditions occurring cycle-by-cycle. This allows, for a given spark timing, to estimate a statistical distribution of a properly defined knock indicator.</p>
            <p>To the aim of validating the developed methodology, a DFT analysis of consecutive experimental pressure cycles is carried out in different operating conditions. High frequency pressure oscillations, typical of knocking occurrence, can be recognized and the statistical distribution of knocking intensity is in this way identified. Numerical and experimental results are finally compared in terms of coefficient of variation, and a good agreement is found.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza F., Fontana G., Galloni E., Torella E., “3D-1D Analyses of the Turbulent Flow Field, Burning Speed and Knock Occurrence in a Turbocharged SI Engine”, SAE Paper 2007-24-0029, also in SAE Transactions, Journal of Engines - section 3, vol. 116, pp. 1495-1507, ISBN 978-0-7680-1982-7, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sawamoto K, Kawamura Y, Kita T, Matsushita K “Individual cylinder knock control by detecting cylinder pressure”, SAE paper 871911, 1987</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Litak G.,·Kaminski T., Czarnigowski J.,·Grzegorz A K., Wendeker G. M., “Combustion process in a spark ignition engine: analysis of cyclic peak pressure and peak pressure angle oscillations”, Meccanica 44: 1–11, DOI 10.1007/s11012-008- 9148-0, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galloni E., “Analyses about parameters that affect cyclic variation in a spark ignition engine”, Applied Thermal Engineering 29, pp.1131–1137, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J.B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw-Hill Int. editions, 1988</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza F., Torella E., "The Employment of a 1D Simulation Model for the A/F Ratio Control in a VVT Engine”, SAE Paper 2003-01-0027, 2003, also in SAE Transactions, Journal of Engines – section 3 – vol. 112, pp. 124-134, ISBN 0-7680-1450-6, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner R. M., Drallmeier J. A., Daw C. S., Origins of Cyclic Dispersion Patterns in Spark Ignition Engines, Proceedings of the 1998 Technical Meeting of the Central States Section of the Combustion Institute</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza F., Gimelli A., Strazzullo L., Torella E., Cascone C, “Steady-state and Transient Operation Simulation of a ‘Downsized’ Turbocharged SI Engine”, SAE Paper 2007-01-0381, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza F., Gimelli A., Tuccillo R., “The Control of a VVA Equipped SI-Engine Operation by Means of 1D Simulation and Mathematical Optimization”, SAE Paper 2002-01-1107, 2002, also in SAE Transactions, Journal of Engines, Section 3 – Volume 111, pp. 1790-1801., ISBN 0-7680-1287-2, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza F., Gimelli A., Siano D., Torella E. Mastrangelo G., “A Quasi-Dimensional Three-Zone Model for Performance and Combustion Noise Evaluation of a Twin-Spark High-EGR Engine”, SAE Paper 2004-01-0619, 2004, also in SAE Transactions, Journal of Engines - section 3, vol. 113-3, pp. 491-501, ISBN 0-7680-1552-9, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bozza F., Gimelli A., Merola S. S., Vaglieco B. M., “Validation of A Fractal Combustion Model through Flame Imaging”, SAE Paper 2005-01-1120, also in SAE Transactions, Journal of Engines - section 3, vol. 114-3, pp. 973-987, ISBN 0-7680-1689-4, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa A.J., Broatch A., Martın J., Monelletta L., “Combustion noise level assessment in direct injection Diesel engines by means of in-cylinder pressure components”, Meas. Sci. Technol., 18 2131-2142 doi:10.1088/0957-0233/18/7/045, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F Payri, A Broatch, B Tormos and V Marant, “New methodology for in-cylinder pressure analysis in direct injection diesel engines—application to combustion noise”, Meas. Sci. Technol., Vol. 16, pp. 540–547 doi:10.1088/0957-0233/16/2/029, 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Poulos S.G., Heywood J.B., “The Effect of Chamber Geometry on Spark-Ignition Engine Combustion”, SAE paper 830334, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GT-Power, User’s Manual and Tutorial, GT-SUITETM Version 6.1, Gamma Technologies</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hu H., Keck J., “Autoignition of Adiabatically Compressed Combustible Gas Mixtures”, SAE 872110, 1987</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keck J., Hu H., “Explosions of Adiabatically Compressed Gases in a Constant Volume Bomb”, 21st International Symposium on Combustion, The Combustion Institute, pp. 521-529, 1986</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka S., Ayala F., Keck J., “A Reduced Chemical Kinetic Model for HCCI Combustion of Primary Reference Fuels”, Combustion &amp; Flame, 132, pp. 219-239, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hudson C., Gao X., Stone R., “Knock measurement for fuel evaluation in spark ignition engines”, Fuel 80 395-407, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Samimy H., Rizzoni G., “Mechanical Signature Analysis Using Time-Frequency Signal Processing: Application to Internal Combustion Engine Knock Detection”, Proceedings of the IEEE, Vol. 84, No. 9, 1996</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
