<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464762</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464767</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Dynamic Equilibrium with Two Stocks, Heterogeneous Investors, and Portfolio Constraints</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Georgy</given-names>
                  <surname>Chabakauri</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3104</fpage>
         <lpage>3141</lpage>
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464767"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We study dynamic equilibrium in a Lucas economy with two stocks, two heterogeneous constant relative risk aversion investors, and portfolio constraints. We focus on margin and leverage constraints, which restrict access to credit. We find a positive relationship between the amount of leverage in the economy and magnitudes of stock return correlations and volatilities. Tighter constraints generate rich patterns in correlations and volatilities, make them less countercyclical, increase risk premia proportionally to assets' margins, and increase prices of low-margin assets more than prices of high-margin assets. We derive closed-form solutions for the unconstrained case and the case of leverage constraints.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d22e141a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e148" publication-type="other">
We note that margin constraint mJo&lt; 1 does not bind for the more risk-averse investor A in equilibrium.
Consequently, the assumption that investor A is unconstrained does not result in a loss of generality. We do
not consider economies with restricted participation (i.e., m; &gt; 1), for which the analysis is complicated by
singularities in the equilibrium processes because the market prices of risk explode when the economy is
dominated by the constrained investor (e.g., Basak and Cuoco 1998; Chabakauri 2010). We leave this case
for future research.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e171a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e178" publication-type="other">
Similarly to Basak and Cuoco (1998) and Basak (2000,2005), it can be demonstrated that the equilibrium in this
economy is equivalent to the equilibrium in an economy with a representative investor with utility
m(c;A./)= max
where Xt =Çv*t/Çt ■ The expressions for the relative risk aversion V and prudence n of the representative investor,
given by (22), are special cases of those in Basak (2000, 2005), derived for general utility functions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e197a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e204" publication-type="other">
The zero-drift Dynkin operator V is defined as follows:
VF=-yX oxaXJJ+y 0y„y-?-2xyaxa,— j.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e214a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e221" publication-type="other">
Quasilinear differential equations also arise in other models with heterogeneous investors that face portfolio
constraints or are unconstrained but have recursive preferences (e.g., Gârleanu and Panageas 2010; Gârleanu
and Pedersen 2011; He and Krishnamurthy 2013). However, we are not aware of any existence results presented
in the literature.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e238a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e245" publication-type="other">
Cuoco (1997) and Gârleanu and Pedersen (2011) derive similar C-CAPMs, but they do not express adjustment
v* in terms of observable processes. We note that our C-CAPM holds for more general preferences, multiple
assets, and time-varying margins.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e258a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e265" publication-type="other">
The procyclicality of consumption share y can be formally demonstrated by substituting ayt with v*=0 from
(18) into the correlation cony(dy/,dDt) = — o~Jtootf(\ayt\\oDt\)-</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e275a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e282" publication-type="other">
Gordon's formula *1&gt;j = \/{r+ci£). kj —/x p. ) is a remarkably accurate approximation of price-dividend ratio ' j
when the consumption share y is close to 0 or 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e292a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e299" publication-type="other">
We note that the choice of state variables is not unique. For example, one can use the ratio of marginal utilities
A.t =(cj) yA /(c*B) yB and aggregate consumption Dt as state variables instead of consumption share y.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e309a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e316" publication-type="other">
Integrals 3.471.9 and 8.432.1 in Gradshteyn and Ryzhik (2007) imply that
c+oo i h r+oo, _ x</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d22e335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e339" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., and G Bekaert. 2002. International asset allocation with regime shifts. Review of Financial Studies
15:1137-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e349a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e353" publication-type="other">
Basak, S. 2000. A model of dynamic equilibrium asset pricing with heterogeneous beliefs and extraneous risk.
Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 24:63-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e363a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e367" publication-type="other">
. 2005. Asset pricing with heterogeneous beliefs. Journal of Banking and Finance 29:2849-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e374a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e378" publication-type="other">
Basak, S., and B. Croitoru. 2000. Equilibrium mispricing in a capital market with portfolio constraints. Review
of Financial Studies 13:715-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e389a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e393" publication-type="other">
. 2006. On the role of arbitrageurs in rational markets. Journal of Financial Economics 81:143-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e404" publication-type="other">
Basak, S., and D. Cuoco. 1998. An equilibrium model with restricted stock market participation. Review of
Financial Studies 11:309-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e414a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e418" publication-type="other">
Bhamra, H. S., and R. Uppal. 2010. Asset prices with heterogeneity in preferences and beliefs. Working Paper,
University of British Columbia.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e428a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e432" publication-type="other">
Black, F. 1972. Capital market equilibrium with restricted borrowing. Journal of Business 45:444-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e443" publication-type="other">
Breeden, D. T. 1979. An intertemporal asset pricing model with stochastic consumption and investment
opportunities. Journal of Financial Economics 7:265-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e453a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e457" publication-type="other">
Brumm, J., M. Grill, F. Kubier, and K. Schmedders. 2012. Margin requirements and asset prices. Working Paper,
University of Zurich.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e468a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e472" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier, M. K. 2009. Deciphering the liquidity and credit crunch 2007-2008. Journal of Economic
Perspectives 23:77-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e482a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e486" publication-type="other">
Brunnermeier, M. K., and L. H. Pedersen. 2009. Market liquidity and funding liquidity. Review of Financial
Studies 22:2201-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e496a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e500" publication-type="other">
Buraschi, A., F. Trojani, and A. Vedolin. 2010. When uncertainty blows in the orchard: Comovement and
equilibrium volatility risk premia. Working Paper, Imperial College London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e510a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e514" publication-type="other">
Buss, A., and B. Dumas. 2012. The equilibrium dynamics of liquidity and illiquid asset prices. Working Paper,
INSEAD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e524a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e528" publication-type="other">
Campbell, J. Y. 2003. Consumption-based asset pricing. In Handbook of economics and finance, ed. G
Constantinides, M. Harris, and R. Stulz. Amsterdam: North Holland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e542" publication-type="other">
Chabakauri, G 2009. Asset pricing in equilibrium with constraints. Working Paper, London School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e550a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e554" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Asset pricing with heterogeneous investors and portfolio constraints. Working Paper, London
School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e564a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e568" publication-type="other">
Chan, Y. L., and L. Kogan. 2002. Catching up with the Joneses: Heterogeneous preferences and the dynamics of
asset prices. Journal of Political Economy 110:1255-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e582" publication-type="other">
Chen, H., and S. Joslin. 2012. Generalized transform analysis of affine processes and applications in finance.
Review of Financial Studies 25:2225-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e592a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e596" publication-type="other">
Chien, Y., H. Cole, and H. Lustig. 2011. A multiplier approach to understanding the macro implications of
household finance. Review of Economic Studies 78:199-234.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e606a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e610" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H., F. A. Longstaff, and P. Santa-Clara. 2008. Two trees. Review of Financial Studies 21:347-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e621" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H., and J. Saa-Requejo. 2000. Beyond arbitrage: Good-deal asset pricing bounds in incomplete
markets. Journal of Political Economy 108:79-119.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e632a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e636" publication-type="other">
Coen-Pirani, D. 2005. Margin requirements and equilibrium asset prices. Journal of Monetary Economics 52:
449-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e646a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e650" publication-type="other">
Cuoco, D. 1997. Optimal consumption and equilibrium prices with portfolio constraints and stochastic income.
Journal of Economic Theory 72:33-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e660a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e664" publication-type="other">
Cvitanid J., and I. Karatzas. 1992. Convex duality in constrained portfolio optimization. Annals of Applied
Probability 2:767-818.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e674a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e678" publication-type="other">
Detemple, J. B., and S. Murthy. 1997. Equilibrium asset prices and no-arbitrage with portfolio constraints. Review
of Financial Studies 10:1133-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e688a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e692" publication-type="other">
Detemple, J. B., and M. Rindisbacher. 2005. Closed-form solutions for optimal portfolio selection with stochastic
interest rate and investment constraints. Mathematical Finance 15:539-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e702a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e706" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D. 2001. Dynamic asset pricing theory. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e714a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e718" publication-type="other">
Dumas, B., and A. Lyasoff. 2012. Incomplete-market equilibria solved recursively on an event tree. Journal of
Finance 67:1897-941.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e728a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e732" publication-type="other">
Ehling, P., and C. Heyerdahl-Larsen. 2012. Correlations. Working Paper, London Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e739a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e743" publication-type="other">
El Karoui, N., S. Peng, and M. C. Quenez. 1997. Backward stochastic differential equations in finance.
Mathematical Finance 7:1-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e753a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e757" publication-type="other">
Fostel, A., and J. Geanakoplos. 2008. Leverage cycles and anxious economy. American Economic Review
98:1211-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e767a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e771" publication-type="other">
Frazzini, A., and L. H. Pedersen. 2011. Betting against beta. Working Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e778a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e782" publication-type="other">
Gallmeyer, M., and B. Hollifield. 2008. An examination of heterogeneous beliefs with a short-sale constraint in
a dynamic equilibrium. Review of Finance 12:323-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e793a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e797" publication-type="other">
Gârleanu, N., and S. Panageas. 2010. Young, old, conservative, and bold: The implications of heterogeneity and
finite lives for asset pricing. Working Paper, University of California, Berkeley.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e807a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e811" publication-type="other">
Gârleanu, N., and L. H. Pedersen. 2011. Margin based asset pricing and the deviations from the law of one price.
Review of Financial Studies 24:1980-2022.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e821a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e825" publication-type="other">
Gomes, F., and A. Michaelides. 2008. Asset pricing with limited risk sharing and heterogeneous agents. Review
of Financial Studies 21:416-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e835a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e839" publication-type="other">
Gradshteyn, I. S., and I. M. Ryzhik. 2007. Table of integrals, series, and products. New York: Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e846a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e850" publication-type="other">
Gromb, D., and D. Vayanos. 2002. Equilibrium and welfare in markets with financially constrained arbitrageurs.
Journal of Financial Economics 66:361-407.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e860a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e864" publication-type="other">
. 2009. Financially constrained arbitrage and cross-market contagion. Working Paper, INSEAD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e872a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e876" publication-type="other">
. 2010. Limits of arbitrage: The state of the theory. Annual Review of Financial Economics 2:
251-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e886a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e890" publication-type="other">
Guvenen, F. 2009. A parsimonious macroeconomic model for asset pricing. Econometrica 77:1711-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e901" publication-type="other">
Hardouvelis, G A., and S. Perestiani. 1992. Margin requirements, speculative trading, and stock price fluctuations:
The case of Japan. Quarterly Journal of Economics 107:1333-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e911a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e915" publication-type="other">
Hardouvelis, G A., and P. Theodossiou. 2002. The asymmetric relation between initial margin requirements and
stock market volatility across bull and bear markets. Review of Financial Studies 15:1525-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e925a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e929" publication-type="other">
He, Z., and A. Krishnamurthy. 2012. A model of capital and crises. Review of Economic Studies 79:735-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e936a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e940" publication-type="other">
. 2013. Intermediary Asset Pricing. American Economic Review 103:732-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e948a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e952" publication-type="other">
Heaton, J., and D. J. Lucas. 1996. Evaluating the effects of incomplete markets on risk sharing and asset pricing.
Journal of Political Economy 104:443-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e962a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e966" publication-type="other">
Huang, C.-F., and H. Pagés. 1992. Optimal consumption and portfolio policies with an infinite horizon: Existence
and convergence. Annals of Applied Probability 2:36-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e976a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e980" publication-type="other">
Hugonnier, J. 2012. Rational asset pricing bubbles and portfolio constraints. Journal of Economic Theory
147:2260-302.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e990a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e994" publication-type="other">
Karatzas, I., and S. E. Shreve. 1998. Methods of mathematical finance. New York: Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1001a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1005" publication-type="other">
Karolyi, A. G, and R. M. Stulz. 1996. Why do markets move together? An investigation of U.S.-Japan stock
return comovements. Journal of Finance 51:951-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1015a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1019" publication-type="other">
Kiyotaki, N., and J. Moore. 1997. Credit cycles. Journal of Political Economy 105:211-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1027a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1031" publication-type="other">
Kogan, L., I. Makarov, and R. Uppal. 2007. The equity premium and the riskfree rate in an economy with
borrowing constraints. Mathematics and Financial Economics 1:1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1041a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1045" publication-type="other">
Lapidus, L., and G F. Pinder. 1999. Numerical solutions of partial differential equations in science and
engineering. Wiley-Blackwell.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1055a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1059" publication-type="other">
Liu, J. 2007. Portfolio selection in stochastic environments. Review of Financial Studies 20:1-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1066a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1070" publication-type="other">
Longstaff, F. A., and J. Wang. 2012. Asset pricing and credit markets. Review of Financial Studies 25:
3169-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1080a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1084" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. E. 1978. Asset prices in an exchange economy. Econometrica 46:1429-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1091a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1095" publication-type="other">
Lustig, H. N., and S. G Van Nieuwerburgh. 2005. Housing collateral, consumption insurance, and risk premia:
An empirical perspective. Journal of Finance 60:1167-219.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1106a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1110" publication-type="other">
Ma, J., and J. Yong. 1999. Forward-backward stochastic differential equations and their applications. Berlin:
Springer-Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1120a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1124" publication-type="other">
Martin, I. 2013. The Lucas orchard. Econometrica 81:55-111.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1131a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1135" publication-type="other">
Menzly, L., T. Santos, and P. Veronesi. 2004. Understanding predictability. Journal of Political Economy 112:
1-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1145a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1149" publication-type="other">
Pavlova, A., and R. Rigobon. 2008. The role of portfolio constraints in the international propagation of shocks.
Review of Economic Studies 75:1215-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1159a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1163" publication-type="other">
Prieto, R. 2010. Dynamic equilibrium with heterogeneous agents and risk constraints. Working Paper, Boston
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1177" publication-type="other">
Ribeiro, R., and P. Veronesi. 2002. The excess comovement of international stock markets in bad times: A rational
expectations equilibrium model. Working Paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1188a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1192" publication-type="other">
Rytchkov, O. 2011. Dynamic margin constraints. Working Paper, Temple University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1203" publication-type="other">
Schornick, A. V. 2009. Competing capital constraints. Working Paper, INSEAD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1210a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1214" publication-type="other">
Schwert, W. 1989. Why does stock market volatility change over time? Journal of Finance 44:1115-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1221a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1225" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R. J. 1981. Do stock prices move too much to be justified by subsequent changes in dividends? American
Economic Review 71:421-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1235a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1239" publication-type="other">
. 1989. Comovements in stock prices and comovements in dividends. Journal of Finance 44:719-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1250" publication-type="other">
Shiryaev, A. N. 1996. Probability. New York: Springer.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


