<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285025</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Calibration and Demonstration of Vehicle Powertrain Thermal Management Using Model Predictive Control</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Bonkoski</surname>
                  <given-names>Phillip</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Karnik</surname>
                  <given-names>Amey Y.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ford Motor Company</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fuxman</surname>
                  <given-names>Adrian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Honeywell Automotive Software</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>173</fpage>
         <lpage>180</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285025"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Control of vehicle powertrain thermal management systems is becoming more challenging as the number of components is growing, and as a result, advanced control methods are being investigated. Model predictive control (MPC) is particularly interesting in this application because it provides a suitable framework to manage actuator and temperature constraints, and can potentially leverage preview information if available in the future. In previous SAE publications (2015-01-0336 and 2016-01-0215), a robust MPC control formulation was proposed, and both simulation and powertrain thermal lab test results were provided. In this work, we discuss the controller deployment in a vehicle; where controller validation is done through road driving and on a wind tunnel chassis dynamometer. This paper discusses challenges of linear MPC implementation related to nonlinearities in this over-actuated thermal system. Specifically, the fan and grill shutter actuators have a nonlinear influence on the individual airflows through the charge air cooler and radiator heat exchangers, and the design choices in dealing with these nonlinearities affects the control performance and controller memory requirements. The memory requirements of the resulting controller are also analyzed and compared to other MPC controllers.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumar Sharma N. and Roy B.K., “Control Strategies for Advanced Thermal Management System in IC Engine - An Overview,” International Journal of Engineering Research &amp; Technology,pp. 225–231, 6(3):2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maciejowski J. M., Predictive Control with Constraints, Pearson Education Ltd. , 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rawlings J. B., “Tutorial Overview of Model Predictive Control,” IEEE Control Systems Magazine., pp. 38–52, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karnik, A., Pachner, D., Fuxman, A., Germann, D. , “Model Predictive Control for Engine Powertrain Thermal Management Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0336, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karnik, A., Fuxman, A., Bonkoski, P., Jankovic, M. , “Vehicle Powertrain Thermal Management System Using Model Predictive Control,” SAE Int. J. Mater. Manf. 9(3):525–533, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. O. website, “http://www.honeywellonramp.com,” [Online].</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stewart G. E., Borrelli F., Pekar J., Germann D., Pachner D. and Kihas D., “Toward a Systematic Design for Turbocharged Engine Control,” in Automotive Model Predictive Control, Springer-Verlag, Berlin-Heidelber 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
