<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">ctbuhj</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50016544</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CTBUH Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19461186</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19461194</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90021077</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Features</subject>
               <subj-group>
                  <subject>Talking Tall: Dr. Cheong Koon Hean</subject>
               </subj-group>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Nation-Building, Singapore-Style</article-title>
            <subtitle>Better Living Through Density</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hean</surname>
                  <given-names>Cheong Koon</given-names>
                  <prefix>Dr.</prefix>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Singapore Housing &amp; Development Board (HDB), 480, Lorong 6 Toa Payoh, HDB Hub. Singapore 310480</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Cheong Koon Hean has been credited with shaping much of Singapore’s urban landscape. In her role as CEO of the Urban Redevelopment Authority from 2004 to 2010, she was the key driver of Marina Bay, Singapore’s new city extension, and also initiated the Urban Design and Architecture Excellence Program. As CEO of the Housing &amp; Development Board, Dr. Cheong has improved the sustainability of the agency’s high-rise housing blocks, which are home to 82% of the nation’s citizens, and of which 94% are owner-occupied. A Colombo Plan Scholar, Dr. Cheong graduated with a first-class honors degree and University Gold Medal in Architecture from the University of Newcastle; a masters degree in Urban Development Planning from University College London, and has completed the Advanced Management Program at Harvard University. She is also the recipient of the CTBUH Lynn S. Beedle Lifetime Achievement Award in 2016.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e90021065</issue-id>
         <fpage>54</fpage>
         <lpage>56</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2018 Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90021077"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Dr. Cheong Koon Hean was the first woman to receive the Lynn S. Beedle Lifetime Achievement Award from CTBUH, in 2016. As the CTBUH Awards program expands into the Tall + Urban Innovation Conference in 2018 and a new CTBUH Technical Guide on urban spaces is released, featuring Marina Bay and many other successful urban developments, editor Daniel Safarik caught up with Dr. Cheong to look back upon the trails she blazed and the future she envisions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
