<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277623</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study of Soot Formation and Oxidation in the Engine Combustion Network (ECN), Spray A</article-title>
            <subtitle>Effects of Ambient Temperature and Oxygen Concentration</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cenker</surname>
                  <given-names>Emre</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP Energies nouvelles</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bruneaux</surname>
                  <given-names>Gilles</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IFP Energies novelles</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schulz</surname>
                  <given-names>Christof</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IVG, University of Duisburg-Essen</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>352</fpage>
         <lpage>365</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277623"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Within the Engine Combustion Network (ECN) spray combustion research frame, simultaneous line-of-sight laser extinction measurements and laser-induced incandescence (LII) imaging were performed to derive the soot volume fraction (<italic>f<sub>v</sub>
               </italic>). Experiments are conducted at engine-relevant high-temperature and high-pressure conditions in a constant-volume pre-combustion type vessel. The target condition, called “Spray A”, uses well-defined ambient (900 K, 60 bar, 22.8 kg/m³, 15% oxygen) and injector conditions (common rail, 1500 bar, KS1.5/86 nozzle, 0.090 mm orifice diameter, n-dodecane, 363 K).</p>
            <p>Extinction measurements are used to calibrate LII images for quantitative soot distribution measurements at cross sections intersecting the spray axis. LII images are taken after the start of injection where quasi-stationary combustion is already established. In addition, by changing the LII timing relative to the injection, the temporal variation of the soot cloud is observed from initial soot formation until soot oxidization. OH-chemiluminescence imaging was used to determine the lift-off length, relative to the soot-forming region and used to interpret the soot measurements.</p>
            <p>Results show that Spray A is a moderately sooting flame where signal trapping is not significant, aiding the potential for quantitative soot diagnostics. Maximum soot volume fractions around 2-3 ppm are obtained at the nominal ambient temperature defined for Spray A (i.e. 900 K) that rise to 12 ppm at elevated temperature (1030 K). At 1.5 ms nominal injection duration the Spray A soot cloud is mainly transient. Therefore, an extended injection duration of 4 ms at identical rail pressure was used to characterize the soot structure in quasi-steady mode. Variations of ambient temperature and oxygen concentration are carried out showing effects on soot formation and oxidation that are consistent with the literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Genzale, C., Bruneaux, G., Malbec, L. et al., “Comparison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High-Temperature, High-Pressure Facilities,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):156-181, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-2106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meijer, M., Somers, L. M. T., Johnson, J., Naber, J., Lee, S.-Y., Pickett, L. M., Malbec, L.-M., Bruneaux, G., Bardi, M., Payri, R., and Bazyn, T., “Engine Combustion Network (ECN): Characterization and Comparison of Boundary Conditions for Different Combustion Vessels,” submitted to Atomization and Sprays, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kastengren, A. L., Tilocco, F. Z., Powell, C. F., Payri, R., Manin, J., Pickett, L. M., and Bazyn, T., “Engine Combustion Network (ECN): Measurements of Nozzle Geometry and Hydraulic Behavior,” submitted to Atomization and Sprays, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bardi, M., Payri, R., Malbec, L.-M., Bruneaux, G., Pickett, L. M., Manin, J., Bazyn, T., and Genzale, C., “Engine Combustion Network (ECN): Comparison of Spray Development, Vaporization and Combustion in Different Combustion Vessels,” submitted to Atomization and Sprays, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“ECN Website.” [Online]. Available: http://www.sandia.gov/ecn/index.php.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. M. and Siebers, D. L., “Soot in Diesel Fuel Jets: Effects of Ambient Temperature, Ambient Density, and Injection Pressure,” Combustion and Flame, 138:1-2:114-135, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2004.04.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “Soot Distribution in a D.I. Diesel Engine Using 2-D Imaging of Laser-induced Incandescence, Elastic Scattering, and Flame Luminosity,” SAE Technical Paper 920115, 1992, doi:10.4271/920115.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Espey, C., “Soot and Fuel Distributions in a D.I. Diesel Engine via 2-D Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 922307, 1992, doi: 10.4271/922307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Espey, C., “Ignition and Early Soot Formation in a DI Diesel Engine Using Multiple 2-D Imaging Diagnostics,” SAE Technical Paper 950456, 1995, doi:10.4271/950456.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser- Sheet Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Combustion Structure of Free and Wall Impinging Diesel Jets by Simultaneous Laser Induced Fluorescence of Formaldehyde, PAH and OH,” International Journal of Engine Research, 9:3, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. M. and Siebers, D. L., “Soot Formation in Diesel Fuel Jets Near the Lift-Off Length,” International Journal of Engine Research, 7: (2):103-130, 2006, doi:10.1243/146808705X57793.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C. A. and Pickett, L. M., “Ignition, Soot Formation, and Endof- combustion Transients in Diesel Combustion Under high-EGR Conditions,” International Journal of Engine Research, 12:4:376-392, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411399505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C. and Pickett, L., “Soot Formation in Diesel Combustion under High-EGR Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3834, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. and Pickett, L. M., “Diagnostic Considerations for Optical Laser-extinction Measurements of Soot in High-pressure Transient Combustion Environments,” Combustion and Flame, 141:4:371-391, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2005.01.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Williams, T. C., Shaddix, C. R., Jensen, K. a., and Suo-Anttila, J. M., “Measurement of the Dimensionless Extinction Coefficient of Soot Within Laminar Diffusion Flames,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, 50:7-8:1616-1630, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2006.08.024.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Axelsson, B., Collin, R., and Bengtsson, P.-E., “Laser-induced Incandescence for Soot Particle Size and Volume Fraction Measurements Using On-line Extinction Calibration,” Applied Physics B, 72:3:367-372, 2001, doi:10.1007/s003400100504.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Francqueville, L., Bruneaux, G., and Thirouard, B., “Soot Volume Fraction Measurements in a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine by Combined Laser Induced Incandescence and Laser Extinction Method,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):163-182, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S. and Pickett, L. M., “Soot Volume Fraction and Morphology of Conventional and Surrogate Jet Fuel Sprays at 1000-K and 6.7-MPa Ambient Conditions,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 33:2:2911-2918, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2010.05.073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., and Idicheria, C., “Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oger, B., “Soot Characterisation in Diesel Engines Using Laser-induced Incandescence,” University of Brighton, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Crua, C., “Combustion Processes in a Diesel Engine,” University of Brighton, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., Verhoeven, D., and Baritaud, T., “High Pressure Diesel Spray and Combustion Visualization in a Transparent Model Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3648, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-3648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pires da Cruz, A., Dumas, J., and Bruneaux, G., “Two-Dimensional In- Cylinder Soot Volume Fractions in Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Mode,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):2023-2047, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1390.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, H. and Ladommatos, N., “Optical Diagnostics for Soot and Temperature Measurement in Diesel Engines,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 24:3:221-255, 1998, doi:10.1016/S0360-1285(97)00033-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S. and Pickett, L., “Soot Volume Fraction and Morphology of Conventional, Fischer-Tropsch, Coal-Derived, and Surrogate Fuel at Diesel Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):647-664, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, C., Kock, B. F., Hofmann, M., Michelsen, H., Will, S., Bougie, B., Suntz, R., and Smallwood, G., “Laser-induced Incandescence: Recent Trends and Current Questions,” Applied Physics B, 83:3:333-354, 2006, doi:10.1007/s00340-006-2260-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Smallwood, G. J., “A Critique of Laser-Induced Incandescence for the Measurement of Soot,” Cranfield University, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hofmann, M., Kock, B. F., Dreier, T., Jander, H., and Schulz, C., “Laser-induced Incandescence for Soot-particle Sizing at Elevated Pressure,” Applied Physics B, 90:3-4:629-639, 2007, doi:10.1007/s00340-007-2877-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ryser, R., Gerber, T., and Dreier, T., “Soot Particle Sizing During Highpressure Diesel Spray Combustion via Time-resolved Laser-induced Incandescence,” Combustion and Flame, 156:1:120-129, 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.combustflame.2008.08.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kock, B. F., Tribalet, B., Schulz, C., and Roth, P., “Two-color Timeresolved LII Applied to Soot Particle Sizing in the Cylinder of a Diesel Engine,” Combustion and Flame, 147:79-92, 2006, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2006.07.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakai, M., Iguma, H., Kondo, K., and Aizawa, T., “Nanostructure Analysis of Primary Soot Particles Directly Sampled in Diesel Spray Flame via HRTEM,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1722, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1722.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aizawa, T., Nishigai, H., Kondo, K., Yamaguchi, T. et al., “Transmission Electron Microscopy of Soot Particles Directly Sampled in Diesel Spray Flame - A Comparison between US#2 and Biodiesel Soot,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):665-673, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0695.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kondo, K., Yamaguchi, T., Nishigai, H., Takano, S. et al., “High- Resolution Transmission Electron Microscopy of Soot Directly Sampled at Different Axial Locations in Diesel Spray Flame,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-24-0068, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-24-0068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dobbins, R. A., Santoro, R. J., and Semerjian, H. G., “Analysis of Light Scattering from Soot Using Optical Cross Sections for Aggregates,” Symposium (International) on Combustion, 23:1:1525-1532, 1990, doi: 10.1016/S0082-0784(06)80422-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mewes, B. and Seitzman, J. M., “Soot Volume Fraction and Particle Size Measurements with Laser-induced Incandescence,” Applied Optics, 36:3:709-717, 1997, doi:10.1364/AO.36.000709.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “A Study of Soot Cloud Structure In High Pressure Single Hole Common Rail Diesel Injection Using Multi-Layered Laser-Induced Incandescence,” in Comodia, 2001, 622-630, pp. 622-630.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Coy, E., “OH Radical Imaging in a DI Diesel Engine and the Structure of the Early Diffusion Flame,” SAE Technical Paper 960831, 1996, doi:10.4271/960831.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., Siebers, D., and Aradi, A., “Diesel-Spray Ignition and Premixed-Burn Behavior,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0940, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, N., Turbulent Combustion. Cambridge: Cambridge Univ. Press, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. M. and Idicheria, C. A., “Effects of Ambient Temperature and Density on Soot Formation Under High-EGR Conditions,” in THIESEL 2006, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
