<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308446</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of Fuel Cell Stack Durability based on Actual Vehicle Test Data</article-title>
            <subtitle>Current Status and Future Work</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Shimoi</surname>
                  <given-names>Ryoichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aoyama</surname>
                  <given-names>Takashi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Iiyama</surname>
                  <given-names>Akihiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Nissan Motor Co., Ltd.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>960</fpage>
         <lpage>970</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308446"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Nissan began developing a fuel cell vehicle (FCV) in 1996 and has participated in fleet programs in the USA (CaFCP) and in Japan (JHFC) since 2001 to promote FCV development and to educate the public on the benefits of FCVs. The X-TRAIL FCV (latest model) is equipped with various new technologies, including a fuel cell stack that was engineered in-house. The X-TRAIL FCV has evolved from a test vehicle in 2002 to today's model, which provides the utility and conventional conveniences consumers would demand. The cruising range, acceleration performance and maximum speed are competitive with existing gasoline vehicles. However, to enable commercialization of FCVs, further improvements in performance and durability as well as reduction in costs will be necessary. Therefore, Nissan is investigating several different approaches for reducing cost and improving durability and performance.</p>
            <p>This paper describes the durability of the fuel cell stack on the X-TRAIL FCV. Stack durability was estimated from the results of durability tests conducted with power train test benches. Stack performance degradation is considered in terms of three factors--start-stop, load cycling and high potential (idling)--which might be the main causes of the performance decline. Each degradation ratio is discussed in detail. The accuracy of the stack life estimation is also described on the basis of a comparison of FCV test data obtained on public roads, including proving ground and durability test data. A new fuel cell stack is now being developed, aimed at achieving lower cost, higher performance and greater durability. The measures taken to improve the durability of the new stack are also described.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoyama, T., Iiyama, A., Shinohara, K., Kamegaya, S. et al., “Status of FCV Development at Nissan and Future Issues” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):314-323, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Iiyama, (2007). FC Development in Nissan, Proceedings of the FC Expo Technical Conference, Tokyo, February 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. A. Reiser, L. Bregoli, T. W. Patterson, J. S. Yi, J. D. Yang, M. L. Perry, T. D. Jarvi, (2005). A Reverse- Current Decay Mechanism for Fuel Cells. Electrochem. Solid-State Lett., 8 A273-A276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. P. Meyers, R. M. Darling, (2006). Model of Carbon Corrosion in PEM Fuel Cells. J. Electrochem. Soc., 153 A1432-A1442.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. M. Darling, J. P. Meyers, (2003). Kinetic Model of Platinum Dissolution in PEMFCs. J. Electrochem. Soc., 150 A1523-A1527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. M. Darling, J. P. Meyers, (2005). Mathematical Model of Platinum Movement in PEM Fuel Cells. J. Electrochem. Soc., 152 A242-A247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">X. Wang, R. Kumar, D. J. Myers, (2006). Effect of Voltage on Platinum Dissolution. Electrochem. Solid- State Lett., 9 A225-A227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Yasuda, A. Taniguchi, T. Akita, T. Ioroi, Z. Siroma, (2006). Platinum dissolution and deposition in the polymer electrolyte membrane of a PEM fuel cell as studied by potential cycling. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 8 746–752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. L. Borup, J. R. Davey, F. H. Garzon, D. L. Wood, M. A. Inbody, (2006). PEM fuel cell electrocatalyst durability measurements. J. Power Sources, 163 76–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Mitsushima, S. Kawahara, K. Ota, N. Kamiya, (2007). Consumption Rate of Pt under Potential Cycling. J. Electrochem. Soc., 154 B153-B158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Uchimura, S. Kocha, (2007). The Impact of Cycle Profile on PEMFC Durability. ECS Trans., 11 (1) 1215-1226.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. J. Ferreira, G. J. la O’, Y. Shao-Horn, D. Morgan, R. Makharia, S. Kocha, and H. A. Gasteiger, (2005). Instability of Pt/C Electrocatalysts in Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell. J. Electrochem. Soc., 152 A2256-A2271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ohma, S. Suga, S. Yamamoto, and K. Shinohara, (2007). Membrane Degradation Behavior during Open-Circuit Voltage Hold Test. J. Electrochem. Soc., 154 B757-B760.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ohma, S. Yamamoto, K. Shinohara, (2007). Analysis of Membrane Degradation Behavior During OCV Hold Test. ECS Trans., 11 (1) 1181-1192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ohma, S. Suga, S. Yamamoto, K. Shinohara, (2006). Phenomenon Analysis of PEFC for Automotive Use (1): Membrane Degradation Behavior During OCV Hold Test. ECS Trans., 3 (1) 519-529.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Ohma, S. Yamamoto, and K. Shinohara, (2008). Membrane degradation mechanism during opencircuit voltage hold test. J. Power Sources, 182 39- 47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. Endoh, S. Terazono, H. Widjaja, Y. Takimoto, (2004). Degradation Study of MEA for PEMFCs under Low Humidity Conditions. Electrochem. Solid- State Lett., 7 A209-A211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Teranishi, K. Kawata, S. Tsushima, S. Hirai, (2006). Degradation Mechanism of PEMFC under Open Circuit Operation. Electrochem. Solid-State Lett., 9 A475-A477.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Inaba, T. Kinumoto, M. Kiriake, R. Umebayashi, A. Tasaka, Z. Ogumi, (2006). Gas crossover and membrane degradation in polymer electrolyte fuel cells. Electrochim. Acta, 51 5746-5753.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">V. O. Mittal, H. R. Kunz, J. M. Fenton, (2006). Is H2O2 Involved in the Membrane Degradation Mechanism in PEMFC?. Electrochem. Solid-State Lett., 9 A299-A302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Sugawara, T. Maruyama, Y. Nagahara, S. S. Kocha, K. Shinohara, K. Tsujita, S. Mitsushima, K. Ota, Performance decay of proton-exchange membrane fuel cells under open circuit conditions induced by membrane decomposition. J. Power Sources, in press</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
