<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465393</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465691</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Bond Supply and Excess Bond Returns</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Robin</given-names>
                  <surname>Greenwood</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dimitri</given-names>
                  <surname>Vayanos</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>663</fpage>
         <lpage>713</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465691"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We examine empirically how the supply and maturity structure of government debt affect bond yields and expected returns. We organize our investigation around a term-structure model in which risk-averse arbitrageurs absorb shocks to the demand and supply for bonds of different maturities. These shocks affect the term structure because they alter the price of duration risk. Consistent with the model, we find that the maturity-weighted-debt-to-GDP ratio is positively related to bond yields and future returns, controlling for the short rate. Moreover, these effects are stronger for longer-maturity bonds and following periods when arbitrageurs have lost money.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e263a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e270" publication-type="other">
See also Bernanke, Reinhart, and Sack (2004) for a broader analysis of QE programs, and Joyce, My les, et al.
(2012) for a survey of the theoretical and empirical literature on QE.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e280a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e287" publication-type="other">
Some papers document price effects of demand rather than of supply. See, for example, Park and Reinganum
(1986), Ogden (1987), Fernald, Mosser, and Keane (1994), Kambhu and Mosser (2001), Sierra (2010), and Baker
and Wurgler (2012).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e300a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e307" publication-type="other">
Recent evidence suggests that supply effects can have a significant local component. For example, in September
2011 the Federal Reserve announced its intention to buy Treasury securities with maturities from six to 30 years
and sell an equal amount of securities with maturities up to three years. Upon announcement short-term yields
increased, contrary to our model. One way to generate more local effects of supply is to assume that the demand
and supply for each maturity in the absence of arbitrageurs are price-elastic. See Vayanos and Vila (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e326a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e333" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Hetzel and Leach (2001) and D'Amico, English, et al. (2012) for a description of the Fed's
policy during that period.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e344a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e351" publication-type="other">
Our results are also robust to scaling by household net worth from Table B100 of the Flow of Funds instead of by
GDP. Either scaling can be viewed a simple way to adjust for time-series variation in the risk-bearing capacity
of arbitrageurs. Finally, our results would not be affected by taking bond callability into account. This is because
there are few callable bonds, and most of them are callable close to their maturity date.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e367a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e374" publication-type="other">
A detailed discussion of the variation in the maturity of government debt from 1952 onward is in Garbade (2007).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e381a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e388" publication-type="other">
An additional concern related to statistical significance is that the coefficient of the return regression may be
biased if innovations in the forecasting variable, i.e., supply, are correlated with innovations in returns (Mankiw
and Shapiro 1986; Stambaugh 1986). This bias is small in our data and works against us because it lowers the
regression coefficient.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e404a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e411" publication-type="other">
Guibaud, Nosbusch, and Vayanos (2013) study issuance policy in the presence of investor clienteles and demand
shocks. They show that a welfare-maximizing government tailors the maturity structure of its debt to the clientele
mix, e.g., issues a larger fraction of its debt long-term when the fraction of long-horizon investors increases.
A supply response to demand shocks could also be generated by the private sector. Koijen, Van Hemert, and
Van Nieuwerburgh (2009) show that households are more likely to take fixed-rate mortgages (effectively issuing
long-term bonds) when long-term bonds are expensive relative to short-term bonds. Greenwood, Hanson, and
Stein (2010) show that private firms issue a larger fraction of their debt long-term when the supply of long-term
bonds by the government is low.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e440a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e447" publication-type="other">
An alternative version of measure (23), which is more in the spirit of Hypothesis 4, is
W MWD/GDP (24)
where denotes the time-series average of maturity-weighted debt to GDP. Under both (24) and
Hypothesis 4, arbitrageurs are short bonds when the dollar duration of government bond supply is low. Under
(23) instead, arbitrageurs hold a small long position. The choice of (23) or (24) does not matter for our results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e466a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e473" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Duffle's (2010) presidential address to the American Finance Association for a model of slow-
moving capital and a survey of the theoretical and empirical work in that area. See also Gromb and Vayanos
(2010) for a survey of the theoretical literature on the limits of arbitrage.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e487a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e494" publication-type="other">
An alternative proxy for ßt could be constructed based on the total supply of debt, i.e., including corporate
and mortgage-backed debt in addition to government debt. This proxy captures the idea that arbitrageurs care
about the total duration risk that they bear, whether it comes from government or non-government debt. If
shocks to the supply of government and non-government debt are positively correlated, then our estimate of
arbitrageur risk aversion a under the alternative proxy will be lower than under our original proxy. Indeed, since
positive correlation implies larger shocks to total duration risk, explaining a given effect of supply requires
lower arbitrageur risk aversion. The opposite will be true if the two sets of shocks are negatively correlated.
Constructing the alternative proxy requires time-series data on the maturity composition of non-government
debt, which are not available for much of our sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e535a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e539" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., R. Greenwood, and J. Wurgler. 2003. The maturity of debt issues and predictable variation in bond
returns. Journal of Financial Economics 70:261-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e549a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e553" publication-type="other">
Baker, M., and J. Wurgler. 2012. Comovement and predictability relationships between bonds and the cross-
section of stocks. Review of Asset Pricing Studies 2:57-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e563a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e567" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. 1974. Are government bonds net wealth? Journal of Political Economy 82:1095-117.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e574a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e578" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, and R. Hodrick. 2001. Expectations hypotheses tests. Journal of Finance 56:1357-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e586a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e590" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, R. Hodrick, and D. Marshall. 2001. Peso problem explanations for term structure anomalies. Journal
of Monetary Economics 48:241-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e600a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e604" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B., V. Reinhart, and B. Sack. 2004. Monetary policy alternatives at the zero bound: An empirical
assessment. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 2:1-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e614a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e618" publication-type="other">
Bohn, H. 2008. The sustainability of fiscal policy in the United States. In R. Neck and J. Sturm (Eds.),
Sustainability of Public Debt, 15-49. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e628a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e632" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. 2008. Comments on "Bond supply and excess bond returns" by Robin Greenwood and Dimitri
Vayanos. Unpublished notes, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e642a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e646" publication-type="other">
Culbertson, J. 1957. The term structure of interest rates. Quarterly Journal of Economics 71:485-517.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e653a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e657" publication-type="other">
Dai, Q., and T. Philippon. 2006. Fiscal policy and the term structure of interest rates. Working Paper, New York
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e672" publication-type="other">
D'Amico, S., W. English, D. Lopez-Salido, andE. Nelson. 2012. The Federal Reserve's large-scale asset purchase
programs: Rationale and effects. Economic Journal 122:F415^16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e686" publication-type="other">
D'Amico, S., and T. King. 2013. Flow and stock effects of large-scale Treasury purchases: Evidence on the
importance of local supply. Journal of Financial Economics 108:425-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e700" publication-type="other">
DeLong, B., A. Shleifer, L. Summers, and R.Waldmann. 1990. Noise trader risk in financial markets. Journal of
Political Economy 98:703-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e710a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e714" publication-type="other">
Doepke, M., and M. Schneider. 2006. Inflation and the redistribution of nominal wealth. Journal of Political
Economy 114:1069-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e724a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e728" publication-type="other">
Duffee, G 1996. Idiosyncratic variation of Treasury bill yields. Journal of Finance 51:527—52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e735a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e739" publication-type="other">
Duffie, D. 2010. Presidential address: Asset price dynamics with slow-moving capital. Journal of Finance
65:1237-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e750a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e754" publication-type="other">
Fama, E., and R. Bliss. 1987. The information in long-maturity forward rates. American Economic Review
77:680-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e764a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e768" publication-type="other">
Fernald, J., P. Mosser, and F. Keane. 1994. Mortgage security hedging and the yield curve. Federal Reserve Bank
of New York Quarterly Review, Summer-Fall. 92-100.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e778a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e782" publication-type="other">
Ferson, W., and C. Harvey. 1991. The variation of economic risk premiums. Journal of Political Economy
99:385-415.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e792a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e796" publication-type="other">
Fleming, M. 2002. Are larger issues more liquid? Evidence from bill reopenings. Journal of Money, Credit and
Banking 34:707-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e806a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e810" publication-type="other">
Fleming, M., and J. Rosenberg. 2007. How do Treasury dealers manage their positions? Staff Report 299, Federal
Reserve Bank of New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e820a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e824" publication-type="other">
Gagnon, J., M. Raskin, J. Remâche, and B. Sack. 2011. The financial market effects of the Federal Reserve's
large-scale asset purchases. International Journal of Central Banking 7:3—43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e835a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e839" publication-type="other">
Garbade, K. 2007. The emergence of "regular and predictable" as a Treasury debt management strategy. Federal
Reserve Bank of New York Economic Policy Review, March. 53-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e849a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e853" publication-type="other">
Garbade, K., and M. Rutherford. 2007. Buybacks in Treasury cash and debt management. Staff Report 304,
Federal Reserve Bank of New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e863a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e867" publication-type="other">
Greenwood, R., S. Hanson, and J. Stein. 2010. A gap-filling theory of corporate debt maturity choice. Journal of
Finance 65:993-1028.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e877a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e881" publication-type="other">
Greenwood, R., and D. Vayanos. 2010. Price pressure in the government bond market. American Economic
Review, Papers and Proceedings, 585-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e891a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e895" publication-type="other">
Gromb, D., and D. Vayanos. 2010. Limits of arbitrage. Annual Review of Financial Economics 2:251-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e902a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e906" publication-type="other">
Guibaud, S., Y. Nosbusch, and D. Vayanos. 2013. Preferred habitat and the optimal maturity structure of
government debt. Review of Financial Studies 26:1914-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e917a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e921" publication-type="other">
Gurkaynak, R., B. Sack, and J. Wright. 2007. The U.S. Treasury yield curve: 1961 to the present. Journal of
Monetary Economics 54:2291-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e931a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e935" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, J., and C. Wu. 2012. The effectiveness of alternative monetary policy tools in a zero lower bound
environment. Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 44:3-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e945a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e949" publication-type="other">
Hanson, S. 2012. Mortgage convexity. Working Paper, Harvard Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e960" publication-type="other">
Hetzel, R., and R. Leach. 2001. The Treasury-Fed accord: A new narrative account. Federal Reserve Bank of
Richmond Economic Quarterly 87:33-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e970a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e974" publication-type="other">
Hong, H., D. Sraer, and J. Yu. 2013. Reaching for maturity. Working Paper, Princeton University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e985" publication-type="other">
Joyce, M., A. Lasaosa, I. Stevens, and M. Tong. 2011. The financial market impact of quantitative easing in the
United Kingdom. International Journal of Central Banking 7:113-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e996a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1000" publication-type="other">
Joyce, M., D. Myles, A. Scott, and D. Vayanos. 2012. Quantitative easing and unconventional monetary policy:
An introduction. Economic Journal 122:F271-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1010a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1014" publication-type="other">
Kambhu, J., and P. Mosser. 2001. The effect of interest rate options hedging on term-structure dynamics. Federal
Reserve Bank of New York Economic Policy Review 7:51-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1024a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1028" publication-type="other">
Koijen, R., O. Van Hemert, and S. Van Nieuwerburgh. 2009. Mortgage timing. Journal of Financial Economics
93:292-324.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1038a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1042" publication-type="other">
Krishnamurthy, A., and A. Vissing-Jorgensen. 2011. The effects of quantitative easing on interest rates: Channels
and implications for policy. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 2:215-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1052a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1056" publication-type="other">
. 2012. The aggregate demand for Treasury debt. Journal of Political Economy 120:233-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1067" publication-type="other">
Kuttner, K. 2006. Can Central Banks Target Bond Prices? Working Paper 12454, National Bureau of Economic
Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1078a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1082" publication-type="other">
Li, C., and M. Wei. 2012. Term structure modeling with supply factors and the Federal Reserve's large scale
asset purchase programs. Working Paper, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1092a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1096" publication-type="other">
Longstaff, F. 2004. The flight-to-liquidity premium in U.S. Treasury bond prices. Journal of Business
77:511-526.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1106a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1110" publication-type="other">
Lou, D., H. Yan, and J. Zhang. 2013. Anticipated and repeated shocks in liquid markets. Review of Financial
Studies 26:1891-912.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1120a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1124" publication-type="other">
Ludvigson, S., and S. Ng. 2009. Macro factors in bond risk premia. Review of Financial Studies 22:5027-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1131a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1135" publication-type="other">
Malkhozov, A., P. Mueller, A. Vedolin, and G Venter. 2013. Mortgage hedging in fixed income markets. Working
Paper, McGill University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1145a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1149" publication-type="other">
Mankiw, G, and M. Shapiro. 1986. Do we reject too often? Small sample properties of tests of rational expectations
models. Economics Letters 20:139—45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1160a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1164" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F., and R. Sutch. 1966. Innovations in interest-rate policy. American Economic Review
56:178-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1174a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1178" publication-type="other">
Newey, W., and K. West. 1987. A simple, positive semi-definite, heteroskedasticity and autocorrelation consistent
covariance matrix. Econometrica 55:703-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1188a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1192" publication-type="other">
Ogden, J. 1987. The end of the month as a preferred habitat: A test of operational efficiency in the money market.
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 22:329-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1202a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1206" publication-type="other">
Park, S.-Y., and M. Reinganum. 1986. The puzzling price behavior of Treasury bills that mature at the end of
calendar months. Journal of Financial Economics 16:267-83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1216a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1220" publication-type="other">
Politis, D., and J. Romano. 1994. The stationary bootstrap. Journal of the American Statistical Association
89:1303-13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1230a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1234" publication-type="other">
Reinhart, V., and B. Sack. 2000. The economic consequences of disappearing government debt. Brookings Papers
on Economic Activity 31:163-220.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1249" publication-type="other">
Ross, M. 1966. Operation Twist': A mistaken policy? Journal of Political Economy 74:195-9.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1256a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1260" publication-type="other">
Sierra, J. 2010. International capital flows and bond risk premia. Working Paper, Bank of Canada.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1267a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1271" publication-type="other">
Simon, D. 1991. Segmentation in the Treasury bill market: Evidence from cash management bills. Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis 26:97-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1281a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1285" publication-type="other">
. 1994. Further evidence on segmentation in the Treasury bill market. Journal of Banking and Finance
18:139-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1295a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1299" publication-type="other">
Spiegel, M. 1998. Stock price volatility in a multiple security overlapping generations model. Review of Financial
Studies 11:419-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1309a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1313" publication-type="other">
Stambaugh, R. 1986. Bias in regressions with lagged stochastic regressors. Working Paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1321a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1325" publication-type="other">
Swanson, E. 2011. Let's twist again: A high-frequency event-study analysis of Operation Twist and its implications
for QE2. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 1:151-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1339" publication-type="other">
Tobin, J. 1958. Liquidity preference as behavior towards risk. Review of Economic Studies 25:124—31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1346a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1350" publication-type="other">
. 1969. A general equilibrium approach to monetary theory. Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 1:15-29.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1357a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1361" publication-type="other">
Vayanos, D., and J.-L. Vila. 2009. A preferred-habitat model of the term structure of interest rates. Working
Paper, London School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1375" publication-type="other">
Wallace, N. 1967. The term structure of interest rates and the maturity composition of the Federal Debt. Journal
of Finance 22:301-12.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


