<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">17</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830353</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830360</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A CREDIT SCORING MODEL FOR DEVELOPMENT BANKS: AN AFRICAN CASE STUDY / UN MODELE DE "CREDIT SCORING" POUR LES BANQUES DE DEVELOPPEMENT: UNE ETUDE DE CAS AFRICAIN</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Laura</given-names>
                  <surname>Viganò</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1993</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>441</fpage>
         <lpage>482</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830360"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Loan portfolio quality could improve through a suitable creditworthiness analysis specifically designed to adapt to the particular LDC's context. In a broader perspective, an effective control of credit risk is a crucial aspect of bank management, especially in a development setting. This is the case of the Caisse Nationale de Crédit Agricole of Burkina Faso where the model proposed in this paper is tested. Two major problems concerning loan analysis are evident: 1. the difficulty and the high cost of collecting relevant information on borrower-customers businesses; 2. the absence of benchmark procedures by loan analysts consistent with bank lending policy. As regards the first point, loan evaluation procedures can be improved through a more efficient diffusion and use of the information necessary to estimate the probability of repayment. The paper identifies the relevant information and defines the criteria through which it can be weighed in the loan evaluation process. Two hypotheses are offered. The first assumes there are some factors affecting the borrower's behavior that are likely to increase the probability of default. Second, the problem of the quality of information is explored. It is assumed that some mistakes can be made in credit risk evaluation related to the difficulty of obtaining the commonly used information on the customers' ability and willingness to repay. To overcome the widespread absence of correct information evaluation models are used to identify symptoms of the borrower's performance and behavior. For this purpose symptomatic variables are employed to create indicators of the borrower-customers' ability and willingness to repay. As concerns the second point - the credit evaluation procedures - there is often a need for shared decisional frameworks and coordination between the head office and bank branches in order to avoid arbitrary decisions. For this purpose an application of a quantitative model for creditworthiness based on multivariate discriminant analysis is proposed; input variables are factors obtained from a wider set of variables. The quantification of the judgement in a score is also important because it gives responsibility to loan officers for the decisions they take according to the score or for an alternative choice. This last aspect is crucial in development banks, where accountability of loan officers is often a problem. The proposed model is also relevant for the theoretical interpretation of credit risk determinants: objective circumstances - personal or firm specific -, the ability of the bank to correctly evaluate these circumstances and the bank capacity to establish loan conditions to reduce uncertainty. The model demonstrates that the theoretical framework presented in the paper is applicable in an LDC's context. This clear relationship between theory and the interpretation of results can be an important tool in improving portfolio management for development banks and the bank personnel decision making and learning processes. La qualité du portefeuille peut être ameliorée à travers une analyse de la capacité de crédit appropriée au contexte des PVD. En général, un contrôle effectif du risque de crédit est un aspect fondamental de la gestion bancaire, surtout dans un milieu en voie de développement. Cela est vrai aussi pour la Caisse Nationale de Crédit Agricole du Burkina Faso où on a construit le modèle présenté. On peut constater deux problèmes principaux dans l'analyse de crédit: 1. la difficulté et le coût élevé de la collecte des renseignements sur l'emprunteur et sur son entreprise 2. l'absence de procédures standardisées en ligne avec la politique de prêt de la banque qui soient aisement disponibles pour les agents de crédit. En ce qui concerne le premier point, les procédures d'évaluation peuvent être ameliorées à travers la diffusion et l'utilisation plus efficaces des renseignements nécessaires pour estimer la probabilité de remboursement. Cette étude identifie les renseignements importants et définit les critères pour les peser au cours de l'évaluation. On présente deux hypothèses. La première dit qu'il y a des facteurs affectant le comportement de l'emprunteur qui peuvent augmenter la probabilité d'impayé. La deuxième concerne le problème de la qualité des renseignements sur l'emprunteur. On pense que la difficulté d'avoir accès aux données usuellement utilisées pour estimer la capacité et la volonté de remboursement puisse entraîner des erreurs d'évaluation. Afin de sur monter cette difficulté on propose un modèle d'évaluation basé sur les symptômes de la performance et du comportement de l'emprunteur. A cet égard on utilise des renseignements symptomatiques qui créent des indicateurs de la capacité et volonté de remboursement. Quant au deuxième point - les procédures d'évaluation - il y a souvent un besoin d'un cadre décisionnel commun et de coordination entre le siège et les agences pour éviter une prise de décision arbitraire. À ce fin on propose l'application d'un modèle quantitatif pour l'analyse de crédit basé sur l'analyse discriminante multivariée. Les variables inputs sont représentées par des facteurs obtenus d'un nombre plus élevé de variables initiales. La quantification du jugement à travers un score est aussi importante parce qu'elle permet d'attribuer les responsabilités aux agents de crédit pour leurs décisions en accord ou en opposition par rapport au score. Cet aspect est très important dans les banques de développement. Le modèle proposé est aussi important pour l'interpretation des facteurs déterminant le risque de crédit: les caractéristiques personnelles ou de l'entreprise de l'emprunteur, la capacité de la banque d'évaluer correctement ces caractéristiques et l'habileté de la banque d'établir des conditions sur le prêt qui contribuent à réduire le risque de crédit. Le modèle démontre que l'approche théorique présentée dans l'étude est valable pour le contexte des PVD. Cette relation évidente entre la théorie et l'interprétation des résultats peut devenir un instrument important pour améliorer la gestion du portefeuille des banques de développement ainsi que la capacité décisionnelle et le processus d'apprentissage du personnel bancaire.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d22e172a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e179" publication-type="other">
Vigano,

              (1992
              
              )
            </mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e192a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e199" publication-type="other">
Masini (1989)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e205" publication-type="other">

              Vigano (1992
              
              )
            </mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e215a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e222" publication-type="other">

              Eisenbeis (1981
              
              )
            </mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e231" publication-type="other">
Orgler (1970)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e238a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e245" publication-type="other">
Joy
e Tollefson, (1975)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e256a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e263" publication-type="other">
Overstreet and Kemp (1986).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e270a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e277" publication-type="other">
Masini (1987).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e284a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e291" publication-type="other">
Lapar and Graham (1988)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e298a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e305" publication-type="other">
Masini (1989)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e311" publication-type="other">

              Vigano (1992
              
              )
            </mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d22e321a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d22e328" publication-type="other">

              Vigano, (1992
              
              )
            </mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d22e347a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e351" publication-type="other">
AA.VV., 1980, Borrowers and Lenders. Rural Financial Markets &amp; Institutions in Developing Countries. Overseas
Development Institute - John Howell, London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e361a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e365" publication-type="other">
AA.VV., 1975, Scritti in onore di Ugo Caprara. Vallardi, Milan.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e372a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e376" publication-type="other">
Adams Dale W, Douglas H. Graham, J.D. Von Pischke, 1984, Undermining Rural Development with Cheap Credit.
Westview Press, Boulder and London, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e386a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e390" publication-type="other">
Adera Abebe, 1987, Agricultural Credit and the Mobilization of Resources in Rural Africa. Savings and
Development-Finafrica, n. 1, p. 29-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e401a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e405" publication-type="other">
Aguilera N.A., C. Gonzalez-Vega, 1990, Loan Repayment in Rural Financial Markets: A Multinomial Logit Analysis.
Economics and Sociology Occasional Paper No. 1776, Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural
Sociology, The Ohio State University, November.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e418a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e422" publication-type="other">
Aguilera Nelson A., Claudio Gonzalez-Vega, Douglas H. Graham, 1990, The Agricultural Development Bank
of the Dominican Republic: a Loan Repayment Analysis. Economics and Sociology Occasional Paper No.
1733, Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology, The Ohio State University, July.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e435a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e439" publication-type="other">
Alberici Adalberto, 1986, Integrazione del modelli di previsione delle insolvenze nella valutazione dei fidi ban-
cari, in: G. Forestieri, ed., La previsione delle insolvenze aziendali, Giuffre, Milano, p. 135-152.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e449a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e453" publication-type="other">
Altman Edward I. (et al.), 1981, Application of Classification Techniques in Business, Banking and Finance, Jai
Press Inc., Greenwich, Connecticut.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e463a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e467" publication-type="other">
Altman Edward I., 1980, Commercial Bank Lending: Process, Credit Scoring, and Costs of Errors in Lending.
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, Proceedings Issue, n. 4, p. 813-832.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e477a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e481" publication-type="other">
Altman Edward I., 1983, Corporate Financial Distress, John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e489a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e493" publication-type="other">
Altman Edward I., 1984, The success of business failure prediction models: An international survey. Journal
of Banking and Finance 2, p. 171-198.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e503a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e507" publication-type="other">
Altman E.I., R.G. Haldeman, P. Narayanan, 1977, ZetaTM Analysis. A new model to identify bankruptcy risk
of corporations. Journal of Banking and Finance 1, p. 29-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e517a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e521" publication-type="other">
Avery Robert B., 1981, Two-Group Classification Techniques: Conceptual Issues, in: E.I. Altman (et al.), Ap-
plication of Classification Techniques in Business, Banking and Finance, Jai Press Inc., Greenwich, Con-
necticut, p. 1-58.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e534a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e538" publication-type="other">
Baker Chester B., Bernadette Dia, 1987, Default Management in an Agricultural Lending Program in Ivory Coast.
Savings and Development-Finafrica, n. 2, p. 161-180.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e548a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e552" publication-type="other">
Barry P.J., C.B. Baker, L.R. Sanint, 1981, Farmers' Credit Risks and Liquidity Management. American Journal
of Agricultural Economics, May, p. 216-227.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e562a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e566" publication-type="other">
Bates James, The Financing of Small Business, 1971, Sweet and Maxwell, London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e574a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e578" publication-type="other">
Bathory Alexander, 1987, The Analysis of Credit, McGraw-Hill, London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e585a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e589" publication-type="other">
Baydas Mayada, Carlos E. Cuevas, 1990, The Demand for Funds from Rural Credit Unions in Togo. Savings
and Development-Finafrica, n. 4, p. 371-380.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e599a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e603" publication-type="other">
Bianchi Tancredi, 1977, / fidi bancari, UTET, Torino.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e610a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e614" publication-type="other">
Chesser Delton L., 1974, Predicting Loan Noncompliance, The Journal of Commercial Bank Lending, August,
p. 28-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e624a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e628" publication-type="other">
CNCA, 1988/89, Rapport d'Activity, Caisse Natiortale de Credit Agricole, Ouagadougou.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e635a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e639" publication-type="other">
Corielli Francesco, 1986, Note sull'applicazione di alcuni modelli per I'analisi discriminante, in: G. Forestieri,
ed., 1986, La previsione delle insolvenze aziendali, Giuffre, Milano, p. 81-110.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e654" publication-type="other">
DeH'Amore Giordano, 1965, Economia delle aziende di credito, Vol. I, I prestiti bancari, Giuffre, Milano.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e661a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e665" publication-type="other">
Dematte Claudio, 1974, La valutazione delta capacita di credito nelle analisi di fido, Vallardi, Milano.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e672a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e676" publication-type="other">
Dillon William R., Matthew Goldstein, 1978, Discrete Discriminant Analysis. John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e683a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e687" publication-type="other">
Edmister Robert O., 1972, An Empirical Test of Financial Ratio Analysis for Small Business Failure Prediction,
Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, March, p. 1477-1493.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e697a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e701" publication-type="other">
Eisenbeis Robert A., 1977, Pitfalls in the Application of Discriminant Analysis in Business, Finance and Economics,
The Journal of Finance 3, p. 875-900.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e711a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e715" publication-type="other">
Eisenbeis Robert A., 1981 (1), Credit Scoring Applications, in: E.I. Altman (et al.), Application of Classification
Techniques in Business, Banking and Finance, Jai Press Inc., Greenwich, Connecticut, p. 167-198.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e726a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e730" publication-type="other">
Eisenbeis Robert A., 1981 (2), Discriminant Analysis Application Problems, in: E.I. Altman (et al.), Application
of Classification Techniques in Business, Banking and Finance, Jai Press Inc., Greenwich, Connecticut,
p. 119-166.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e743a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e747" publication-type="other">
Ellsasser Konrad, Diop Modou, 1990, La Banque Experimental de Banh. Une demarche de recherche-
developpement sur le credit en milieu rural sahelien, DSA-CIRAD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e757a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e761" publication-type="other">
Forestieri Giancarlo (ed.), 1986, La previsione delle insolvenze aziendali, Giuffre, Milano.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e768a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e772" publication-type="other">
Gilbert Ethel S., 1968, On Discrimination Using Qualitative Variables. Journal of the American Statistical Associa-
tion, December, p. 1399-1412.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e782a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e786" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez-Vega Claudio, 1989, Prestiti all'agricoltura e razionamento del credito: la legge ferrea del tasso di
interesse, in Mauri, 1989, Problematiche finanziarie dello sviluppo rurale, Finafrica-Cariplo, Giuffre, Milano,
p.87-106.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e799a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e803" publication-type="other">
Jensen Michael C, William H. Mackling, 1976, Theory of the Firm: Managerial Behavior, Agency Costs and
Ownership Structure, Journal of Financial Economics, Vol. 3 p. 305-360.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e814a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e818" publication-type="other">
Joy Maurice O., John O. Tollefson, 1975, On the Financial Applications of Discriminant Analysis, Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis, Dec, p. 723-739.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e828a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e832" publication-type="other">
Khalily Baqui M.A., Richard L. Meyer, 1990, Political Economy and Rural Loan Recovery: an Example from
Bangladesh. Economics and Sociology Occasional Paper No. 1773, Department of Agricultural Economics
and Rural Sociology, The Ohio State University, November.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e845a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e849" publication-type="other">
Koch Timothy W., 1988, Bank Management, The Dryden Press, Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e856a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e860" publication-type="other">
Lachenbruch Peter A., 1975, Discriminant Analysis, Hafner Press, New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e867a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e871" publication-type="other">
L'Aot L., 1989, Rapport d'evaluation du renforcement de la structure financiere et des ressources de la Caisse
Nationale de Credit Agricole du Burkina Faso, Caisse Centrale de Cooperation Economique, Juin.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e881a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e885" publication-type="other">
Lapar Lucila A., Douglas H. Graham, 1988, Credit Rationing under a Deregulated Financial System. Paper
presented at the Seminar-Workshop on "Financial Intermediation in the Rural Sector: Research Results
and Policy Issues", ACPC, PIDS, OSU, Central Bank of Philippine, 26-27 Sept.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e899a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e903" publication-type="other">
Lee W.F., M.D. Boehlje, A.G. Nelson, W.G. Murray, 1988, Agricultural Finance. Eighth Edition, Iowa State Univer-
sity Press, Ames, Iowa.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e913a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e917" publication-type="other">
Maddala G.S., 1988, Introduction to Econometrics, MacMillan Publishing Company, New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e928" publication-type="other">
Masini Mario, 1985, Alcune relazioni tra tassi di interesse, propensione al rischio e valore delta capacita di credito,
in Studi in onore di Francesco Parrillo, Volume Primo, Giuffre, Milano, p. 405-417, Estratto.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e938a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e942" publication-type="other">
Masini Mario, 1987, Mali. In Masini Mario (ed.), Rural Finance Profiles in African Countries, Vol. I, FAO-Finafrica
Working Group, Finafrica-Cariplo, Milano, p. 79-118.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e952a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e956" publication-type="other">
Masini Mario (ed.), 1987 and 1989, Rural Finance Profiles in African Countries, Vol. I e II. FAO-Finafrica Work-
ing Group, Finafrica-Cariplo, Milano.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e966a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e970" publication-type="other">
Masini Mario, 1975, Un'applicazione dell'analisi delle decision'! alle indagini svolte negli uffici fidi, in AA.VV.,
Scritti in onore di Ugo Caprara, Vallardi, Milano, p. 433-447.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e981a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e985" publication-type="other">
Mauri Arnaldo (ed.), 1989, Problematiche finanziarie dello sviluppo rurale, Finafrica-Cariplo, Giuffre, Milano.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e992a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e996" publication-type="other">
Maxwell Albert Ernest, 1977, Multivariate Analysis in Behavioural Research, Chapman and Hall, London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1003a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1007" publication-type="other">
McLeod Ross H., 1991, Informal and Formal Sector Finance in Indonesia: The Financial Evolution of Small
Business, Savings and Development-Finafrica, n. 2, p. 187-209.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1017a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1021" publication-type="other">
Mensah Yaw M., 1984, An Examination of the Stationary of Multivariate Bankruptcy Prediction Models: A
Methodological Study, Journal of Accounting Research 1, p. 380-395.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1031a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1035" publication-type="other">
Meyer Richard L., Adelaida P. Alicbusan, 1984, Farm-Household Heterogeneity and Rural Financial Markets:
Insights from Thailand. In: Adams, Graham, Von Pischke, 1984, Undermining Rural Development with
Cheap Credit, Westview Press, Boulder and London, p. 22-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1048a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1052" publication-type="other">
Myers J.H., E.W. Forgy, 1963, The Development of Numerical Credit Evaluation Systems, Journal of the American
Statistical Association 58, p. 799-806.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1063a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1067" publication-type="other">
Nelson Gerald C, Ricardo Cruz-Letona, 1991, The Importance of Default Risk to Agricultural Development Banks:
An Example from El Salvador. Savings and Development-Finafrica, n. 1, p. 19-38.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1077a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1081" publication-type="other">
Nelson Mark, 1974, Comment: Evaluative Techniques in Consumer Finance - Experimental Results and Policy
Implications for Financial Institutions. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis, March, p. 285-286.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1091a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1095" publication-type="other">
Njoku J.E., P.C. Obasi, 1991, Loan Repayment and its Determinants Under the Agricultural Credit Guarantee
Scheme in Imo State, Nigeria. African Review of Money Finance and Banking - Finafrica, n. 2, p. 167-180.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1105a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1109" publication-type="other">
Njoku J.E., M.A.C.A. Odii, 1991, Determinants of Loan Repayment under the Special Emergency Loan Scheme
(SEALS) in Nigeria: a Case Study of Imo State. African Review of Money Finance and Banking - Finafrica,
n. 1, p. 39-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1122a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1126" publication-type="other">
Odii M.A.C.A., J.E. Njoku, Major Factors Influencing Loan Repayment by Poultry Producers Under the Super-
vised Agricultural Credit Scheme in Imo State, Nigeria, School of Agriculture and Agricultural Technology.
Federal University of Technology, Owerri, Imo State, Nigeria.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1139a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1143" publication-type="other">
Orgler Yair E., 1970, Analytical Methods in Loan Evaluation, Lexington Books, D.C. Heath and Company, Lex-
ington.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1154a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1158" publication-type="other">
Ousseni Cisse Abdou, 1991, Experience de la Caisse Nationale de Credit Agricole du Burkina Faso (CNCA-B),
Atelier sur "Les structures institutionnelles pour ameliorer les services financiers en milieu rural", Abid-
jan, Fevrier.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1175" publication-type="other">
Overstreet George A., Jr., Robert S. Kemp, Jr., 1986, Managerial Control in Credit Scoring Systems. Journal
of Retail Banking, n. 1-2, p. 79-86.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1189" publication-type="other">
Pindyck R.S., D.L. Rubinfeld, 1981, Econometric Models and Economic Forecasts, McGraw-Hill, New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1196a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1200" publication-type="other">
Roberts R.J.A., M. Harper (eds.), 1980, Agricultural Credit Training, FAO-The Plunkett Foundation, Roma, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1207a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1211" publication-type="other">
Rossi Claudia, 1988, Indicator! di bilancio, modelli di classificazione e previsione delle insolvenze aziendali, Giuffre,
Milano.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1221a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1225" publication-type="other">
Rossignoli Bruno, 1989, Agricoltura, investimenti e credito agrario nei Paesi in via di sviluppo. In Mauri, Pro-
blematiche finanziarie dello sviluppo rurale, Finafrica-Cariplo, Giuffre, Milano, p. 45-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1236a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1240" publication-type="other">
Ruozi Roberto, 1964, L'analisi delle caratteristiche finanziarie aziendalinella valutazione del fidi agrari. II Rispar-
mio, p. 1319-1361, Agosto.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1250a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1254" publication-type="other">
Sanderatne Nimal, 1989, La mancata restituzione del prestiti da parte del piccoli coltivatori: un approccio analitico.
In Mauri (ed.), Problematiche finanziarie dello sviluppo rurale, Finafrica-Cariplo, Giuffre, Milano, p. 107-124.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1264a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1268" publication-type="other">
Sanderatne Nimal, 1986, The political Economy of Small Farmer Loan Delinquency. Savings and Development,
n. 4, p. 343-354.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1278a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1282" publication-type="other">
SAS, 1985, Procedures Guide for Personal Computers, Version 6 Edition, SAS Institute Inc., Cary, North Carolina.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1289a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1293" publication-type="other">
SAS, 1987, SAS/STAT Guide for Personal Computers, Version 6 Edition, SAS Institute Inc., Cary, North Carolina.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1304" publication-type="other">
Sinkey Joseph F., Jr., 1981, Failure-Prediction Models for Nonfinancial Firms. In: Altman (et al.), Application
of Classification Techniques in Business, Banking and Finance, Jai Press Inc., Greenwich, Connecticut,
p. 255-306.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1318a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1322" publication-type="other">
Slangen Anthon, 1989, Burkina Faso. In Masini (ed.), Rural Finance Profiles in African Countries, Vol. II, FAO-
Finafrica Working Group, Finafrica-Cariplo, Milano, p. 3-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1332a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1336" publication-type="other">
Stickley Thomas, Edouard Tapsoba, 1980, Loan Repayment Delinquency in Upper Volta. In AA.VV., Borrowers
and Lenders. Rural Financial Markets &amp; Institutions in Developing Countries. Overseas Development In-
stitute - John Howell, London, p. 273-285.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1349a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1353" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz Joseph E., Andrew Weiss, 1981, Credit Rationing in Markets with Imperfect Information. The American
Economic Review, June, p. 393-410.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1363a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1367" publication-type="other">
Tagliavini Giulio, 1988, La valutazione del merito creditizio nei prestiti personal! e nel credito al consumo. II Rispar-
mio, n. 2, p. 277-339.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1377a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1381" publication-type="other">
Teodori Claudio, 1989, Modelli di previsione nell'analisi economico-aziendale, Giappicchelli, Torino.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1388a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1392" publication-type="other">
Vigano Laura, 1992 (1), African Banks' Funding Policies and Effective Lending, Universita degli Studi di Bergamo,
Quaderni del Dipartimento di Economia Aziendale, n. 4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1403a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1407" publication-type="other">
Vigano Laura, 1992 (2), La capacita di credito: analisi delle determinant! e strumenti per la valutazione in un
contesto di sottosviluppo, Dissertazione di Dottorato di Ricerca, Universita degli Studi di Bergamo, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1417a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1421" publication-type="other">
Vigano Laura, 1992 (3), The rural demand for financial services, the response of the informal financial market
and the intervention of credit projects. Critical evaluation. Universita degli Studi di Bergamo, Quaderni
del Dipartimento di Economia Aziendale, n. 5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1434a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1438" publication-type="other">
Vogel Robert C., 1981, Rural Financial Market Performance: Implications of Low Delinquency Rates. American
Journal of Agricultural Economics, Feb., p. 58-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1448a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1452" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke J.D., 1991, Finance at the Frontier. Debt Capacity and the Role of Credit in the Private Economy.
Economic Development Institute of The World Bank, Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1462a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1466" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke J.D., 1989, Risk: the Neglected Dimension in Rural Credit Projects. Savings and Development-
Finafrica, n. 2, p. 133-147.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1476a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1480" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke J.D., 1983, The Quantification of Farm Debt Capacity, EDI Training Materials, IBRD.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1492" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke J.D., Dale W Adams, 1980, Fungibility and the Design and Evaluation of Agricultural Credit Pro-
jects. American Journal of Agricultural Economics, Nov., p. 719-726.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1502a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1506" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke J.D., Dale W Adams, Gordon Donald, 1983, Rural Financial Markets in Developing Countries. Their
Use and Abuse. The Economic Development Institute of The World Bank- The Johns Hopkins University
Press, Baltimore and London.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1519a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1523" publication-type="other">
Von Pischke J.D., R.C. Vogel, P. Flath, M.C. Mould, 1988, Measurement of Loan Repayment Performance.
Economic Development Institute of The World Bank, The International Bank for Reconstruction and Develop-
ment, April.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1536a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1540" publication-type="other">
Yabile K.R., 1987, Provision of Liquidity Management: An Incentive to Curb Loan Default in the Ivory Coast's
Agricultural Credit Programs. Savings and Development-Finafrica, n. 4, p. 403-422.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d22e1550a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d22e1554" publication-type="other">
Zmijewski Mark E., 1984, Methodological Issues Related to the Estimation of Financial Distress Prediction Models,
Journal of Accounting Research 22, Suppl., p. 59-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


