<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26422611</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reduced Convective Combustion Chamber Wall Heat Transfer Losses of Hydrogen-Fueled Engines by Vortex-Stratified Combustion - Part 1</article-title>
            <subtitle>Background and Optical Engine Observations</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Oh</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Brouillette</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Plante</surname>
                  <given-names>Jean-Sebastien</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Université de Sherbrooke</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>December 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26422609</issue-id>
         <fpage>2248</fpage>
         <lpage>2258</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26422611"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>A vortex-stratified combustion process for hydrogen-fueled reciprocating internal combustion engines is introduced to increase the thermal efficiency by reducing the convective heat transfer losses to the surrounding walls during combustion. The process imposes a highly ordered rotational field upon the charge in a separate, transverse, cylindrically shaped combustion chamber by means of channels that connect with the main chamber enclosed by the engine cylinder and piston. Gaseous hydrogen is injected directly during the compression stroke, while air enters into the combustion chamber tangentially and preferentially along the circumference due to the Coandă effect. The two streams entrain one another and develop into a vigorous vortex by virtue of the chamber and channel geometries. As mixing proceeds, the fuel is confined radially from the combination of finite-time diffusion being outpaced by the replenishment of pure air at the periphery, and the centripetal field formed by the rotating flow acting on the different density gas mixture. Combustion takes place with a flame propagation that initially follows the rotation of the bulk flow, and then curls radially inward toward the center. This work investigates the process in a fired, optically accessible 2-stroke hydrogen-fueled direct-injected engine tested at up to 5000 RPM. This paper, the first of two parts, explains the theoretical background; presents the schlieren observations; results of zero-dimensional cylinder pressure indication; and apparent heat release measurements comparing two combustion chamber designs - one that actualizes a homogeneous mixture without specific charge motion directionality, and another with the here-introduced vortex-stratified approach.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verhelst, S., Wallner, T., “Hydrogen-Fueled Internal Combustion Engines,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci., 35(6):490-527, December 2009, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2009.08.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichlseder, H., Wallner, T., Freymann, R., and Ringler, J., "The Potential of Hydrogen Internal Combustion Engines in a Future Mobility Scenario," SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-2267, 2003, https://doi.org/10.4271/2003-01-2267.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wimmer, A., Wallner, T., Ringler, J., and Gerbig, F., "H2-Direct Injection - A Highly Promising Combustion Concept," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0108, 2005, https://doi.org/10.4271/2005-01-0108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shudo, T., “Improving thermal efficiency by reducing cooling losses in hydrogen combustion engines,” Int J Hydrogen Energy 32 (17):4285-4293, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2007.06.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eichlseder, H., Grabner, P., Gerbig, F., Heller, K., “Advanced Combustion Concepts and Development Methods for Hydrogen IC Engines, FISITA 2008 World Automotive Congress, F2008-06-103, 2008, Munich, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Michl, J., Schenk, M., Rottengruber, H., Huhn, W., “Thermal Boundary Conditions in a Stoichiometric Operating Hydrogen Engine,” FISITA 2008 World Automotive Congress, F2008-06-110, 2008, Munich, Germany.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shudo, T., Nabetani, S., Nakajima, Y., “Analysis of the degree of constant volume and cooling loss in a spark ignition engine fuelled with hydrogen,” International Journal of Engine Research, 2(1):81-92, February 2001, doi:10.1243/1468087011545361.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shudo T., Oba S., “Mixture distribution measurements using laser induced breakdown spectroscopy in hydrogen direct injection stratified charge,” Int J Hydrogen Energy 34(5):2488-2493, March 2009, doi:10.1016/j.ijhydene.2009.01.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grabner, P., Eichlseder, H., Gerbig, F., Gerke, U., “Optimisation of a Hydrogen Internal Combustion Engine With Inner Mixture Formation,” 1st International Symposium on Hydrogen Internal Combustion Engines, September 28-29, 2006, Graz, Austria.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oppenheim, A., "Prospects for Combustion in Piston Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0999, 2002, https://doi.org/10.4271/2002-01-0999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heitland, H., Rinne, G., and Wislocki, K., "Can the Best Fuel Economy of Today's Engines Still Be Improved?," SAE Technical Paper 981912, 1998, https://doi.org/10.4271/981912.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals,” 1988, New York, McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Norton, D. G., Vlachos, D. G., “Combustion characteristics and flame stability at the microscale: a CFD study of premixed methane/air mixtures,” Chemical Engineering Science 58(21):4871-4882, November 2003, doi:10.1016/j.ces.2002.12.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toulson, E., Schock, H., and Attard, W., "A Review of Pre-Chamber Initiated Jet Ignition Combustion Systems," SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2263, 2010, https://doi.org/10.4271/2010-01-2263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brandstetter, W., Decker, G., and Reichel, K., "The Water-Cooled Volkswagen PCI-Stratified Charge Engine," SAE Technical Paper 750869, 1975, https://doi.org/10.4271/750869.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brandstetter, W., „Über neuere Arbeiten am VW-PCI- und VW-PCVSchichtladeverfahren,“ MTZ 38(7/8):327-330, 1977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brandstetter, W., "The Volkswagen Lean Burn PC-Engine Concept," SAE Technical Paper 800456, 1980, https://doi.org/10.4271/800456.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, R. C., Alkidas, A. C., “A Visual Study of Divided-Chamber Diesel Combustion Using a Rapid Compression Machine,” Combustion and Flame 53(1-3):65-81, November 1983, doi:10.1016/0010-2180(83)90007-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arcoumanis, C., Hull, D., and Whitelaw, J., "An Approach to Charge Stratification in Lean-Burn, Spark-Ignition Engines," SAE Technical Paper 941878, 1994, https://doi.org/10.4271/941878.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapsa, A. P., Dahm, W. J. A., “Hyperacceleration effects on turbulent combustion,” Proc. of the Combustion Institute 32(2):1731-1738, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2008.05.038.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dumitrache, A., Frunzulica, F., Ionescu, T. C., “Mathematical Modelling and Numerical Investigations on the Coanda Effect,” In Nonlinearity, Bifurcation and Chaos - Theory and Applications, edited by Awrejcewicz, J., Hagedorn P., 2012, accessed 2015/02/01, http://cdn. intechopen.com/pdfs-wm/40430.pdf, doi: 10.5772/50403.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oh D., Plante J., “A Highly Efficient Small-Displacement Marine Two-Stroke H2DI Engine With Low Emissions,” ASME. J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power 135(8):082001-082001-10, 2013, doi:10.1115/1.4023752.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Namazian, M., Hansen, S., Lyford-Pike, E., Sanchez-Barsse, J. et al., "Schlieren Visualization of the Flow and Density Fields in the Cylinder of a Spark-Ignition Engine," SAE Technical Paper 800044, 1980, https://doi.org/10.4271/800044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salazar, V. and Kaiser, S., "Influence of the Flow Field on Flame Propagation in a Hydrogen-Fueled Internal Combustion Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2376-2394, 2011, https://doi.org/10.4271/2011-24-0098.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weinrotter, M., Wintner, E., Iskra, K., Neger, T. et al., "Optical Diagnostics of Laser-Induced and Spark Plug-Assisted HCCI Combustion," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0129, 2005, https://doi.org/10.4271/2005-01-0129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baritaud, T., "High Speed Schlieren Visualization of Flame Initiation in a Lean Operating S.I. Engine," SAE Technical Paper 872152, 1987, https://doi.org/10.4271/872152.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meier, F., Köhler, J., Stolz, W., Bloss, W. et al., "Cycle-Resolved Hydrogen Flame Speed Measurements with High Speed Schlieren Technique in a Hydrogen Direct Injection SI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 942036, 1994, https://doi.org/10.4271/942036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spicher, U., Kröger, H., and Ganser, J., "Detection of Knocking Combustion Using Simultaneously High-Speed Schlieren Cinematography and Multi Optical Fiber Technique," SAE Technical Paper 912312, 1991, https://doi.org/10.4271/912312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.photron.com/datasheet/FASTCAM_SA-X2.pdf, accessed 2016/02/24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luminus PT121 Product Datasheet, http://www.mouser.com/pdfdocs/Luminus_PT121Specifcation_PDS1384_Rev08E3.pdf, accessed 2016/02/24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kaiser, S. A., Salazar, V. M., Hoops, A. A., “Schlieren measurements in the round cylinder of an optically accessible internal combustion engine,” Applied Optics, 52(14): 3433-3443, 2013, doi:10.1364/AO.52.003433.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
