<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830710</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830714</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>PRODUCTION CREDIT FOR AFRICAN SMALL-HOLDERS: CONDITIONS FOR PRIVATE PROVISION / DU CRÉDIT POUR LES PAYSANS AFRICAINS: QU'EST-CE QU'IL FAUT POUR QUE LE SECTEUR PRIVÉ LE FOURNISSE?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Ann</given-names>
                  <surname>Gordon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
                  <surname>Goodland</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>55</fpage>
         <lpage>84</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830714"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>It was hoped that market reforms in sub-Saharan Africa would unleash the private sector, such that farmers would benefit from access to new markets and dynamic privately provided services. The reality is that commercial activity has been highly selective and often disappointing. Many farmers face a deterioration in market access and services, including credit. This paper examines the conditions for private sector provision of production credit for smallholders. Drawing on recent field work in Uganda and Zimbabwe, it analyses the performance of two contrasting approaches to small holder credit. These schemes have coverage far in excess of any other formal sector source of credit for smallholders (300,000 and 53,000 farmers respectively). The Zimbabwean scheme is an apparently commercially sustainable text book model of how to run such a scheme. The Ugandan scheme is paternalistic, institutionally complicated and subject to significant inefficiencies in its operation, but nonetheless a potentially significant improvement on the "without scheme" scenario. Of note also is the scale of coverage, and its strong poverty focus. The paper concludes with a discussion of generic lessons for other credit schemes and commodities. Il était prévu que les réformes des marchés en Afrique sous-Saharienne lâcheraient le secteur privé, tant que les paysans auraient accès aux marchés nouveaux et aux services dynamiques provisionés par le secteur privé. Cependant les activités commerciales sont très limitées et souvent décevantes. Beaucoup de paysans ont de pires accès aux marchés et aux services, y compris le crédit. Cet article examine les conditions qui sont nécessaires pour que le secteur privé fournisse du crédit. Basé sur un travail récent en Ouganda et dans le Zimbabwe, il analyse les résultats de deux approches différentes au crédit pour les petits producteurs de coton. Ces systèmes ont une couverture beaucoup plus grande qu'aucun système du crédit officiel pour les paysans (réspectivement 300,000 et 53,000 paysans). Celui du Zimbabwe est apparamment un modèle classique de comment faire marcher le crédit d'une manière soutenable et commerciale. Par contre, le système Ougandais est paternaliste, très compliqué au niveau des institutions et vulnérable aux inefficacités operationelles très importantes. Il réprésente, néanmoins, une amélioration importante par rapport à la situation "sans système". En plus, l'accent très fort sur la pauvreté et la grande échelle de la couverture sont remarquables. L'article se conclut avec une discussion des leçons genériques pour les autres systèmes de crédit et les autres produits agricoles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d36e174a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e181" publication-type="other">
Poulton, 1998</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d36e188a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e195" publication-type="other">
Poulton, 1998.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d36e211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e215" publication-type="other">
Badiane, O. and Delgado, C. L, 1995, A 2020 vision for food, agriculture and the environment in sub-Saharan
Africa, 2020 Vision discussion paper 4, Washington: IFPRI.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e229" publication-type="other">
Dorward Andrew, Kydd Jonathan, and Poulton Colin (eds) Small-holder cash crop production under market li-
beralisation: a new institutional economics perspective. CAB International: Wallingford, UK., 1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e239a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e243" publication-type="other">
Lipton, Michael, "The place of agricultural research in the development of sub-Saharan Africa", World Deve-
lopment, Vol 16, No 10, 1988, pp 1231-1257.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e253a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e257" publication-type="other">
Marter Alan and Gordon Ann, "Emerging issues confronting the renewable natural resources sector in sub-
Saharan Africa", Food Policy, Vol 21, No 2, 1996, pp 229-241.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e268a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e272" publication-type="other">
Poulton Colin, Dorward Andrew, Kydd, Jonathan, Poole Nigel, and Smith Lawrence," A new institutional eco-
nomics perspective on current policy debates", in Dorward Andrew, Kydd Jonathan, and Poulton Colin
(eds) Small-holder cash crop production under market liberalisation: a new institutional economics per-
spective. CAB International: Wallingford, UK., 1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e292" publication-type="other">
Poulton Colin, "Cotton production and marketing in northern Ghana: the dynamics of competition in a system
of interlocking transactions", in Dorward Andrew, Kydd Jonathan, and Poulton Colin (eds) Small-holder
cash crop production under market liberalisation: a new institutional economics perspective. CAB Inter-
national: Wallingford, UK., 1998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


