<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308273</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Simulation of a Valve Train Using Non-Smooth Mechanics</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Huber</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ulbrich</surname>
                  <given-names>Heinz</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Institute of Applied Mechanics, Technical University Munich</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>208</fpage>
         <lpage>217</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308273"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Nowadays, multi-body systems theory including bilateral and unilateral constraints is comparatively well established by means of set-valued force laws. Although methods of non-smooth mechanics enable a highly efficient modeling, they are not conventionally used in industrial practice. Therefore in the present paper a valve train including hydraulic elements like a hydraulic lash adjuster is modeled using above mentioned methods.</p>
            <p>A main focus is laid upon the treatment of contact problems and two different models are investigated. Contacts in multi-body dynamics are classically described using spring and damper elements minimizing penetration. This approach results in stiff differential equations with unintentional high eigenfrequencies and long computing times as well as uncertainties in the parameters for contact stiffness and damping. Whereas in rigid contact models the contact is supposed to be completely stiff leading to non-smooth systems. The contact forces are subject to set-valued force laws describing the physical properties of the contact, namely the condition of non-penetration. Thus, stiff differential equations can be avoided and efficient models of these systems are obtained. For the rigid model discussed herein, only one interpretable physical parameter describing the dissipation of energy has to be adjusted.</p>
            <p>The dynamics of the system are described in terms of a measure differential equation augmented by projection functions representing set-valued force laws. Integration is done by a half-explicit time-stepping scheme. The set-valued laws are solved by methods of convex analysis.</p>
            <p>The concepts of non-smooth mechanics are adopted to hydraulic components. Using these methods a hydraulic lash adjuster is modeled and the simulation is compared to experimental results. Finally a non-smooth model of a valve train is investigated briefly and the different contact models are compared.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Foerg, T. Engelhardt, and H. Ulbrich. Analysis of ifferent time-integration methods applied to a nonsmooth ndustrial problem. In ENOC, Eindhoven, etherlands, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Pfeifer and Ch. Glocker. Multibody Dynamics with nilateral Contacts. John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. J. Moreau, P.D. Panagiotopoulos, and eds. Nonsmooth echanics and Applications. In CISM ourses and Lectures, volume 302, Wien, New York, 1988. Springer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ch. Glocker. Set-valued force laws, Dynamics of on-smooth systems. Springer, Berlin, New York, 2001. Lecture notes in applied mechanics 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Glocker. Dynamik von Starrkorpersystemen mit eibung und St oßen. PhD thesis, TU Munchen, usseldorf, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I.N. Bronstein and K.A. Semendjajew. Taschenbuch er Mathematik. 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K.L. Johnson. Contact Mechanics. cambridge University ress, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. T. Rockafellar. Augmented Lagrangians and applications f the proximal point algorithm in convex rogramming. Mathematics of Operations Research, 1:97–116, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P. Alart and A. Curnier. A mixed formulation for frictional ontact problems prone to NEWTON like solution ethods. Computer Methods in Applied Mechanics nd Engineering, 92:353–375, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Forg, L. Neumann, Th. Geier, and H. Ulbrich. rfactor trategies for the Augmented Lagrangian Approach n Multi-Body Contact Mechanics. In Proceedings f the III European Conference on Computational echanics, Lisbon, Portugal, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A. Stiegelmeyr and F. Pfeiffer. A Time Stepping Algorithm or Mechanical Systems with Unilateral Contacts. n Proc. of the ASME Design Engineering echnical Conferences, Las Vegas, Nevada, USA, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Funk and F. Pfeiffer. A Time-Stepping Algorithm or Stiff Mechanical Systems with Unilateral Constraints. n Proc. of the International Conference n Nonsmooth/Nonconvex Mechanics with Applications n Engineering, pages 307–314, Thessaloniki, reece, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. I. Leine and Ch. Glocker. A set-valued force law or spatial COULOMB-CONTENSOU friction. European ournal of Mechanics, 22:193–216, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Forg. Mehrk orpersysteme mit mengenwertigen raftgesetzen – Theorie und Numerik. PhD thesis, U Munchen, Dusseldorf, 2007. to appear.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Forg, R. Zander, and H. Ulbrich. A Framework or the Efficient Simulation of Spatial Contact Problems. n Proceedings of the ECCOMAS Conference n Multi-Body Systems, Milano, Italy, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Borchsenius, M. Foerg, and F. Pfeiffer. New Hydraulic ystem Modelling. In Proc. of the ASME Design ngineering Technical Conferences, Chicago, llinois, USA, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F. Kahr, M. Foerg, and H. Ulbrich. Hydraulics in nonsmooth ultibody systems. In Multibody Dynamics 2007, ECCOMAS Thematic Conference, Milano, taly, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. Krueger, Th. Engelhardt, L. Ginzinger, and H. Ulbrich. ynamical analysis of hydraulic chain tensioners - experiment and simulation. In Proceedings of he SAE 2007 World Congress, Detroit, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Foerg, Th. Engelhardt, and H. Ulbrich. Comparison f differnt contact models within valve train simulations. n Proceedings of ACMD06, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
