<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i24464784</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24464820</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Consequences of Entrepreneurial Finance: Evidence from Angel Financings</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>William R.</given-names>
                  <surname>Kerr</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Josh</given-names>
                  <surname>Lerner</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Antoinette</given-names>
                  <surname>Schoar</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>20</fpage>
         <lpage>55</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24464820"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This article documents the fact that ventures funded by two successful angel groups experience superior outcomes to rejected ventures: They have improved survival, exits, employment, patenting, Web traffic, and financing. We use strong discontinuities in angel-funding behavior over small changes in their collective interest levels to implement a regression discontinuity approach. We confirm the positive effects for venture operations, with qualitative support for a higher likelihood of successful exits. On the other hand, there is no difference in access to additional financing around the discontinuity. This might suggest that financing is not a central input of angel groups.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d43e284a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e291" publication-type="other">
Examples include Admati and Pfleiderer ( 1994), Berglöf ( 1994), Bergemann and Hege ( 1998), Hellmann ( 1998),
and Cornelli and Yosha (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e301a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e308" publication-type="other">
A similar approach is taken in Puri and Zarutskie (forthcoming) and Chemmanur et al. (2011), who employ
comprehensive Census Bureau records of private firms in order to form more detailed control groups based on
observable characteristics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e321a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e328" publication-type="other">
By way of contrast, the venture firms that we talked to all employ a consensual process in which controversial
proposals are withdrawn before coming up for a formal vote or disagreements are resolved in conversations
before the actual voting takes place. In addition, venture firms also rarely document the detailed voting behind
their decisions. Angel group members, in contrast, often express their interest for deals independently from one
another and based upon personal assessment.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e347a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e354" publication-type="other">
Our article is closest in spirit to work in the entrepreneurial finance literature on the investment selection process
and returns of venture capitalists. Sorensen (2007) assesses the returns to being funded by different tiers of
investors. Our work instead focuses on the margin of obtaining initial funding or not. Kaplan and Strömberg
(2004) and Kaplan et al. (2009) examine characteristics and dimensions that venture capitalists rely on when
making investment decisions. Goldfarb et al. (2007) and Conti et al. (2011) consider choices between angels and
venture investors.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e378a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e385" publication-type="other">
Thus, our work encompasses many of the matching traits used by prior work—such as industry, employment
levels and growth rates, age, etc.—but also better captures the motivations of entrepreneurs (i.e., the control
group also approached the investor at the same time as the treatment group) and the underlying qualities of the
ventures (i.e., the angels rated the ventures comparably at the time of their pitch). To illustrate these gains more
graphically, consider the case of Twitter (which is not part of our sample). Researchers can observe that Twitter
is four years old, has approximately 300 employees (http://twitter.com/about, accessed December 20, 2010), is
growing rapidly in terms of employment but not revenue, is located in Silicon Valley, and so on. But even with
this information set, it is very hard to identify companies with which one should compare to Twitter. Our data
allow us to compare funded ventures to others that the same sophisticated investors thought comparable at the
time of the investment pitch.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e420a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e427" publication-type="other">
While common in economics, this approach is underutilized in finance. Exceptions include Rauh (2006),
Chernenko and Sunderam (2009), and Bakke and Whited (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e437a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e444" publication-type="other">
Statistics are based on http://www.angelcapitalassociation.org/ (accessed February 15, 2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e451a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e458" publication-type="other">
Tech Coast Angels grows from two to four chapters during our period of study, with on average 30-40 active
angels per chapter. Table Al (see Appendix) provides additional details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e468a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e477" publication-type="other">
There is also a discrete step in funding probability around having ten or more interested angels, relative to
having five to nine interested angels. This margin would be interesting to study as well, but it is operationally
quite difficult, as the information collected for the typical unfunded venture declines at lower interest levels (e.g.,
due diligence reviews are not undertaken). We set the lower bound for our study to be above this threshold of
ten angels being interested.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e496a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e503" publication-type="other">
Despite the power of these tests, we recognize that there are limits to what we can discern regarding the ventures.
Most importantly, soft features (e.g., quality perceptions of management team) may systematically vary in ways
not captured by our data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e517a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e524" publication-type="other">
CommonAngels had about fifty members throughout our period of study, before expanding in recent years to
seventy members.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e534a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e541" publication-type="other">
Industry databases include CorpTech, VentureXpert, Dun &amp; Bradstreet, and Hoover's. Industry news sources (all
sources are online with a ".com" suffix) include yahoo, linkedin, inc, businessweek, spoke, manta, venturebeat,
wikipedia, crunchbase, glassdoor, insideview, healthcareitnews, socaltech, masshightech, xconomy, and boston.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e554a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e561" publication-type="other">
In cases of acquisitions, we code whether or not the venture is alive through making a judgment about the size
of the acquisition. Ventures are counted as alive if the acquisition or merger was a successful exit that included
major announcements or exit valuations greater than US$5 million (where known). If the event was termed an
"asset sale" or similar phrase, we code the venture as not having survived. The results below are robust to simply
dropping these cases.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e580a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e587" publication-type="other">
In five of our eight successful acquisition cases, acquisition values greater than US$40 million are reported in the
media. In a sixth case, while the acquisition value was not disclosed, the acquired company disclosed substantial
revenues (&gt;US$12 million) and investor returns (&gt;200%). Two cases are more difficult to assign. In the first,
the venture (funded and above border) received major press attention at acquisition, with significant discussion
of its integration and then joint release of the next product. This venture still operates as a private subsidiary of
the acquiring company and the investor considers it a success while not disclosing the returns. In the second,
the venture (unfunded and below border) was estimated to have had more than fifty employees and four funding
rounds at acquisition and was described as "major" in the press. Recoding the last two cases as unsuccessful
acquisitions marginally strengthens our empirical results below.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e619a1310">
            <label>*5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e626" publication-type="other">
Alexa collects its data primarily by tracking the browsing patterns of Web users who have installed the Alexa
Toolbar, a piece of software that attaches itself to a user's Internet browser and records in detail the user's website.
According to the company, there are currently millions of such users. The statistics are then extrapolated from
this user subset to the Internet population as a whole. The two pieces of information collected by the toolbar are
Web reach and page views. Web reach is a measure of what percentage of the total number of Internet users visit
a website in question, and page views measures on average how many pages they visit on that website. Multiple
page views by the same user in the same day only count as one entry in the data. The two usage variables are then
combined to produce a variable known as site rank, with the most visited sites like Yahoo and Google having
lower ranks.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e658a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e665" publication-type="other">
If we observe the Web ranks in both 2008 and 2010, the indicator variable takes a value of one if the rank in
2010 is better than that in 2008. If we only observe the firm on the Web in 2008, we deem its Web performance
to have declined by 2010. Likewise, if we only observe the firm in 2010, we deem its Web performance to have
improved.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e682a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e689" publication-type="other">
Where possible, we also cross-checked the Alexa trends for ventures against Google Insights. Google Insights is
based upon the search queries that are made by users. While Google Insights allows for historical monthly
measurement, the quality of the search results varied much more across ventures than did the Web traffic
measures. These differences are because relevant search terms can be much more ambiguous when ventures
have common names or products than measures of the Web traffic that went to a specific URL.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e708a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e715" publication-type="other">
Our data description highlighted the need to cap very high employment or successful exits at a certain
employment level. The measured employment effect with controls is higher at 38.8 (16.5) employees if the
cap is increased to 250 employees. On the other hand, the estimated effect is 12.2 (3.6) employees if the cap is
lowered to fifty employees. Based upon the data we could collect for very successful ventures in our sample, a
cap of 100 employees appears most appropriate and our preferred estimate is the 19-20 employee figure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e734a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e741" publication-type="other">
We do not find that being financed by the angel groups materially influences the types of venture investors
subsequently accessed, at least in terms of venture fund size or age (two common proxies for the prestige of
venture funds). These results question one common rationale given for pitching to angel investors: that they
provide an entry to prestigious venture capital firms later.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e757a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e764" publication-type="other">
The matched sample in Table 4 includes ventures outside our primary interest region where an appropriate
match could be identified. We have further confirmed that our results across the other outcome variables hold
when using a matched sample approach within our primary interest region.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e777a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e784" publication-type="other">
We find similar results in a variety of robustness checks. To report one, concern could exist that angels have fixed
voting patterns that skew the scores. For example, the most meaningful endorsement for a venture could come
from an angel who very rarely expresses interest in any deal, and so his or her vote carries unequal weight in
the decisions. These patterns could be obscured in our aggregated measures. To check this, we develop a second
measure of the interest level in deals that normalizes each angel's total expressed interest to be the same. That
is, we down-weight the votes of angels who express interest in every deal. We find very similar results to those
reported below, which suggests that our identification strategy is not being contaminated by bandwagon effects
and angel-specific heterogeneity in voting.
It is also worth noting that the professional managers of both angel groups found this funding discontinuity
a reasonable description of their groups' behavior. One manager noted that because the angels need to jointly
invest, the development of critical mass behind a deal is essential and nonlinear. He also noted that the group
early on (before our sample) changed its meeting procedures so that angels scored their sheets before an open
group discussion was held to allow collection of more independent views of the venture.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e829a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e836" publication-type="other">
The coefficients would be comparable if we used the border discontinuity in an instrumental variables
framework. Given the substantial fuzziness of our funding discontinuity, we only use this empirical approach to
confirm the overall qualitative direction of our findings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e850a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e857" publication-type="other">
We have confirmed the border results in several ways. Perhaps most importantly, the results do not depend upon
how the two angel groups are combined or changes in angel group size over the sample. Similar patterns emerge,
e.g., when considering Tech Coast Angels in the period after 2001. We also find positive associations for each
group individually, although some results are not statistically significant due to smaller sample sizes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d43e873a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e880" publication-type="other">
Of course, this analysis does not prove that the findings about the impact of angel investors carry over to other
investors. For instance, even if the returns were equal, it might be that the angel groups invest more unobservable
effort and their approach would not be sustainable if they priced their inputs at market rate. Again, it is important
to note that both funds have professional managers and that CommonAngels further raises venture funds from
limited partners that its professional managers invest alongside the angels (Applegate and Simpson 2011 ).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d43e908a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e912" publication-type="other">
Admati, A. R., and P. Pfleidere. 1994. Robust Financial Contracting and the Role of Venture Capitalists. Journal
of Finance 49:371^102.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e922a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e926" publication-type="other">
Applegate, L., and K. Simpson. 2011. CommonAngels A. Case 810-082, Harvard Business School.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e933a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e937" publication-type="other">
Bakke, T.-E., and T. M. Whited. 2010. The Real Effects of Market Liquidity: Causal Evidence from Delisting.
Unpublished Working Paper, University of Rochester.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e947a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e951" publication-type="other">
Bergemann, D., and U. Hege. 1998. Venture Capital Financing, Moral Hazard, and Learning. Journal of
Banking &amp; Finance 22:703-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e962a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e966" publication-type="other">
Berglöf, E. 1994. A Control Theory of Venture Capital Finance. Journal of Law, Economics, and Organizations
10:247-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e976a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e980" publication-type="other">
Chemmanur, T. J., K. Krishnan, and D. K. Nandy. Forthcoming. How Does Venture Capital Financing Improve
Efficiency in Private Firms? A Look Beneath the Surface. Review of Financial Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e990a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e994" publication-type="other">
Chernenko, S., and A. Sunderam. 2009. The Real Consequences of Market Segmentation. Unpublished Working
Paper, Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1004a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1008" publication-type="other">
Conti, A., M. C. Thursby, and F. Rothaermel. 2011. Show Me the Right Stuff: Signals for High-tech Startups.
Working Paper Series No. 17050, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1018a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1022" publication-type="other">
Comelli, F., and O. Yosha. 2003. Stage Financing and the Role of Convertible Debt. Review of Economic Studies
70:1-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1032a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1036" publication-type="other">
Goldfarb, B., G. Hoberg, D. Kirsch, and A. Triantis. 2007. Are Angels Preferred Series A Investors? Unpublished
Working Paper, University of Maryland.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1047a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1051" publication-type="other">
Hellmann, T. 1998. The Allocation of Control Rights in Venture Capital Contracts. RAND Journal of Economics
29:57-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1061a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1065" publication-type="other">
Hellmann, T., and M. Puri. 2000. The Interaction Between Product Market and Financing Strategy: The Role of
Venture Capital. Review of Financial Studies 13:959-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1079" publication-type="other">
Hsu, D. H. 2004. What Do Entrepreneurs Pay for Venture Capital Affiliation? Journal of Finance 59:1805^44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1086a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1090" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., and A. Schoar. 2005. Private Equity Performance: Returns, Persistence and Capital Flows. Journal
of Finance 60:1791-823.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1100a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1104" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., and P. Strömberg. 2004. Characteristics, Contracts, and Actions: Evidence from Venture Capitalist
Analyses. Journal of Finance 59:2177-210.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1114a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1118" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S. N., B. Sensoy, and P. Strömberg. 2009. Should Investors Bet on the Jockey or the Horse? Evidence
from the Evolution of Firms from Early Business Plans to Public Companies. Journal of Finance 64:75-115.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1129a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1133" publication-type="other">
Kerr, W., and R. Nanda. 2009. Democratizing Entry: Banking Deregulations, Financing Constraints, and
Entrepreneurship. Journal of Financial Economics 94:124—49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1143a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1147" publication-type="other">
Kortum, S., and J. Lerner. 2000. Assessing the Contribution of Venture Capital to Innovation. RAND Journal of
Economics 31:674-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1157a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1161" publication-type="other">
Lamoreaux, N., M. Levenstein, and K. Sokoloff. 2004. Financing Invention During the Second Industrial
Revolution: Cleveland, Ohio, 1870-1920. Working Paper Series No. 10923, National Bureau of Economic
Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1174a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1178" publication-type="other">
Lee, D. S., and T. Lemieux. 2010. Regression Discontinuity Designs in Economics. Journal of Economic
Literature 48:281-355.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1188a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1192" publication-type="other">
Mollica, M., and L. Zingales. 2007. The Impact of Venture Capital on Innovation and the Creation of New
Businesses. Unpublished Working Paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1202a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1206" publication-type="other">
Puri, M., and R. Zarutskie. Forthcoming. On the Life-cycle Dynamics of Venture-capital- and Non-venture-
capital-financed Firms. Journal of Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1217a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1221" publication-type="other">
Rauh, J. D. 2006. Investment and Financing Constraints: Evidence from the Funding of Corporate Pension Plans.
Journal of Finance 61:31-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1231a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1235" publication-type="other">
Samila, S., and O. Sorenson. 2011. Venture Capital, Entrepreneurship, and Economic Growth. Review of
Economics and Statistics 93:338-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1249" publication-type="other">
Shane, S. 2008. The Importance of Angel Investing in Financing the Growth of Entrepreneurial Ventures.
Working Paper No. 331, U.S. Small Business Administration, Office of Advocacy.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1259a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1263" publication-type="other">
Sorensen, M. 2007. How Smart Is the Smart Money? A Two-sided Matching Model of Venture Capital. Journal
of Finance 62:2725-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d43e1273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1277" publication-type="other">
Sudek, R., C. Mitteness, and M. Baucus. 2008. Betting on the Horse or the Jockey: The Impact of Expertise on
Angel Investing. Academy of Management Best Paper Proceedings.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


