<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663706</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/339907</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB750308</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Notes</article-title>
            <subtitle>University Schools of Business</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>07</month>
            <year>2002</year>
            <string-date>July 2002</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>75</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2002.75.issue-3</issue-id>
         <fpage>555</fpage>
         <lpage>557</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/339907"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Appointments</title>
         <p>Juan Alcacer, asst. prof., management and international business, NYU, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Mimi Alciatore, assoc. prof., accountancy and taxation, Houston, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Paul C. Allaire, asst. dean and director, Career Resource Center, SUNY at Buffalo, Feb. 2002.</p>
         <p>Robert P. Arnott, visiting prof., UCLA, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Sridhar Balasubramanian, visiting prof., North Carolina at Chapel Hill, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Orn Bodvarsson, visiting prof., Nebraska—Lincoln, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Robert E. Boehmer, assoc. provost, Univ. Georgia, Dec. 2001.</p>
         <p>Henry Cao, asst. prof., North Carolina at Chapel Hill, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Rohan Christie‐David, assoc. prof., Louisiana Tech, July 2001.</p>
         <p>W. Randy Clark, asst. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Daniel Daianu, visiting professor, UCLA, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Tom Dean, assoc. prof., strategy and entrepreneurship, Univ. Colorado, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Ted D. Englebrecht, prof. and Harold J. Smolinski Chair, Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Anderson Fletcher, assoc. dean for administration and M.B.A. programs, Houston, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Robert Getty, asst. prof., Univ. North Texas, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>David Hofmann, assoc. prof., North Carolina at Chapel Hill, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Sin Hoon Hum, visiting assoc. prof., UCLA, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Blake Ives, prof., decision and information sciences, and Charles T. Bauer Chair of Business Leadership, Houston, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Eli Jones, asst. professor, marketing and entrepreneurship, and director, Program for Excellence in Selling, Houston, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Mary Jones, asst. prof., Univ. North Texas, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Yi‐ching Kao, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Yang Min Kim, asst. prof., Marquette, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dalia Marciukaityte, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Lynn F. Muller, asst. prof., South Dakota, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Dan Peak, assoc. prof., Univ. North Texas, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>William Putsis, prof., North Carolina at Chapel Hill, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Adam Reed, asst. prof., North Carolina at Chapel Hill, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Jorge M. Silva‐Risso, visiting asst. prof., UCLA, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>David Strutton, prof. and chair, Univ. North Texas, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Baohong Sun, asst. prof., North Carolina at Chapel Hill, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Arthur Warga, prof., finance, and interim dean, Houston, July 2001.</p>
         <p>Scott Whisenant, asst. prof., accountancy and taxation, Houston, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Robert Willis, asst. prof., Marquette, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Michael Wittmann, asst. prof., Univ. North Texas, Sept. 2001.</p>
         <p>Huimin Zhao, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Milwaukee, Sept. 2002.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Grants</title>
         <p>Fred Glover, prof., operations management and operations research, Univ. Colorado; 2001–3; $1,204,335; Office of Naval Research; to study innovations in optimization methodologies.</p>
         <p>Fred Glover, prof., operations management and operations research, Univ. Colorado; Oct. 2001–Sept. 2002; $236,467; Office of Naval Research; to work on solution procedures designed to solve optimization problems in organizations and to develop new and improved decision strategies.</p>
         <p>Manuel Laguna, assoc. prof., operations management, Univ. Colorado; Oct. 2001–Sept. 2002; $236,467; Office of Naval Research; to work on solution procedures designed to solve optimization problems in organizations and to develop new and improved decision strategies.</p>
         <p>Peter Toumanoff, assoc. prof., Marquette; January 15, 2002; Fulbright; to serve as lecturer in graduate and executive M.B.A. programs and to collect data on comparative economic development in Yekaterinburg, Russia.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Leaves</title>
         <p>Ronald Lau, assoc. prof., South Dakota; Aug. 2001–May 2002; to serve as visiting scholar in the Department of Information Systems Management, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Promotions</title>
         <p>Maqbool Dada, prof., management, Purdue, Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Srinivas Durvasula, prof., Marquette, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Terry Dworkin, Jack R. Wentworth Professor, Indiana, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Joanne E. Hale, assoc. prof., Alabama, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Robert Jennings, Gregg T. and Judith A. Summerville Endowed Chair in Finance, Indiana, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Gerald L. Lynch, prof., economics, Purdue, Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Steven Lysonski, prof., Marquette, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Scott MacKenzie, Neal Gilliatt Chair, Indiana, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Michael Mayo, assoc. prof., Kent State, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Patricia McDougall, Haeberle Professor, Indiana, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Janet S. Netz, assoc. prof., economics, Purdue, Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Annette B. Poulsen, prof. and department head, Univ. Georgia, Jan. 2002.</p>
         <p>Eric Rasmusen, Indiana University Foundation Professorship, Indiana, Oct. 2001.</p>
         <p>Susan G. Watts, assoc. prof., Purdue, Fall 2001.</p>
         <p>Michael Way, senior lecturer, Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
         <p>Xiaoyun Yu, asst. prof., Indiana, Aug. 2001.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Resignations</title>
         <p>John Barkoulas, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, July 2001.</p>
         <p>James Jiang, assoc. prof., Louisiana Tech, Aug. 2001.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Retirements</title>
         <p>Gene Iverson, prof., South Dakota, Dec. 2001.</p>
         <p>Jerry L. Petr, prof., Nebraska—Lincoln, May 2001.</p>
         <p>Joseph Sinkey, Jr., prof., Univ. Georgia, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Bette Ann Stead, prof., marketing and entrepreneurship, Houston, Jan. 2002.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
