<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939381</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Taxes on Consumption in Developing Countries</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Taxation and Supplier Networks</article-title>
            <subtitle>Evidence from India</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gadenne</surname>
                  <given-names>Lucie</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nandi</surname>
                  <given-names>Tushar K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rathelot</surname>
                  <given-names>Roland</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>31</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939381"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Do tax systems affect the efficiency of supplier networks in developing countries? This paper considers the implications of tax policy for supply chain efficiency using administrative tax data on the universe of firms paying taxes in West Bengal, India, between 2010 and 2015; this data includes information on nearly 5 million annual transactions between suppliers and buyers. We first document substantial market segmentation between firms paying Value-Added-Taxes (VAT) and non-VAT-paying firms, even after observable heterogeneity is controlled for. We then develop a theoretical framework to understand how firms’ production, sourcing and tax status decisions interact and are affected by tax policy. The model predicts equilibrium (partial) market segmentation because of both supply-chain distortions (taxes affect how much firms trade with each other) and complementarities in tax status decisions. Finally we test the model’s predictions using a 2013 reform which increases the VAT rate on some commodities. We find evidence of a causal impact of taxes on supplier networks: the tax rate increase reduces transactions between VAT- and non-VAT-paying firms and we see exits from the VAT of both firms directly affected by the reform and their clients, in line with predicted complementarities in tax status choices.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Allen, T. (2014): “Information Frictions in Trade,” Econometrica, 82, 2041–2083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Almunia, M., L. Liu, and B. Lo (2016): “VAT notches, voluntary registration and bunching: Theory and UK,” Tech. rep., Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation Working Paper No.16/10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Atalay, E., A. Hortacşu, J. Roberts, and C. Syverson (2011): “Network structure of production,” Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 108, 5199–5202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Bachas, P. and M. Soto (2017): “Not(ch) Your Average Tax System: Corporate Taxation Under Weak Enforcement,” Tech. rep., Mimeo, World Bank.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Banerjee, A. V. and E. Duflo (2000): “Reputation Effects and the Limits of Contracting: A Study of the Indian Software Industry*,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 115, 989–1017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Banerjee, A. V. (2005): “Growth Theory through the Lens of Development Economics,” in Handbook of Economic Growth, ed. by P. Aghion and S. Durlauf, Elsevier, vol. 1 of Handbook of Economic Growth, chap. 7, 473–552.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bernard, A. and A. Moxnes (2017): “Networks and Trade,” Tech. rep., Annual Review of Economics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bernard, A. B., A. Moxnes, and Y. U. Saito (2015): “Production Networks, Geography and Firm Performance,” Working Paper 21082, National Bureau of Economic Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Best, M., A. Brockmeyer, H. J. Kleven, J. Spinnewijn, and M. Waseem (2015): “Production vs Revenue Efficiency With Limited Tax Capacity: Theory and Evidence From Pakistan,” Journal of Political Economy, 123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bird, R. and P.-P. Gendron (2007): The VAT in Developing and Transitional Countries, Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Boadway, R. and M. Sato (2009): “Optimal Tax Design and Enforcement with an Informal Sector,” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 1, 1–27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Brandt, L., T. Tombe, and X. Zhu (2013): “Factor Market Distortions Across Time, Space, and Sectors in China,” Review of Economic Dynamics, 16, 39–58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Broda, C., J. Greenfield, and D. E. Weinstein (2017): “From groundnuts to globalization: A structural estimate of trade and growth,” Research in Economics, 71, 759–783.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Cagé, J. and L. Gadenne (2017): “Tax Revenues, Development, and the Fiscal Cost of Trade Liberalization, 1792-2006,” PSE Working Papers halshs-00705354, CEPR Working Paper 12469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Carrillo, P., D. Pomeranz, and M. Singhal (2017): “Dodging the Taxman: Firm Misreporting and Limits to Tax Enforcement,” American Economic Journal: Applied Economics, 9, 144–164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Carvalho, V. M., M. Nirei, Y. Saito, and A. Tahbaz-Salehi (2016): “Supply Chain Disruptions: Evidence from the Great East Japan Earthquake,” Tech. rep., Becker Friedman Institute for Research in Economics Working Paper No. 2017-01.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">de Paula, A. and J. A. Scheinkman (2010): “Value-Added Taxes, Chain Effects, and Informality,” American Economic Journal: Macroeconomics, 2, 195-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Emran, M. S. and J. E. Stiglitz (2005): “On Selective Indirect Tax Reform in Developing Countries,” Journal of Public Economics, 89, 599–623.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Gerard, F. and G. Gonzaga (2016): “Informal Labor and the Cost of Social Programs: Evidence from 15 Years of Unemployment Insurance in Brazil,” Tech. rep., NBER Working Paper Nb 22608.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gerard, F., J. Naritomi, and A. Seibold (2018): “Tax systems and inter-firm trade: evidence from the VAT in Brazil,” Tech. rep., Mimeo London School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Hsieh, C.-T. and P. J. Klenow (2009): “Misallocation and Manufacturing TFP in China and India,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 124, 1403–1448.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Khwaja, A. I. and A. Mian (2005): “Do Lenders Favor Politically Connected Firms? Rent Provision in an Emerging Financial Market,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 120, 1371–1411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Kleven, H. J. and M. Waseem (2013): “Using Notches to Uncover Optimization Frictions and Structural Elasticities: Theory and Evidence from Pakistan,” Quarterly Journal of Economics, 128, 669–723, preliminary Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Macchiavello, R. and A. Morjaria (2015): “The Value of Relationships: Evidence from a Supply Shock to Kenyan Rose Exports,” American Economic Review, 105, 2911–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">McMillan, J. and C. Woodruff (1999): “Interfirm Relationships and Informal Credit in Vietnam,” The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 114, 1285–1320.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Naritomi, J. (2016): “Consumers as Tax Auditors,” Tech. rep., Harvard University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Pomeranz, D. (2015): “No Taxation without Information: Deterrence and Self-Enforcement in the Value Added Tax,” American Economic Review, 105, 2539–2569.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Tintelnot, F., A. Kikkawa, M. Mogstad, and E. Dhyne (2017): “Trade and Domestic Production Networks,” Mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Effective VAT rate paid on sales over time by tax schedule</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Evolution of outcomes over time by treatment group</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Descriptive statistics on firms in 2010-2011</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Correlation between a firm’s tax status and its use of VAT trading partners</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Commodities sold and firm tax status in 2010-2011</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Post reform treatment by type of commodity sold and tax scheme</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Impact of the reform on sales</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Impact of the reform on supply chains</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Transaction level evidence on supply chain distortions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
