<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186468</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44436728</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Application of Photoelasticity to the Study of Indeterminate Truss-Stresses</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>D. L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Pellett</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1932</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>469</fpage>
         <lpage>474</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44436728"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>THIS paper contains a brief description of the history, theory and application of photoelasticity, which is a new and useful optical method of stress analysis. A simple, cheap and compact photoelastic polariscope developed for the purpose is described. The application of photoelasticity to indeterminate truss-stress analysis produces quantitative stress measurements within a maximum experimental error of 6 per cent. The tests yield with considerable speed and convenience information concerning stress concentrations at corners and fillets that cannot be obtained by other methods. The author describes a photoelastic test of an airplane-wing-rib model whereby the axial and bending stresses in the members are determined and severe stress concentrations at the spar corners are noted. The stress distribution in a truss bent, as shown by photoelasticity, is illustrated, and a design procedure that makes possible the application of the results of the tests to the design of a stamped-metal rib is developed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


