<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278233</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Evaluation of Diesel Oxidation Catalyst Conversion of Hydrocarbons and Particulate Matter from Premixed Low Temperature Combustion of Biodiesel</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Northrop</surname>
                  <given-names>William F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ. of Michigan-Ann Arbor</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Assanis</surname>
                  <given-names>Dennis</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bohac</surname>
                  <given-names>Stani</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Michigan</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1431</fpage>
         <lpage>1444</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278233"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Premixed low temperature combustion (LTC) in diesel engines simultaneously reduces soot and NO<sub>X</sub>at the expense of increased hydrocarbon (HC) and CO emissions. The use of biodiesel in the LTC regime has been shown to produce lower HC emissions than petroleum diesel; however, unburned methyl esters from biodiesel are more susceptible to particulate matter (PM) formation following atmospheric dilution due to their low volatility. In this study, the efficacy of a production-type diesel oxidation catalyst (DOC) for the conversion of light hydrocarbons species and heavier, semi-volatile species like those in unburned fuel is examined. Experimental data were taken from a high speed direct-injection diesel engine operating in a mid-load, late injection partially premixed LTC mode on ultra low sulfur diesel (ULSD) and neat soy-based biodiesel (B100). Gaseous emissions were recorded using a conventional suite of analyzers and individual light HCs were measured using an FT-IR analyzer. PM emissions data were collected from filter samples taken before and after the DOC using gravimetric analysis, Soxhlet extraction with speciation of extracted HCs, and total organic versus elemental carbon (OCEC) analysis. The previous results were confirmed with LTC of B100 resulting in over an order of magnitude increase in engine-out PM. It was found in the experimental study that 76% of the unburned fuel species responsible for this increase can be converted by a production-type DOC with an inlet temperature of 240°C and gas hourly space velocity (GHSV) of 85,000 hr<sup>−1</sup>. Unfortunately, the remaining unburned biodiesel left unconverted by the DOC still contributed significantly to the PM following dilution. Methyl esters from biodiesel were found to be the primary species contributing to the higher total organic fraction (&gt;95%) on the PM for biodiesel LTC following a DOC.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E. (2009). Advances compression-ignition engines - understanding the in-cylinder processes. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 32, 2727-2742.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta, M., Armas, O., &amp; Rodriguez-Fernandez, J. (2008). Effect of biodiesel fuels on diesel engine emissions. Prog. Energy and Combustion Science, 34, 198-223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Northrop, W. F., Bohac, S. V. and Assanis, D. N., “Premixed Low Temperature Combustion of Biodiesel and Blends in a High Speed Compression Ignition Engine,”. SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(1):28-40, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0133.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, M., Mulenga, M. C., Reader, G. T., Wang, M., &amp; Ting, D. S-K., “Influence of Biodiesel Fuel on Diesel Engine Performance and Emissions in Low Temperature Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3281, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3281.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Northrop, W.F., Madathil, P.V., Bohac, S.V. and Assanis, D.N. (2011). Condensational growth of particulate matter from partially premixed low temperature combustion of biodiesel in a compression ignition engine. Aerosol Science and Technology. 45, 26-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Otto, K., Sieg, M. H., Zinbo, M., and Bartosiewicz, L., “The Oxidation of Soot Deposits from Diesel Engines, SAE Technical Paper 800336, 1980, doi: 10.4271/800336.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, A. P. (2004). Controlling particulate emissions from diesel vehicles. Topics in Catalysis, 28 (1-4), 165-170.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zelenka, P., Ostgathe, K., &amp; Lox, E., “Reduction of Diesel Exhaust Emissions by Using Oxidation Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper 902111, 1990, doi: 10.4271/902111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morlang, A., Neuhausen, U., Klementiev, K. V., Schutze, F. W., Miehe, G., Fuess, H., et al. (2005). Bimetallic Pt/Pd diesel oxidation catalysts structural characterization and catalytic behavior. Applied Catalysis B:Environmental, 60, 191-199.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamijo, M., Kamikubo, M., Akama, H., &amp; Matsushita, K. (2001). Study of an oxidation catalyst system for diesel engine control utilizing HC adsorption. JSAE Review, 22, 277-280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farrauto, R. J., &amp; Beasley, D. E. (1996). Monolithic diesel oxidation catalysts. Applied Catalysis B:Environmental, 10, 29-51.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bohac, S. V., Han, M., Jacobs, T. J., Lopez, A. J., Assanis, D. N., &amp; Szymkowicz, P. G., “Speciated Hydrocarbon Emissions from an Automotive Diesel Engine and DOC Utilizing Conventional and PCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0201, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-0201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knafl, A., Jacobs, T. J., Bohac, S. V., &amp; Assanis, D. N. (2006). The load limits of low temperature premixed compression ignition diesel combustion. ISCE 2006, The 2nd International Symposium on “Clean and High-Efficiency Combustion in Engines”.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Northrop, W. F., Jacobs, T. J., Assanis, D. N., &amp; Bohac, S. V. (2007). Deactivation of a diesel oxidation catalyst due to the exhaust species from rich premixed compression ignition combustion in a light-duty diesel engine. Int. J. Engine Res., 8, 497-498.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, M., Assanis, D. N., Jacobs, T. J., &amp; Bohac, S. V. (2008). Method and detailed analysis of individual hydrocarbon species from diesel combustion modes and diesel oxidation catalyst. J. Eng. Gas Turbines and Power, 130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peterson, A., Lee, P-I., Lai, M-C., Wu, M-C., and Dimaggio, C., “Impact of Biodiesel Emission Products from a Multi-Cylinder Direct Injection Diesel Engine on Particulate Filter Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1184, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1184.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Theinnoi, K., Rounce, A., Tsolakis, A., Wyszynski, M. L., Xu, H. M., &amp; York, A. P., “Activity of Prototype Catalysts on Exhaust Emissions from Biodiesel Fuelled Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2514, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-2514.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Purcell, D. L., McClure, B. T., McDonald, J., &amp; Basu, H. N. (1996). Transient testing of soy methyl ester fuels in an indirect injection, compression ignition engine. JOACS, 381-388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sharp, C. A., Howell, S. A., and Jobe, J., “The Effect of Biodiesel Fuels on Transient Emissions from Modern Diesel Engines, Part I Regulated Emissions and Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1967, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-1967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stein, H. J. (1996). Diesel oxidation catalysts for commercial vehicle engines: strategies on their application for controlling particulate emissions. Applied Catalysis B:Environmental, 10, 69-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baik, D. S., &amp; Han, Y. C. (2005). The effect of biodiesel and ultra low sulfur diesel fuels on emissions in 11,000 cc heavy duty engine. J. Mech. Sci. Tech., 19 (3), 870-876.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, T. J., Bohac, S. V., Assanis, D. N., and Szymkowicz, P. G., “Lean and Rich Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0166, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depcik, C., Jacobs, T. J., Hagena, J., &amp; Assanis, D. N. (2005). Instructional use of a single zone, pre-mixed sparkignition heat release simulation. Int. J. Mechanical Engineering Education, 35, 1-31.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krieger, R., &amp; Borman, G. (1966). The computation of apparent heat release for internal combustion engines. American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Technical Paper 66-WA/DGP-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoenberg, G., “Advanced Approaches for Heat Transfer Calculations,” SAE Technical Paper 790825, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ickes, A. M., Bohac, S. V., &amp; Assanis, D. N. (2009). Effect of fuel cetane number on a premixed diesel combustion mode. Int. J. Engine Research, 10, 251-263.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Birch, M. E., &amp; Cary, R. A. (1996). Elemental carbonbased method for monitoring occupational exposures to particulate diesel exhaust. Aerosol Science and Technology, 25 (3), 221-240.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bagley, S. T., Gratz, L. D., Johnson, J. H., &amp; McDonald, J. F. (1998). Effects of an oxidation catalytic converter and a biodiesel fuel on the chemical, mutagenic, and particle size characteristics of emissions from a diesel engine. Environ. Sci. Technol., 32, 1183-1191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McNair, H. M., &amp; Miller, J. M. (1997). Basic Gas Chromotography John Wiley and Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scanlon, J. T., &amp; Willis, D. E. (1985). The calculation of FID response factors using the effective carbon number concept. J. Chromatographic Sci., 23, 333-340.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ulberth, F., Gabernig, R. G., &amp; Schrammel, F. (1999). Flame-ionization detector response to methyl, ethyl, propyl, and butyl esters of fatty acids. J. Am. Org. Chem. Society, 76 (2), 263-266.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stivender, D. L., “Development of a Fuel-Based Mass Emission Measurement Procedure,” SAE Technical Paper 710604, 1971, doi: 10.4271/710604.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, M., Assanis, D. N., &amp; Bohac, S. V. (2009). Sources of hydrocarbon emissions from low-temperature premixed compression ignition combustion from a common-rail direct injection diesel engine. Combustion Science and Technology, 181, 496-517.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christian, V. R., Knopf, F., Jaschek, A., &amp; Schneider, W. (1993). Eine neue messmethodik der Bosch-Zahl mit erhoehter empfindlichkeit. Motortechnische Zeitschrift, 54 (1), 16-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Figliola, R., &amp; Beasley, D. (2000). Theory and design for mechanical measurements (3rd Edition ed.). New York: John Wiley and Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, T.J., Assanis, D.N. (2007). The attainment of premixed compression ignition low-temperature combustion in a compression ignition direct injection engine. Proceedings of the Combusiton Institute, 31, 2913-2920.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katare, S.R., Patterson, J.E., Laing, P.M., “Aged DOC is a Net Consumer of NO2: Analysis of Vehicle, Enginedynamometer and Reactor Data,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-3984, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-3984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cook, D. J., Pitsch, H., &amp; Nentwig, G., “Numerical Investigation of Unburnt Hydrocarbon Emissions in a Homogeneous-Charge Late-Injection Diesel-Fueled Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1666, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1666.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huynh, L. K., &amp; Violi, A. (2008). Thermal decomposition of methyl butanoate: ab initio study of a biodiesel fuel surrogate. J. Organic Chem., 73, 94-101.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herbinet, O., Pitz, W. J., &amp; Westbrook, C. K. (2008). Detailed chemical kinetic oxidation mechanism for a biodiesel surrogate. Combustion and Flame, 154, 507-528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chang, D. Y. and Van Gerpen, J. H., “Determination of Particulate and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions from Diesel Engines Fueled with Biodiesel,” SAE Technical Paper 982527, 1998, doi: 10.4271/982527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mueller, C., Pitz, W., Pickett, L., Martin, G., Siebers, D. and Westbrook, C.K., “Effects of Oxygenates on Soot Processes in DI Diesel Engines: Experiments and Numerical Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1791, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
