<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440028</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Why Are Mothers Working Longer Hours in Austria than in Germany? A Comparative Microsimulation Analysis</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Helene</given-names>
                  <surname>Dearing</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Helmut</given-names>
                  <surname>Hofer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Christine</given-names>
                  <surname>Lietz</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Rudolf</given-names>
                  <surname>Winter-Ebmer</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Katharina</given-names>
                  <surname>Wrohlich</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2007</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440023</issue-id>
         <fpage>463</fpage>
         <lpage>495</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2007</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440028"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Labour force participation rates of mothers in Austria and Germany are similar; however, full-time employment rates are much higher among Austrian mothers. In order to find out to what extent these differences can be attributed to differences in the tax–transfer system, we perform a comparative microsimulation exercise. After estimating structural labour supply models for both countries, we interchange two important institutional characteristics of the two countries – namely, (i) the definition of the tax unit within the personal income tax and (ii) the parental leave benefit scheme. As our analysis shows, differences in mothers' employment patterns can partly be explained by the different tax systems: while Germany has a system of joint taxation with income splitting for married couples, Austria taxes everyone individually, which leads to lower marginal tax rates for secondary earners than in the German system.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1e299a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e306" publication-type="other">
Submitted June 2007.
Katharina Wrohlich would like to thank the Fritz-Thyssen Foundation for financial support of the
project 'Labour Market and Welfare Effects of Public Family Support'. Furthermore, the authors thank
the Austrian Central Bank for financial support by means of the 'Jubiläumsfonds' (project 11421). They
would also like to thank Peter Flaan and Viktor Steiner as well as seminar participants in Vienna and
Bonn for helpful comments on an earlier draft and Nicole Scheremet for editorial assistance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e329a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e336" publication-type="other">
The total fertility rate amounted to 1.34 in Germany and 1.38 in Austria in 2003. The mean age of
women at first birth was 28.23 in Germany and 28.77 in Austria, also in 2003. Source: Eurostat, 2006.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e346a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e353" publication-type="other">
See also Geisler and Kreyenfeld (2005) for a detailed analysis of mothers' employment patterns in
East and West Germany after Reunification.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e363a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e370" publication-type="other">
Since we use data from 2003 for the empirical analysis, we describe the institutional characteristics of
both countries for the same year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e381a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e388" publication-type="other">
Note that joint filing is optional, not mandatory, in Germany.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e395a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e402" publication-type="other">
See Steiner and Wrohlich (2004) for more details on the 'splitting advantage' in Germany.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e409a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e416" publication-type="other">
Note that Germany introduced a new parental leave benefit (Elterngeld) in 2007. This new benefit
replaces the Erziehungsgeld and amounts to 67 per cent of net earnings prior to the birth for the stay-at-
home parent for a maximum duration of one year. If both parents share parental leave, the maximum
duration can be extended by two more months. Spiess and Wrohlich (2008) provide a detailed description
of the new German parental leave benefit.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e435a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e442" publication-type="other">
See Dörfler (2007) for a detailed comparison of childcare institutions in Austria and Germany.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e449a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e456" publication-type="other">
See Dörfler (2004) and Wrohlich (2008) for empirical evidence on excess demand for childcare in
Austria and Germany respectively.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e466a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e473" publication-type="other">
Wrohlich (2007) has calculated the probability of being rationed with respect to centre-based care in
Germany as 34 per cent for children aged 0-2 years, 6 per cent for children aged 3-6 years and 26 per
cent for children aged 7-10 years.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e487a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e494" publication-type="other">
Note that the Austrian figures refer to values from the city of Vienna only, whereas the numbers for
Germany refer to the national average. As a consequence, the parental fees for Austria shown in Table 2
are considerably higher than those for Germany. See Appendix B for a more detailed discussion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e507a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e514" publication-type="other">
While in Germany prices of day-care mothers are used as a yardstick (www.tagesmutter.de), in
Austria this would not be appropriate. Austrian day-care mothers get around €2 per hour (www.efk.at/
main/m_tagesmutter_3.htm), which is only slightly above the hourly cost of public childcare slots, but
day-care-mother slots are not always readily available either. However, even if private childcare by day-
care mothers is limited in Austria, there is no restriction on getting childcare by 'Leihomas' (surrogate
grandparents) or childminders. Leihomas cost €6 per hour (Omadienst, katholischer Familienverband der
Erzdiözese Wien), whereas childminder prices vary between €3 and €7 per hour
(www.kinderbetreuung.at).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e543a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e550" publication-type="other">
Table Al in Appendix A illustrates that sample sizes get very small for subgroups such as single
mothers. Therefore we are not able to perform a separate analysis for this group.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e560a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e567" publication-type="other">
Non-participation also includes mothers who are on maternity leave, who are coded as employed in
many data-sets but not in ours.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e577a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e584" publication-type="other">
For more information on the SOEP, see www.diw.de/soep. For the SILC for Austria, see
www.statistik.at/web_de/frageboegen/private_haushalte/eu_silc/index.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e594a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e601" publication-type="other">
We use the tax-benefit models STSM (Steiner, Haan and Wrohlich, 2005) for Germany and
ITABENA (Dealing and Lietz, 2007) for Austria.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e612a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e619" publication-type="other">
This model is a special case of van Soest's (1995) model with joint estimation of couples' working
hours. In our model, the husband's hours are fixed. This can be justified by empirical findings of
relatively inelastic labour supply of men, as shown by Blundell and MaCurdy (1999) or Steiner and
Wrohlich (2004) for Germany.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e635a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e642" publication-type="other">
Average working hours in the part-time category amount to 20.5 in Austria and 17.2 in Germany; in
the full-time category, the average working hours amount to 34.6 in Austria and 35.6 in Germany.
Fathers' working hours, which are assumed to be exogenous in our analysis, amount on average to 39.2 in
Germany and 33.6 in Austria.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e658a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e665" publication-type="other">
We assume that 80 hours per week is the maximum time budget that can be allocated to market work
and leisure. Note that leisure includes all sorts of non-market activities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e675a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e682" publication-type="other">
The assumption that the error term follows an extreme-value distribution is rather restrictive and
results in the property of the independence of irrelevant alternatives (IIA). Haan (2006) has shown for the
case of women's labour supply estimated on the SOEP database that labour supply elasticities resulting
from a conditional logit model as outlined above are not significantly different from elasticities derived
from the estimation of a random coefficient model that is not based on the IIA assumption.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e701a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e708" publication-type="other">
In order to check whether the elasticities derived from our models are sensitive to the assumption
concerning the amount of childcare that needs to be purchased as a function of mothers' working hours,
we estimated a model under the assumption that all children aged 3 to 6 years are in kindergarten. In other
words, we assumed in this estimation that even non-working mothers with children in this age group have
to purchase part-time childcare. The elasticities derived from this model are not significantly different
from those presented in Table 5.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e731a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e738" publication-type="other">
In simulations A2 and G2 (and A3 and G3), benefits and income thresholds are taken from the
respective country and are not adapted to different income levels.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e749a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e756" publication-type="other">
Note that with the data at hand, it is not possible to model the change in the 'marginal employment'
category. From what we have shown in Section II.3, we would expect this category to become more
attractive for Austrian mothers if German institutions were introduced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e769a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e776" publication-type="other">
This is not necessarily the case considering the highly non-linear character of the simulations.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e783a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e790" publication-type="other">
For example, in 2003, the 'splitting advantage' of a single-earner couple with a taxable income of
€40,000 per year amounted to €3,676 in Germany but only to €3,211 in Austria. Single-earner couples
with a taxable income of €50,000 or €60,000 had a splitting advantage of €4,926 or €6,366, respectively,
in Germany but of only €3,671 or €4,403, respectively, in Austria.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e806a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e813" publication-type="other">
For further discussion of this approach, see Wrohlich (2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e820a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e827" publication-type="other">
For Austria, this number is taken from Statistik Austria (2003/04). For Germany, it is taken from
Statistisches Bundesamt (2004).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1e846a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e850" publication-type="other">
Bach, S., Buslei, H., Svindland, D., Baumgartner, H., Flach, J. and Teichmann, D. (2003),
'Untersuchungen zu den Wirkungen der gegenwaertigen Ehegattenbesteuerung auf
Grundlage von fortgeschriebenen Einzeldaten der Einkommensteuerstatistik'
(Examination of the effects of the current income splitting on the basis of updated micro-
data from the income tax statistics), German Institute for Economic Research (DIW),
mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e873a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e877" publication-type="other">
Beblo, M., Bender, S. and Wolf, E. (2006), 'The wage effects of entering motherhood: a
within-firm matching approach', Institut für Arbeitsmarkt- und Berufsforschung (IAB),
Discussion Paper no. 13/2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e890a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e894" publication-type="other">
—, Beninger, D., Heinze, A. and Laisney, F. (2003), 'Measuring selectivity-corrected gender
wage gaps in the EU', Centre for European Economic Research (ZEW), Discussion Paper
no. 03-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e907a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e911" publication-type="other">
Becker, I. (2007), 'Armut in Deutschland: Leben unterhalb der Algll-Grenze' (Poverty in
Germany: living under the Algll level), SOEP Papers on Multidisciplinary Panel Data
Research at DIW Berlin, no. 4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e925a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e929" publication-type="other">
Blau, F. D. and Kahn, L. M. (2003), 'Understanding international differences in the gender
pay gap', Journal of Labor Economics, vol. 21, pp. 106—44.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e939a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e943" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. and MaCurdy, T. (1999), 'Labour supply: a review of alternative approaches', in
O. Ashenfelter and D. Card (eds), Handbook of Labor Economics, vol. 3A, Amsterdam:
North Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e956a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e960" publication-type="other">
Dearing, H. and Lietz, C. (2007), 'Dokumentation des IHS Steuer-Transfer-
Mikrosimulationsmodells ITABENA' (Documentation on the IHS tax-transfer
microsimulation model ITABENA), Institute for Advanced Studies (IHS), mimeo.
Dingeldey, I. (2001), 'European tax systems and their impact on family employment
patterns', Journal of Social Policy, vol. 30, pp. 653-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e979a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e983" publication-type="other">
Dörfler, S. (2004), 'Außerfamiliale Kinderbetreuung in Österreich: Status Quo und Bedarf
(Non-domestic childcare in Austria: status quo and demand), Austrian Institute for Family
Studies (ÖIF), Discussion Paper no. 43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e996a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1000" publication-type="other">
— (2007), 'Kinderbetreuungskulturen in Europa: ein Vergleich vorschulischer
Kinderbetreuung in Österreich, Deutschland, Frankreich und Schweden' (Childcare
arrangements in Europe: comparing pre-school childcare in Austria, Germany, France and
Sweden), Austrian Institute for Family Studies (ÖIF), Discussion Paper no. 57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1016a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1020" publication-type="other">
Dupuy, A. and Fernandez-Kranz, D. (2007), 'International differences in the family gap in
pay: the role of labor market institutions', Institute for the Study of Labour (IZA),
Discussion Paper no. 2719.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1034a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1038" publication-type="other">
Esping-Andersen, G. (1990), The Three Worlds of Welfare Capitalism, Princeton: Princeton
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1048a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1052" publication-type="other">
Eurostat (2006), Demographic Statistics: Fertility, Luxembourg.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1059a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1063" publication-type="other">
Fagan, C. (2003), 'Working-time preferences and work-life balance in the EU: some policy
considerations for enhancing the quality of life', European Foundation for the
Improvement of Living and Working Conditions, www.eurofound.europa.eu/pubdocs/
2003/42/en/1 /ef0342en.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1079a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1083" publication-type="other">
Geisler, E. and Kreyenfeld, M. (2005), 'Müttererwerbstätigkeit in Ost- und Westdeutschland:
eine Analyse mit den Mikrozensen 1991-2002' (Mothers' labour supply in East and West
Germany: an analysis with Microcensus 1991-2002), Max Planck Institute for
Demographic Research (MPIDR), Working Paper no. 2005-033.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1099a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1103" publication-type="other">
Gottschall, K. and Hagemann, K. (2002), 'Die Halbtagsschule in Deutschland: ein Sonderfall
in Europa?' (The half-day school in Germany: an exception in Europe?), Aus Politik und
Zeitgeschichte, vol. 41, pp. 12-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1116a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1120" publication-type="other">
Gustafsson, S. (1992), 'Separate taxation and married women's labour supply: a comparison
of West Germany and Sweden', Journal of Population Economics, vol. 5, pp. 61-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1131a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1135" publication-type="other">
Haan, P. (2006), 'Much ado about nothing: conditional logit vs. random coefficient models
for estimating labour supply elasticities', Applied Economics Letters, vol. 13, pp. 251-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1145a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1149" publication-type="other">
Jaumotte, F. (2003), 'Female labour force participation: past trends and main determinants in
OECD countries', OECD Economics Department, Working Paper no. 376.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1159a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1163" publication-type="other">
Mahringer, H. (2005), Child Care Costs and Mothers ' Employment Rates in Austria, Vienna:
Austrian Institute for Economic Research (WIFO).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1173a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1177" publication-type="other">
McFadden, D. (1973), 'Conditional logit analysis of qualitative choice behaviour', in P.
Zarembka (ed.), Frontiers in Econometrics, New York: Academic Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1187a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1191" publication-type="other">
McGinnity, F. and McManus, P. (2007), 'Paying the price for reconciling work and family
life: comparing the wage penalty for women's part-time work in Britain, Germany and
the United States', Journal of Comparative Policy Analysis: Research and Practice, vol.
9, pp. 115-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1207a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1211" publication-type="other">
Merkle, L. (1994), Frauenerwerbstätigkeit und Kinderbetreuung. Eine theoretische und
empirische Analyse für die Bundesrepublik Deutschland (Women's Labour Supply and
Childcare: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis for Germany), Heidelberg: Physica-
Verlag.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1228a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1232" publication-type="other">
OECD (2002), Employment Outlook, Paris: Organisation for Economic Cooperation and
Development.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1242a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1246" publication-type="other">
Rosenfeld, R. A., Trappe, H. and Gomick, J. (2004), 'Gender and work in Germany before
and after Reunification', Annual Review of Sociology, vol. 30, pp. 103-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1256a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1260" publication-type="other">
Spiess, C. K. and Wrohlich, K. (2008), 'Parental leave benefit reform in Germany: costs and
labor market outcomes of moving towards the Nordic model', Population Research and
Policy Review, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1273a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1277" publication-type="other">
Statistik Austria (2003/04), Kindertagesheimstatistik (Day-Care Statistics), Vienna.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1284a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1288" publication-type="other">
Statistisches Bundesamt (2004), Kindertagesbetreuung in Deutschland. Einrichtungen,
Plätze, Personal und Kosten 1990 bis 2002 (Day-Care in Germany: Institutions, Slots,
Personnel and Costs 1990-2002), Wiesbaden.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1301a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1305" publication-type="other">
Steiner, V., Haan, P. and Wrohlich, K. (2005), Dokumentation des Steuer-Transfer-
Mikrosimulationsmodells STSM 1999-2002 (Documentation on the Tax-Benefit
Microsimulation Model STSM 1999-2002), Data Documentation no. 9, Berlin: German
Institute for Economic Research (DIW).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1322a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1326" publication-type="other">
— and Wrohlich, K. (2004), 'Household taxation, income splitting and labor supply
incentives: a microsimulation study for Germany', CESifo Economic Studies, vol. 50, pp.
541-68.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1339a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1343" publication-type="other">
— and — (2006), 'Introducing family tax splitting in Germany: how would it affect the
income distribution and work incentives?', Institute for the Study of Labour (IZA),
Discussion Paper no. 2245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1356a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1360" publication-type="other">
Strom, S. and Wagenhals, G. (1991), 'Female labour supply in the Federal Republic',
Jahrbücher für Nationalökonomie und Statistik, vol. 208, pp. 575-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1370a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1374" publication-type="other">
Van Soest, A. (1995), 'Structural models of family labour supply: a discrete choice
approach', Journal of Human Resources, vol. 30, pp. 63-88.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1384a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1388" publication-type="other">
Wrohlich, K. (2006), 'Labour supply and child care choices in a rationed child care market',
Institute for the Study of Labour (IZA), Discussion Paper no. 2053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1398a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1402" publication-type="other">
— (2007), 'Evaluating family policy reforms using behavioural microsimulation: the example
of childcare and income tax reforms in Germany', Doctoral Dissertation, Free University
of Berlin, www.diss.fu-berlin.de/2007/531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1416a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1420" publication-type="other">
— (2008), 'The excess demand for subsidized child care in Germany', Applied Economics,
forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
