<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440231</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Commentary on "Tax by Design: The Mirrlees Review"</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Roger</given-names>
                  <surname>Gordon</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">32</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440225</issue-id>
         <fpage>395</fpage>
         <lpage>414</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440231"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The objective of this commentary is to explore the relationship between the reforms proposed in Tax by Design and the recent academic literature. This literature provides solid support for the Mirrlees Review's dramatic proposals to eliminate any personal taxes on the normal rate of return to savings and to eliminate any net tax on new business investment. There is also solid support for the full taxation of any excess returns on financial investments, including income from capital gains. The commentary does raise questions, though, about the specific methods proposed to achieve these reforms. The proposal advocates adoption of rate-of-return allowances for individual savings under the personal tax and for business investment under the corporate tax. A commonly proposed alternative is to redefine the personal tax base to equal annual consumption and to allow expensing of new investment under the corporate tax. With such reforms to the personal tax, there is no longer even a clear reason to retain a corporate tax. The commentary also emphasises the pressures arising from cross-border investments and cross-border migration of individuals, issues given little attention in the review. These questions regard details of implementation. The overall proposals receive strong support in the academic literature.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d64e107a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e114" publication-type="other">
Submitted December 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e121a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e128" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees et al., 2010 and 201 la.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e135a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e142" publication-type="other">
I should acknowledge up front that I was one of those asked to provide comments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e149a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e156" publication-type="other">
Meade, 1978.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e164a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e171" publication-type="other">
Gordon, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e178a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e185" publication-type="other">
As an example of an article laying out these arguments, see Gordon (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e192a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e199" publication-type="other">
The tax law also has made no attempt to impose a tax on investments in human capital comparable to
the tax that is imposed on investments in financial capital.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e209a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e216" publication-type="other">
See Hubbard and Judd (1986) for such an argument.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e223a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e230" publication-type="other">
See Peterman (2010) for a demonstration that capital income taxes provide an indirect means of
imposing higher tax rates on the labour income of the young, since these earnings are likely to be saved
for the longest time period. Note, though, that the lower tax rates proposed in the review for older workers
directly address this presumption that the young are less responsive to distorting taxes, reducing the gain
from taxes on capital income.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e249a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e256" publication-type="other">
To the extent that saving is discouraged, however, portfolio distortions are introduced. These
distortions exist whenever securities with equal rates of return without taxes on savings no longer have
equal rates of return with such taxes. Whenever the timing of payouts differs across securities - for
example, capital gains income is deferred until realisation - the relative values of securities change as the
discount rate changes, introducing such distortions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e276a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e285" publication-type="other">
This, for example, is the tax treatment of pension savings. The government bears a fraction of the
initial costs equal to the tax rate and receives a fraction of the future return equal to the tax rate prevailing
then. If the tax rate is constant over time, this sharing of costs and benefits of the investment with the
government has no effect on the rate of return received by the investor.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e301a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e308" publication-type="other">
If households can borrow and lend freely, then these changes in the timing of taxes are irrelevant.
However, individuals cannot easily borrow against their future income, so are forced to save out of their
low earnings while young in order to finance down payments on a house or car purchase, and expenses
for child rearing. Easing these liquidity constraints through use of an expenditure tax can then provide an
efficiency gain. Note, though, that if the household is a net borrower, so that income is below
consumption, then liquidity constraints are more severe under an expenditure tax than under a tax using
an RRA.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e334a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e341" publication-type="other">
At the time of Bradford's proposal, economists were less focused on the potential for shifting of
labour income into capital income, a motivation for the RRA base.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e351a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e358" publication-type="other">
The Reagan administration made use of such fiscal illusion when introducing a Roth IRA as an
alternative to a regular IRA (Individual Retirement Account). Compared with a regular IRA,
contributions are not deductible under a Roth IRA, leading to an immediate revenue increase, but
withdrawals are not taxable, leading to a future revenue loss. The budgetary window at that point was
very short, making a shift from a regular IRA to a Roth IRA artificially look like a net revenue gain.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e377a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e384" publication-type="other">
The lemons problem refers to the problem faced when selling a used car, since buyers fear they are
getting a 'lemon'. Analogously, if a small business wants to sell shares, it could well be doing so because
the shares are overpriced, in which case investors should be hesitant to buy them.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e397a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e404" publication-type="other">
See Aaron (1973) for graphs of net income versus gross earnings very similar to those presented in
the review.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e415a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e422" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Deaton and Muelbauer (1980).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e429a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e436" publication-type="other">
Formal contracts and bank loans both provide evidence potentially available to the tax authorities
about the existence and activity of informal firms, undermining their attempted tax evasion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e446a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e453" publication-type="other">
For evidence on relative evasion rates by sector, see Andreoni, Erard and Feinstein (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e460a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e467" publication-type="other">
See Auerbach and Gordon (2002) for an examination of the appropriate tax treatment of the financial
sector under a VAT.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e477a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e484" publication-type="other">
I write this while on sabbatical in London, a choice driven in large part, but not entirely, by the
stimulating academic environment at UCL and 1FS!</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e494a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e501" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Gordon and Varian (1989), who note that countries that are small relative to world
capital markets should not impose taxes on capital invested in the country.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e512a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e519" publication-type="other">
For empirical evidence that corporate taxes are shifted to workers, see Arulampalam, Devereux and
Maffini (2009).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e529a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e536" publication-type="other">
Losses can be carried forward with interest, for example, to compensate for deferral. However, firms
that end up failing before fully using up such loss carry-forwards still end up facing a net tax on new
investment, both discouraging investment in start-up firms, where the failure rate is high, and favouring
investment in firms with substantial income from other sources, as shown in Altshuler and Auerbach
(1990).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e555a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e562" publication-type="other">
Problems would also disappear if the corporate tax were eliminated, a possibility explored below.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e569a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e576" publication-type="other">
A related policy exists in many countries, including the UK, in their dividend imputation schemes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e583a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e590" publication-type="other">
Complications arise, though, when shares are traded during the year, since it is unclear how much of
the ultimate tax liability accrued during the period in which any given investors owned the shares.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e600a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e607" publication-type="other">
Note, though, that the timing of tax payments by corporate and non-corporate firms becomes more
dramatically different if there is no corporate tax. Non-corporate firms face tax on accrual of income,
whereas corporate owners face tax only when the resulting profits are paid out. This difference in timing
matters when tax rates change over time.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e624a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e631" publication-type="other">
For a more extended discussion of these issues, see Cremer and Pestieau (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e638a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e645" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees et al. (201 la, ch. 20), republished in this issue.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e652a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e659" publication-type="other">
Net recipients can include not only the low-skilled, who qualify for various safety-net programmes,
hut also those with medical problems, who benefit from the available healthcare in a country, and
students, who benefit from low tuition fees.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e672a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e679" publication-type="other">
See Gordon and Cullen (2011) for a formal analysis of the effects of mobility on redistribution.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e686a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e693" publication-type="other">
For example, they can borrow to invest in assets whose returns are not realised until after the move to
the tax haven.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e703a1310">
            <label>33</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e710" publication-type="other">
There are special provisions to impose UK taxes at accrual on income accruing in tax havens.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e718a1310">
            <label>34</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e725" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Gordon and Hines (2002) for an overview of the past literature documenting
income shifting by multinationals.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e735a1310">
            <label>35</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e742" publication-type="other">
This is just an example of use of transfer pricing to lower reported profits in high-tax countries and
raise them in low-tax countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d64e752a1310">
            <label>36</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d64e759" publication-type="other">
The same would be true under an expenditure tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d64e775a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e779" publication-type="other">
Aaron, H. (1973), Why Is Welfare So Hard to Reform?, Washington, DC: Brookings
Institution.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e793" publication-type="other">
Albouy, D. (2009), 'The unequal geographic burden of federal taxation', Journal of Political
Economy, vol. 117, pp. 635-67.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e803a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e807" publication-type="other">
Altshuler, R. and Auerbach, A. J. (1990), 'The significance of tax-law asymmetries: an
empirical investigation', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 105, pp. 63-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e817a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e821" publication-type="other">
Andreoni, J., Erard, B. and Feinstein, J. (1998), 'Tax compliance', Journal of Economic
Literature, vol. 36, pp. 818-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e832a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e836" publication-type="other">
Arulampalam, W., Devereux, M. P. and Mafftni, G. (2009), 'The direct incidence of corporate
income tax on wages', Oxford University Centre for Business Taxation, Working Paper
no. 09/17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e849a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e853" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. and Stiglitz, J. E. (1976), 'The design of tax structure: direct vs. indirect
taxation Journal of Public Economics, vol. 6, pp. 55-75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e863a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e867" publication-type="other">
Auerbach, A. and Gordon, R. (2002), 'Taxation of financial services under a VAT', American
Economic Review, vol. 92, pp. 411-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e877a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e881" publication-type="other">
Bergstrom, T. and Blomquist, S. (1996), 'The political economy of subsidized day care',
European Journal of Political Economy, vol. 12, pp. 443-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e891a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e895" publication-type="other">
Besley, T. and Coate, S. (1992), 'Workfare versus welfare incentive arguments for work
requirements in poverty alleviation programs', American Economic Review, vol. 82, pp.
249-61.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e908a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e912" publication-type="other">
Bradford, D. F. (1984), Blueprints for Basic Tax Reform, Arlington, VA: Tax Analysts.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e920a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e924" publication-type="other">
Chamley, C. (1986), 'Optimal taxation of capital income in general equilibrium with infinite
lives', Econometrica, vol. 54, pp. 607-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e934a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e938" publication-type="other">
Conesa, J. C., Kitao, S. and Krueger, D. (2009), 'Taxing capital? Not a bad idea after all!',
American Economic Review, vol. 99, pp. 25-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e948a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e952" publication-type="other">
Cremer, H. and Pestieau, P. (2003), 'Wealth transfer taxation: a survey', CESifo, Working
Paper no. 1061.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e962a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e966" publication-type="other">
Cullen, J. and Gordon, R. (2007), 'Taxes and entrepreneurial risk-taking: theory and evidence
for the US', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 91, pp. 1479-505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e976a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e980" publication-type="other">
Deaton, A. and Muellbauer, J. (1980), Economics and Consumer Behavior, Cambridge:
Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e990a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e994" publication-type="other">
Diamond, P. (1967), 'The role of a stock market in a general equilibrium model with
technological uncertainty', American Economic Review, vol. 57, pp. 759-76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1005a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1009" publication-type="other">
Domar, E. D. and Musgrave, R. (1944), 'Proportional income taxation and risk taking',
Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 58, pp. 388-422.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1019a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1023" publication-type="other">
Golosov, M., Tsyvinski, A. and Weming, I. (2006), 'New dynamic public finance: a user's
guide', in D. Acemoglu, K. Rogoff and M. Woodford (eds), NBER Macroeconomics
Annual, Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1036a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1040" publication-type="other">
Gordon, R. (2000), 'Taxation of capital income vs. labour income: an overview', in S.
Cnossen (ed.), Taxing Capital Income in the EU, Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1050a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1054" publication-type="other">
— (forthcoming), 'A review of the "Mirrlees Review'", in D. Acemoglu, M. Arellano and E.
Dekel (eds), Invited Papers from the Econometric Society World Congress 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1064a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1068" publication-type="other">
— and Cullen, J. (2011), 'Income redistribution in a federal system of governments', Journal
of Public Economics, in press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1078a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1082" publication-type="other">
— and Hines, J. R., Jr (2002), 'International taxation', in A. J. Auerbach and M. Feldstein
(eds), Handbook of Public Economics, volume 4, Amsterdam: North-Holland.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1093a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1097" publication-type="other">
—, Kalambokidis, L. and Slemrod, J. (2004), 'A new summary measure of the effective tax
rate on investment', in P. B. Sorensen (ed.), Measuring the Tax Burden on Capital and
Labor, Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1110a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1114" publication-type="other">
— and Kopczuk, W. (2010), 'The choice of the personal income tax base', mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1121a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1125" publication-type="other">
— and Slemrod, J. (1988), 'Do we collect any revenue from taxing capital income?', Tax
Policy and the Economy, vol. 2, pp. 89-130.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1135a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1139" publication-type="other">
— and Varian, H. (1989), 'Taxation of asset income in the presence of a world securities
market', Journal of International Economics, vol. 26, pp. 205-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1149a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1153" publication-type="other">
Hubbard, R. G. and Judd, K. L. (1986), 'Liquidity constraints, fiscal policy, and
consumption', Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, vol. 1986, pp. 1-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1163a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1167" publication-type="other">
IFS Capital Taxes Group (1991), Equity for Companies: A Corporation Tax for the 1990s,
Commentary no. 26, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1178a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1182" publication-type="other">
Judd, K. L. (1985), 'Redistributive taxation in a simple perfect foresight model', Journal of
Public Economics, vol. 28, pp. 59-83.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1192a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1196" publication-type="other">
Meade, J. (1978), The Structure and Reform of Direct Taxation: Report of a Committee
Chaired by Professor J. E. Meade for the Institute for Fiscal Studies, London: George
Allen and Unwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1209a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1213" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees, J., Adam, S., Besley, T., Blundell, R., Bond, S., Chote, R., Gammie, M., Johnson,
P., Myles, G. and Poterba, J. (eds) (2010), Dimensions of Tax Design: The Mirrlees
Review, Oxford: Oxford University Press for Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1226a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1230" publication-type="other">
—, —, —, —, —, —, —, —, — and — (2011a), Tax by Design: The Mirrlees Review,
Oxford: Oxford University Press for Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1240a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1244" publication-type="other">
—, —, —, —, —, —, —, —, — and — (201 lb), 'The Mirrlees Review: conclusions and
recommendations for reform', Fiscal Studies, vol. 32, pp. 331-59 (this issue).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1254a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1258" publication-type="other">
Peterman, W. (2010), 'Determining the motives for a possible tax on capital', mimeo.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1266a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1270" publication-type="other">
Piggott, J. and Whalley, J. (2001), 'VAT base broadening, self supply, and the informal
sector', American Economic Review, vol. 91, pp. 1084-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1280a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1284" publication-type="other">
Saez, E. (2002), 'The desirability of commodity taxation under non-linear income taxation
and heterogeneous tastes', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 83, pp. 217-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d64e1294a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d64e1298" publication-type="other">
Sorenscn, P. B. (2005), 'Dual income taxation: why and how', CESifo, Working Paper no.
1551.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
