<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">6</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465645</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465648</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Investors' and Central Bank's Uncertainty Embedded in Index Options</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
                  <surname>David</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Pietro</given-names>
                  <surname>Veronesi</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1661</fpage>
         <lpage>1716</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465648"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Shocks to equity options' implied volatility are followed by persistently lower short-term rates. Shocks to puts' over calls' out-of-the-money implied volatilities (P/C) are followed by persistently higher rates. Stock and Treasury bond implied volatilities, which measure market and policy uncertainty, are countercyclical, while P/C, which measures downside risk, is procyclical. An equilibrium model in which investors and the central bank learn about composite regimes of economic and policy variables explains these dynamics, linking them to a learning-based, forward-looking Taylor rule. Survey data support our model's predictions on the effect of uncertainty on the level and fluctuations of implied volatilities.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e281a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e288" publication-type="other">
For example, Bernanke and Kuttner (2005) report that monetary policy surprises affect the stock market, while
Rigobon and Sack (2003) show that the monetary policy responds to stock returns with a greater reaction during
times of higher volatility. More recently Bekaert, Hoerova, and Duca (2010) find a significant reaction of options
prices to lead and lag measures of monetary policy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e304a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e311" publication-type="other">
In our empirical analysis, we use the three-month Treasury bill rate as our short-term rate, rather than the federal
funds rate, as the latter is affected by banks' default premium, which is absent in our model. The three-month
Treasury bill rate and the federal funds rate are very highly correlated.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e324a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e333" publication-type="other">
Interestingly, we find that the put-to-call ratio P/C strongly predicts future interest rates, while we do not find
such relation with other measures of crash risk, such as the difference in implied volatility of out-of-the-money
puts versus at-the-money puts. Our fitted model is also consistent with this evidence. Panel F of Figure 1 shows
that shocks to the bond ATMIV also do not predict future interest rates, which is not inconsistent with our model
either, as we will show.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e352a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e359" publication-type="other">
The new Keynesian economics approach shows the optimality of such rules in settings where price stickiness
implies deviations from short-run full employment and capacity utilization (see, e.g., Woodford 2003). Gallmeyer,
Hollifield, and Zin (2005), Gallmeyer et al. (2007), and Bekaert, Cho, and Moreno (2010) build term-structure
models using policy variables.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e376a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e383" publication-type="other">
Lucas (2007) complains about the lack of use of monetary aggregates in recent models of monetary policy and
recommends their use in information extraction:
One source of this concern is the increasing reliance of central bank research on New-Keynesian
modeling. New-Keynesian models define monetary policy in terms of a choice of money market
rate and so make direct contact with central banking practice. Money supply measures play no
role in their estimation, testing or policy simulation. Arole for money in the long run is sometimes
verbally acknowledged, but the models themselves are formulated in terms of deviation from
trends that are themselves somewhere off stage. It seems likely that these models could be
reformulated to give a unified account of trends, including trends in monetary aggregates, and
deviations about trend but so far they have not been. This remains an unresolved issue on the
frontier of monetary theory. Until it is resolved, monetary information should continue to be
used as a kind of add-on or cross-check, just as it is in the ECB policy formulation today.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e425a1310">
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e429" publication-type="other">
Coenen, Levin, and Wieland (2005) and Beck and Wieland (2008) show that money growth can help predict
real activity when the real output and real money are economically linked but the central bank, which partially
controls money growth, receives noisy information on the former.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e442a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e451" publication-type="other">
For example, Guidolin and Timmermann (2005) and Buraschi and Jiltsov (2006) study option prices and volume
in models with learning about fundamentals. Dubinsky and Johannes (2006) study the reaction of options prices
on individual stocks to news about earnings. Benzoni, Collin-Dufresne, and Goldstein (2011) show that the
increase in investors' perception about the average jump size of stock prices led to a steepening of the implied
volatility smirk after the stock market crash of 1987, but do not study its time variation in subsequent years.
In a paper related to ours, Shaliastovich (2009) models investors' non-Bayesian (behavioral) learning about the
long-run drift of consumption to generate the smile, but does not study its time-series fit to data series.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e477a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e484" publication-type="other">
There is also a large literature that explains the volatility smile by assuming exogenous processes for stock
prices, volatilities, and jumps. Indeed, since the classic work of Black and Scholes (1973) the major innovations
have been the addition of stochastic volatility (see, e.g., Hull and White 1987 and Heston 1993), jumps in prices
(see, e.g., Bates 1996, 2000, Pan 2002), and jumps in volatility (see, e.g., Eraker, Johannes, and Poison 2003).
A tremendous amount of empirical work has been done on these extensions of the Black Scholes formula that
has enriched our understanding of stock price dynamics, and of options returns. Bakshi, Cao, and Chen (1997)
provide a specification analysis of some of these models. Among more recent innovations, Christoffersen et al.
(2008) build multifactor stochastic volatility models, and somewhat related to our paper, Johannes, Poison, and
Stroud (2009) price options when exogenously specified volatility follows an unobserved process that investors
learn about. Constantinides, Jackwerth, and Perrakis (2009) find that several exogenously specified volatility
models, such as GARCH, can be rejected as possible data-generating processes for S&amp;P 500 index options.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e522a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e529" publication-type="other">
We allowed for a generalization of the Taylor rule to let interest rates be directly affected by money growth but
did not estimate a significant effect.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e539a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e546" publication-type="other">
The original Taylor rule (see Taylor 1993) is it =itt +r* +an (nt ay (yt — yt ), where it is the target nominal
rate, 7tt is the realized tate of r* is the assumed «çaàltbrittm real rate of interest, n* is the desired
inflation rate, yt is the log of gross domestic product (GDP), and yt is the log of potential GDP.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e560a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e567" publication-type="other">
Indeed, from Equation (8): TtJ =E[&lt;f&gt;(st)J:t]=aQ+aßE[ß(st)Jrt]+cipE[p(st)J:t], which yields
Equation (6).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e577a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e584" publication-type="other">
The first application of the Wonham filter in financial economics, as well as several properties of the filtering
process, are derived in David (1997). We find it useful to recall that a main advantage of this modeling strategy
as opposed to the more commonly used Kaiman filter is that investors' uncertainty (conditional variance of
expectations about the drift terms) fluctuates forever, while in the Kaiman filter, this uncertainty converges to
a constant. The fluctuating confidence (inverse of the conditional variance) is the driver of the options' indices
that we seek to explain in this paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e607a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e614" publication-type="other">
In Proposition 5 we report the risk-neutral dynamics of zero coupon bonds. The Appendix discusses how we
modify the model to price options on futures on coupon bonds, which correspond to our data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e624a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e631" publication-type="other">
The remaining parameters of the model are as estimated in Table 2 with the exception of the infinitesimal
generator, where we assume booms are longer than recessions, and the recession can be accessed by either boom
regime.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e644a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e651" publication-type="other">
We emphasize that this is not, however, a general result. Parameters can be found that increase the impact of
monetary policy uncertainty on stock option's volatility.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e661a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e668" publication-type="other">
While the relations between options and monetary policy described in this example are intuitive, we should
remember they depend on the three regimes used. As shown in Section 2, in reality there are many additional
composite macroeconomic-policy regimes, such as stagflation regimes, whose implications for the relation
between monetary policy and options may differ from what discussed in the simple example.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e685a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e692" publication-type="other">
The number of "factors" in a factor model depends on the number of uncorrected Brownian motions. The number
of state variables may be larger than the number of factors driving them.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e702a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e709" publication-type="other">
The first six regimes are similar to those in David and Veronesi (2013), who only fit inflation and real earnings,
but no monetary policy variables. Indeed, note that the last two regimes (7 and 8) are identical to Regime 1 and 2
for inflation and earnings, but differ in their monetary policy regime. Compared with David and Veronesi (2013),
the two additional fundamental series to fit (CU and MG) required an expansion of the number of composite
regimes from six to eight. See discussion in previous section.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e728a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e735" publication-type="other">
In such case, we have EconUnc=Y^j=injt(^^ ~£f[0])2=7ri/U —it/X#1 —02)2. We note that because in the
data we regress only on the quantity nt ( 1 — nt ), the slope coefficient also includes (01 — 02)2, and thus regression
coefficients in data and model are not directly comparable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e748a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e755" publication-type="other">
Specifically, we compute InfUnc=Y^Jj= PjPFVj ~ Et IV])2 where PjFF is the SPF probability that inflation
will be in the unit interval centered at Ij. We compute the probabilities on unit intervals by interpolating the SPF
inflation probabilities, as discussed in David and Veronesi (2013).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e768a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e775" publication-type="other">
The variance risk premium, defined as the difference between expected variance under risk-neutral and objective
measure, is positive in our model. It appears that ATMIV does not capture well the tails of the risk neutral
distribution due to the large risk neutral jump sizes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e788a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e795" publication-type="other">
We log linearize the model's growth rate of the moving average. In particular the first order approximation of
the growth rate is
log ~ -(w+z+y+x).
For the subset of the earnings data, where we have the quarterly growth rates available, the approximation leads
to a growth rate very close to the growth rate of the moving average.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e823a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e827" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., and M. Piazzesi. 2003. A no-arbitrage vector autoregression of term structure dynamics with
macroeconomic and latent variables. Journal of Monetary Economics 50:745-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e837a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e841" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., M. Piazzesi, and M. Wei. 2006. What does the yield curve tell us about GDP growth? Journal of
Econometrics 131:359^03.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e851a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e855" publication-type="other">
Bakshi, G, C. Cao, and Z. Chen. 1997. Empirical performance of alternative option pricing models. Journal of
Finance 52:2003-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e865a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e869" publication-type="other">
Bansal, R., and H. Zhou. 2002. Term structure of interest rates with regime shifts. Journal of Finance 57:1997-
2044.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e880a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e884" publication-type="other">
Bates, D. S. 1991. The crash of '87: Was it expected? The evidence from options markets. Journal of Finance
46:1009-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e894a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e898" publication-type="other">
. 1996. Jumps and stochastic volatility: Exchange rate processes implicit in PHLX Deutsche mark options.
Review of Financial Studies 9:69-107.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e908a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e912" publication-type="other">
. 2000. Post-'87 crash fears in the S&amp;P 500 futures option market. Journal of Econometrics 94:
181-238.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e922a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e926" publication-type="other">
Beck, G, and V. Wieland. 2008. Central bank misperceptions and the role of money in interest rate rules. Journal
of Monetary Economics 55:35-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e936a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e940" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, S. Cho, and A. Moreno. 2010. New-Keynesian macroeconomics and the term structure. Journal of
Money Credit and Banking 42:33-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e950a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e954" publication-type="other">
Bekaert, G, M. Hoerova, and M. L. Duca. 2010. Risk, uncertainty and monetary policy. NBER Working Paper
# 16397.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e965a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e969" publication-type="other">
Benzoni, L., P. Collin-Dufresne, and R. S. Goldstein. 2011. Explaining asset pricing puzzles associated with the
1987 market crash. Journal of Financial Economics 101:552-73.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e979a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e983" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B. S., and K. N. Kuttner. 2005. What explains the stock market's reaction to federal reserve policy?
Journal of Finance 60:1221-57.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e993a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e997" publication-type="other">
Black, F., and M. Scholes. 1973. The pricing of options and corporate liabilities. Journal of Political Economy
81:637-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1007a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1011" publication-type="other">
Bollen, N. P. B., and R. E. Whaley. 2004. Does net buying pressure affect the shape of implied volatility functions?
Journal of Finance 59:711-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1025" publication-type="other">
Bollerslev, T., G Tauchen, and H. Zhou. 2009. Expected stock returns and variance risk premia. Review of
Financial Studies 22:4462-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1039" publication-type="other">
Brandt, M. W., and P. Santa-Clara. 2002. Simulated likelihood estimation of diffusions with an application to
exchange rate dynamics in incomplete markets. Journal of Financial Economics 63:161-210.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1050a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1054" publication-type="other">
Buraschi, A., and A. Jiltsov. 2006. Model uncertainty and options markets with heterogeneous beliefs. Journal
of Finance 61:2841-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1064a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1068" publication-type="other">
Chicago Board of Option Exchange. 2009. The CBOE Volatility Index - VIX.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1079" publication-type="other">
Chan, K., G A. Karolyi, F. A. Longstaff, and A. B. Sanders. 1992. An empirical comparison of alternative models
of the short-term interest rate. Journal of Finance 47:1209-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1093" publication-type="other">
Christoffersen, P. F., K. Jacobs, C. Ornthanalai, and Y. Wang. 2008. Option valuation with long-run and short-run
volatility components. Journal of Financial Economics 90:272-97.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1107" publication-type="other">
Clarida, R., J. Gali, and M. Gertler. 2000. Monetary policy rules and macroeconomic stability: Evidence and
some theory. Quarterly Journal of Economics 140:147-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1121" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. H. 2001. Asset pricing. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1129a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1133" publication-type="other">
Coenen, G, A. T. Levin, and V. Wieland. 2005. Data uncertainty and the role of money as an information variable
in monetary policy. European Economic Review 975-1006.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1143a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1147" publication-type="other">
Constantinides, G, J. C. Jackwerth, and S. Perrakis. 2009. Mispricing of s&amp;p 500 index options. Review of
Financial Studies 22: 1247-77.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1157a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1161" publication-type="other">
David, A. 1997. Fluctuating confidence in stock markets: Implications for returns and volatility. Journal of
Financial and Quantitative Analysis 32:427-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1171a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1175" publication-type="other">
. 2008. Inflation uncertainty, asset valuations, and the credit spreads puzzle. Review of Financial Studies
21:2487-534.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1189" publication-type="other">
David, A., and P. Veronesi. 2013. What ties return volatilities to price valuations and fundamentals? Journal of
Political Economy 121:682-746.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1203" publication-type="other">
Drechsler, I. 2013. Uncertainty, time-varying fear, and asset prices. Journal of Finance 68:1843-89.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1211a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1215" publication-type="other">
Drechsler, I., and A. Yaron. 2012. What's vol got to do with it? Review of Financial Studies 24:1-45.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1222a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1226" publication-type="other">
Du, D. 2011. General equilibrium pricing of options with habit formation and event risks. Journal of Financial
Economics 99:400-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1236a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1240" publication-type="other">
Duan, J., and J. Simonato. 1998. Empirical Martingale Simulation for Asset Prices. Management Science
44:1218-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1250a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1254" publication-type="other">
Dubinsky, A., and M. Johannes. 2006. Earnings announcements and option prices. Working Paper, Columbia
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1264a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1268" publication-type="other">
Eraker, B. 2008. The volatility premium. Working Paper, University of Wisconsin Madison.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1275a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1279" publication-type="other">
Eraker, B., M. Johannes, and N. Poison. 2003. The impact of jumps in equity index volatility and returns. Journal
of Finance 58:1269-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1290a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1294" publication-type="other">
Gallmeyer, M., B. Hollifield, F. Palomino, and S. Zin. 2007. Arbitrage-free bond pricing with dynamic
macroeconomic models. Federal Reserve of St. Louis Review.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1308" publication-type="other">
Gallmeyer, M. F., B. Hollifield, and S. E. Zin. 2005. Taylor rules, mccallum rules and the term structure of interest
rates. Journal of Monetary Economics 52:921-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1318a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1322" publication-type="other">
Garcia, R. 1998. Asymptotic null distribution of the likelihood ratio test in markov switching models.
International Economic Review 39:763-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1332a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1336" publication-type="other">
Garleanu, N., L. H. Pederson, and A. M. Poteshman. 2009. Demand-based option pricing. Review of Financial
Studies 22:4259-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1346a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1350" publication-type="other">
Gray, S. 1996. Modeling the conditional distribution of interest rates as a regime switching process. Journal of
Financial Economics 42:27-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1360a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1364" publication-type="other">
Guidolin, M., and A. Timmermann. 2005. Option prices under Bayesian learning: Implied volatility dynamics
and predictive densities. Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 27:717-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1375a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1379" publication-type="other">
Gurkaynak, R. S., B. Sack, and J. H. Wright. 2007. The u.s. treasury yield curve: 1961 to the present. Journal of
Monetary Economics 54:2291-304.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1389a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1393" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, J. D. 1994. Time series analysis. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1400a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1404" publication-type="other">
Hansen, L. P. 2007. Beliefs, doubts and learning: Valuing macroeconomic risk. American Economic Review
97:1-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1414a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1418" publication-type="other">
Heston, S. L. 1993. A closed-form solution for options with stochastic volatility and applications to bond and
currency options. Review of Financial Studies 6:326-43.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1428a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1432" publication-type="other">
Hull, J. C., and A. White. 1987. The pricing of options on assets with stochastic volatility. Journal of Finance
42:281-300.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1442a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1446" publication-type="other">
Johannes, M., N. Poison, and J. Stroud. 2009. Optimal filtering of jump-diffusions: Extracting latent states from
asset prices. Review of Financial Studies 22:2259-99.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1457a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1461" publication-type="other">
Jones, C. S. 2003. The dynamics of stochastic volatility: Evidence from underlying and options markets. Journal
of Econometrics 116:181-224.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1471a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1475" publication-type="other">
Kloeden, P. E., and E. Platen. 1992. Numeric solutions of stochastic differential equations. New York: Springer-
Verlag.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1485a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1489" publication-type="other">
Liu, J., J. Pan, and T. Wang. 2005. An equilibrium model of rare event premia and its implications for option
smirks. Review of Financial Studies 19:131-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1499a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1503" publication-type="other">
Lucas, R. E. 1978. Asset prices in an exchange economy. Econometrica 46:1429-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1510a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1514" publication-type="other">
. 2007. Central banking: Is science replacing art? In Monetary Policy: A Journey from Theory to Practice.
European Central Bank.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1524a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1528" publication-type="other">
Mueller, P., A. Vedolin, and Y.-M. Yen. 2013. Bond variance risk premiums. Working Paper, London School of
Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1539a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1543" publication-type="other">
Pan, J. 2002. The jump-risk premia implicit in options: Evidence from an integrated time-series study. Journal
of Financial Economics 63:3-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1553a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1557" publication-type="other">
Piazzesi, M. 2005. Bond yields and the Federal Reserve. Journal of Political Economy 113:311-44.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1564a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1568" publication-type="other">
Rigobon, R., and B. Sack. 2003. Measuring the reaction of monetary policy to the stock market. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 118:639-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1578a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1582" publication-type="other">
Rudebusch, G D., and T. Wu. 2008. A macro-finance model of the term-structure, monetary policy, and the
economy. Economic Journal 188:906-26.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1592a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1596" publication-type="other">
Shaliastovich, I. 2009. Learning, confidence and option prices. Working Paper, Wharton School of Business.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1603a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1607" publication-type="other">
Taylor, J. B. 1993. Discretion versus policy rules in practice. Carnegie-Rochester Conference Series on Public
Policy 39:195-214.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1618a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1622" publication-type="other">
Veronesi, P. 2000. How does information quality affect stock returns? Journal of Finance 55:807-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1629a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1633" publication-type="other">
Whaley, R. E. 2000. The Investors Fear Gauge. Journal of Portfolio Management 26:12-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1644" publication-type="other">
Wonham, W. J. 1964. Some applications of stochastic differential equations to optimal filtering. SIAM Journal
of Control 2:347-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1658" publication-type="other">
Woodford, M. 2003. Interest and prices: Foundations of a theory of monetary policy. Princeton, NJ: Princeton
University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


