<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014698</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Learning “About” and Learning “Through” Technology</article-title>
            <subtitle>An Analysis of Syllabi from Foreign Language Teaching Methods Courses</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Angus</surname>
                  <given-names>Katie B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>The University of Southern Mississippi.</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Katie B. Angus received her Ph.D. from the Second Language Acquisition and Teaching (SLAT) Interdisciplinary program at the University of Arizona after completing her dissertation on the professional development of foreign language teaching assistants. She is currently an Assistant Professor of French in the Department of Foreign Languages and Literatures at the University of Southern Mississippi. She teaches French and Second Language Acquisition courses online and face-to-face to undergraduate students of French and graduate students enrolled in the Master of Arts in the Teaching of Languages (MATL) program.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014695</issue-id>
         <fpage>317</fpage>
         <lpage>335</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014698"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>The 2007 Modern Language Association (MLA) report recommended that foreign language (FL) graduate students be provided with “substantive training in language teaching and in the use of new technologies”. In the present study, I examined teaching methodology (“methods”) course syllabi in order to gauge the extent of professional development in technology after the publication of the MLA report. Using data from methods course syllabi (N = 31), I explored how FL Teaching Assistants (TAs) learned about technology and learned through technology and found that there were considerable missed opportunities for both. Data suggest that technology in the methods course is not keeping pace with advances in technology and that the methods course needs to be rethought.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>fl teaching methods course</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>teaching assistants</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>graduate students</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>professional development</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>syllabi</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen, H., &amp; Negueruela-Azarola, E. (2010). The professional development of future professors of foreign languages: Looking back, looking forward. Modern Language Journal, 94(3), 377–395. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2010.01056.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold, N. (2013). The role of methods textbooks in providing early training for teaching with technology in the language classroom. Foreign Language Annals, 46(2), 230–245. https://doi.org/10.1111/flan.12020</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold, N., &amp; Ducate, L. (2006). Future foreign language teachers’ social and cognitive collaboration in an online environment. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 10(1), 42–66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blyth, C. (Ed.). (2010). Foreign language teaching methods. Austin, TX: University of Texas at Austin, Language Technology Center.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brandl, K. (2008). Communicative language teaching in action: Putting principles to work. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Byrd, D. (2007). Investigating how second language teachers are prepared to teach culture: An analysis of methods course syllabi. (Doctoral dissertation). Retrieved from ProQuest Dissertations and Theses. (UMI No. 3281348)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapelle, C., &amp; Hegelheimer, V. (2004). The language teacher in the 21st century. In S. Fotos &amp; M. Browne (Eds.), New perspectives on CALL for second language classrooms (pp. 299–316). New York, NY: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Compton, L. K. L. (2009). Preparing language teachers to teach language online: A look at skills, roles, and responsibilities. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 22(1), 73–99. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588220802613831</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dhonau, S., McAlpine, D., &amp; Shrum, J. (2010). What is taught in the foreign language methods course ? NECTFL Review, 66, 73–95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egbert, J., Paulus, T., &amp; Nakamichi, Y. (2002). The impact of CALL instruction on language classroom technology use: A foundation for rethinking CALL teacher education? Language Learning &amp; Technology, 6(3), 108–126.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Erben, T. (1999). Constructing learning in a virtual immersion bath: LOTE teacher education through audiographics. In R. Debski &amp; M. Levy (Eds.), WORLDCALL: International perspectives on computer-assisted language learning (pp. 229–248). Lisse, The Netherlands: Swets &amp; Zeitlinger Publishers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gruba, P. (2006). Playing the video text: A media literacy perspective on video-mediated L2 listening. Language, Learning and Technology, 10(2), 77–92.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herron, C. (1994). Investigation of the effectiveness of using an advocate organizer to introduce video in the foreign language classroom. Modern Language Journal, 78, 190–198. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.1994.tb02032.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herron, C., Cole, S. P., Corrie, C., &amp; Dubreil, S. (1999). The effectiveness of a video-based curriculum in teaching culture. The Modern Language Journal, 83(4), 518–533. https://doi.org/10.1111/0026-7902.00038</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoven, D. (2007). The affordance of technology for student teachers to shape their education experience. In M. A. Kassen, R. Z. Lavine, K. Murphy-Judy, &amp; M. Peters (Eds.), Preparing and developing technology-proficient L2 teachers. (CALICO Monograph Series, pp. 133–164). Texas: Computer Assisted Language Instruction Consortium (CALICO).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubbard, P. (2008). CALL and the future of language teacher education. CALICO Journal, 25(2), 175–188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kern, R., &amp; Warschauer, M. (2000). Introduction: Theory and practice of network-based language teaching. In M. Warschauer &amp; R. Kern (Eds.), Network based language teaching: Concepts and practice. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139524735.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kessler, G. (2006). Assessing CALL teacher training: What are we doing and what could we do better? In P. Hubbard &amp; M. Levy (Eds.), Teacher education in CALL (pp. 23–44). Philadelphia: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.14.05kes</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, J., &amp; VanPatten, B. (2003). Making communicative language teaching happen. Boston, MA: McGraw-Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lightbown, P., &amp; Spada, N. (2006). How languages are learned. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lord, G. (2014). Language program direction: Theory and practice. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lord, G., &amp; Lomicka, L. L. (2004). Developing collaborative cyber communities to prepare tomorrow’s teachers. Foreign Language Annals, 37(3), 401–408. https://doi.org/10. 1111/j.1944-9720.2004.tb02698.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mills, N. (2011a). Situated learning through social networking communities: The development of joint enterprise, mutal engagement, and a shared repertoire. CALICO Journal, 28(2), 345–368. https://doi.org/10.11139/cj.28.2.345-368</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mills, N. (2011b). Teaching assistants’ self-efficacy in teaching literature: Sources, personal assessments, and consequences. Modern Language Journal, 95(1), 60–80. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2010.01145.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MLA Ad Hoc Committee on Foreign Languages. (2007). Foreign languages and higher education: New structures for a changed world. Profession 2007, 234–245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moore, Z. (2006). Technology and teaching culture: What Spanish teachers do. Foreign Language Annals, 39(4), 579–594. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2006.tb02277.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Omaggio-Hadley, A. (2001). Teaching language in context. Boston: Heinle &amp; Heinle.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pfeiffer, P. C. (2008). The discipline of foreign language studies and reforming foreign language education. Modern Language Journal, 92, 296–298. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2007.00719_4.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reinders, H. (2009). Technology and second language teacher education. In A. Burns &amp; J. C. Richards (Eds.), Cambridge guide to second language teacher education (pp. 230–237). New York, NY: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reinhardt, J., &amp; Thorne, S. (2011). Beyond comparisons: Frameworks for developing digital L2 literacies. In N. Arnold &amp; L. Ducate (Eds.), Present and future promises of CALL: From theory and research to new directions in language teaching (pp. 257–280). San Marcos, TX: CALICO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rifkin, B. (2000). Video in the proficiency-based advanced conversation class: An example from the Russian-language curriculum. Foreign Language Annals, 33(1), 63–70. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1944-9720.2000.tb00891.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosa, E. M., &amp; Leow, R. P. (2004). Computerized task-based exposure, explicitness, type of feedback, and Spanish L2 development. Modern Language Journal, 88, 192–216. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0026-7902.2004.00225.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Royce, T. (2002). Multimodality in the TESOL classroom: Exploring visual-verbal synergy. TESOL Quarterly, 36(2), 191–205. https://doi.org/10.2307/3588330</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sanz, C., &amp; Morgan-Short, K. (2004). Positive evidence versus explicit rule presentation and explicit negative feedback: A computer-assisted study. Language Learning, 53(4), 35–78. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2004.00248.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shrum, J., &amp; Glisan, E. (2009). Teacher’s handbook: Contextualized language instruction. Boston, MA: Heinle Cengage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stapleton, P., &amp; Radia, P. (2010). Tech-era L2 writing: Towards a new kind of process. ELT Journal, 64(2), 175–183. https://doi.org/10.1093/elt/ccp038</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swaffer, J., &amp; Vlatten, A. (1997). A sequential model for video viewing in the foreign language curriculum. Modern Language Journal, 81, 175–188. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.1997.tb01173.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thoms, J. (2013). Investigating foreign language graduate student instructors’ perceptions and use of technology in the classroom. In H. W. Allen &amp; H. Maxim (Eds.), Educating the future foreign language professoriate for the 21st century (pp. 192–211). Boston, MA: Heinle Cengage.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S., &amp; Payne, J. (2005). Evolutionary trajectories, internet-mediated expression, and language education. CALICO Journal, 22(3), 371–397.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
