<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277528</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Pressure Sensitivity of HCCI Auto-Ignition Temperature for Primary Reference Fuels</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Truedsson</surname>
                  <given-names>Ida</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tuner</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johansson</surname>
                  <given-names>Bengt</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cannella</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chevron USA Inc</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>August 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277500</issue-id>
         <fpage>1089</fpage>
         <lpage>1108</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277528"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Some fuels with the same research octane number (RON) have different HCCI engine performance. Therefore RON alone cannot be used for determining auto ignition in HCCI combustion. The current research focuses on creating an HCCI fuel index suitable for comparing different fuels for HCCI operation. More thorough studies are needed to map the fuel effects. One way to characterize a fuel is by using the Auto Ignition Temperature (AIT). The AIT and the amount of Low Temperature Heat Release (LTHR) together describe the auto ignition properties of the fuel. Both can be extracted from the pressure trace. The assumption is that the pressure and temperature are known at inlet valve closing (IVC) and that the mass in the cylinder does not change after IVC.</p>
            <p>The purpose of this study was to map the AIT of different Primary Reference Fuels (PRF) for HCCI combustion at different cylinder pressures. Different pressure levels were achieved by changing inlet air temperatures in 5 steps from 50°C to 150°C. A Cooperative Fuel Research (CFR) engine with variable compression ratio was used. The compression ratio was varied from 5.5 to 15.5 to keep combustion phasing, defined as 50% of total heat released, constant at 3±1° after TDC. The experiments were carried out in lean operation with a constant equivalence ratio of 0.33 and with a constant engine speed of 600 rpm.</p>
            <p>The results showed that the AITs of the PRFs ranged from around 580 K for PRF 0 to up to 800 K for PRF 100. Auto ignition was defined as the point where the rate of heat released had reached 0.2 J/CAD. At the lowest inlet air temperatures all fuels except PRF 100 showed Low Temperature Heat Release (LTHR) from about 3% LTHR/Total Heat Release for PRF 95 with up to 19% for PRF 0. Amount of LTHR was found to decrease linearly with increasing octane rating.</p>
            <p>The low octane PRFs ignited at almost the same temperature independent of the cylinder pressure. The high octane number PRFs (PRF 95 - 100) displayed a wide range of auto ignition temperatures resulting from the different inlet air temperatures. PRF 80, PRF 85 and PRF 90 showed an intermediate behavior. A constant auto ignition temperature was seen at the low inlet air temperature but at higher inlet air temperatures the IAT quicky rised when the LTHR disappeared.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., “Auto-Ignition Quality of Practical Fuels and Implications for Fuel Requirements of Future SI and HCCI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0239, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shibata, G. and Urushihara, T., “Auto-Ignition Characteristics of Hydrocarbons and Development of HCCI Fuel Index,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0220, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0220.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shibata, G., Oyama, K., Urushihara, T., and Nakano, T., “Correlation of Low Temperature Heat Release With Fuel Composition and HCCI Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0138, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hosseini, V., Neill, W., and Chippior, W., “Influence of Engine Speed on HCCI Combustion Characteristics using Dual-Stage Autoignition Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1107, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., “EGR and Intake Boost for Managing HCCI Low-Temperature Heat Release over Wide Ranges of Engine Speed,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0051, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0051.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanaka, S., Ayala, F., Keck, J.C, Heywood, J.B., “Two-stage ignition in HCCI combustion and HCCI control by fuels and additives”, Combustion and Flame, 132 (2003) 219-239</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Machrafi, H., Cavadiasa, S., “An experimental and numerical analysis of the influence of the inlet temperature, equivalence ratio and compression ratio on the HCCI auto-ignition process of Primary Reference Fuels in an engine”, Fuel Processing Technology, 89 (2008) 1218-1226</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christenssen, M., “HCCI Combustion - Engine Operation and Emission Characteristics”, Doctoral Thesis, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Silke, E., Pitz, W., Westbrook, C., Sjöberg, M. et al., “Understanding the Chemical Effects of Increased Boost Pressure under HCCI Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):12-25, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehl, M., Faravelli, T., Ranzi, E., Miller, D., Cernansky, N., “Experimental and kinetic modeling study of the effect of fuel composition in HCCI engines”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 32 (2009) 2843-2850</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., 1988, “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”, McGraw Hill, New York, 1989</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warnatz, J., Maas, U., Dibble, R.W., “Combustion - Physical and Chemical Fundamentals, Modeling and Simulation, Experiments, Pollutant Formation”, Springer, Berlin, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
