<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278009</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Operation Strategy on First Cycle CO, HC, and PM/PN Emissions in a GDI Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rodriguez</surname>
                  <given-names>J. Felipe</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Cheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Wai K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>June 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277995</issue-id>
         <fpage>1098</fpage>
         <lpage>1106</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278009"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The impact of the operating strategy on emissions from the first combustion cycle during cranking was studied quantitatively in a production gasoline direct injection engine. A single injection early in the compression cycle after IVC gives the best tradeoff between HC, particulate mass (PM) and number (PN) emissions and net indicated effective pressure (NIMEP). Retarding the spark timing, it does not materially affect the HC emissions, but lowers the PM/PN emissions substantially. Increasing the injection pressure (at constant fuel mass) increases the NIMEP but also the PM/PN emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Façanha, Cristiano, Blumber Kate, and Miller Josh. Global Transportation Energy and Climate Roadmap. International Council on Clean Transportation, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, Hui, and Bandivadekar Anup, “Passenger Car Fuel- Efficiency Standards in China and the US: Stringency and Technology, 2020-2025.” International Council on Clean Transportation, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA; NHTSA. “Final Rulemaking for 2017-2025 Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards.” 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fan, Q., Bian J., Lu H., Li L., and Deng J.. “Effect of the Fuel Injection Strategy on First-Cycle Firing and Combustion Characteristics during Cold Start in a TSDI Gasoline Engine.” International Journal of Automotive Technology 13 (4): 523-31. doi:10.1007/s12239-012-0050-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fan, Q. and Li, L., “Transient Characteristics of Cold Start Emissions from a Two-Stage Direct Injection Gasoline Engines Employing the Total Stoichiometric Ratio and Local Rich Mixture Start-up Strategy,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1068, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whitaker, P., Kapus, P., Ogris, M., and Hollerer, P., “Measures to Reduce Particulate Emissions from Gasoline DI engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1498-1512, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Geringer, Bernhard, Hofmann Peter, and Holub Florian. 2010. “Verbesserung des Hochlaufs und des Emissionsverhaltens im Kaltstart und Warmlauf bei Ottomotoren.” MTZ - Motortechnische Zeitschrift 71 (5): 368-72. doi:10.1007/BF03225576.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wiemer, S., Kubach, H., and Spicher, U., “Investigations on the Start-Up Process of a DISI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4012, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, S., Hyun, S., and Park, J., “Optimization of Cold Start Operating Conditions in a Stoichiometric GDI Engine with Wall-guided Piston using CFD Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2650, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2650.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malaguti, S., Cantore, G., Fontanesi, S., Lupi, R. et al., “CFD Investigation of Wall Wetting in a GDI Engine under Low Temperature Cranking Operations,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0704, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0704.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malaguti, S., Fontanesi, S., and Severi, E., “Numerical Analysis of GDI Engine Cold-Start at Low Ambient Temperatures,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-2123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2123.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, Z., Yi, J., Wooldridge, S., Reiche, D. et al., “Modeling the Cold Start of the Ford 3.5L V6 EcoBoost Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1367- 1387, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1493.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lang, K. and Cheng, W., “Effect of Fuel Properties on First Cycle Fuel Delivery in a SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-3057, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-3057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lang, K., Cheng, W., Borland, M., Thomas, C. et al., “Effect of Intake Cam Phasing on First Cycle Fuel Delivery and HC Emissions in an SI Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1852, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004- 01-1852.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cowart, J., “Air-Fuel Ratio Measurement Diagnostics During Cranking and Startup in a Port-Fuel-Injected Spark-Ignition Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1915, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1915.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santoso, H. and Cheng, W., “Mixture Preparation and Hydrocarbon Emissions Behaviors in the First Cycle of SI Engine Cranking,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2805, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2805.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klein, D. and Cheng, W., “Spark Ignition Engine Hydrocarbon Emissions Behaviors in Stopping and Restarting,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2804, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2804.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao, F., “Transient Engine Startup and Shutdown Processes,” in “Technologies for Near-Zero-Emission Gasoline-Powered Vehicles,” (Warrendale, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc., 2006), doi:10.4271/R-359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cambustion. “Gasoline Direct Injection Particulate Measurement with the DMS Series”. Application Note DMS08.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eiglmeier, C., Pfalzgraf B., Helbig J., Adam S., Grigo M., Dornhöfer R., and Eiser A.. “Der Neue R4 - 2,0l TFSI SULEV/PZEV-Motor von Audi.” In, 16. Aachener Kolloquium Fahrzeug- und Motorentechnik, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kudo, H., Hirose I., Kihara T., Yamakawa M., and Hitomi M.. “MAZDA SKYACTIV-G 2.0L Gasoline Engine.” In, 20th Aachen Colloquium Automobile and Engine Technology, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kufferath, Andreas, Samenfink Wolfgang, and Gerhardt Jürgen. “Die neue Emissionsstrategie der Benzin-Direkteinspritzung.” MTZ - Motortechnische Zeitschrift, Nov. 2003, doi:10.1007/BF03227138.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J., “The Effect of Spark Retard on Engine-out Hydrocarbon Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3867, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3867.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cedrone, K. and Cheng, W., “SI Engine Control in the Cold- Fast-Idle Period for Low HC Emissions and Fast Catalyst Light Off,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):968-976, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cedrone, K. and Cheng, W., “Using Valve Timing and Exhaust Back Pressure to Improve Catalyst Warm-Up Time,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-2656, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2656.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodríguez, Felipe J., and Cheng Wai K.. “Fuel Accounting for the First Cranking Cycle of a GDI Engine.” In THIESEL 8th International Conference on Thermo-and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Direct Injection Engines. Valencia, Spain, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, John B. “Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals”. New York, McGraw-Hill, 1988. ISBN 978-0070286375</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cheng, W., Hamrin, D., Heywood, J., Hochgreb, S. et al., “An Overview of Hydrocarbon Emissions Mechanisms in Spark- Ignition Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 932708, 1993, doi:10.4271/932708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ketterer, J. and Cheng, W., “On the Nature of Particulate Emissions from DISI Engines at Cold-Fast-Idle,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(2):986-994, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoffmann, G., Befrui, B., Berndorfer, A., Piock, W. et al., “Fuel System Pressure Increase for Enhanced Performance of GDi Multi- Hole Injection Systems,” SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):519-527, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burke, D., Foti, D., Haller, J., and Fedor, W., “Fuel Rail Pressure Rise during Cold Start of a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0393, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0393.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
