<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014700</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Short-Term and Long-Term Effects of AWE Feedback on ESL Students’ Development of Grammatical Accuracy</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Zhi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a1">
                  <sup>1</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Zhi Li is a language assessment specialist at Paragon Testing Enterprises, BC, Canada. He holds a PhD degree in applied linguistics and technology from Iowa State University, USA and an MA degree in applied linguistics from Hunan University, China. His research interests include language assessment, computerassisted language learning, corpus linguistics, and systemic functional linguistics. He has presented his work at a number of professional conferences such as AAAL, LTRC, and TESOL. His research papers have been published in System and Language Learning &amp;Technology.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Feng</surname>
                  <given-names>Hui-Hsien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a2">
                  <sup>2</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Hui-Hsien Feng is a postdoctoral research associate at Iowa State University. She holds an MA in TESOL at the Ohio State University and a PhD in Applied Linguistics and Technology at Iowa State University. Her research interests include second language writing, automated writing evaluation, English for specific purposes, computational linguistics, and computer-assisted language learning. She has disseminated her research findings regularly in national and international conferences, including the conference of the American Association for Applied Linguistics (AAAL), the Computer Assisted Language Instruction Consortium (CALICO), Second Language Research Forum (SLRF) Conference, Symposium on Second Language Writing (SSLW), and International Conference on Computers in Education (ICCE).</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Saricaoglu</surname>
                  <given-names>Aysel</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <xref ref-type="aff" rid="a3">
                  <sup>3</sup>
               </xref>
               <bio>
                  <p>Aysel Saricaoglu (Ph.D., Applied Linguistics and Technology, Iowa State University) is an assistant professor in English Language Education, TED University. She investigates academic writing with a focus on automated formative assessment, and corpus linguistics. Her work has appeared in journals such as Computer-Assisted Language Learning and CALICO.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="a1">
               <sup>1</sup>Paragon Testing Enterprises, Inc.</aff>
            <aff id="a2">
               <sup>2</sup>Iowa State University.</aff>
            <aff id="a3">
               <sup>3</sup>TED University, Turkey.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014695</issue-id>
         <fpage>355</fpage>
         <lpage>375</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014700"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>This classroom-based study employs a mixed-methods approach to exploring both short-term and long-term effects of Criterion feedback on ESL students’ development of grammatical accuracy. The results of multilevel growth modeling indicate that Criterion feedback helps students in both intermediate-high and advanced-low levels reduce errors in eight out of nine categories from first drafts to final drafts within the same papers (short-term effects). However, there is only one error reduction of statistical significance in the category of Run-on Sentence from the first drafts of the first paper to the first drafts in the subsequent papers for both levels of students (long-term effects). The findings from interviews with the participants reveal students’ perceptions of Criterion feedback and help us understand the feedback effect. Implications for a more effective use of AWE tools in ESL classrooms are discussed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>automated writing evaluation</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>corrective feedback</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>short-term effects</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>long-term effects</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>grammatical accuracy</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bazeley, P. (2007). Qualitative data analysis with NVivo. Thousand Oaks, California: SAGE Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bickel, R. (2007). Multilevel analysis for applied research: It’s just regression! New York: The Guilford Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chandler, J. (2003). The efficacy of various kinds of error feedback for improvement in the accuracy and fluency of L2 student writing. Journal of Second Language Writing, 12(3), 267–296. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1060-3743(03)00038-9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapelle, C. A. (2003). English language learning and technology: Lectures on applied linguistics in the age of information and communication. Amsterdam: John Benjamin Publishing Company. https://doi.org/10.1075/lllt.7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H. J., Chiu, T. L., &amp; Liao, P. (2009). Analyzing the grammar feedback of two automated writing evaluation systems: My Access and Criterion. English Teaching and Learning, 33(2), 1–43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, C. F., &amp; Cheng, W. Y. (2008). Beyond the design of automated writing evaluation: Pedagogical practices and perceived learning effectiveness in EFL writing classes. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 12(2), 94–112.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Creswell, J. W. (2009). Research design: Qualitative, quantitative, and mixed methods approaches. Los Angeles: SAGE Publications.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dikli, S., &amp; Bleyle, S. (2014). Automated essay scoring feedback for second language writers: How does it compare to instructor feedback? Assessing Writing, 22, 1–17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asw.2014.03.006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ebyary, K., &amp; Windeatt, S. (2010). The impact of computer-based feedback on students’ written work. International Journal of English Studies, 10(2), 121–142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Elliot, N., Gere, A. R., Gibson, G., Toth, C., Whithaus, C., &amp; Presswood, A. (2013). Uses and limitations of automated writing evaluation software. WPA-CompPile Research Bibliographies, 23. Retrieved from http://comppile.org/wpa/bibliographies/Bib23/AutoWritingEvaluation.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellis, R. (2008). A typology of written corrective feedback types. ELT Journal, 63(2), 97–107. https://doi.org/10.1093/elt/ccn023</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grimes, D., &amp; Warschauer, M. (2010). Utility in a fallible tool: A Multi-Site case study of automated writing evaluation. Journal of Technology, Learning, and Assessment, 8(6). Retrieved from http://www.jtla.org</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferris, D. R. (2006). Does error feedback help student writers? New evidence on the short- and long-term effects of written error correction. In K. Hyland &amp; F. Hyland (Eds.), Feedback in second language writing: Contexts and issues (pp. 81–104). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139524742.007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ferris, D. R. (2012). Technology and corrective feedback for L2 writers: Principles, practices, and problems. In G. Kessler, A. Oskoz, and I. Elola (Eds.), Technology across writing contexts and tasks. CALICO Monograph. San Marcos, TX: CALICO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayes, A. F. (2006). A primer on multilevel modeling. Human Communication Research, 32, 385–410. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-2958.2006.00281.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hyland, K., &amp; Hyland, F. (2006). Feedback on second language students’ writing. Language Teaching, 39, 83–101. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0261444806003399</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IBM Corp. (2012). IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows, Version 21.0. Armonk, NY: IBM Corp. Kennedy, S. (2010). Corrective feedback for learners of varied proficiency levels: A teacher’s choices. TESL Canada Journal, 27(2), 31–50. https://doi.org/10.18806/tesl.v27i2.1054</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, J., Link, S., &amp; Hegelheimer, V. (2015). Rethinking the role of automated writing evaluation (AWE) feedback in ESL writing instruction. Journal of Second Language Writing, 27, 1–18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jslw.2014.10.004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, S. (2010). The effectiveness of corrective feedback in SLA: A meta-analysis. Language Learning, 60(2), 309–365. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2010.00561.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Z., Link, S., Ma, H., Yang, H., &amp; Hegelheimer, V. (2014). The role of automated writing evaluation holistic scores in the ESL classroom. System, 44, 66–78. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2014.02.007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Link, S., Dursun, A., Karakaya, K., &amp; Hegelheimer, V. (2014). Towards better ESL practices for implementing automated writing evaluation. CALICO Journal, 31(3), 323–344. https://doi.org/10.11139/cj.31.3.323-344</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Otoshi, J. (2005). An analysis of the use of Criterion in a writing classroom. The JALT CALL Journal, 1(1), 30–38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rich, C. S. (2012). The impact of online automated writing evaluation: A case study from Dalian. Chinese Journal of Applied Linguistics, 35(1), 63–79. https://doi.org/10.1515/cjal-2012-0006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stevenson, M., &amp; Phakiti, A. (2014). The effects of computer-generated feedback on the quality of writing. Assessing Writing, 19, 51–65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asw.2013.11.007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tabachnick, B. G., &amp; Fidell, L. S. (2013). Using Multivariate Statistics (4th ed.). Boston: Allyn and Bacon.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Truscott, J. (1996). The case against grammar correction in L2 writing classes. Language Learning, 46, 327–369. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-1770.1996.tb01238.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Truscott, J. (2007). The effect of error correction on learners’ ability to write accurately. Journal of Second Language Writing, 16(4), 255–272. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jslw.2007.06.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, P. (2013). Can automated writing evaluation programs help students improve their English writing? International Journal of Applied Linguistics &amp; English Literature, 2(1), 6–12. https://doi.org/10.7575/ijalel.v.2n.1p.6</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y.-J., Shang, H.-F., &amp; Briody, P. (2013). Exploring the impact of using automated writing evaluation in English as a foreign language university students’ writing. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 26(3), 234–257. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2012.655300</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ware, P., &amp; Hellmich, E. (2014). CALL in the K–12 context: Language learning outcomes and opportunities. CALICO Journal, 31(2), 140–157. https://doi.org/10.11139/cj.31.2.140-157</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
