<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562375</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Limitations of Two-Stage Turbocharging at High Flight Altitudes</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Fass</surname>
                  <given-names>Yehuda</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tartakovsky</surname>
                  <given-names>Leonid</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Technion Israel Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>5</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562374</issue-id>
         <fpage>511</fpage>
         <lpage>524</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562375"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>High-altitude long-endurance (HALE) unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) are used for high flight altitudes, which enable low drag and fast flight with minimal fuel consumption. Two-stage turbocharging is necessary to sustain sea-level power at high flight altitudes. In this study, the limitations of two-stage turbocharging at high flight altitudes typical for HALE UAVs are analyzed for the first time. The obtained results show that the minimum available engine power increases as the altitude rises. This will limit the ability of the aircraft to descend rapidly. Furthermore, at high altitudes, if a lower operating point is required for a fast descent, further recovery to full power for climbing or cruising could be unavailable. In the latter cases, a lower altitude must be reached before full power would be available again. A basic algorithm for the assessment and analysis of the limitations of UAV engines with two-stage turbochargers operating at high altitudes is suggested.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>UAV engine</kwd> 
            <kwd>High flight altitude</kwd> 
            <kwd>Two-stage turbocharging</kwd> 
            <kwd>Turbocharger energy balance</kwd> 
            <kwd>Power command</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D’Oliveira, F.A., De Melo, F.C.L., and Devezas, T.C., “High- Altitude Platforms - Present Situation and Technology Trends,” Journal of Aerospace Technology and Management 8(3):249-262, 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amiel, R. and Tartakovsky, L., “Effect of Flight Altitude on the Knock Tendency of SI Reciprocating Turbocharged Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2016-32-0006, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-32-0006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiereth, H. and Prenninger, P., Charging the Internal Combustion Engine (Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2007).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tiimus, K., Murumäe, M., Väljaots, E., Tamre, M. et al., “High-Efficiency Internal Combustion Engine Used in the Unmanned Aircraft,” Solid State Phenomena 220(221):928- 933, 2015, http://www.scientific.net/SSP.220-221.928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stone, R., Introduction to Internal Combustion Engines Fourth Edition (Palgrave Macmillan, 2012).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tartakovsky, L., Gutman, M., and Mosyak, A., “Chapter 3: Energy Efficiency of Road Vehicles - Trends and Challenges,” in: Cavalcanti, E.F.S. and Barbosa, M.R. eds., Energy Efficiency: Methods, Limitations and Challenges (Nova Science Publishers, 2012), 63-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ter-Mkrtichian, G.G., Terenchenko, A.S., and Karpukhin, K.E., “Alternative Ways for Vehicle ICE Development,” International Journal of Mechanical Engineering and Technology 9(5):966-973, 2018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Taylor, C.F., The Internal Combustion Engine in Theory and Practice (MIT, 1985).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baines, N.C., Fundamentals of Turbocharging (Vermont: Concepts NREC, 2005).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, J., Zhuge, W., Zheng, X., Zhang, Y. et al., “Investigation of Influence of Two-Stage Turbocharging System on Engine Performance Using a Pre-Design Model,” ASME Turbo Expo, 2013, (55195), V05AT23A014, doi:10.1115/GT2013-94602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Canova, M., Chiara, F., Rizzoni, G., Wang, Y. et al., “Design and Validation of a Control-Oriented Model of a Diesel Engine with Two-Stage Turbocharger,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 2(2):387-397, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodgers, C., “Turbocharging a High Altitude UAV C.I. Engine,” 37th Joint Propulsion Conference and Exhibit. Joint Propulsion Conferences, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, 2001, doi:10.2514/6.2001-3970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bents, D., Mockler, T., Maldonado, J., Harp, J. et al., “Propulsion System for Very High Altitude Subsonic Unmanned Aircraft,” SAE Technical Paper 981261, 1998, doi:10.4271/981261.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Loth, J.L., Morris, G.J., and Metlapalli, P.B., “Staged Turbocharging for High Altitude 1C Engines,” 33rd Joint Propulsion Conference and Exhibit, 1997, 1-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shi, X., Wang, T., and Ma, C., “Simulations of the Diesel Engine Performance with a Two-Stage Sequential Turbocharging System at Different Altitudes,” Journal of Automobile Engineering 228(14):1718-1726, 2014, http://search. ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;site=edslive&amp; db=edb&amp;AN=99724999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Shi, L., and Deng, K., “Research on the Power Recovery of Diesel Engines with Regulated Two-Stage Turbocharging System at Different Altitudes,” International Journal of Rotating Machinery (3):1-10, 2014, http://search. ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;site=edslive&amp; db=a9h&amp;AN=100521118 OP.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, M., Gu, Y., Deng, K., Yang, Z. et al., “Analysis on Altitude Adaptability of Turbocharging Systems for a Heavy- Duty Diesel Engine,” Applied Thermal Engineering 128:1196- 1207, 2018a, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2017.09.065.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yanbin, L., Weilin, Z., Yangjun, Z., Shuyong, Z. et al., “A Matching Method for Two-Stage Turbocharging System,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 137:22604, Feb. 2014, http://gasturbinespower. asmedigitalcollection.asme.org/article. aspx?doi=10.1115/1.4028387.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shan, P., Zhou, Y., and Zhu, D., “Mathematical Model of Two-Stage Turbocharging Gasoline Engine Propeller Propulsion System and Analysis of Its Flying Characteristic,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 137(5):51201, 2015, doi:10.1115/1.4028664.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodgers, C., “The Efficiencies of Single-Stage Centrifugal Compressors for Aircraft Applications,” ASME Turbo Expo, 1991, 1-10.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guzzella, L. and Onder, C., Introduction to Modeling and Control of Internal Combustion Engine Systems (Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2009).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ming-shan, W., Shen-jun, S., and Fa-zhan, P., “Simulation Study of Turbocharging Systems for a Piston Aero-Gasoline Engine,” Transactions of Beijing Institute of Technology 6:652-656, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tancrez, M., Galindo, J., Guardiola, C., Fajardo, P. et al., “Turbine Adapted Maps for Turbocharger Engine Matching,” Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 35(1):146-153, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2010.07.018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, H., Zhang, G., Zhang, H., Shi, L. et al., “Equivalent Matching Model of a Regulated Two-Stage Turbocharging System for the Plateau Adaptability,” Journal of Automobile Engineering 230(12):1654-1669, 2016, http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;site=edslive&amp; db=edb&amp;AN=118145408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yang, M., Gu, Y., Deng, K., Yang, Z. et al., “Influence of Altitude on Two-Stage Turbocharging System in a Heavy- Duty Diesel Engine Based on Analysis of Available Flow Energy,” Applied Thermal Engineering 129:12-21, http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1359431116344684, 2018b.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rozenkranc, M., and Ernst, J., “Tactical Uav Engines Integration in Iai,” 2nd AIAA “Unmanned Unlimited” Systems, Technologies, and Operations - Aerospac, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, San Diego, CA, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, K., Szedlmayer, M.T., Kweon, C.-B.M., Kruger, K. et al., “The Effect of Outside Air Temperature and Cetane Number on Combustion and Performance in a UAV Diesel Engine at Various Altitude Conditions,” 53rd AIAA/SAE/ASEE Joint Propulsion Conference, AIAA Propulsion and Energy Forum, (AIAA 2017-5027), Atlanta, GA, 2017, doi:10.2514/6.2017-5027.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eriksson, L., “Mean Value Models for Exhaust System Temperatures,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0374, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0374.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
