<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308488</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Heavy Duty Particle Measurement Programme (PMP)</article-title>
            <subtitle>Exploratory Work for the Definition of the Test Protocol</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Giechaskiel</surname>
                  <given-names>Barouch</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Transport and Air Quality Unit, Joint Research Centre of the European Commission</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Carriero</surname>
                  <given-names>Massimo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Transport and Air Quality Unit, Joint Research Centre of the European Commission</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Martini</surname>
                  <given-names>Giorgio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Transport and Air Quality Unit, Joint Research Centre of the European Commission</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Jon</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ricardo UK</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1528</fpage>
         <lpage>1546</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308488"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The heavy duty Particle Measurement Programme (PMP) inter-laboratory exercise consists of three parts: 1) the exploratory work to refine the measurement protocol, 2) the validation exercise where each lab will measure the emissions of a “golden” engine with two “golden” particle number systems simultaneously sampling from full and partial flow dilution systems, and 3) the round-robin where the emissions of a “reference” engine will be determined with a lab’s own particle number instrumentation. This paper presents the results of the exploratory work and describes the final protocol for testing in the validation exercise (and round robin) along with the necessary facility modifications required for compliance with the protocol. Key aspects of the protocol (e.g. filter material, flow rates at the full and partial flow systems, the pre-conditioning etc.) are explained and justified. Finally, the results of particle emissions measurements during the World harmonized and the European cycles are given focusing on volatility and the presence of non-volatile materials above and below 23 nm.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">PMP (2003). Report of the GRPE Particle Measurement Programme (PMP): Government Sponsored Work Programmes. Availale at: http://www.unece.org/trans/doc/2003/wp29grpe/TRA NS-WP29-GRPE-specinf01e.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CFR (2001). Code of Federal Regulations Title 40 Part 86 Subpart N – Emission regulations for new otto-cycle and diesel heavy-duty engines; Gaseous and particulate exhaust test procedures (Revised July 1 2001)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson J., Giechaskiel B., Munoz-Bueno R., Sandbach E., Dilara P. (2007). Particle Measurement Programme (PMP): Light-duty interlaboratory correlation exercise (ILCE_LD)-Final report (EUR 22775 EN) GRPE-54-08-Rev.1, available at: http://www.unece.org/trans/main/wp29/wp29wgs/wp 29grpe/grpeinf54.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Dilara P., Andersson J. (2008). Particle Measurement Programme (PMP) light-duty inter-laboratory exercise: Repeatability and reproducibility of the particle number method. Aerosol Sci. Technology, 42, 528-543</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Dilara P., Sandbach E., Andersson J. (2008). Particle Measurement Programme (PMP) light-duty inter-laboratory exercise: Comparison of different particle number measurement systems. Measurement Sci. Technology, 19, 095401</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson J., Clarke D. (2004). UN-GRPE PMP Phase 3: Inter-laboratory correlation exercise: Framework and laboratory guide. Available at: http://www.unece.org/trans/doc/2004/wp29grpe/PM P-2004-13-02e.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson J., Clarke D. (2008). UN-GRPE PMP Phase 3: Inter-laboratory correlation exercise: updated framework and laboratory guide for heavyduty (HD) engine testing. Available at: http://www.unece.org/trans/doc/2008/wp29grpe/PM P-22-04e.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Alessandrini S., Forni F., Martinez- Lozano P., Lesueur D., Carriero M., Martini G. (2008). Particle Measurement Programme (PMP): Heavy-duty (HD) inter-laboratory exercise: Exploratory work at JRC (Oct ’07 – Feb ’08). EU report 23426</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Martinez-Lozano P., Alessandrini S., Forni F., Montigny F., Fumagalli I., Carriero M., Martini G. (2008). Particle Measurement Programme (PMP) Heavy duty (HD) inter-laboratory exercise: Validation exercise tests at JRC (Feb 08). EU report 23496</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reg. 49 – Rev. 4 – Uniform provisions concerning the approval of compression ignition (CI) and natural gas (NG) as well as positive ignition (PI) engines fuelled with liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) and vehicles equipped with CI and NG engines and PI engines fuelled with LPG with regard to the emissions of pollutants by the engine.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei Q., Oestergaard K., Porter S., Asano I, Adachi M., Rahman M. (2006). Real-time measuring system for engine exhaust solid particle number emission – design and performance. SAE 2006-01-0864</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson D. B., Watts W. F., Johnson J. P. (2006). On-road and laboratory evaluation of combustion aerosols. Part1: Summary of diesel engine results. J. Aerosol Sci., 37, 913–930</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rönkkö T., Virtanen A., Kannosto J., Keskinen J., Lappi M., Pirjola L. (2007). Nucleation mode particles with a nonvolatile core in the exhaust of a heavy duty diesel vehicle. Environ. Sci. Technol., 41, 6384–6389</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lähde T., Rönkkö T., Virtanen A., Schuck T. J., Pirjola L., Hämeri K., Kulmala M., Arnold F., Rothe D., Keskinen J. (2009). Heavy Duty diesel engine exhaust aerosol particle and ion measurements. Env. Sci. Technol., 43, 163-168</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ISO16183 Heavy-Duty Engines – Measurement of gaseous emissions from raw exhaust gas and of particulate emissions using partial flow dilution systems under transient test conditions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek I. (2006). 2007 Diesel particulate measurement research. CRC Project E-66 Phase 2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Alessandrini S., Forni F., Carriero M., Krasenbrink A., Spielvogel J., Gerhart C., Wang X., Horn H.G., Southgate J., Jörgl H., Winkler G., Jing L., Kasper M. (2008). Calibration of PMP condensation particle number counters: Effect of material on linearity and counting efficiency. EU report 23495</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Carriero M., Martini G., Krasenbrink A., Scheder D. (2009). Calibration and validation of various commercial particle number measurement systems. SAE 2009-01-1115</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson J., Clarke D., Watson J. (2004). UK Particulate Measurement Programme (PMP): A near US 2007 approach to heavy duty diesel particulate measurements – Comparison with the standard European method. SAE 2004-01-1990</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek I. (2005). 2007 Diesel particulate measurement research. CRC Project E-66 Phase 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek I. (2007). 2007 Diesel particulate measurement research. CRC Project E-66 Phase 3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chase R. E., Duszkiewicz G. J., Richert J. F. O., Lewis D., Maricq M. M., Xu N. (2004). PM measurement artifact: Organic vapor deposition on different filter media. SAE 2004-01-0967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reg. 83 - Rev.3 - Emission of pollutants according to engine fuel requirements, http://www.unece.org/trans/main/wp29/wp29regs81- 100.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Ntziachristos L., Samaras Z., Casati R., Volker S., Rainer V. (2007). Effect of speed and speed transition on the formation of nucleation mode particles from a light duty diesel vehicle. SAE 2007- 01-1110</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vaaraslati K., Keskinen J., Giechaskiel B., Solla A., Murtonen T., Vesala H. (2005). Effect of lubricant on the formation of heavy-duty diesel exhaust nanoparticles. Environ. Sci. Technol. 39, 8497-8504</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Ntziachristos L., Samaras Z. (2004). Calibration and modeling of ejector dilutors for automotive exhaust sampling. Measurement Science &amp; Technology 15:1-8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bernemyr H., ngström H. E. (2007). Number measurements and size dependent volatility study of diesel exhaust particles. SAE 2007-24-0107</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">GTR 4 (2007). Global technical regulation No. 4. Test procedure for compression-ignition (C.I.) engines and positive ignition (P.I.) engines fuelled with natural gas (NG) or liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) with regard to the emission of pollutants. http://www.unece.org/trans/main/wp29/wp29wgs/wp 29gen/wp29registry/ECE-TRANS-180a4e.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Ntziachristos L., Samaras Z., Casati R., Scheer V., Vogt R. (2005). Formation potential of vehicle exhaust nucleation mode particles on-road and in the laboratory. Atmospheric Environment, 39, 3191-3198</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giechaskiel B., Munoz-Bueno R., Rubino L., Manfredi U., Dilara P., De Santi G., Andersson J. (2007). Particle Measurement Programme (PMP): Particle size and number emissions before, during and after regeneration events of a Euro 4 DPF equipped light-duty diesel vehicle. SAE 2007-01- 1944</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D. B., Watts W. F., Johnson J. P., Rowntree, C., Payne M., Goodier S., Warrens C., Preston H., Zink U., Ortiz M., Goersmann C., Twigg M. V., Walker A. P., Caldow R. (2006). On-road evaluation of two Diesel exhaust aftertreatment devices. J. Aerosol Sci., 37, 1140 – 1151</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Biswas S., Hu S., Verma V., Herner J. D., Robertson W. H., Ayala A., Sioutas C. (2008). Physical properties of particulate matter (PM) from late model heavy-duty diesel vehicles operating with advanced PM and NOx emission control technologies. Atmosph. Envir., 42, 5622-5634</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson J. D., Jemma C. A., Bosteels D., Searles R. (2002). Particle emissions from a EU III heavyduty diesel engine with catalyst-based diesel particle filter and selective catalytic reduction system: Size, number, mass &amp; chemistry. 11th Aachen Colloquium On Vehicle &amp; Engine Technology, 2002</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek I., Kittelson D. B., Brear F. (2000). Nanoparticle growth during dilution and cooling of diesel exhaust: Experimental investigation and theoretical assessment. SAE 2000-01-0515</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vouitsis E., Ntziachristos L., Samaras Z. (2005). Modeling of diesel exhaust aerosol during laboratory sampling. Atmospheric Environment, 39, 1335–1345</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herner J. D., Robertson W. H., Ayala A. (2007). Investigation of ultrafine particle number measurements from a clean diesel truck using the European PMP protocol. SAE 2007-01-1114</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayala A., Herner J. D. (2005). Transient ultrafine particle emission measurements with a new fast particle aerosol sizer for a trap equipped diesel truck. SAE 2005-01-3800</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
