<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">83</volume>
         <issue-id>i40198794</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44723986</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Impact Tolerance and Response of the Human Thorax II</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Charles K.</given-names>
                  <surname>Kroell</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dennis C.</given-names>
                  <surname>Schneider</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alan M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Nahum</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1974</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>3724</fpage>
         <lpage>3762</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc. 1976</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44723986"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Previous studies of human thoracic injury tolerance and mechanical response to blunt, midsternal, anteroposterior impact loading were reported by the authors at the 1970 SAE International Automobile Safety Conference and at the Fifteenth Stapp Car Crash Conference. The present paper documents additional studies from this continuing research program and provides an expansion and refinement of the data base established by the earlier work. Twenty-three additional unembalmed cadavers were tested using basically the same equipment and procedures reported previously, but for which new combinations of impactor mass and velocity were used in addition to supplementing other data already presented. Specifically, the 43 lb/11 mph (19.5 kg/4.9m/s) and 51 lb/16 mph (23.1 kg/7.2 m/s) conditions were intercrossed and data obtained at 43 lb/16 mph (19.5 kg/7.2 m/s) and 51 lb/11 mph (23.1 kg/4.9 m/s). Several additional tests were run at 22 mph (9.8 m/s) and confirm a strong velocity sensitivity of the force response throughout the velocity range investigated. Also included are several tests in which the cadaver subjects were rigidly supported midsagittally along the spine to preclude whole body motion. Finally, the kinematics of thoracic compression under blunt, A-P impact have been demonstrated by high-speed cinematography of a thorax unilaterally denuded of skin and superficial tissues to enable visualization of the rib surfaces and intercostal musculature during loading. Response in terms of force-time and deflection-time histories and force versus deflection crossplots, and tolerance in terms of associated necropsy findings and AIS ratings, are presented for all tests. Correlations of the AIS rating with both maximum force and normalized chest deflection, several composite summary plots, and a general data tabulation are also included.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d400e385a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d400e392" publication-type="other">
A. M. Nahum, C. W. Gadd, D. C. Schneider, and C. K.
Kroell, "Deflection of the Human Thorax Under Sternal
Impact." Paper No. 700400 presented at SAE International
Automobile Safety Conference, Detroit, May 1970.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d400e408a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d400e415" publication-type="other">
C. K. Kroell, D. C. Schneider, and A. M. Nahum, "Im-
pact Tolerance and Response of the Human Thorax." Paper
71085 1, Proceedings of Fifteenth Stapp Car Crash Conference,
P-39. New York: Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.,
1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d400e434a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d400e441" publication-type="other">
T. E. Lobdell, C. K. Kroell, D. C. Schneider, W. E. Hering,
and A. M. Nahum, "Impact Response of the Human Thorax."
"Human Impact Response-Measurement and Simulation."
Proceedings of Symposium at General Motors Research Lab-
oratories, Oct. 2, 3, 1972, edited by W. F. King and H. J.
Mertz, London: Plenum Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d400e464a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
          
            <mixed-citation id="d400e473" publication-type="other">
J. M. States, H. J. Fenner, Jr., E. E. Flamboe, W. D.
Nelson, and L. N. Hames, "Field Application and Research
Development of the Abbreviated Injury Scale." Paper
710873, Proceedings of Fifteenth Stapp Car Crash Con-
ference, P-39. New York: Society of Automotive Engineers,
Inc., 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d400e497a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d400e504" publication-type="other">
C. K. Kroell, C. W. Gadd, and D. C. Schneider, "Bio-
mechanics in Crash Injury Research." Proceedings of Nine-
teenth International Instrument Society of America Aerospace
Instrumentation Symposium, 1973.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d400e520a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d400e527" publication-type="other">
D. L. Beckman and B. A. Friedman, "Mechanics of
Cardiothoracic Injury in Primates." Jrl. Trauma, Vol. 12,
No. 7, July 1972.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d400e540a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d400e547" publication-type="other">
R. F. Neathery, "An Analysis of Chest Impact Response
Data and Scaled Performance Recommendations." Paper
741 188, Proceedings of Eighteenth Stapp Car Crash Confer-
ence, P-56. Warrendale, Pa.: Society of Automotive Engin-
eers, Inc., 1974.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


