<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277843</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optimization of LNT-SCR Dual-Layer Catalysts for Diesel NOₓ Emission Control</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zheng</surname>
                  <given-names>Yang</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Luss</surname>
                  <given-names>Dan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Harold</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Houston</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>August 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277829</issue-id>
         <fpage>1280</fpage>
         <lpage>1289</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277843"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Monolithic catalysts consisting of a layer of SCR catalyst deposited on top of a LNT catalyst were optimized to provide high NOₓ conversion at both low and high temperatures with minimal precious group metal (PGM) loading for effective diesel NOₓ emission control. In this study we demonstrate the application of LNT &amp; SCR zoning in dual-layer catalyst to improve NOₓ reduction efficiency and show the potential to reduce the expensive PGM loading by up to 40% from that of LNT only catalyst without degrading its deNOₓ performance under simulated diesel exhaust conditions. We investigated the NOₓ reduction pathway in the SCR layer of the dual-layer catalyst using simulated rich exhaust of C₃H₆/CO/H₂ as reductants. The non-NH₃ reduction pathway by N-containing organic intermediates via the synergy of LNT and SCR catalysts can play a major role in the incremental NOₓ conversion over SCR layer at low temperatures (&lt;= 225 °C). The roles of NH₃ and C₃H₆ as reductants for NOₓ conversion over the SCR catalyst increase with temperature (&gt; 225 °C). The impact of SCR and LNT zoning as well as SCR layer thickness, were studied. Zoning of either or both the SCR and LNT in the dual-layer catalysts improved the low-temperature NOₓ conversion, and minimized the high-temperature (300-400 °C) conversion loss caused by the SCR layer diffusion resistance and undesired NH₃ oxidation. The performance decline due to the Cu-zeolite layer diffusion resistance was confirmed by replacing it with an inert Na-zeolite layer with a high Si/Al ratio.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maunula, T., “Intensification of Catalytic Aftertreatments Systems for Mobile Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0530, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Theis, J., Dearth, M., and McCabe, R., “LNT+SCR Catalyst Systems Optimized for NOx Conversion on Diesel Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0305, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01- 0305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, L., McCabe, R., Ruona, W., and Cavataio, G., “Impact of a Cu-zeolite SCR Catalyst on the Performance of a Diesel LNT+SCR System,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0285, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, L., McCabe, R., Dearth, M., and Ruona, W., “Laboratory and Vehicle Demonstration of “2nd-Generation” LNT + in-situ SCR Diesel NOx Emission Control Systems,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):37-49, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0305.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCarthy, Jr., J., Dykes, E., Ngan, E., and Strots, V., “Aftertreatment System Performance of a Fuel Reformer, LNT and SCR System Meeting EPA 2010 Emissions Standards on a Heavy- Duty Vehicle,” SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 3(1):130-142, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1942.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsuo, Y., Ishimaru, S., Amano, M., Komatsu, N. et al., “Development of Highly Efficient Lean NOx Catalyst System in Low Exhaust Gas Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0536, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0536.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Y., Zheng, Y., Harold, M.P., and Luss, D., “Lean NOx Reduction on LNT-SCR Dual-Layer Catalysts by H2 and CO,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 132:293-303, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Waldbuesser, N., Guenther, J., Hoffmann, H., Erlenmayer, O. et al., “Specifics of Daimler's new SCR system (BLUETEC) in the Diesel Sprinter Van - Certified for NAFTA 2010,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-1172, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, L., McCabe, R., Tennison, P., and Jen, H., “Laboratory and Vehicle Demonstration of “2nd-Generation” LNT + in-situ SCR Diesel Emission Control Systems,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):158- 174, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0308.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morita, T., Suzuki, N., Satoh, N., Wada, K. et al., “Study on Low NOX Emission Control Using Newly Developed Lean NOX Catalyst for Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0239, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koltsakis, G., Haralampous, O., and Koutoufaris, I., “Applications of Multi-layer Catalyst Modeling in deNOx and DPF Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0893, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0893.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, Y., Zheng, Y., Harold, M.P., and Luss, D., “Lean NOx Reduction with H2 and CO in Dual-Layer LNT-SCR Monolithic Catalysts: Impact of Ceria Loading,” Top. Catal. 56(1-8):104-108, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, Y., Liu, Y., Harold, M.P., and Luss, D., “LNT-SCR Dual- Layer Catalysts Optimized for Lean NOx Reduction by H2 and CO,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 148-149:311-321, 2014. doi:10.1016/j.apcatb.2013.11.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Harbi, M., Radtke, D. Epling, W.S., “Regeneration of A Model NOx Strorage/Reduction Catalyst Using Hydrocarbons as The Reductant,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 96(3):524-532, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, J., Ji, Y., He, Z.W., Crocker, M. et al., “A Non-NH3 Pathway for NOx Conversion in Coupled LNT-SCR Systems,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 111-112: 562-570, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gorce, O., Baudin, F., Thomas, C., Da Costa, P. et al., “On The Role of Organic Nitrogen-Containing Species as Intermediates in The Hydrocarbon-Assisted SCR of NOx,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 54:69-84, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burch, R., Breen, J.P., Meunier, F.C., “A Review of The Selective Reducation of NOx with Hydrocarbons under Lean-Burn Conditions with Non-Zeolitic Oxide and Platinum Group Metal Catalysts,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 39:283-303, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H.Y., Voskoboinikov, T., Sachtler, W.M.H., “Reduction of NOx over Fe/ZSM-5 Catalysts: Adsorption Complexes and Their Reactivity toward Hydrocarbons,” J. Catal. 180:171-183, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, H.Y., Voskoboinikov, T., Sachtler, W.M.H., “Reaction Intermediates in the Selective Catalytic Reduction of NOx over Fe/ZSM-5,” J. Catal. 186:91-99, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adelman, B.J., Beutle, T., Lei, G.D., Sachtler, W.M.H., “On the mechanism of selective NOx reduction with alkanes over Cu/ZSM- 5,” Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 11(1):1-9, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zuzaniuk, V., Meunier, F.C., Ross, J.R.H., “Differences in the Reactivity of Organo-Nitro and Nitrito Compounds over Al2O3- Based Catalysts Active for the Selective Reduction of NOx,” J. Catal. 202(2):340-353, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dasari, P., Muncrief, R., Harold, M.P., “Cyclic Lean Reduction of NO by CO in Excess H2O on Pt-Rh/Ba/Al2O3: Elucidating Mechanistic Features and Catalyst Performance,” Top. Catal. 56:1922-1936, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shakya, B.M., Harold, M.P., Balakotaiah, V., “Modeling and Analysis of Dual-layer NOx Storage and Reduction and Selective Catalytic Reduction Monolithic Catalyst,” Chem. Eng. J., 2013, doi:10.1016/j.cej.2013.10.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Theis, J., Lupescu, J., Ura, J., and McCabe, R., “Lean NOx Trap System Design for Cost Reduction and Performance Improvement,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1069, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-1069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Posada, F., Bandivadekar, A., and German, J., “Estimated Cost of Emission Control Technologies for Light-Duty Vehicles Part 2 - Diesel,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0539, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0539.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Platinum market cost data were obtained from Platinum Today, http://www.platinum.matthey.com/(last observed September 2013).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Collins, N., Cooper, J., Morris, D., Ravenscroft, A. et al., “Advanced Three-Way Catalysts - Optimisation by Targeted Zoning of Precious Metal,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2158, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
