<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i23027493</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23027502</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CREDIT SUPPLY, MONETARY POLICY AND STRUCTURAL ADJUSTMENT IN GHANA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
                  <surname>Brownbridge</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>155</fpage>
         <lpage>175</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23027502"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Structural adjustment programmes in sub-Saharan Africa aim to provide incentives to stimulate an expansion of the private sector in production and trade. If the private sector is to respond positively to these incentives, it is likely to require an increase in the supply of bank credit to finance fixed and working capital expenditures. An expansion of bank credit may however face a number of institutional and policy related constraints. This paper explores these issues by examining the impact of structural adjustment on credit markets in Ghana. Beginning in 1983, Ghana has implemented a wide ranging SAP which has included reductions in government domestic borrowing, measures to boost financial savings through higher interest rates, and other financial market reforms. Despite these reforms there was only a small increase in real terms, from a very low base, in private sector borrowing from domestic banks during the SAP. Credit shortages were reported by private sector firms to be serious constraint on their expansion, and are likely to have contributed to the very weak response of private investment to the SAP reforms. The principal constraint on a more vigorous increase in private sector borrowing was the credit ceilings applied by the Bank of Ghana to the banks as part of its strategy to control inflation. The impact of monetary policy restrictions on private borrowing was exacerbated by the large proportion of non performing loans in the portfolios of banks, the lack alternative sources of finance for firms other than bank loans, and the rise in the cost of capital and intermediate goods as a consequence of exchange rate devaluation. The experience of Ghana illustrates the difficulties involved in providing adequate finance to support private sector investment while at the same time maintaining macroeconomic stability in the context of very poorly developed financial markets. Les programmes d'ajustement en Afrique sub-Saharienne visent à encourager le développement du secteur privé en matière de production et de commerce. Si le secteur privé devait réserver un accueil à ces encouragements, il est probable qu'une augmentation des possibilité de prêt bancaire pour financer les dépenses de fonctionnement serait exigée. Toutefois, l'expansion du crédit bancaire pourrait se heurter à des contraintes d'ordre institutionnel liées aux politiques. Ces questions sont étudiées dans ce document, se fondant sur l'impact de l'ajustement structurel sur les marchés financiers du Ghana. Au début 1983, le Ghana a mis en oeuvre toute une série de programmes d'ajustement structurel, notamment en ce qui concerne la baisse de l'emprunt public intérieur, les mesures de renforcement de l'épargne à travers des taux d'intérêt plus élevés, et les réformes des marchés financiers. Malgré ces réformes, et durant l'application de ces programmes, il ne s'est produit qu'une petite augmentation en termes réels, partant d'une base très faible, des emprunts effectués par le secteur privé auprès des banques locales. Selon les entreprises du secteur privé, la pénurie de capitaux représente una sérieuse entrave à leur développement et il est probable que cela ait contribué au manque de réaction des investisseurs privés quant aux orientations des programmes d'ajustment structurel. Les plafonds du crédit imposés par la Banque du Ghana aux banques locales pour contrôler l'inflation a été la principale contrainte à une augmentation plus conséquente des emprunts du secteur privé. L'impact des mesures de restriction monétaire sur les emprunts du secteur privé a été aggravé, pour una large part, par l'insolvabilité des encours de prêts bancaires, le manque d'options financières des entreprises autres que les prêts bancaires, et l'augmentation du coût du capital et des produits semi-finis, consequence de la dévaluation du taux de change. L'expérience du Ghana montre les difficultés rencontrées dans la fourniture de financements adéquats pour soutenir les investissements du secteur privé et dans le maintien de la stabilité macroeconomique dans le contexte de marchés financiers sous-développés.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d764e144a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d764e151" publication-type="other">
Aryeetey,
Asante, Kyei and Gockel (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d764e161a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d764e168" publication-type="other">
World
Bank, 1986: 33-35</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d764e178a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d764e185" publication-type="other">
Kapur et al (1991:48)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d764e192a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d764e201" publication-type="other">
World Bank, 1991:38-45</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d764e207" publication-type="other">
Baah-Nuakoh and Teal, 1993</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d764e214" publication-type="other">
Steel and Webster (1992)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d764e222a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d764e229" publication-type="other">
IMF, 1989B, 88-90</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d764e245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e249" publication-type="other">
Abbey, JLS, "Ghana's Experience with Structural Adjustment: Some lessons", in Pickett James and Hans Singer
(eds), Towards Economic Recovery in Sub-Saharan Africa, Routledge, London, 1990, pp. 32-42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e259a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e263" publication-type="other">
Aryeetey, E, E Asante, A Kyei and F Gockel, "Mobilizing Domestic Savings for African Development and
Diversification: A Ghanaian Case-Study", Research Report Presented at a Workshop on Domestic
Resource Mobilisation at the International Development Centre, Queen Elizabeth House, University of
Oxford, 1990.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e279a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e283" publication-type="other">
Baah-Nuakoh, Amoah and Francis Teal, (eds) "Economic Reform and the Manufacturing Sector in Ghana, Final
Report", The Africa Regional Program of Enterprise Development, World Bank, Washington DC, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e297" publication-type="other">
Bank of Ghana, Annual Reports, Bank of Ghana, Accra, 1985, 1986, 1987, 1989/90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e305a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e309" publication-type="other">
Beckerman, Paul, "The Consequences of 'Upward Financial Repression"', International Review of Applied
Economics, Vol 2, N° 2, 1988, pp. 232-249.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e319a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e323" publication-type="other">
Bhatt, VV, "On Financial Sector Reform and Development: A Case Study of Ghana", African Review of Money,
Finance and Banking, 1/93, 1993, pp. 5-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e333a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e337" publication-type="other">
Fry, Maxwell J, Money Interest, and Banking in Economic Development, John Hopkins University Press, Baltimore, 1988.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e344a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e348" publication-type="other">
Giovannini, Alberto, "The Interest Elasticity of Savings in Developing Countries: The Existing Evidence", World
Development, Vol 11, N° 7, 1983, pp. 601-607.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e358a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e362" publication-type="other">
Harvey, Charles, "The Role of Commercial Banking in Recovery from Economic Disaster in Ghana, Tiziana, Uganda
and Zambia", IDS Discussion Paper 325, IDS, Sussex, 1993.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e372a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e376" publication-type="other">
Hutchful, Eboe, "From Revolution to Monetarism in Ghana", in Campbell, Bonnie K and John Loxley (eds), Structural
Adjustment in Africa, MacMillan, Basingstoke, 1989, pp. 92-131.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e387a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e391" publication-type="other">
Institute of Statistical, Social and Economic Research (ISSER), The State of the Ghanaian Economy in 1991,
ISSER, University of Ghana, Accra, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e401a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e405" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund, "Theoretical Aspects of the Design of Fund-Supported Adjustment Programs",
Occasional Paper 55, International Monetary Fund, Washington DC, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e415a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e419" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund, "Ghana - Staff Report for the Midterm Review of the First Annual Arrangement Under
the Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility", International Monerary Fund, Washington DC, 1989A.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e429a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e433" publication-type="other">
International Monetary Fund, "Monetary Management in Ghana", Central Banking Department, International
Monetary Fund, Washington DC, 1989B.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e443a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e447" publication-type="other">
Islam, Roumeen and Deborah L Wetzel, "The Macroeconomics of Public Sector Deficits", Policy, Research and
External Affairs Working Papers, WPS 672, World Bank, Washington DC. 1991</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e457a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e461" publication-type="other">
Jaffee, Dwight and Joseph Stiglitz, "Credit Rationing", in Friedman, Benjamin M and Frank H. Hahn (eds) Handbook
of Monetary Economics, Vol 11, North Holland, Amsterdam, 1990, pp. 837-888.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e472a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e476" publication-type="other">
Kapur, Ishan, Michael T Hadjimichael, Paul Hilbers, Jerald Schiff, and Philippe Szymczak, "Ghana: Adjustment and
Growth 1983-91", Occasional Paper N° 86, International Monetary Fund, Washington DC, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e486a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e490" publication-type="other">
Kusi, Newman Kwadwo, "Macroeconomic Adjustment, Economic Growth and the Balance of Payments in Ghana,
1983-88", Journal of International Development, Vol 4, N° 5, 1992, pp. 541-559.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e500a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e504" publication-type="other">
Leith, J Clark, Foreign Trade Regimes and Economic Development: Ghana, National Bureau of Economic
Research, Columbia University Press, New York, 1974.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e514a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e518" publication-type="other">
Nissanke, Machiko, "Theoretical Issues in Finance and Development: A Critical Literature Survey", Queen Elizabeth
House Development Studies Working Paper N° 36, Oxford 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e528a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e532" publication-type="other">
Repubblic of Ghana, Statistical Service, Quarterly Digest of Statistics, Government of Ghana, Accra, various years.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e539a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e543" publication-type="other">
Roe, Alan R, "High Interest Rates: A New Conventional Wisdom for Development Policy? Some Conclusions from
Sri Lanka Experience", World Development, Vol 10, N° 3, 1982, pp. 211-222.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e558" publication-type="other">
Sowa, Nii K, "Monetary Control in Ghana 1957-1988", ODI Working Paper 45, Overseas Development Institute,
London,1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e568a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e572" publication-type="other">
Steel, William F and Leila M Webster, "How Small Enterprises in Ghana have Responded to Adjustment", The World
Bank Economic Hewiev, Vol 6, N° 3,1992, pp. 423-438.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e582a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e586" publication-type="other">
Taylor, Lance, Structuralist Macroeconomics: Applicable Models for the Third World, Basic Books, New York, 1983.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e593a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e597" publication-type="other">
Wetzel, Deborah L, "Temporary Trade Shocks in Developing Countries: A Case Study of the Ghanaian Cocoa
Boom", mimeo, Centre for the Study of African Economies, Oxford, 1992.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e607a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e611" publication-type="other">
World Bank, Ghana, Policies and Program for Adjustment,</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e618a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e622" publication-type="other">
World Bank, Washington DC, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e630a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e634" publication-type="other">
World Bank, "Ghana: Financial Sector Review, World Bank, Washington DC, 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e641a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e645" publication-type="other">
World Bank, World Development Report, World Bank, Washington DC, 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e652a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e656" publication-type="other">
World Bank, Ghana Progress on Adjustment World Bank, Washington DC, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e663a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e667" publication-type="other">
World Bank, Ghana Financial Sector Review: Bringing Savers and Investors Together, World Bank, Washington
DC, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d764e677a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d764e681" publication-type="other">
Younger, Stephen D, "Aid and the Dutch Disease: Macroeconomic Management When Everybody Loves You",
World Development, Vol 20, N° 11, 1992, pp. 1587-1597.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


