<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26897928</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Eleven Instrumented Motorcycle Crash Tests and Development of Updated Motorcycle Impact-Speed Equations</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Peck</surname>
                  <given-names>Louis</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Manning</surname>
                  <given-names>Joseph</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bartlett</surname>
                  <given-names>Wade</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dickerson</surname>
                  <given-names>Charles</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Deyerl</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>


         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26897924</issue-id>
         <fpage>41</fpage>
         <lpage>68</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26897928"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Eleven instrumented crash tests were performed as part of the 2016 World Reconstruction Exposition (WREX2016), using seven Harley-Davidson motorcycles and three automobiles. For all tests, the automobile was stationary while the motorcycle was delivered into the vehicle, while upright with tires rolling, at varying speeds. Seven tests were performed at speeds between 30 and 46 mph while four low-speed tests were performed to establish the onset of permanent motorcycle deformation. Data from these tests, and other published testing, was analyzed using previously published equations to determine their accuracy when predicting the impact speed of Harley-Davidson motorcycles. The most accurate model was the Modifi ed Eubanks set of equations introduced in 2009, producing errors with an average of 0.4 mph and a standard deviation (SD) of 4.8 mph.</p> 
            <p>An updated set of Eubanks-style equations were developed adding data published since 2009, and further partitioning from two equations (pillars/axles and doors/fenders) to four equations (axles, pillars/bumpers, doors, and fenders). When applied to the subject tests, the newly developed set of equations produced an average error of 3.5 mph (SD = 4.3 mph). With respect to all available data (<italic>N</italic> = 99), the equations produced an average error of 0.1 mph and an SD of 5.8 mph. The errors were also analyzed for each of the four equations developed here, and confidence intervals offered. This research, which represents the first detailed analysis of Harley-Davidson motorcycles’ collision response, indicates they behave in a manner similar to previously tested motorcycles. Further, the equations developed and presented here give accident investigators a refined method for estimating the impact speed of an upright motorcycle, Harley-Davidson or otherwise, having struck an automobile with its front tire.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Jiang, T., Grzebieta, R.H., Rechnitzer, G., Richardson, S. et al., “Review of Car Frontal Stiffness Equations for Estimating Vehicle Impact Velocities,” in The 18th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles Proceedings, Nagoya, Japan, May 19-22, DOT HS 809 543, 2003 (accessed online at http://www.nrd.nhtsa.dot.gov/pdf/esv/esv18/CD/proceed/00192.pdf, August 12, 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Severy, D., Brink, H., and Blaisdell, D., “Motorcycle Collision Experiments,” SAE Technical Paper 700897, 1970, doi:10.4271/700897.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Grandel, J. and Zeisberger, H., “New Findings Providing Ways to Reconstruct Cycle/Passenger Car Accidents through Experimental Determination of Vehicle Deformation Energies,” in 29th Annual AAAM Proceedings, Washington, DC, Oct. 7-9, 1985, 243-254.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Adamson, K., Alexander, P., Robinson, E., Johnson, G. et al., “Seventeen Motorcycle Crash Tests into Vehicles and a Barrier,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0551, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0551.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Deyerl, E. and Cheng, L., “Computer Simulation of Staged Motorcycle-Vehicle Collisions Using EDSMAC4,” Accident Reconstruction Journal, July/Aug. 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Warner, M. and Nordhagen, R., “Development of Pole Impact Testing at Multiple Vehicle Side Locations as Applied to the Ford Taurus Structural Platform,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0062, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0062.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bartlett, W., “Motorcycle Crush Analysis,” Accident Reconstruction Journal, Mar./Apr. 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Eubanks, J., “Motorcycle Speed-from-Damage Estimates Update,” Society ofAccident Reconstruction 22 , Oct. 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Wo1od, D., Glynn, C., and Walsh, D., “Motorcycle-to-Car and Scooter-to-Car Collisions: Speed Estimation from Permanent Deformation,” in Proc. IMechE Vol. 223 Part D: J. Automobile Engineering, 2009, 737-756, 10.1243/09544070JAUT01069.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Wood, D., Glynn, C., O’Dea, C., and Walsh, D., “Physical and Empirical Models for Motorcycle Speed Estimation from Crush,” International Journal of Crashworthiness 19(5): 540 -554 , 2014, doi:10.1080/13588265.2014.918300 .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Glynn, C. and Wood, D., “Collision Speed from Individual Vehicle Deformation in Motorcycle to Car Collisions,” in Proc. of the EVU, 23. EVU Conference, Copenhagen , 2014 .</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Searle, J., “The Reconstruction of Speed in Motorcycle Collisions from the Extent of Damage,” IMPACT, Journal of the ITAI, Kent, UK, Spring, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Bartlett, W., “Evaluating Motorcycle Speed from Crush Damage Using the Searle Method,” IMPACT, Journal of the ITAI, Spring, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Harley-Davidson, “Historical Shipments, Retail Sales, MSRP, and Dealerships,” http://investor.harley-davidson.com/phoenix.zhtml?c=87981&amp;p=irol-factbook, accessed Aug. 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c15">CloudCompare (version 2.7.0), EDF R&amp;D, Telecom ParisTech, 2016, retrieved from http://www.cloudcompare.org/release/http://www.cloudcompare.org/release/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Erickson, M.S., Bauer, J.J., and Hayes, W.C., “The Accuracy of Photo-Based Three­Dimensional Scanning for Collision Reconstruction Using 123D Catch,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0784, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0784.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Details of motorcycles and automobiles used during the subject tests. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 1</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>2013 Harley-Davidson Softail Breakout (M1) prepared for testing and being weighed using digital scales. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>2013 Dyna Street Bob (M2) attached to the custom delivery system. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Example of motorcycle speed trace acquired from VBOX Sport mounted to the rear of M1 during Test 3. Note the decrease in speed as the motorcycle releases from the delivery system (9.5 s), and subsequent increase as the rear of the motorcycle rotates upward upon impact (11.8 s). © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Upper image: postimpact 3-D scan data of the 2006 Nissan Maxima (C1). Lower image: compilation of pre- and post-impact scan data, merged using CloudCompare. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Color-coded output from CloudCompare, showing the distance between the pre- and post-impact point clouds, where blue is the shortest distance and red is the largest. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 2</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Summary of full-speed tests where MC identifies the involved motorcycle, TV identifies the involved target vehicle, L is the wheelbase reduction, and C is the maximum deformation to the target vehicle. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Example of low-speed test impact configuration and behavior. Here, first contact and maximum engagement are shown for the 7.1 mph test. Notice the trailing edge of the front fender is contacting the leading portion of the frame and the rear tire is lifted of the ground. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 7</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Right-side view of C1 showing the impact damage sustained during Test 3, where the maximum crush was 18.7 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 8</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Right-side view of M1 showing damage sustained during Test 3, where the wheelbase reduction was 11.3 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 9</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Left-side view of C1 showing the impact damage sustained during Test 5, where the maximum crush was 8.6in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 10</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Left-side view of M2 showing damage sustained during Test 5, where the wheelbase reduction was 12.8 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 11</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Left rear view of C2 showing damage sustained during Test 8, where the maximum crush was 9.1 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 12</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Left-side view of M3 showing damage sustained during Test 8, where the documented wheelbase reduction was 3.3 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 13</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>Right-side view of C2 showing damage sustained during Test 11, where the maximum crush was 10.3 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 14</label>
         <caption id="ca-16">
            <p>Left-side view of M4 showing damage sustained during Test 11, where the documented wheelbase reduction was 10.7 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 15</label>
         <caption id="ca-17">
            <p>Right rear view of C3 showing damage sustained during Test 22, where the maximum crush was 2.1 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 16</label>
         <caption id="ca-18">
            <p>Right-side view of M5 showing damage sustained during Test 22, where the documented wheelbase reduction was 4.3 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 17</label>
         <caption id="ca-19">
            <p>Right-side view of C3 showing damage sustained during Test 23, where the maximum crush was 7.1 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 18</label>
         <caption id="ca-20">
            <p>Right-side view of M6 showing damage sustained during Test 23, where the documented wheelbase reduction was 8.8 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 19</label>
         <caption id="ca-21">
            <p>Right-side view of C3 showing damage sustained during Test 24, where the maximum crush was 4.2 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 20</label>
         <caption id="ca-22">
            <p>Right-side view of M7 showing damage sustained during Test 24, where the documented wheelbase reduction was 8.9 in. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 3</label>
         <caption id="ca-23">
            <p>Motorcycles and automobiles used during the ARC-CSI 2016 testing. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 4</label>
         <caption id="ca-24">
            <p>Summary of the ARC-CSI 2016 Harley-Davidson testing results. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 21</label>
         <caption id="ca-25">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to the Severy model. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 22</label>
         <caption id="ca-26">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to the Adamson wheelbase-only model. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 23</label>
         <caption id="ca-27">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to the Adamson total crush model © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 24</label>
         <caption id="ca-28">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to Bartlett’s Modified Eubanks model. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 25</label>
         <caption id="ca-29">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to Wood’s 2014 model. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 26</label>
         <caption id="ca-30">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to Glynn’s car-alone model. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 27</label>
         <caption id="ca-31">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to Glynn’s motorcycle-alone model. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 28</label>
         <caption id="ca-32">
            <p>WREX2016 and ARC-CSI 2016 data compared to the modified Searle model. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 5</label>
         <caption id="ca-33">
            <p>Statistical summary of each model’s fit relative to the subject Harley-Davidson data. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 29</label>
         <caption id="ca-34">
            <p>Test data vs. the MB axle equation including 68% and 95% confidence intervals. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 30</label>
         <caption id="ca-35">
            <p>Test data vs. the MB bumper/pillar equation including 68% and 95% confidence intervals. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 31</label>
         <caption id="ca-36">
            <p>Test data vs. the MB door equation, including 68% and 95% confidence intervals. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 32</label>
         <caption id="ca-37">
            <p>Test data vs. the MB fender equation including 68% and 95% confidence intervals. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>TABLE 6</label>
         <caption id="ca-38">
            <p>Average error and SD for each of the MB equations. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>FIGURE 33</label>
         <caption id="ca-39">
            <p>Damage to the right door/pillar area of the Hyundai sustained during Test 23. © 2019 SAE International. All Rights Reserved</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A -</label>
         <caption id="ca-40">
            <p>Test 3 Photographs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A -</label>
         <caption id="ca-41">
            <p>Test 5 Photographs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A -</label>
         <caption id="ca-42">
            <p>Test 8 Photographs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A -</label>
         <caption id="ca-43">
            <p>Test 11 Photographs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A -</label>
         <caption id="ca-44">
            <p>Test 22 Photographs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A -</label>
         <caption id="ca-45">
            <p>Test 23 Photographs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix A -</label>
         <caption id="ca-46">
            <p>Test 24 Photographs</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix B -</label>
         <caption id="ca-47">
            <p>Source Data</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
