<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186500</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44437732</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Dr. Abbott's Paper on Sound Measurements in Automotive-Noise Reduction Discussed</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1934</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>336</fpage>
         <lpage>343</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44437732"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>THE paper was published in the August, 1934, issue of the S.A.E. Journal, pages 271 to 287. It expressed the desirability of measuring sound by soundmeter rather than by listening with the human ear, since soundmeter measurements indicate definitely just what components of noises must be reduced and also just what has been accomplished by any given change. In the following discussion of the paper resonance noises are cited as a cause of complaints, a direct method of sound analysis is recommended, and emphasis is placed on having acoustical data interpreted by experienced observers. It is stated and enlarged upon that the two aspects of automotive-noise reduction—the use of acoustical aids to locate weaknesses in manufacture and to locate sounds which annoy the customer—require separate consideration. Noise-elimination materials are cited and commented upon, riding-comfort and noise-problem treatment is analyzed, the time element is emphasized as an important factor of sound analysis, and the term "audibel" is suggested as a substitute for the term "weighted sound-pressure level."</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


