<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285068</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Modeling Non-Premixed Combustion Using Tabulated Kinetics and Different Fame Structure Assumptions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Lucchini</surname>
                  <given-names>Tommaso</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>D'Errico</surname>
                  <given-names>Gianluca</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Onorati</surname>
                  <given-names>Angelo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Frassoldati</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Stagni</surname>
                  <given-names>Alessandro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Politecnico di Milano</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Hardy</surname>
                  <given-names>Gilles</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FPT Motorenforschung AG</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>593</fpage>
         <lpage>607</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285068"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Nowadays, detailed kinetics is necessary for a proper estimation of both flame structure and pollutant formation in compression ignition engines. However, large mechanisms and the need to include turbulence/chemistry interaction introduce significant computational overheads. For this reason, tabulated kinetics is employed as a possible solution to reduce the CPU time even if table discretization is generally limited by memory occupation. In this work the authors applied tabulated homogeneous reactors (HR) in combination with different turbulent-chemistry interaction approaches to model non-premixed turbulent combustion. The proposed methodologies represent good compromises between accuracy, required memory and computational time. The experimental validation was carried out by considering both constant-volume vessel and Diesel engine experiments. First, the ECN Spray A configuration was simulated at different operating conditions and results from different flame structures are compared with experimental data of ignition delay, flame lift-off, heat release rates, radicals and soot distributions. Afterwards, engine simulations were carried out and computed data are validated by cylinder pressure and heat release rate profiles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Funayama, Y., Nakajima, H., and Shimokawa, K., "A Study on the Effects of a Higher Compression Ratio in the Combustion Chamber on Diesel Engine Performance," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0722, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016-01-0722.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hashimoto, M., Aoyagi, Y., Kobayashi, M., Murayama, T. et al., "BSFC Improvement and NOx Reduction by Sequential Turbo System in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0712, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0712.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flynn, P., Durrett, R., Hunter, G., zur Loye, A. et al., "Diesel Combustion: An Integrated View Combining Laser Diagnostics, Chemical Kinetics, And Empirical Validation," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0509, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., "Mixing Process in High Pressure Diesel Jets by Normalized Laser Induced Exciplex Fluorescence Part I: Free Jet," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2100, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D’Errico G., Lucchini T., Contino F., Jangi M., and Bai X.-S.. Comparison of well-mixed and multiple representative interactive flamelet approaches for diesel spray combustion modelling. Combustion Theory and Modelling, 18(1):65-88, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pei Y., Hawkes E. R., and Kook S.. Transported probability density function modelling of the vapour phase of an n-heptane jet at diesel engine conditions. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 34(2):3039 - 3047, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barths H., Hasse C., and Peters N.. Computational fluid dynamics modelling of non-premixed combustion in direct injection diesel engines. International Journal of Engine Research, 1 (3):pp. 249-267, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wright, Y., Boulouchos, K., De Paola, G., and Mastorakos, E., "Multidimensional Conditional Moment Closure Modelling Applied to a Heavy-duty Common-rail Diesel Engine," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):714- 726, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0717.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diwakar R. and Singh S.. NOx and Soot Reduction in Diesel Engine PCCI Combustion: A Computational Investigation. International Journal of Engine Research, 9(3):pp. 195-214, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J., "Smoothing HCCI Heat-Release Rates Using Partial Fuel Stratification with Two-Stage Ignition Fuels," SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0629, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0629.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Contino F., Jeanmart H., Lucchini T., and DErrico G.. Coupling of in situ adaptive tabulation and dynamic adaptive chemistry: An effective method for solving combustion in engine simulations. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, Vol. 33(2):pp. 3057-3064, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Embouazza, M., Haworth, D., and Darabiha, N., "Implementation of Detailed Chemical Mechanisms into Multidimensional CFD Using in situ Adaptive Tabulation: Application to HCCI Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2773, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-2773.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos A., Assanis D. N., Flowers D. L., Aceves S. M., and Hessel R. P.. A fully coupled computational fluid dynamics and multi-zone model with detailed chemical kinetics for the simulation of premixed charge compression ignition engines. International Journal of Engine Research, Vol. 6:497-512, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raju, M., Wang, M., Dai, M., Piggott, W. et al., "Acceleration of Detailed Chemical Kinetics Using Multi-zone Modeling for CFD in Internal Combustion Engine Simulations," SAE Technical Paper 2012- 01-0135, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucchini, T., D'Errico, G., Contino, F., and Jangi, M., "Towards the Use of Eulerian Field PDF Methods for Combustion Modeling in IC Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 7(1):286-296, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1144.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maas U. and Pope S. B.. Simplifying Chemical Kinetics: Intrinsic Low- Dimensional Manifolds in Composition Space. Combustion and Flame, Vol. 88:239-264, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wankhede M.J., Tap F.A., Schapotschnikow P., and Ramaekers W.J.S.. Numerical study of unsteady flow-field and flame dynamics in a gas turbine model combustor. Proceedings of the ASME Turbo Expo, 4A, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pera C., Colin O., and Jay S.. Development of a fpi detailed chemistry tabulation methodology for internal combustion engines [dveloppement d’une tabulation fpi pour la prise en compte de la chimie complexe dans la simulation 3d moteurs]. Oil and Gas Science and Technology, 64(3), 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bekdemir C., Somers L.M.T., and de Goey L.P.H.. Modeling diesel engine combustion using pressure dependent flamelet generated manifolds. Proceedings of the Combustion Institute, 33(2):2887 - 2894, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lehtiniemi, H., Zhang, Y., Rawat, R., and Mauss, F., "Efficient 3-D CFD Combustion Modeling with Transient Flamelet Models," SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0957, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naud B., Novella R., Pastor J.M., and Winklinger J.F.. Rans modelling of a lifted h2/n2 flame using an unsteady flamelet progress variable approach with presumed pdf. Combustion and Flame, 162(4):893-906, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J-Michel B., Colin O., Angelberger C., and Veynante D.. Using the tabulated diffusion flamelet model adf-pcm to simulate a lifted methaneair jet flame. Combustion and Flame, 156(7):1318 - 1331, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J-Michel B., Colin O., Angelberger C., and Veynante D.. A tabulated diffusion flame model applied to diesel engine simulations. International Journal of Engine Research, 15:346 - 369, 2009. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D’Errico G., Lucchini T., Onorati A., and Hardy G.. Computational fluid dynamics modeling of combustion in heavy-duty diesel engines. International Journal of Engine Research, 16 (1):pp. 112-124, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lucchini, T., Della Torre, A., D'Errico, G., Montenegro, G. et al., "Automatic Mesh Generation for CFD Simulations of Direct- Injection Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0376, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0376.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ihme M., Shunn L., and Zhang J.. Regularization of reaction progress variable for application to flameletbased combustion models. Journal of Computational Physics, 231(23):7715-7721, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aglave R., Riedel U., and Warnatz J.. Turbulence-Chemistry Interactions in CFD Modelling of Diesel Engines. Combustion Theory and Modelling, 12(2):pp. 305-328, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krisman A., Tang J.C.K., Hawkes E. R., Lignell D. O., and Chen J. H.. A {DNS} evaluation of mixing models for transported {PDF} modelling of turbulent non-premixed flames. Combustion and Flame, 161(8):2085 - 2106, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J. B.. Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals. McGraw- Hill, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leung K.M., Lindstedt R.P., and Jones W.P.. A simplified reaction mechanism for soot formation in non-premixed flames. Combustion and Flame., 87:289-305, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bolla M., Farrace D., Wright Y. M., Boulouchos K., and Mastorakos E.. Influence of turbulencechemistry interaction for n-heptane spray combustion under diesel engine conditions with emphasis on soot formation and oxidation. Combustion Theory and Modelling, 18(2):330-360, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim T. and Kim Y.. Interactive transient flamelet modeling for soot formation and oxidation processes in laminar non-premixed jet flames. Combustion and Flame., 162:1660-1678, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz R. D.. Modeling Atomization Processes In High Pressure Vaporizing Sprays. Atomization and Spray Technology, Vol. 3:pp. 309- 337, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frassoldati A., D’Errico G., Lucchini T., Stagni A., Cuoci A., Faravelli T., Onorati A., and Ranzi E.. Reduced kinetic mechanisms of diesel fuel surrogate for engine {CFD} simulations. Combustion and Flame, 162(10):3991 - 4007, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meijer M., Somers B., Johnson J., Naber J., Lee S.-Y., Malbec L. M., Bruneaux G., Pickett L. M., Bardi M., Payri R., and Bazyn T.. Engine combustion network (ecn): Characterization and comparison of boundary conditions for different combustion vessels. Atomization and Sprays, 22(9):777-806, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manin, J., Pickett, L., and Skeen, S., "Two-Color Diffused Back- Illumination Imaging as a Diagnostic for Time-Resolved Soot Measurements in Reacting Sprays," SAE Int. J. Engines 6(4):1908-1921, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2548.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Genzale, C., Bruneaux, G., Malbec, L. et al., "Com parison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High-Temperature, High- Pressure Facilities," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):156-181, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Kook, S., and Williams, T., "Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool-Flame, Ignition, High-Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High-Speed Imaging," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):439-459, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
