<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437851</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Windfall Tax</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>LUCY</given-names>
                  <surname>CHENNELLS</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">18</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437846</issue-id>
         <fpage>279</fpage>
         <lpage>291</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1997</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437851"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper analyses the windfall tax on the privatised utilities, introduced in the 1997 Budget. It describes the main arguments put forward for the tax and sets out the details of its scope, scale and method of implementation. The tax is examined against the guidelines of economic efficiency, fairness and administrative feasibility. A one-off tax based on past profits should be efficient, provided that the statement that it is one-off is credible. However, as a tax levied on companies, it does not directly tax the windfall gains that were made in the past by shareholders in the companies concerned.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d29e132a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e139" publication-type="other">
See Curwen and Holmes (1992) for a discussion of the gains to stags from privatisation, i.e. those who sold
their shares on the first day of dealing.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e149a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e156" publication-type="other">
The actual wording of the regulator's duty with respect to competition has varied in some cases from assisting,
to securing effective competition, to promoting competition. An assessment of the current state of competition
in all but one of the industries covered by the windfall tax can be found in OXREP (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e169a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e176" publication-type="other">
A thorough review of the debate over the future of the UK regulatory regime is not possible here, but a
presentation of the debate can be found in Trade and Industry Committee (1997). Armstrong, Cowan and
Vickers (1994) study the UK experience of price-cap regulation, and an economic critique of profit-sharing can
be found in Mayer and Vickers (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e192a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e199" publication-type="other">
Details of the amounts to be paid by sector can be found in the Budget speech, while the exact calculations
and the companies covered can be found in press release Inland Revenue 1, 2 July 1997, entitled 'Windfall
tax'.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e213a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e220" publication-type="other">
The fourth such airport is Manchester, owned by the 10 Manchester local authorities. The price caps apply to
the landing charge, the aircraft parking charge and the passenger charge.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e230a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e237" publication-type="other">
In other words, the total market value of the utility companies believed to be affected was about £5 billion less
than would have been the case if the tax had never been suggested. See, for example, UK Weekly Analyst (11
April 1997), Goldman Sachs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e250a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e257" publication-type="other">
Where four full years are not available, as in the case of British Energy (privatised in July 1996) and Railtrack
(privatised in May 1996), the information on their profits earned up to April 1997 is to be used to determine the
base of the tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e270a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e277" publication-type="other">
(For a discussion of some of the alternative tax bases being discussed before the Budget, see Chennells (1997).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e284a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e291" publication-type="other">
The actual timing of the tax might have affected their behaviour, because the fact that the tax would be
imposed was pre-announced, without any knowledge of its details. Once the policy was announced and there
was a significant expectation that it would be implemented, companies might have adjusted their behaviour in
an attempt to minimise whatever they believed would be the basis for the tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e307a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e314" publication-type="other">
Under the current system of price caps, the regulators allow companies to earn a rate of return that will cover
the cost of financing their investment (i.e. the cost of capital). In addition, an increase in the cost of capital
implies that some marginal investment projects (i.e. those projects that only earn a return sufficient to cover the
original cost of capital) are no longer profitable.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e331a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e338" publication-type="other">
it would also make the incidence of the tax more transparent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d29e345a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d29e352" publication-type="other">
The most vociferous warnings about legal challenges to the tax were made by the chairman of BT, Sir Iain
Vallance, two weeks after the general election. A statement issued after the Budget by the BT board ruled out
any attempt at legal action, despite criticising the inclusion of BT in the scope of the tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d29e374a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e378" publication-type="other">
Armstrong, M., Cowan, S. and Vickers, J. (1994), Regulatory Reform: Economic Analysis and
British Experience, Cambridge, Mass.: MIT.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e388a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e392" publication-type="other">
Chennells, L. (1997), Labour's Windfall Levy, Commentary no. 59, London: Institute for Fiscal
Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e402a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e406" publication-type="other">
Curwen, P. and Holmes, D. (1992), 'Returns to small shareholders from privatisation'. National
Westminster Bank Quarterly Review, February, pp. 41-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e416a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e420" publication-type="other">
Leape, J. (1990), 'The impossibility of perfect neutrality: fundamental issues in tax reform', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 11, no. 2, pp. 39-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e431a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e435" publication-type="other">
Mayer, C. and Vickers, J. (1996), 'Profit-sharing regulation: an economic appraisal', Fiscal
Studies, vol. 17, no. 1, pp. 1-18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e445a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e449" publication-type="other">
OXREP (1997), 'Competition in regulated industries', Oxford Review of Economic Policy, vol. 13,
no. 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d29e459a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d29e463" publication-type="other">
Trade and Industry Committee (1997), First Report: Energy Regulation, HC50-I, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
