<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308298</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A New Constant Dilution Ratio Concept for Vehicle and Engine Exhaust Particle Sampling</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ntziachristos</surname>
                  <given-names>Leonidas</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tzamkiozis</surname>
                  <given-names>Theodoros</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mamakos</surname>
                  <given-names>Athanasios</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Samaras</surname>
                  <given-names>Zissis</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University Thessaloniki, Greece</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>491</fpage>
         <lpage>500</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308298"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a new concept of a partial flow sampling system (PFSS), involving a two–stage dilutor which operates at underpressure, while exhaust is sampled through a capillary. The sample flowrate is in the order of few cubic centimeters per minute. Due to the low flowrate, no tight fixation is required between the exhaust line and the capillary inlet. The dilutor may sample from an opening in the exhaust line which freely exhausts to ambient pressure. As a result, the PFSS operates at constant pressure conditions even upstream of diesel particle filters (DPF). A straightforward mathematical model is then developed to calculate the dilution ratio (DR), depending on the dilution air flowrate and the dilutor underpressure. The model is validated using CO₂ as a trace gas, and a very good agreement is demonstrated between the calculated and the measured DR values. After validation, the PFSS is combined with electrical aerosol detection devices to measure the exhaust particle concentration of a diesel engine operating at different steady-state modes. Also, the filtration efficiency of two particle filters is examined by respectively providing exhaust samples upstream and downstream of each filter. These applications demonstrate the stability and applicability of the PFSS combined with an aerosol instrument to measure the filtration efficiency of a DPF at low cost. Future applications of such configuration may include particle exhaust concentration measurements and on-board (portable) emission measurements.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vouitsis, E.; Ntziachristos, L.; Samaras, Z. 2003. articulate matter mass measurements for low mitting diesel powered vehicles: what’s next?, rogress in Energy and Combustion Science, 29, 635-672.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A. 2007. Sampling System for Solid and olatile Exhaust Particle Size, Number, and Mass missions. SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A. et al. 2002.Performance of Partial Flow ampling Systems Relative to Full Flow CVS for etermination of Particulate Emissions under teady-State and Transient Diesel Engine peration. SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1718.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ntziachristos, L.; Giechaskiel, B.; Pistikopoulos, P.; amaras, Z.; Mathis, U.; Mohr, M.; Ristimäki, J.; eskinen, J.; Mikkanen, P. 2004. Performance valuation of a Novel Sampling and Measurement ystem for Exhaust Particle Characterization. SAE echnical Paper 2004-01-1439.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perry R.H., Green D.W., 1997. “Perry’s Chemical ngineers’ Book”, 7th. Edition, McGraw – Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
