<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167731</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Characterizing Thermal Runaway of Lithium-ion Cells in a Battery System Using Finite Element Analysis Approach</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yeow</surname>
                  <given-names>Kim F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Teng</surname>
                  <given-names>Ho</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>AVL Powertrain Engineering Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167713</issue-id>
         <fpage>179</fpage>
         <lpage>186</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167731"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In this study, thermal runaway of a 3-cell Li-ion battery module is analyzed using a 3D finite-element-analysis (FEA) method. The module is stacked with three 70Ah lithium-nickel-manganese-cobalt (NMC) pouch cells and indirectly cooled with a liquid-cooled cold plate. Thermal runaway of the module is assumed to be triggered by the instantaneous increase of the middle cell temperature due to an abusive condition. The self-heating rate for the runaway cell is modeled on the basis of Accelerating Rate Calorimetry (ARC) test data. Thermal runaway of the battery module is simulated with and without cooling from the cold plate; with the latter representing a failed cooling system. Simulation results reveal that a minimum of 165 °C for the middle cell is needed to trigger thermal runaway of the 3-cell module for cases with and without cold plate cooling. During thermal runaway, the cell heat propagates through all the available thermal paths, including the cooling plates that are in contact with the cold plate, the thermal pads that separate the battery cooling units, and the busbars that connect the terminal tabs of the cells. With the functioning cooling system, heat transfer to the neighboring cells is slower and thus it takes a longer time for these cells to runaway. However, the cold plate cooling could not prevent the thermal runaway of these cells because the cooling capacity of the cold plate is designed only for dissipating the cell ohmic heat during normal module operations. The simulation results demonstrate that the FEA model developed in this study can provide useful information on the cell thermal runaway, such as the onset of thermal runaway, maximum runaway temperature, and thermal propagation from the runaway cell to the neighboring cells. This information can be used to predict gas venting from the cell and to provide guidance in the design of safety features of a battery pack enclosure. The analysis approach developed in this study can also be used for cells with different chemistry if the ARC data are available.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Linden, D. and Reddy, T.B., Handbook of Batteries, 3rd ed., McGraw- Hill, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brodd, R.J., Advances in Lithium-Ion Batteries, Van Schalkwijk W.A. and Scrosati B. (ed.), Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newman, J. and Thomas-Alyea, K.E., Electrochemical Systems, 3rd ed., John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshio, M., Brodd, R.J. and Kozawa, A., Lithium-Ion Batteries - Science and Technologies, Springer, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buchmann, I., Batteries in a Portable World - A Handbook on Rechargeable Batteries for Non-Engineers, Cadex Electronics, Inc., 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Roth, E.P., Crafts, C.C., Doughty, D.H. and McBreen, J., “Advanced Technology Development Program for Lithium-Ion Batteries: Thermal Abuse Performance of 18650 Li-Ion Cells,” SANDIA Report, No.SAND2004-0584, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Electropaedia, “Lithium battery failure,” http://www.mpoweruk.com/lithium_failures.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BatteryFAQ.net, “Do you agree li-ion battery is the solution for the electric vehicle?” http://www.batteryfaq.net/battery-technology.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nagasubramanian, G., Orendorff, C. and Ingersoll, D., “Safety related materials issues for batteries,” New Industrial Chemistry and Engineering Workshop on Materials For Large Scale Energy Storage, National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), Gaithersburg, MD, September 16-17, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Whittingham, M.S., “Lithium batteries and cathode materials,” Chem. Rev., Vol.104, pp.4271-4301, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teng, H. and Yeow, K., “Design of Direct and Indirect Liquid Cooling Systems for High- Capacity, High-Power Lithium-Ion Battery Packs,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 1(2):525-536, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma, Y. and Teng, H., “Comparative Study of Thermal Characteristics of Lithium-ion Batteries for Vehicle Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0668, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0668.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teng, H., Ma, Y., Yeow, K., and Thelliez, M., “An Analysis of a Lithium-ion Battery System with Indirect Air Cooling and Warm-Up,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 4(3):1343-1357, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-2249.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
