<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277701</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study of Motor Oil Cooling at Low Reynolds Number in Multi-Port Narrow Channels</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Saadi</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohammed S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ismail</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohammed</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fotowat</surname>
                  <given-names>Shahram</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Quaiyum</surname>
                  <given-names>Md Abdul</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fartaj</surname>
                  <given-names>Amir</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ of Windsor</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1287</fpage>
         <lpage>1298</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277701"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Mini and micro-scale channels have drawn researchers' attention in the past three decades. The use of these tiny channels in a heat exchanger is considered as one of the pioneered works on the narrow channels as minichannels provide high heat transfer rates per unit volume. Motor oil, known as engine oil, is one of the vital fluids in automotive applications. Its cooling process is confronted by its thermo-physical properties, especially viscosity, which makes this process difficult.</p>
            <p>In current investigations, experimental endeavors have been performed using a closed loop thermal wind tunnel to verify the aptness of cooling the motor oil through a cross-flow minichannel heat exchanger. The prototype heat exchanger consists of 3 circuits; each circuit has five slabs which are connected to each other by four serpentines. There are 68 channels of 1 mm circular diameter drilled through each slab. The minichannel heat exchanger comprises of wavy fins arranged parallel to the flow of air. The inlet temperature of the motor oil was kept constant at 75°C while the air inlet temperatures were varied within the range of 20°C and 40°C.</p>
            <p>The flow of the oil fell in the laminar regime due to its high viscosity, which consequently resulted in low Reynolds numbers (<italic>Re</italic>). The range of was found to be from 0.85 to 3.5 whereas the air flow rates were between 6 m/s and 18 m/s. Correlations were developed between the oil Nusselt number and oil<italic>Re</italic>and Prandtl numbers. The effect of<italic>Re</italic>on the heat transfer coefficient,<italic>NTU</italic>, and effectiveness were investigated. The results were compared with the findings of another highly viscous fluid where a similar test specimen was used and same trends were observed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS:</label>
            <kwd>Minichannel heat exchanger</kwd>
            <kwd>Motor oil</kwd>
            <kwd>Heat transfer</kwd>
            <kwd>Thermo-physical properties</kwd>
            <kwd>Reynolds number</kwd>
            <kwd>Thermal wind tunnel</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehendale, S.S., Jacobi, A.M., and Shah, R.K., “Fluid Flow and Heat Transfer at Micro- and Meso-Scales With Application to Heat Exchanger Design,” Applied Mechanics Reviews. 53(7):175, 2000, doi: 10.1115/1.3097347.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kandlikar, S.G. and Grande, W.J., “Evaluation of Single Phase Flow in Microchannels for High Heat Flux Chip Cooling-Thermohydraulic Performance Enhancement and Fabrication Technology,” Heat Transfer Engineering. 25(8):5-16, 2004, doi: 10.1080/01457630490519772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tuckerman, D.B. and Pease, R.F.W., “High-Performance Heat Sinking for VLSI,” IEEE Electron Device Letters. 2(5):126-129, May 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Phillips, R.J., “Forced-Convection, Liquid-Cooled, Microchannel Heat Sinks,” M.A. Sc. Thesis, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MA, 2: 286-291, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, S.B., Barron, R.R., and Warrington, R.Q., “Fluid Flow and Heat Transfer in Microtubes, Micromechanical Sensors, Actuators, and systems,” ASME DSC. 32:89-90, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qu, W., Mala, M., and Li, D., “Heat Transfer for Water Flow in Trapezoidal Silicon Microchannels,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 43(21): 3925-3936, 2000, doi: 10.1016/S0017-9310(00)00045-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, H.Y. and Cheng, P., “An Experimental Study of Convective Heat Transfer in Silicon Microchannels with Different Surface Conditions,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 46(14):2547-2556, 2003. 10.1016/S0017-9310(03)00035-8.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kandlikar, S.G., “Microchannels and Minichannels-History, Terminology, Classification and Current Research Needs,” First International Conference on Microchannels and Minichannels, NY, ICMM2003-1000, Apr. 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morini, G.L., “Scaling Effects for Liquid Flows in Microchannels” Heat Transfer Engineering. 27(4): 64-73, Aug. 2006, doi: 10.1080/01457630500523865.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herwig, H. and Hausner, O., “Critical View on New Results in Micro- Fluid Mechanics: an example.” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 46(5): 935-937, 2003, 10.1016/S0017-9310(02)00306-X.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hetsroni, G., Mosyak, A., Pogrebnyak, E., and Yarin, L.P., “Fluid Flow in Microchannels,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 48(10): 1982-1998, 2005, doi: 10.1016/2004.12.019.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qu, W. and Mudawar, I., “Experimental and Numerical Study of Pressure Drop and Heat Transfer in a Single-Phase Micro-Channel Heat Sink,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 45(12): 2549-2565, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xie, C. and Hartnett, J.P., “Influence of Variable Viscosity of Mineral Oil on Laminar Heat Transfer in a 2:1 Rectangular Duct,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 35(3):641-648, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shin, S.S. and Cho, Y., “Improved Heat Transfer Design of a Liquid Cooling Module: the Use of Variable Viscosity Liquids in a 2:1 Rectangular Duct,” ASME International Electronics Packaging Conference. 4(2):641-648, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, H.J., Son, S.Y., Choi, M.C., Lim, G. et al. “Temperature- Dependent Property Effects on Laminar Flow Characteristics in a Rectangular MicroChannel,” ASME Micro-Electromechanical Systems Division Publication (MEMS), 3:443-448, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, J., Peterson, G.P., Cheng, P., “Three-Dimensional Analysis of Heat Transfer in a Micro-Heat Sink with Single Phase Flow,” International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 47(19-20):4215-4231, 2004, doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2004.04.018.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Quaiyum, M., Fartaj, A., and Askar, S., “An Experimental Characterization of Automatic Transmission Fluid Flowing Through Air Cooled MicroChannel Heat Exchanger,” SAE Int. J. Mater. Manf. 5(2): 503-516, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khan, M.G. and Fartaj, A., “A Review on Microchannel Heat Exchangers and Potential Applications,” International Journal of Energy Research. 35(7):553-582, 2011, doi: 10.1002/er.1720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heisler, H. “Vehicle and Engine Technology”, Second Edition, Elsevier, London, UK, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SAE International Surface Vehicle Information Report, “Physical and Chemical Properties of Engine Oils,” SAE Standard J375, Rev. Nov. 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kumar, V., Gupta, P., and Nigam, K.D.P., “Fluid Flow and Heat Transfer in Curved Tubes with Temperature-dependent Properties, Ind. Eng. Chem. Res., 46(10): 226-3236, 2007, doi: 10.1021/ie0608399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Can-Am Instruments Limited, 2851 Brighton Road, Oakville, Ontario, L6H 6C9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shell Nederland Verkoopmaatschappij B.V. Visit address: Rivium Boulevard 156, 2909 LB Capellea/d Ijssel.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kandlikar, S.G., and King, M.R., “Heat Transfer and Fluid Flow in Minichannels and Microchannels,” First Edition, Elsevier, Amsterdam, Boston, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, R.K. and London, A.L., “Laminar Flow Forced Convection in Ducts: A source Book for Compact Heat Exchangers Analytical Data,” New York: Academic Press, Inc, NY, 1978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Çengel, Y.A., “Heat and Mass Transfer: A practical Approach”, Third Edition, McGraw Hill, New York, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shah, R.K. and Sekulić, D.P., “Fundamentals of Heat Exchanger Design,” John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., New Jersey, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yataghene, M., Fayolle, F., and Legrand, J., “Experimental and Numerical Analysis of Heat Transfer Including Viscous Dissipation in a Scraped Surface Heat Exchanger,” Chemical Engineering and Processing: Process Intensification. 48(10):1447-1458, 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.cep.2009.07.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kays, W.M., and London, A.L., “Compact Heat Exchangers”, Third Edition, Krieger Publishing Company, Florida, ISBN 1-57524-060-2:102-107, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASME PTC 30, “Air cooled heat exchangers. An American National Standard, Performance Test Code (PTC) 30,” American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME), NY, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
