<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">24</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830737</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830740</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE FINANCIAL STRUCTURE OF BARBADOS / LA STRUCTURE FINANCIÈRE DE BARBADE</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
                  <surname>Howard</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>405</fpage>
         <lpage>422</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830740"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper examines the contemporary financial structure of Barbados. The analysis suggests that commercial banks dominate the financial structure, and the role of non-banks is relatively small. Commercial banks are the major mobilizers of financial savings. Commercial bank lending is oriented towards the household and services sectors including tourism, transport, entertainment and professional services. The decline of manufacturing and agriculture has reduced the share of credit going to these sectors. Credit unions and the National Insurance Fund are becoming more important in mobilizing financial savings. The Barbadian financial system has experienced a significant degree of financial innovation including the institution of mutual funds, venture capital companies, a stock exchange, as well as the introduction of new financial instruments. Government's policy is to continue to broaden the capital market by providing appropriate fiscal incentives. L'article examine la structure financière actuelle de la Barbade. L'analyse suggère que les banques commerciales dominent la stucture financière, et que le rôle des institutions non-bancaires est relativement petit. Les banques commerciales sont les mobilisateurs les plus importants d'épargnes financières. Le prêt bancaire commercial est orienté plutôt vers les ménages et les services - tourisme, transport, loisirs et services professionels inclus. La baisse des secteurs de fabrication et d'agriculture a réduit le pourcentage de crédit qui leur est attribué. Néanmoins, les sociétés de crédit et le Fonds d'Assurances Sociales (National Insurance Fund) deviennent plus importants dans le processus de mobilisation d'épargnes financières. En outre, le système financier de la Barbade est devenu plus innovateur avec la création des fonds communs de placement, société de capital risque, la Bourse, et la production de nouveaux instruments financiers. La politique de gouvernement est de continuer à élargir le marché de capital en apportant les incitations fiscals appropiées.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d29e172a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e176" publication-type="other">
Bourne, C. (1988), "Contemporary Financial Structure of Trinidad and Tobago", C. Bourne and R. Ramsaran (eds),
Money and Finance in Trinidad and Tobago, Mona, Kingston: Institute of Social and Economic Research, University of
the West Indies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e189a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e193" publication-type="other">
Codrington, H. and A. Coppin (1989), "The Financial Structure and the Allocation of credit in Barbados", Social
and Economic Studies, Vol. 38, No. 4, December.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e203a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e207" publication-type="other">
Craigwell, R. C. and Grandbois, C. (1999), "The Performance of the Securities Exchange of Barbados", Savings
and Development, No. 4</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e217a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e221" publication-type="other">
Doyle, M. and Johnson, A. "Does Offshore Business mean onshore Economic Gains?", Central Bank of Barbados,
Working Papers, 1999.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e232a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e236" publication-type="other">
Fabozzi, et al. (1994), Foundations of Financial Markets and Institutions. Englewood Cliffs: New Jersey, Prentice
Hall Inc.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e250" publication-type="other">
Fama, E. (1970), "Efficient Capital Markets: A Review of Theory and Empirical Work", Journal of Finance Vol. 25,
No. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e260a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e264" publication-type="other">
Goldsmith, R. (1969), Financial Structure and Development, New Haven: Yale University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e271a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e275" publication-type="other">
Haynes, C. (1997), "The evolution of the financial sector in Barbados (1970 -1996)", L. Clarke and D. Danns (eds),
The Financial Evolution of the Caribbean Community (1970 - 1996). St. Augustine: Trinidad and Tobago, Caribbean
Centre for Monetary Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e292" publication-type="other">
Howard, M. (1989), Dependence and Development in Barbados, Bridgetown: Carib Research and Publication.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e303" publication-type="other">
Lawrenceson, J. and Chai, J. C. H. (1998), "Financial Liberalization and Financial Depth in China." Savings and
Development, No.4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e318" publication-type="other">
Worrell, D. and R. Prescod (1983), "Development of the Financial Sector in Barbados", Central Bank of Barbados,
Economic Review, Vol. 10, No. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d29e328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d29e332" publication-type="other">
Zephirin, M. G. and D. Seerattan (1997), Financial Innovations in the Caribbean, St. Augustine, University of the
West Indies, Trinidad and Tobago, Caribbean Centre for Monetary Studies.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


