<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24908827</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Agent-Based Modeling Approach to Quantifying the Value of Battlefield Information</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kewley</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ Robert Kewley current serves as an operational capabilities analyst at the Center for Army Analysis. He has analysis or research experience in the areas of theater campaign modeling, combat identification, C4ISR modeling, and agent-based models. He holds a M.S. in Industrial and Managerial Engineering and a Ph.D. in Decision Science and Engineering Systems from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Larimer</surname>
                  <given-names>Larry</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ Larry Larimer currently serves as a combat operations research analyst at the TRADOC Analysis Center, White Sands Missile Range. He has analysis experience in the areas of C4ISR assessment, and Brigade through Corps level combat modeling. He has research experience and personal interest in agent-based modeling. He holds a B.S. degree from the United States Military Academy and a M.S. degree in Operations Research from the Naval Postgraduate School.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2003</year>
            <string-date>June 2003</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>36</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e24908820</issue-id>
         <fpage>10</fpage>
         <lpage>27</lpage>
         <page-range>10-13, 25-27</page-range>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24908827"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">TRADOC Pamphlet 525-3-90, “Objective Force Maneuver Units of Action,” United States Army Training and Doctrine Command, 1 November 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cy Staniec, Stuart Starr, and Charles Taylor, “MORS Workshop on Advancing C4ISR Assessment,” PHALANX, Volume 34, Number 1, March 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrew Ilachinski, Land Warfare and Complexity, Part I: Mathematical Background and Technical Sourcebook, Alexandria, VA: Center for Naval Analysis, July 1996, pp. 101-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ibid, pp. 100-103.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andrew Ilachinski, 2000. Irreducible semi-autonomous adaptive combat: An artificial life approach to land combat. Military Operations Research, 5(3): 27- 46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larry Larimer and William B. Carlton. “Using Complex Adaptive System Theory and Agent Based Modeling to Quantify the Value of Battlefield Information.” Presentation delivered at INFORMS Military Applications Society International Meeting, May 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Robert Kewley and Mark Embrechts. “A Multiagent System For Tactical Control Of Automated Forces.” Unpublished manuscript submitted to Military Operations Research, November 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cem Hocaoglu and Arthur C. Sanderson.” Multimodal function optimization using minimal representation size clustering and its application to planning multipaths.” Evolutionary Computation, 5(1):81-104, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jing Xiao, Zbigniew Michalwicz, Lixin Zhang, and Krzysztof Trojanowski. Adaptive evolutionary planner/navigator for mobile robots. IEEE Transactions on Evolutionary Computation, 1(1):18-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devore, Jay L. Probability and Statistics for Engineering and the Sciences. Brooks/Cole, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
