<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169002</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Design of Direct and Indirect Liquid Cooling Systems for High-Capacity, High-Power Lithium-Ion Battery Packs</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Teng</surname>
                  <given-names>Ho</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yeow</surname>
                  <given-names>Kim</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>AVL Powertrain Engineering, Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>December 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26168993</issue-id>
         <fpage>525</fpage>
         <lpage>536</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169002"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Battery packs for plug-in hybrid electrical vehicle (PHEV) applications can be characterized as high-capacity and high-power packs. For PHEV battery packs, their power and electrical-energy capacities are determined by the range of the electrical-energy-driven operation and the required vehicle drive power. PHEV packs often employ high-power lithium-ion (Li-ion) pouch cells with large cell capacity in order to achieve high packing efficiency. Lithium-ion battery packs for PHEV applications generally have a 96SnP configuration, where S is for cells in series, P is for cells in parallel, and n = 1, 2 or 3. Two PHEV battery packs with 355V nominal voltage and 25-kWh nominal energy capacity are studied. The first pack is assembled with 96 70Ah high-power Li-ion pouch cells in 96S1P configuration. The second pack is assembled with 192 35Ah high-power Li-ion pouch cells in 96S2P configuration. The battery temperatures are managed with a direct liquid cooling system for the 96S1P pack and with an indirect liquid cooling system for the 96S2P pack. Procedures are discussed for the cooling system design for both direct liquid cooling and indirect liquid cooling packs. A design criterion is proposed for obtaining a uniform coolant flow distribution in the battery pack. Thermal behavior of the cells in both battery packs are simulated using 3D finite element models under 4C continuous discharge from a fully charged state to 90% depth of discharge, simulating the worst condition for the PHEV battery pack utilization.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuper, C., Hoh, M., Houchin-Miller, G. and Fuhr, J., “Thermal Management of Hybrid Vehicle Battery Systems,” Paper presented at the 24th International Battery, Hybrid and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicle Conference and Exhibition (EVS-24), Stavanger, Norway, May 13-16, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teng, H., Ma, Y., Yeow, K., and Thelliez, M., “An Analysis of a Lithium-ion Battery System with Indirect Air Cooling and Warm-Up,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 4(3):1343-1357, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-2249.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pesaran, A.A., “Battery Thermal Management in EVs and HEVs: Issues and Solutions,” Paper presented at First Annual Advanced Automotive Battery Conference, Las Vegas, Nevada, February 5-8, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, G.H. and Pesaran, A., “Battery Thermal Management System Design Modeling,” Paper presented at the 22nd International Battery, Hybrid and Fuel Cell Electric Vehicle Conference and Exhibition (EVS-22), Yokohama, Japan, October 23-28, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber, D.R., Spencer, S.J. and Spacher, P.F., “Battery Cooling Plate Design with Discrete Channels,” US patent, US2009/0258289 A1, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kruger, D.D. and Beer, R.C., “Prismatic-cell Battery Pack with Integral Coolant Passages,” US patent, US2010/0143782 A1, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payne, J., Isayev, I., Yang, H., Koetting, W., Morris, P. and Metarajan, V.M., “Battery Cell Assembly Having Heat Exchanger with Serpentine Flow Path,” US patent, US2009/0325054 A1, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Teng, H., “Thermal Analysis of a High-Power Lithium-Ion Battery System with Indirect Air Cooling,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 1(1):79-88, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0333.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yeow, K., Teng, H., Thelliez, M., and Tan, E., “Thermal Analysis of a Li-ion Battery System with Indirect Liquid Cooling Using Finite Element Analysis Approach,” SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 1(1):65-78, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0331.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dassault Systemes, http://www.3ds.com/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ma, Y., Teng, H., and Thelliez, M., “Electro-Thermal Modeling of a Lithium-ion Battery System,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):306-317, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2204.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
