<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285115</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Next Improvement Potentials for Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine - Tailor the Fuel Injection System to the Combustion Needs</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Weber</surname>
                  <given-names>Jost</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO AUTOMOTIVE Deutschland GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Herrmann</surname>
                  <given-names>Olaf</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO AUTOMOTIVE Deutschland GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Puts</surname>
                  <given-names>Ron</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO AUTOMOTIVE Deutschland GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Kawamura</surname>
                  <given-names>Jyun</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO CORPORATION</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Tomida</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasufumi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO CORPORATION</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Mashida</surname>
                  <given-names>Makoto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO CORPORATION</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>1119</fpage>
         <lpage>1127</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285115"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Future diesel engine legislation Tier 4 / Stage V and EU6d demand further improvements to reduce CO₂ while keeping the already low NOₓ emissions levels. For US trucks a more strict limit of 0.2 g/bhp-hr NOₓ emissions need to be achieved. In this trade-off, system costs and complexity of the after-treatment are defining the constraint in which the common rail fuel injection system layout has to be defined. The increase of rail pressure was in the past the major step to control the soot emissions in view of low engine-out NOₓ emissions by applying massive EGR. With the on-going development of NOₓ-aftertreatment by Selective Catalytic Reduction (SCR), conversion efficiencies of up to 97% allow to reduce the EGR usage and rail pressure usage. In that context, the steepness of injection rate, the nozzle flow rate and the injection pressure are remaining parameters to control the NOₓ emissions. A shallow injection rate in combination with larger nozzle flow rates is beneficial to reduce the NOₓ emissions thanks to a reduced premixing of fuel with air. To study this effect, the latest solenoid injector with improved magnetic actuation is utilized. The influence of the steepness of injection rate is studied on a 6 cylinder heavy-duty Diesel engine on 3 representative part- load points of the WLTC cycle. Depending on the engine-out NOₓ emissions requirements, two scenarios are considered. In case of a strong NOₓ aftertreatment, the shallow injection rate steepness is beneficial for the fuel consumption. In case of less NOₓ aftertreatment, high EGR rates are required and soot emissions can be controlled through the steepness of injection rate.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fleiss M., Crabb D., Somhorst J., Möller N., Kvarfordt J., Samuelsson K., ”VEA - Volvo Environmental Architecture: Extreme Downsizing &amp; Maximum Commonality While Maintaining Highly Competitive Customer Attributes”, 22. Aachen Colloquium Vehicle and Engine Technology, Aachen, 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herrmann O., Nakagawa M., Kenhard M., Schwab H., Miyaki M., Shinohara Y., Takeuchi K., Uchiyama K. “Ultra High Pressure and Enhanced Multiple Injection - Potentials for the Diesel Engine and Challenge for the Fuel Injection System”, IMechE, London, 2012</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishizuka K., Uchiyama K., Higuchi K., Yamada N., Takeuchi K., Herrmann O., Nakagawa M., Joyce M., Koerfer T., Laumen H.-J., Ruhkamp L., Rajamani V., Schönfeld S., “Further Innovations for Diesel Fuel Injection Systems: Closed-loop Control of Fuel Quantity by i-ART &amp; Ultra High Injection Pressure”, 19. Aachen Colloquium Vehicle and Engine Technology, Aachen, 2010</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber J., Ruwe J., Sashima N., Hagen J., Ueda D., Sugawara S., Uchiyama K., Ishizuka K., “Investigation on Advanced Common Rail Injector Improvements - Challenge to Balance Robustness, Fuel Accuracy and Emissions Potential”, IMechE, London, 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takeuchi K., Shinohara Y., Kojima A., Ishizuka K., Uchiyama K., Nakagawa M., Dr.-Ing. Herrmann O. E., „Weitere Innovationen beim Diesel Motor Management und Abgasnachbehandlungssystem“, 36. Int. Wiener Motorensymposium, 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruwe J., Herrmann O., Queck D., Visser S., Uchiyama K., Takeuchi K., Ishizuka K., „Diesel Engine Potentials by Hydraulic Tuning of the G4S Solenoid Common Rail Injector with 3-Way Function”, 10th Conference on „Diesel and Gasoline Direct Injection”, Haus der Tdechnik, Berlin, 2014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ueda, D., Tanada, H., Utsunomiya, A., Kawamura, J. et al., "4th Generation Diesel Piezo Injector (Realizing Enhanced High Response Injector)," SAE Technical Paper 2016-01-0846, 2016, doi:10.4271/2016- 01-0846.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsumoto S., Date K., Taguchi T., Herrmann O. E., “The New DENSO Common Rail Solenoid Injector“, MTZ 02/2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber J., Ruwe J., Kiyanni J., Sashima N., Hagen J., Ueda D., Sugawara S., Uchiyama K., Ishizuka K., Suzuki M., “The Next Generation of Common Rail Injector - Steps to Control Diesel Combustion in Time”, Symposium for Combustion Controls, Aachen, 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagen J., Nakagawa M., Herrmann O., Weber J.. Queck D., Uchiyama K., Ishizuka K., Kawamura J., Tomida Y., Mashida M., “Diesel Combustion Potentials by further Injector Improvement in case of different engine applications”, 24. Aachen Colloquium Vehicle and Engine Technology, Aachen, 2015</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagen J., Herrmann O., Weber J.. Queck D., “Diesel Combustion Potentials by Further Injector Improvement”, MTZ 04/2016, Vol. 77, Springer Edition, 2016</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruhkamp L., Kind M., Laumen H. J., Maassen F., Mashida M., Takeuchi K., Shinohara Y., Herrmann O., Kudo T., Nakagawa M., Rajamani V., “Further Options for Diesel Engine Improvements by Increased Injection Pressure up to 3000 Bar”, 20. Aachen Colloquium Vehicle and Engine Technology, Aachen, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
