<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">77</volume>
         <issue-id>i40191547</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44580824</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>What Should Engineering Administration Do for the Chief Project Engineer?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>J. H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Richards</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>J. R.</given-names>
                  <surname>Blackwell</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1968</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2675</fpage>
         <lpage>2696</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc., 1969</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44580824"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>In order for a large aerospace company to deliver a good product, on time, and to make a profit, its Engineering Department must be efficient and must also operate profitably, measured as a separate budget function. The Chief Project Engineer is responsible for the total performance of engineering on his program, and must see that all parts of the program are planned and accomplished efficiently and profitably. He requires much assistance from Engineering Administration; in fact, Administration must do for him many of the things that have to be done. Administration has functions deemed important in each of the three areas of work performance: technical, schedule, and cost. In the cost area of quoting and selling engineering manpower, which includes estimating, verifying estimates, preparing cost proposals, and negotiating contracts, Administration is key in each step. Methods of making accurate estimates and preparing convincing justifications are discussed. Such methods need to be used to yield correct initial budget baselines. Fast reaction mechanized budget monitoring techniques have been developed. They provide capability to adjust budgets or manpower or job depth in time to stay profitable without letting quality deteriorate. In the schedule area, complete initial scheduling along with accurate "time now" progress reporting can provide visibility so that Project Engineers can move before it is too late. In the technical work performance area, Administration provides the drawing release system, and also has a role in morale building. The program/project management concept is accepted as one of the most effective organizational management techniques. It is utilized extensively throughout the aerospace industry in an attempt to insure technical and business management competence in the accomplishment of established objectives. Research and development program/project team operations are usually directed by personnel of the company's engineering organization, with the major administrative support effort being supplied by personnel assigned from the engineering administration functions. It is this area of service and support, to a typical research and development type project, that is the major topic of this paper. There is substantial evidence that through the lack of effective engineering administration many otherwise successful research and development projects have received the mark of poor management. This paper discusses those major aspects of engineering administration service and support believed necessary for the successful accomplishment of efficient and effective program/project management. Primarily, these aspects are the support required in the areas of planning, organization, staffing, communications, and control in order to provide responsible engineering personnel the means for effective direction.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d351e355a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d351e362" publication-type="other">
D. Karger and R. Murdick, "Managing Engineering
and Research." New York: The Industrial Press, 1963.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d351e372a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d351e379" publication-type="other">
Koonty and O'Donnell, "Principles of Management."
New York: McGraw-Hill Inc., 1964, 3rd Edition.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d351e389a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d351e396" publication-type="other">
John M. Steward, "Business Horizons." Vol. 8, No. 3,
Indiana U., 1965.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d351e406a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d351e413" publication-type="other">
D. Fuller, "Engineering Operations." Boston: Indus-
trial Education Institute, 1962.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d351e424a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d351e431" publication-type="other">
J. Baumgartner, "Project Management." Homewood,
111.: Richard D. Irwin Inc., 1963.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d351e441a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d351e448" publication-type="other">
V. G. Hajek, "Project Engineering." New York:
McGraw-Hill Inc., 1965.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


