<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275511</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Thermodynamic Study on Boosted HCCI</article-title>
            <subtitle>Motivation, Analysis and Potential</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kulzer</surname>
                  <given-names>André</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lejsek</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nier</surname>
                  <given-names>Tobias</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Robert Bosch GmbH, Stuttgart</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>733</fpage>
         <lpage>749</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275511"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Due to the increasingly stricter emission legislation and growing demands for lower fuel consumption, there have been significant efforts to improve combustion efficiency while satisfying the emission requirements. Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) combined with turbo/supercharging on gasoline engines provides a particularly promising and, at the same time, a challenging approach.</p>
            <p>Naturally aspirated (n.a.) HCCI has already shown a considerable potential of about 14% in the New European Driving Cycle (NEDC) compared with a conventional 4-cylinder 2.0 liter gasoline Port Fuel Injection (PFI) engine without any advanced valve-train technology. The HCCI n.a. operation range is air breathing limited due to the hot residuals required for the self-ignition and to slow down reaction kinetics, and therefore is limited to a part-load operation area.</p>
            <p>Considering the future gasoline engine market with growing potentials identified on downsized gasoline engines, it becomes necessary to thoroughly investigate the synergies and challenges of boosted HCCI. Additional HCCI potentials can be realized through the additional breathing, resulting in extension of the operation map and further optimization of fuel efficiency. This provides additional potentials regarding test cycle efficiency. These potentials will be addressed in this work by thermodynamic analysis, drive-cycle simulations and split of losses. These analysis and simulations are based on single-cylinder and 4-cylinder engine data. As an outlook the new challenges associated with the boosted HCCI will also be discussed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A., Christ, A., Rauscher, M., Sauer, C., Würfel, G., Blank, T., “Thermodynamic Analyses and Benchmark of Various Gasoline Combustion Concepts,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0231, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weberbauer, F.; Rauscher, M.; Kulzer, A.; Knopf, M.; Bargende, M.: “Generally applicable split of losses for new combustion concepts”, Motortechnische Zeitschrift MTZ 2/2005, Jahrgang 66.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wolters, P., Salber, W., Geiger, J., Duesmann, M., Dilthey, J., “Controlled Autoignition Combustion Process With An Electromechanical Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0032, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oakley, A., Zhao, H., Ladommatos, N., Ma, T., “Experimental Studies on Controlled Auto-Ignition (CAI) Combustion of Gasoline in a 4-Stroke Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1030, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A.; Fischer, W.; Karrelmeyer, R.; Sauer, C.; Wintrich, T.; Benninger, K.: “The CO2 Potential of Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition on Gasoline Engines under Controlled Operation”, Motortechnische Zeitschrift MTZ 1/2009, Jahrgang 70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A.; Rauscher, M.; Sauer, C.; Orlandini, I.; Weberbauer, F.: “Methods for Analysis of SI-HCCI Combustion with Variable Valve Actuation”, 6th International Symposium Stuttgart 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauer, Ch.; Rauscher, M.; Kulzer, A.; Orlandini, I; Bargende, M.: “Characteristics of Gasoline HCCI using Direct Injection and Variable Valvetrain”. Haus der Technik - Direkteinspritzung im Ottomotor, June 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alt, M.; Grebe, U.; Najt, P.; Wermuth, N.; Huebler, M.; Reuss, D.: “HCCI - vom thermodynamischen Potential zum realen Kraftstoffverbrauch im Mehrzylinder-Ottomotor”. 11th Conference on The Working Cycle of the Internal Combustion Process, Graz, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mischker, K.; Denger, D.: “Anforderungen an einem vollvariablen Ventiltrieb und Realisierung durch die elektrohydraulische Ventilsteuerung EHVS”, 24. International Viena Engine Symposium 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortmann, R., Arndt, S., Raimann, J., Würfel, G., Grzeszik, R., “Methods and Analysis of Fuel Injection, Mixture Preparation and Charge Stratification in Different Direct-Injected SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0970, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A.; Hathout, J.-P.; Sauer, C.; Christ, A.: “Controlled Auto Ignition based on GDI - Strategies derived from experiment and simulation”, IMechE Internal Combustion Engines: Performance, Fuel Economy and Emissions, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Orlandini, I.; Kulzer, A.; Weberbauer, F.; Rauscher, M.: “Simulation of self ignition in HCCI and partial HCCI engines using a reduced order model”, SAE Paper 2005-01-0159</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A.; Lejsek, D.: “BeCAT - Bosch Engine Combustion Analysis Tool”, Robert Bosch GmbH Report, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A.; Kufferath, A.; Christ, A.; Knopf, M.; Benninger, K.: “CAI - A Combustion Concept based on GDI Technology”, 15. Aachen Colloquium, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
