<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169135</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optimal Supervisory Control of the Series HEV with Consideration of Temperature Effects on Battery Fading and Cooling Loss</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Xueyu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Filipi</surname>
                  <given-names>Zoran</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Clemson-ICAR</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>July 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169125</issue-id>
         <fpage>299</fpage>
         <lpage>307</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169135"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper develops a methodology to optimize the supervisory controller for a heavy-duty series hybrid electric vehicle, with consideration of battery aging and cooling loss. Electrochemistrybased battery aging model is integrated into vehicle model. The side reaction, reductive electrolyte decomposition, is modeled to determine battery aging rate, and the thermal effect on this reaction rate is considered by Arrhenius Law. The resulting capacity and power fading is included in the system-level study. Sensitivity analysis shows that battery aging could cause fuel economy loss by 5.9%, and increasing temperature could improve fuel economy at any given state-of-health, while accelerating battery aging. Stochastic dynamic programming algorithm is applied to a modeled system to handle the tradeoff between two objectives: maximizing fuel economy and minimizing battery aging. The strategy developed by the stochastic dynamic programming improves fuel economy by 8%, and reduces the lithium ion loss by 17% after 9e3 cycles.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, X., Ivanco, A., Tao, X., Wagner, J. et al., "Optimization of the Series-HEV Control with Consideration of the Impact of Battery Cooling Auxiliary Losses," SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 3(2):234-243, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1904.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jalil, N., Kheir, N.A., Salman, M., "A rule-based energy management strategy for a series hybrid vehicle," American Control Conference, 1997, Proceedings of the 1997, vol.1, no., pp.689, 693 vol.1, 4-6 Jun 1997, doi: 10.1109/ACC.1997.611889.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, Y. and Filipi, Z., "Series Hydraulic Hybrid Propulsion for a Light Truck - Optimizing the Thermostatic Power Management," SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0080, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-24-0080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salman, M., Schouten, N.J., Kheir, N.A., "Control strategies for parallel hybrid vehicles," American Control Conference, 2000. Proceedings of the 2000, vol.1, no.6, pp.524, 528 vol.1, Sep 2000, doi: 10.1109/ACC.2000.878955.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, B., Lin, C., Filipi, Z., Peng, H. et al, "Optimization of Power Management Strategies for a Hydraulic Hybrid Medium Truck,” Proceedings of the 2002 Advanced Vehicle Control Conference, Hiroshima, Japan, September 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, X., Ivanco, A., and Filipi, Z., "Optimization of Rule-Based Control Strategy for a Hydraulic-Electric Hybrid Light Urban Vehicle Based on Dynamic Programming," SAE Int. J. Alt. Power. 1(1):249-259, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ebbesen, S. and Guzzella, L., "Trade-Off between Fuel Economy and Battery Life for Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” ASME Conference Proceedings, (54761): p. 217-223, 2011, doi: 10.1115/DSCC2011-5950.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Peng, H., Grizzle, J.W., Kang, K-M., "Power management strategy for a parallel hybrid electric truck," Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on, vol.11, no.6, pp.839,849, Nov. 2003, doi: 10.1109/TCST.2003.815606.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, Y., K., Mohan, S., Samad, N., Siegel, J.et al., "Optimal power management for a series hybrid electric vehicle cognizant of battery mechanical effects," American Control Conference (ACC), 4-6 June 2014, doi: 10.1109/acc.2014.6859505.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johri, R. and Filipi, Z., "Low-Cost Pathway to Ultra Efficient City Car: Series Hydraulic Hybrid System with Optimized Supervisory Control," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):505-520, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0065.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C., Peng, H., Grizzle, J.W., "A stochastic control strategy for hybrid electric vehicles," American Control Conference, 2004. Proceedings of the 2004, vol.5, no., pp.4710, 4715 vol.5, June 30 2004- July 2 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lars, J., Mattias, A. and Bo, E., "Assessing the Potential of Predictive Control for Hybrid Vehicle Powertrains Using Stochastic Dynamic Programming," Intelligent Transportation Systems, IEEE Transactions on 8 (1): p. 71-83, 2007, doi: 10.1109/tits.2006.884887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moura, S., Fathy, H., Callaway, D. and Stein, J., "A Stochastic Optimal Control Approach for Power Management in Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on 19(3): p. 545-555, 2011, doi: 10.1109/tcst.2010.2043736.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moura, S., Stein, J. and Fathy, H. "Battery-Health Conscious Power Management in Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles via Electrochemical Modeling and Stochastic Control., " Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on 21(3): p. 679-694, 2013, doi: 10.1109/tcst.2012.2189773</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borhan, H., Vahidi, A., Phillips, A., Kuang, M. et al, "MPCBased Energy Management of a Power-Split Hybrid Electric Vehicle," Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on, vol.20, no.3, pp.593,603, May 2012, doi: 10.1109/TCST.2011.2134852.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lescot, J., Sciarretta, A., Chamaillard, Y. and Charlet, A., "On the integration of optimal energy management and thermal management of hybrid electric vehicles," Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference (VPPC), 2010 IEEE 1-3 Sept. 2010, doi: 10.1109/vppc.2010.5729158.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Onori, S., Serrao, L., "On Adaptive-ECMS strategies for hybrid electric vehicles", 2nd International scientific conference on hybrid and electric vehicles RHEVE 2011, Rueil-Malmaison, France 6-7 December 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gu, B. and Rizzoni, G., "An Adaptive Algorithm for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Management Based on Driving Pattern Recognition," ASME Conference Proceedings 2006(47683): p. 249-258, 2006, doi: 10.1115/IMECE2006-13951.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pisu, P. and Rizzoni. G., "A supervisory control strategy for series hybrid electric vehicles with two energy storage systems," Vehicle Power and Propulsion, 2005 IEEE Conference, 7-9 Sept. 2005, doi: 10.1109/vppc.2005.1554534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nüesch, T., Wang, M., Voser, C., Guzzella, L., “Optimal energy management and sizing for hybrid electric vehicles considering transient emissions”, in 2012 IFAC Workshop on Engine and Powertrain Control Simulation and Modeling. 2012: Paris, France, doi: 0.3182/20121023-3- FR-4025.00015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musardo, C., Rizzoni, G., Staccia, B., "A-ECMS: An Adaptive Algorithm for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Energy Management," Decision and Control, 2005 and 2005 European Control Conference. CDC-ECC '05. 44th IEEE Conference on, vol., no., pp.1816,1823, 12-15 Dec. 2005, doi: 10.1109/CDC.2005.1582424.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim. N., Cha, S. and Peng, H., "Optimal Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicles Based on Pontryagin's Minimum Principle, " Control Systems Technology, IEEE Transactions on 19(5): p. 1279-1287, 2011, doi: 10.1109/tcst.2010.2061232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, T., Rizzoni, G. and Onori, S., "Optimal energy management of HEVs with consideration of battery aging, " Transportation Electrification Asia-Pacific (ITEC Asia-Pacific), 2014 IEEE Conference and Expo. Aug. 31 2014-Sept. 3 2014, doi: 10.1109/itec-ap.2014.6941202.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serrao, L., Onori, S., Sciarretta, A., Guezennec, Y., Rizzoni, G., "Optimal energy management of hybrid electric vehicles including battery aging," American Control Conference (ACC), 2011, vol., no., pp.2125,2130, June 29 2011-July 1 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ebbesen, S., Elbert, P., Guzzella, L., "Battery State-of-Health Perceptive Energy Management for Hybrid Electric Vehicles," Vehicular Technology, IEEE Transactions on, vol.61, no.7, pp.2893, 2900, Sept. 2012, doi: 10.1109/TVT.2012.2203836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johri, R., Salvi, A., and Filipi, Z., "Optimal Energy Management for a Hybrid Vehicle Using Neuro-Dynamic Programming to Consider Transient Engine Operation", Proceedings of 4th Annual Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johri, R. and Filipi Z., "Optimal energy management of a series hybrid vehicle with combined fuel economy and low-emission objectives,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering 228(12): p. 1424-1439, 2014, doi: 10.1177/0954407014522444.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalil, G., "Challenges of hybrid electric vehicles for military applications," Vehicle Power and Propulsion Conference, 2009. VPPC '09. IEEE, vol., no., pp.1,3, 7-10 Sept. 2009, doi: 10.1109/VPPC.2009.5289878.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Forgez, C., Do, D.V., Friedrich, G., Morcrette, M., et al., "Thermal Modeling of a Cylindrical LiFePO4/graphite Lithium-ion Battery", Journal of Power Sources, vol. 195, pp. 2961-2968, May 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prada, E., Domenico, D., Creff, Y., Bernard, J. et al., "A Simplified Electrochemical and Thermal Aging Model of LiFePO4-Graphite Liion Batteries: Power and Capacity Fade Simulations, " Journal of The Electrochemical Society, vol. 160, no. 4, pp.A616 -A628 2013, doi: 10.1149/2.053304jes.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, X and Wagner, J., "Cooling Air Temperature and Mass Flow Rate Control for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Battery Thermal Management," ASME 2014 Dynamic Systems and Control Conference, San Antonio, Texas, USA, October 22-24, 2014, doi:10.1115/DSCC2014-6001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sutton RS and Barto AG. Reinforcement learning: an introduction. Cambridge, Massachusetts: MIT Press, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
