<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275538</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Improved PHEV Emission Measurements in a Chassis Dynamometer Test Cell</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nevius</surname>
                  <given-names>Tim A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rooney</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Horiba Automotive Test Systems</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>1113</fpage>
         <lpage>1123</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275538"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A Constant Volume Sampler (CVS) over dilutes the exhaust gas sample when testing Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles (PHEV). This is because the CVS continues to fill the sample bag when the engine is shutdown. With a PHEV, it is possible to complete an FTP test with the engine running less than 20% of the time, resulting in a CVS bag dilution ratio in the range of 100 to 300. The CVS dilution ratio should be in the range of 5-25 for accurate results. At higher dilution ratios, the gas concentrations of CO, NOx and THC approach the ambient background level in the test cell. At a dilution of 100, the CO₂ concentration in the sample bag is about 0.13%, which is only 3 times the air background concentration. The measurement errors caused by over dilution create errors of 10% to 30% in the calculated mass of CO₂, CO, and NOx. Estimated errors for THC are in the range of 200%</p>
            <p>Many of the limitations of a CVS can be eliminated by using a partial flow sampling system, such as a bag minidilutor (BMD), which maintains a constant dilution ratio of 5:1 at all exhaust flow rates. A BMD dilutes the exhaust gas with pure air, so no background correction for ambient air contamination is necessary. Testing a PHEV still poses measurement issues with a BMD, because the internal combustion engine may not run long enough during a test for the BMD to acquire a volume of exhaust gas sample sufficient for the gas analyzers to read accurately.</p>
            <p>Modifications have been made to the CVS and BMD hardware and software to improve the measurement accuracy for PHEV testing. Vehicle emission data obtained with the modified test equipment is compared to data obtained previously with standard CVS and BMD sampling systems.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carlson. R. W., “Testing and Analysis of Three Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0283, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Transportation Technology R&amp;D Center, Dynamometer Database, Energy CS Prius data: UDDS. https://webapps.anl.gov/vehicle_data.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CARB 2006 ZEV Technology Review, Sacramento Municipal Utility Department, Test of PHEV and HEV Prius.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inoue, K., Ishihara, M., Akashi, K., Adachi, M., Ishida, K., “Numerical Analysis of Mass Emission Measurement Systems for Low Emission Vehicles,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0150, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ERC Technical Report: The Bag Mini-Diluter Alternative to CVS Sampling, Environmental Research Consortium, May 1, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guenther, M., Landry, M., Sherman, M., Brown, K., Wu, D-Y., “Refinement of a Bag Mini-Diluter System,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0212, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guenther, M., Vaillancourt, M., Sherman, M., Carpenter, D., Rooney, R., Porter, S., “Advanced Emissions Test Site for Confident PZEV Measurement,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0046, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Influence of Driving Conditions on Fuel Economy and Exhaust Emissions of the Toyota Prius HEV, Kim G.C., Lee Y.J., 20th International Electric Vehicle Symposium, Nov. 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MOVES2004 Energy and Emissions Input, Koupal J., Landman L., Nam E., Warila J., Glover E., Gianelli B., EPA Document 420-P-04-020, Dec. 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuel Consumption Modeling of Conventional and Advanced Technology Vehicles in the Physical Emission Rate Estimator (PERE), EPA Document 420-P-05-001, Feb. 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Austin, T. C., Caretto, L. S., “Improving the Calculation of Exhaust Gas Dilution During Constant Volume Sampling,” SAE Technical Paper 980678, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Energy Control Systems Engineering Inc., Monrovia, CA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
