<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939380</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Environmental Taxes, Cross-border effects and Government Interaction</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effect of Carbon Taxation on Cross Border Competition and Energy Efficiency Investments</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dorsey-Palmateer</surname>
                  <given-names>Reid</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Niu</surname>
                  <given-names>Ben</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>18</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939380"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Carbon taxes increase costs for energy-consuming firms and can impact firms’ ability to compete with other firms located in regions without that tax. This paper considers the effect of asymmetric carbon taxation when firms are able to adjust their energy efficiency investment levels. Using a dynamic model of firm competition, we find that endogeneity in energy efficiency levels could allow firms facing a carbon tax to significantly mitigate competition effects. In our baseline parameterization, additional energy efficiency investments non-trivially mitigates profit loss for the firm facing the carbon tax as well as spurring adding energy efficiency investments in the non-taxing jurisdiction, thus reducing carbon leakage. Strikingly, this increase in energy efficiency can reduce total energy usage by the firm in the taxing jurisdiction by more than the carbon tax alone. While the quantitative impact of energy efficiency investments on firm competitiveness depends on the nature of the industry, from a policy standpoint, the ability of energy efficiency investments to mitigate cross-border emissions leakage and negative competition effects without policy interventions such as a carbon border tax softens these two common criticisms of unilateral carbon taxes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Albonico, A., S. Kalyvitis, and E. Pappa (2014). Capital maintenance and depreciation over the business cycle. Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 39, 273–286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Anderson, S. and R. Newell (2004). Information programs for technology adoption: the case of energy-efficiency audits. Resource and Energy Economics 26(1), 27–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Antimiani, A., V. Costantini, C. Martini, L. Salvatici, and M. C. Tommasino (2013). Assessing alternative solutions to carbon leakage. Energy Journal 36, 299–311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Baker, E. and E. Shitto (2006). Profit-Maximizing R&amp;D in Response to a Random Carbon Tax. Resource and Energy Economics 28, 160–180.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Boyd, G. (2017). Comparing the statistical distributions of energy efficiency in manufacturing: meta-analysis of 24 Case studies to develop industry-specific energy performance indicators (EPI). Energy Efficiency 10(1), 217–238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Dissou, Y. and T. Eyland (2011). Carbon control policies, competitiveness, and border tax adjustments. Energy Economics 33, 556–564.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Elliott, J., I. Foster, S. Kortum, T. Munson, F. P. Cervantes, and D. Weisbach (2010). Trade and Carbon Taxes. American Economic Review: Papers &amp; Proceedings 100, 465–469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Ericson, R. and A. Pakes (1995). Markov-Perfect Industry Dynamics: A Framework for Empirical Work. Review of Economic Studies 62(1), 53–82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Green, R. (2008). Carbon Tax or Carbon Permits: The Impact on Generators’ Risks. Energy Journal 29(3), 67–89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Hoel, M. (1996). Should a Carbon Tax be Differentiated Across Sectors? Journal of public economics 59(1), 17–32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Lyubich, E., J. Shapiro, and R. Walker (2018). Regulating Mismeasured Pollution: Implications of Firm Heterogeneity for Environmental Policy. EI @ Haas WP 286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Qiao-Mei Liang, Tao Wang, M.-M. X. (2016). Addressing the competitiveness effects of taxing carbon in China: domestic tax cuts versus border tax adjustments. Journal of Cleaner Production 112, 1568–1581.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Baseline Parameterization</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Evolution of Key Outputs By Firm (Baseline Parameterization)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Baseline Impact of Energy Efficiency on Effect of Carbon Tax</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Energy Efficiency Mitigation of Carbon Tax Effects Across Parameterizations</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
