<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="research-article"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663733</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/381519</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB772204</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Is Advertising a Good or a Bad? Evidence from U.S. Magazine Subscriptions<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">*</xref>
            </article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Craig A.</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Depken II</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_1">University of Texas at Arlington</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Dennis P.</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Wilson</surname>
               </string-name>
               <x xml:space="preserve"/>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_2">University of Texas at Arlington</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>04</month>
            <year>2004</year>
            <string-date>April 2004</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>77</volume>
         <issue>S2</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2004.77.issue-s2</issue-id>
         <fpage>S61</fpage>
         <lpage>S80</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2004 by The University of Chicago. All rights reserved.</copyright-statement>
            <copyright-year>2004</copyright-year>
            <copyright-holder>The University of Chicago</copyright-holder>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/381519"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This article investigates whether advertising has a beneficial or deleterious impact on the demand for magazine subscriptions. Specifically, we test whether the demand for magazines indicates if consumers consider advertising a “bad” or a “good.” Using data describing 95 U.S. magazines for the years 1996–98 we find that advertising substituted for editorial content reduces both the quantity and price of magazine subscriptions. However, the full impact of additonal advertising on subscription price and quantity is tied to the percentage of a magazine dedicated to advertising. We show how this ambiguity is reflected in the magazines included in our sample.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
      <notes notes-type="footnote">
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn1">
               <label>*</label>
               <p>The value of advertising in magazine subscriptionsWe wish to thank Melissa Lind, Thirapan Gulyanamitta, and Onur Kececigil for their assistance in gathering the data used in this study. We also acknowledge Sam Allgood, Mike Ward, participants at the 2001 Southern Economic Association annual meetings, and two anonymous referees for helpful comments on earlier versions of this manuscript. Any remaining errors are our sole responsibility. Contact Craig A. Depken II at<email xlink:href="mailto:depken@uta.edu" xlink:type="simple">depken@uta.edu</email>and Dennis P. Wilson at<email xlink:href="mailto:dpwilson@uta.edu" xlink:type="simple">dpwilson@uta.edu</email>.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </notes>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <label>I.</label>
         <title>Introduction</title>
         <p>The need to advertise manifests itself in two forms: promoting a product’s existence and promoting the product's virtues vis‐à‐vis the competition. Kaldor (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf21">1951</xref>) argues that advertising may be a social bad if it offers no extra benefit to society when information is perfect. By focusing on advertising as a shift parameter in the preferences of consumers, Dixit and Norman (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf15">1978</xref>) predict that advertising is oversupplied in most market structures. In general, the demand for advertised goods is the point of departure in studies of advertising. However, this may ignore the direct effect of advertising on utility.</p>
         <p>The assumption that advertising has a deleterious effect on social welfare was questioned when Benham (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf4">1972</xref>) showed that advertising may cause reductions in price. Stigler and Becker (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf30">1977</xref>), building on the product qua characteristic‐bundle theory, developed by Lancaster (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf22">1966</xref>) and extended by Rosen (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf25">1974</xref>), treat consumption as a function of product attributes, information, and idiosyncratic human capital, in which tastes and preferences remain fixed over time. Rather than changing preferences, advertising influences the shadow price of consumption, thereby increasing or decreasing the consumption of the advertised goods.</p>
         <p>However, advertising is commonly delivered in a vertically dependent market: advertising firms pay for access to an advertising delivery vehicle to contact potential and actual clients. The level of advertising provided in a particular “vehicle,” such as a television or radio program, a newspaper, or a magazine, is dependent on the demand for the vehicle and the profit maximizing choices of the publishing firm and the advertiser. These vehicles represent commodity bundles of advertising and some other item, such as editorial content or entertainment. An alternative method to determine the value of advertising for consumers is to investigate the impact advertising has on the demand for the advertising vehicle (hereafter, the bundle). This article investigates the impact of advertising on the demand for magazines, which have long been recognized as bundling editorial and advertising content. Our empirical results allow us to test various hypotheses developed in the literature focusing on newspapers and magazines against a unique theory of advertising provided by Becker and Murphy (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf3">1993</xref>).</p>
         <p>Becker and Murphy allow advertising itself to be a consumption good with its own shadow price, rather than simply contributing to the shadow price of another consumption decision or acting as a demand shifter for the advertised good (e.g., Dorfman and Steiner<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf16">1954</xref>). Under their construct, consumers actively choose a level of advertising consistent with utility maximization when advertising appears in the budget constraint. In contrast with models in which unsolicited advertising must be consumed (e.g., Grossman and Shapiro<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf20">1984</xref>), the Becker‐Murphy approach allows for the shadow price of advertising to be positive (negative) when advertising is a good (bad), thereby motivating active pursuit (avoidance) of advertising. Unfortunately, Becker and Murphy’s model, as presented, has no empirical support beyond compelling anecdotal evidence.</p>
         <p>While some authors have extended the Becker‐Murphy hypothesis, there has been little empirical work focusing directly on the hypothesis as originally presented.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn2">1</xref>In this article, we provide a direct test of the Becker‐Murphy hypothesis against alternatives developed in the circulation‐industry literature. We test whether those who purchase magazine subscriptions treat advertising included in magazines as a good or a bad, with implications for magazine publishers and those who wish to advertise their product.</p>
         <p>By estimating a structural model relating the price and the quantity of magazine subscriptions to advertising, readership, and magazine characteristics (including readership income and age, readers per issue, percentage of newsstand sales, local distribution, and number of issues per year), it is possible to discern whether the average consumer is willing to pay for access to extra advertising. Using data describing 95 U.S. magazines from 1996 through 1998, separated into five genres, the empirical evidence indicates that advertising substituted for editorial content reduces the quantity and the price of subscriptions. However, the full impact of additional advertising on subscription price and quantity is ambiguous, as it is tied to the percentage of a magazine dedicated to advertising. We show how this ambiguity is reflected in the magazines included in our sample.</p>
         <p>The remainder of this article is structured as follows.<xref ref-type="sec" rid="sc2">Section II</xref>outlines different testable hypotheses about the role of advertising in circulation industries, for example, magazines. We compare these hypotheses to the alternative offered by Becker and Murphy (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf3">1993</xref>).<xref ref-type="sec" rid="sc3">Section III</xref>presents our empirical model and our data and discusses our results.<xref ref-type="sec" rid="sc4">Section IV</xref>offers concluding remarks.</p>
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn2">
               <label>1.</label>
               <p>Tremblay and Tremblay (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf32">1995</xref>) and Farr, Tremblay, and Tremblay (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf18">2001</xref>) have empirically applied Becker and Murphy’s model to the beer and cigarette industries, respectively, using industry‐level data. In these studies, the benefits of advertising to individual consumers (such as reduced search costs) are outweighed by the cost of higher prices and negative social externalities. However, in the cigarette industry, the limitations on advertising act to lower social welfare by decreasing market competition and increasing firms’ market power.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <label>II.</label>
         <title>The Role of Advertising in Circulation Industries</title>
         <p>A circulation industry is defined as a market in which publishers disseminate information on a regular basis to subscribers, either in a futures market (e.g., subscriptions) or a spot market (e.g., newsstand sales). Magazine and newspaper markets are both clearly circulation industries (Chaudhri<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf9">1998</xref>); magazines are published in fairly specific genres and sold in both subscription and newsstand form. The economic analysis of circulation industries has primarily focused on the publisher’s trade‐off between revenue generated by sales to subscribers and revenue from advertising (e.g., Reddaway<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1963</xref>; Blair and Romano<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf5">1993</xref>; Chaudhri<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf9">1998</xref>).</p>
         <p>A magazine typically bundles advertising and editorial content. Stigler’s (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf29">1968</xref>) economic analysis of bundling suggests that bundling is only beneficial if the firm can extract consumer surplus. However, Adams and Yellen (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf2">1976</xref>) suggest that bundling may increase consumer surplus by reducing search costs; therefore, consumers may be willing to pay a premium for bundles. In the context of a magazine bundle, the question is whether advertising increases or decreases the value of a magazine. Magazines are often published with editorial content targeted to a specific readership. If advertising is targeted likewise, advertising might be a desirable component of the commodity bundle. The economic theory of commodity bundling also suggests that component(s) of a bundle may be purchased, if not directly consumed, even if consumers do not place positive value on the component(s).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn3">2</xref>
         </p>
         <p>It is often thought that magazines exist to “force” people to consume advertising. Yet, some magazines, such as<italic>Modern Bride</italic>and<italic>Computer Shopper,</italic>are composed almost entirely of advertising content, while others, such as<italic>Liberty</italic>and<italic>Harvard Business Review,</italic>consist almost entirely of editorial content. Moreover, the claim that magazines must bundle advertising and editorial content to extract consumer surplus is undermined by magazines such as<italic>Shoes</italic>and<italic>Swimsuit Magazine,</italic>which are composed solely of shoe and swimsuit advertisements, respectively. Casual observation at any hair salon provides anecdotal evidence that some magazines aim primarily to deliver advertising content, with editorial content being of secondary concern. Indeed, the table of contents for a magazine such as<italic>Cosmopolitan</italic>is often not reached until 30 or more pages of advertising have been “viewed.” Such a situation does not lend credence to the editorial value of<italic>Cosmopolitan.</italic>
            <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn4">3</xref>
         </p>
         <p>If magazines “force” readers to view advertising, the implicit assumption is that consumers consider advertising to be a “bad,” thereby requiring publishers to subsidize price (and thus circulation revenue) with advertising revenues. Although some have questioned this, little empirical evidence has been proffered to support either side of the argument. Reddaway (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1963</xref>, p. 207), using data from the Royal Commission on the Press, 1961–62, estimated that at most only one‐third of advertising revenue would be available to subsidize readers. Casual observation of U.S. magazines reveals that those magazines with large amounts of advertising tend to have little editorial content, perhaps supporting the “cover‐price subsidization” argument.</p>
         <p>The investigation of newspapers and magazines started in the traditional structure‐conduct‐performance paradigm of the 1930s (Cover, Thompson, and Cohenour<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf11">1931</xref>). Early in the investigation of circulation industries, it was recognized that they provide two distinct but not mutually exclusive sources of revenue to publishers: circulation sales and advertising revenue.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn5">4</xref>Most analyses of newspaper monopolies view the end product as a bundle of advertising and editorial content and explicitly model the choices facing the publisher.</p>
         <p>Blair and Romano (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf5">1993</xref>) present a model of a newspaper monopolist in which they analyze the positive feedback of advertising on circulation. They show that the price elasticity of demand for newspapers is underestimated using traditional econometric models that do not accurately account for the feedback of advertising on circulation that, in turn, motivates more advertising. Their empirical support is borrowed from Rosse (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf26">1980</xref>).</p>
         <p>Chaudhri (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf9">1998</xref>) analyzes a circulation‐industry monopolist and shows that price‐taking behavior in both circulation and advertising leads to marginal cost pricing in both submarkets. However, market power in advertising may motivate the information provider to sell subscriptions below marginal cost. The intuition is that the greater the number of subscribers, the more a publisher can charge for the advertising included in the bundle. Similarly, Abrahamson (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf1">1998</xref>) contends that circulation levels increase the value of a given stock of advertising, thereby increasing its value to advertising firms, but claims, simultaneously, that advertising reduces the value of the newspaper or magazine to the reader. However, Thompson (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf31">1989</xref>) asserts that increased circulation may actually reduce the value of a given stock of advertising because of a diluted readership; small readerships may have specific characteristics of value to advertising firms, such as greater disposable incomes or preferences for certain goods. The dilution of these desirable characteristics could, in turn, reduce advertising revenue.</p>
         <p>The literature of circulation industries therefore provides two competing hypotheses about the role of advertising in the demand for magazines (or newspapers). Advertising would be considered a weak good if it decreases the quantity of magazines demanded and simultaneously increases the price paid. On the other hand, advertising would be considered a weak bad if it increases the quantity of magazines sold and simultaneously decreases the price consumers are willing to pay. From the point of view of the publisher, any loss in circulation revenue might be recovered, on the margin, by gains in advertising revenues (see, e.g., Corden<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf10">1953</xref>; Reddaway<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1963</xref>; Dertouzos and Trautman<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf14">1990</xref>). While this feedback hypothesis has potential merit, empirical support is relatively sparse (see Rosse<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf26">1980</xref>; Thompson<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf31">1989</xref>).</p>
         <p>The preceding hypotheses are developed from the perspective of the publishing firm. An alternative, offered by Becker and Murphy, is that consumers may not suffer but actively pursue advertising. In this approach, advertising is an unambiguous good if consumers are willing to pay to consume additional advertising, ceteris paribus; that is, advertising increases the price and quantity of bundles sold. On the other hand, advertising is an unambiguous bad if advertising simultaneously lowers the price and the quantity of bundles sold.</p>
         <p>The magazine industry offers a unique opportunity to test these competing hypotheses. The distinctly different treatments of advertising in the circulation industry literature and by Becker and Murphy allow for strong statistical hypotheses to be developed, as depicted in<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">figure 1</xref>. If subscriptions and subscription prices respond to changes in advertising in the same direction, then the Becker‐Murphy hypothesis is applicable; if increased advertising leads to greater (lower) subscription sales and greater (lower) subscription prices, advertising can be concluded to be an unambiguous good (bad) in magazine subscriptions. However, if advertising decreases (increases) subscription quantity and increases (decreases) subscription price, then advertising is an ambiguous good (bad), as hypothesized by Blair and Romano (Abrahamson).<fig-group content-type="figgrp" id="fg1" position="float">
               <label>Fig. 1.<x xml:space="preserve">—</x>
               </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>The value of advertising in magazine subscriptions</p>
               </caption>
               <fig position="float" fig-type="figure">
                  <graphic xlink:href="fg1"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </fig>
            </fig-group>
         </p>
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn3">
               <label>2.</label>
               <p>For example, Emmons and Prager (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf17">1997</xref>) investigate commodity bundling to the cable television industry.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn4">
               <label>3.</label>
               <p>Indeed, today’s reader of<italic>Cosmopolitan</italic>would likely not recognize a 1930s issue of the magazine, which started out as a public policy vehicle.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn5">
               <label>4.</label>
               <p>Buchan and Siegfried (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf7">1978</xref>) provide a detailed analysis of the vertical relationships in the U.S. magazine industry. We rely on their explanation, as it accords with the way the industry operates today.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <label>III.</label>
         <title>Empirical Evidence from U.S. Magazine Subscriptions</title>
         <p>To implement an empirical test of the hypotheses outlined in the previous section, we employ a data set describing 95 U.S. magazines for the period 1996–98.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn6">5</xref>We apply three‐stage least squares (3SLS) to a two‐equation system describing the yearly price of subscriptions and the annual number of subscriptions for each magazine. The 3SLS approach allows us to enhance the efficiency of parameter estimates by taking advantage of the information embodied in any cross‐equation correlation. We are able to identify how advertising affects the demand for magazine subscriptions, indicating whether consumers consider advertising a good or a bad.</p>
         <p>Our two‐equation system treats the quantity of subscriptions and subscription price as endogenous. Explanatory variables follow previous empirical models of circulation industries (e.g., Cecchetti<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf8">1986</xref>; Thompson<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf31">1989</xref>; Depken and Wilson<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf13">2001</xref>). In this study, we focus on the value of advertising to subscribers of magazines. The data were obtained from Media Mark,<italic>Advertising Age,</italic>the Audit Bureau of Circulation (ABC), and hardcopies of issues published during the time span of the sample.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn7">6</xref>The variables used in this study and their sources are listed in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">table 1</xref>, descriptive statistics for the entire sample are reported in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">table 2</xref>, the magazines used in the study are listed in<xref ref-type="app" rid="apa">appendix A</xref>, and genre‐specific descriptive statistics for selected variables are reported in<xref ref-type="app" rid="apb">appendix B.</xref>
            <table-wrap id="tb1" position="float">
               <label>Table 1</label>
               <caption>
                  <title>Variables Used in the Study</title>
               </caption>
               <graphic xlink:href="tb1"
                        position="float"
                        mimetype="image"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
               <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                              xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                              frame="topbot"
                              colsep="0"
                              rowsep="1"
                              pgwide="1"
                              orient="port">
                  <oasis_0:tgroup cols="3" align="left">
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="10.99pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="10.99pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="10.99pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Variable Name</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Description</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Source</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">SUBS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Annual subscriptions sold</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Audit Bureau of Circulation</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">PRICE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">1‐year subscription price</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Audit Bureau of Circulation</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">PREVADV</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Advertising pages in previous volume</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">PREVPPS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Total number of pages in previous volume</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">ADSISSUE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Average advertising pages per issue</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                              <italic>Advertising Age</italic>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">INCOME</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Average reader’s household income</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                              <italic>Media Mark</italic>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">AGE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Average reader age</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                              <italic>Media Mark</italic>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">NUMREAD</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Average number of readers per copy sold</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                              <italic>Media Mark</italic>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">ISSUES</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Number of issues per volume</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Audit Bureau of Circulation</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">LOCAL</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Local distribution (Yes = 1)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">NSBASE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">% Newsstand sales</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Audit Bureau of Circulation</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">BN</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Business and news (1 = Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">EGT</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Entertainment, general, and travel (1 = Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">HHFL</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Health, home, food, and leisure (1 = Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">SCM</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Sports, cars, and men’s (1= Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">WFP</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Women’s, fashion, and parenting (1 = Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">YR96</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Year 1996 (1 = Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">YR97</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Year 1997 (1 = Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top">YR98</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top">Year 1998 (1 = Yes)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top">Self‐generated</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                     </oasis_0:tbody>
                  </oasis_0:tgroup>
               </oasis_0:table>
            </table-wrap>
            <table-wrap id="tb2" position="float">
               <label>Table 2</label>
               <caption>
                  <title>Descriptive Statistics for the Entire Data Set</title>
               </caption>
               <graphic xlink:href="tb2"
                        position="float"
                        mimetype="image"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
               <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                              xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                              frame="topbot"
                              colsep="0"
                              rowsep="1"
                              pgwide="1"
                              orient="port">
                  <oasis_0:tgroup cols="5" align="left">
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Variable</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Mean</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">SD</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Minimum</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Maximum</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">SUBS (1,000s)</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">111.45</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">154.70</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">7.09</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1,191.12</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PRICE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">26.84</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">14.90</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">11.97</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">103.48</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PREVADV</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1,299.68</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">848.29</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">144.06</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">4,662.83</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PREVPPS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2,543.41</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1,674.57</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">572.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1,1516.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">ADSISSUE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">89.66</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">58.94</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">11.89</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">503.16</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">INCOME</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">49,532.01</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">10,852.06</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">25,937.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">81,280.50</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">AGE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">39.55</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">5.69</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">27.10</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">51.90</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">READERS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">5.37</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.18</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.17</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">17.48</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">ISSUES</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">17.27</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">13.89</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">6.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">55.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">LOCAL</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.03</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.18</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">NSBASE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">18.18</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">16.63</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.36</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">84.86</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">BN</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.13</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.34</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">EGT</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.22</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.41</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">HHFL</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.19</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.39</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">SCM</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.23</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.42</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">WFP</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.21</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.41</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">YR96</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.31</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.46</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">YR97</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.35</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.47</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">YR98</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.34</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.47</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Observations</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">268</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                     </oasis_0:tbody>
                  </oasis_0:tgroup>
               </oasis_0:table>
               <table-wrap-foot>
                  <p>Note.—The genre means do not sum to one because of rounding errors.</p>
               </table-wrap-foot>
            </table-wrap>
         </p>
         <p>The two dependent variables measure the total quantity of subscriptions sold and the total price of a subscription. Quantity is measured as the total number of annual subscriptions.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn8">7</xref>Subscription price is measured as the price of a 1‐year subscription, as reported by publishers. We note that the subscription price is universally less than the “newsstand price,” which would be obtained by buying each issue at the newsstand.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn9">8</xref>We also note that the subscription price may actually overstate the real cost of subscriptions if giveaways and promotional items are used as inducements for subscriptions. We do not anticipate this (potential) measurement error to statistically affect our parameter estimates.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn10">9</xref>
         </p>
         <p>Because the subscription market is essentially a futures market in which the actual levels and quality of editorial and advertising content of issues included in the subscription are unknown at the time of purchase, we include the number of advertising pages published in the previous year’s volume. The previous volume’s advertising proxies for the expected level of advertising in the current volume. If a magazine’s size or page count is limited, increases in advertising content might only be achieved by decreasing the (absolute) level of editorial content included in the magazine. If, in addition, the editorial content is also a valued component of the magazine bundle, a decrease in such content may reduce the value of the bundle. Therefore, the total number of pages printed in the previous volume (both advertising and editorial content) is also included. This variable controls for the size (in pages) of the magazine, implicitly controlling for the trade‐off between editorial and advertising content within the short‐run physical limitations of the magazine.</p>
         <p>Because magazines are targeted to different markets, we control for the influences of readership characteristics on the demand for a particular magazine (consistent with Reddaway<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1963</xref>and Thompson<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf31">1989</xref>). These characteristics include the average age of the readership (e.g., 28.6 years for<italic>Seventeen</italic>and 35.7 years for<italic>Car &amp; Driver</italic>), the average household income of the readership (e.g., $51,782 for<italic>Car &amp; Driver</italic>and $70,392 for<italic>Forbes),</italic>and the average number of readers per copy sold (e.g., 2.76 for<italic>Kiplinger’s</italic>and 6.47 for<italic>Architectural Digest</italic>). The readers‐per‐copy variable measures the number of readers of each copy sold, as reported by<italic>Media Mark.</italic>
            <xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn11">10</xref>Other control variables include the number of issues and the percentage of sales that take place at the newsstand.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn12">11</xref>To roughly control for economies of scale on the part of publishers, those magazines with a strictly local distribution are also identified (see Reddaway<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1963</xref>; Dertouzos and Trautman<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf14">1990</xref>).</p>
         <p>For other influences on magazine demand that are difficult to measure, we categorize each magazine into one of five genres, based on its editorial and advertising content. These genres include business and news (BN); entertainment, general, and travel (EGT); health, home, food, and lifestyle (HHFL); sports, cars, and men’s (SCM); and women’s, fashion, and parenting (WFP).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn13">12</xref>While the choice of a magazine’s genre is often a matter of common sense, for example, in the cases of<italic>Road and Track</italic>and<italic>Modern Bride</italic>, less easily sorted magazines are categorized as by Magazines.com, Inc. (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri"
                      xlink:href="http://www.magazines.com"
                      xlink:type="simple">http://www.magazines.com</ext-link>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn14">13</xref>
         </p>
         <p>The data are used to estimate a fully identified, two‐equation system that describes magazine subscription demand and captures the feedback effects of advertising on subscriptions and subscription price.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn15">14</xref>The subscription equation is defined as<disp-formula id="df1">
               <graphic xlink:href="df1"
                        mimetype="image"
                        position="float"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
            </disp-formula>where the β’s are parameters to be estimated and ε is a zero‐mean error structure. The independent variables include the price of a subscription, the total number of advertising pages, the total number of pages, whether the magazine has only local distribution, the average age of the magazine’s readership, genre‐specific dummy variables (WFP is the reference category), and three year dummy variables. We expect an inverse relationship between price and quantity demanded. Further, an older readership is expected to enhance the quantity of magazine subscriptions demanded, whereas a magazine with regional focus and local distribution is expected to reduce the quantity of magazine subscriptions demanded. The remaining variables have ambiguous effects on the number of subscriptions.</p>
         <p>To fully test the Becker‐Murphy hypothesis against the alternatives developed in the circulation‐industry literature, it is necessary to know how advertising affects the price of magazine subscriptions. Therefore, we simultaneously model the price of magazine subscriptions as<disp-formula id="df2">
               <graphic xlink:href="df2"
                        mimetype="image"
                        position="float"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
            </disp-formula>where the δ’s are parameters to be estimated and<inline-formula>
               <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\omega $ \end{document}</tex-math>
            </inline-formula>is a zero‐mean error structure. In<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df2">equation (2)</xref>, the dependent variable is the price of an annual subscription. The independent variables include the quantity of subscriptions sold, the number of advertising pages published in the previous year’s volume, the total number of pages printed in the previous year’s volume, the average household income of the magazine’s readership, the number of readers per copy sold, the percentage of a magazine’s sales that occur at the newsstand, the number of issues published each year, genre‐specific dummy variables (WFP is the reference category), and three year dummy variables. It is expected that the quantity of subscriptions will decrease the price of a subscription, whereas readership income, the number of readers per copy, the percentage of newsstand sales, and the number of issues per volume are expected to increase the subscription price.</p>
         <p>One would expect an increase in readership income to correlate with higher magazine subscription prices. The average number of readers per copy might increase the subscription price, as the publisher has only one chance to transfer consumer surplus from readers; it is impossible for the publisher to charge those who free ride on the purchase of another. This is the case in the spot market for magazines, that is, newsstand sales (see Depken and Wilson<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf13">2001</xref>). The percentage of sales that occur at newsstands introduces an element of risk to the publisher, whereas subscription sales are guaranteed. The introduction of risk into circulation revenue may cause an increase in subscription price. The number of issues in an annual subscription volume is also expected to positively influence subscription price. The remaining variables are ambiguous in their expected effects.</p>
         <p>A brief explanation of our identifying restrictions is in order. As we estimate the demand for subscriptions without information on publishers’ costs, the identifying restrictions are a bit ad hoc, although the estimator employed allows for cross‐equation correlations that enhance the efficiency of our parameter estimates. We do not expect the average age of a magazine’s readership nor a publication’s local focus to directly influence the price of a subscription. Rather, older readerships may be expected to have a greater need for home/office delivery of magazines. Local magazines, by definition, have limited geographical appeal and would therefore have lower subscription sales. On the other hand, readership income, the number of readers per copy, the percentage of newsstand sales, and the number of issues per volume are expected to directly affect the price of subscriptions (as mentioned above).</p>
         <p>The estimated parameters on the level of advertising and total pages published in a magazine allow for a test of whether advertising enhances the value of the bundle offered by magazine publishers. If advertising reduces subscriptions but increases subscription price, publishers may be targeting a specific audience willing and able to purchase the advertising information contained within a given magazine.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn16">15</xref>This would indicate that advertising is an ambiguous (or weak) good (the upper‐right‐hand corner of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">fig. 1</xref>). If advertising increases the quantity demanded but lowers price, advertising is an ambiguous (or weak) bad (the lower‐left‐hand corner of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">fig. 1</xref>). However, if advertising increases (decreases) both subscriptions and subscription price (corresponding to the diagonal elements of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">fig. 1</xref>), it would indicate that advertising is treated as a good (bad) by a relatively large proportion of the magazine audience, offering strong support to the Becker‐Murphy hypothesis.</p>
         <p>The results from estimating equations<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df1">(1)</xref>and<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df2">(2)</xref>simultaneously using the log‐log and linear functional forms are reported in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">tables 3</xref>and<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">4</xref>, respectively.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn17">16</xref>While we report both functional forms, we note that the log‐log form is statistically superior, according to the MacKinnon‐White‐Davidson (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf23">1983</xref>) test. The results conform to economic intuition and provide insight on the value of advertising in the market for U.S. magazine subscriptions. Most of the estimated parameters have the expected sign and are statistically significant. The standard errors are calculated using the asymptotic covariance matrix, taking advantage of any correlation between the two equations. We discuss the impact of advertising on subscription quantity and price after briefly reviewing the estimation results for the other variables.<table-wrap id="tb3" position="float">
               <label>Table 3</label>
               <caption>
                  <title>Three‐Stage Least Squares Estimation Results for Subscription Quantity Equation</title>
               </caption>
               <graphic xlink:href="tb3"
                        position="float"
                        mimetype="image"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
               <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                              xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                              frame="topbot"
                              colsep="0"
                              rowsep="1"
                              pgwide="1"
                              orient="port">
                  <oasis_0:tgroup cols="5" align="left">
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom"
                                          morerows="1">Variable</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                          nameend="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Log‐Log Model</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry namest="4"
                                          nameend="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Linear Model</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Coefficient</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Standard Error</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Coefficient</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Standard Error</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PRICE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−3.0959<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.397</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−15,679.70<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">215.88</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PREVADV</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−1.0590<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.270</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">15.97<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">34.97</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PREVPPS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.5795<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.446</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">63.44<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">19.14</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">LOCAL</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−1.3524<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.303</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−154,011.00<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">66,889.20</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">AGE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.3868<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.424</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">9,552.28<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2,408.94</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">BN</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.3781</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.273</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">11,858.80<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">51,425.30</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">EGT</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.5074<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.226</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1,387,727.00<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">53,359.40</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">HHFL</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.6918<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.224</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">80,673.10<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">52,511.90</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">SCM</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.5163<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.204</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">107,417.00<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">50,762.50</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Yr96</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−.5163<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.997</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−180,361.00<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">152,729.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Yr97</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−.5049<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.002</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−183,448.00<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">99,593.60</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Yr98</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−.5400<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.010</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−191,223.00<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fnb">+</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">101,121.00</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Observations</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">268</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">268</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">
                              <italic>R</italic>
                              <sup>2</sup>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.225</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.070</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                     </oasis_0:tbody>
                  </oasis_0:tgroup>
               </oasis_0:table>
               <table-wrap-foot>
                  <p>Note.—The dependent variable is annual subscriptions. Standard errors are heteroscedastic‐consistent and robust to autocorrelation.</p>
                  <fn id="tb3fnb">
                     <label>+</label>
                     <p>Statistically significant at the 10% level.</p>
                  </fn>
                  <fn id="tb3fna">
                     <label>*</label>
                     <p>Statistically significant at the 5% level.</p>
                  </fn>
               </table-wrap-foot>
            </table-wrap>
            <table-wrap id="tb4" position="float">
               <label>Table 4</label>
               <caption>
                  <title>Three‐Stage Least Squares Estimation Results for Subscription Price Equation</title>
               </caption>
               <graphic xlink:href="tb4"
                        position="float"
                        mimetype="image"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
               <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                              xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                              frame="topbot"
                              colsep="0"
                              rowsep="1"
                              pgwide="1"
                              orient="port">
                  <oasis_0:tgroup cols="5" align="left">
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom"
                                          morerows="1">Variable</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                          nameend="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Log‐Log Model</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry namest="4"
                                          nameend="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Linear Model</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Coefficient</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Standard Error</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Coefficient</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Standard Error</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">SUBS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.0738</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.049</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.68 × 10<sup>−3</sup>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.36 × 10<sup>−3</sup>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PREVADV</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−.4309<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.052</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−3.66 × 10<sup>−2</sup>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.001</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">PREVPPS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.6340<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.067</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.002<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">8.15 × 10<sup>−2</sup>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">INCOME</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.6125<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.103</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">3.78 × 10<sup>−2</sup>
                              <xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">9.58 × 10<sup>−3</sup>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">READERS</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.2998<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.056</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.436<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.372</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">NSBASE</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.0732<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.019</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.025</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.040</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">ISSUES</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.3710<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.052</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.633<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.070</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">BN</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.2618<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.054</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.723</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.288</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">EGT</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.1686<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.044</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.797</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.202</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">HHFL</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.1334<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.049</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2.948</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.973</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">SCM</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.1280<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.043</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">4.508<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.831</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Yr96</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−7.8705<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.581</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−20.255<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">7.006</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Yr97</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−7.9043<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.589</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−21.307<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">7.309</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Yr98</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−7.9076<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">1.590</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">−21.738<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb4fna">*</xref>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">7.396</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">Observations</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">268</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">268</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom">
                              <italic>R</italic>
                              <sup>2</sup>
                           </oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.746</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">.700</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom"/>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                     </oasis_0:tbody>
                  </oasis_0:tgroup>
               </oasis_0:table>
               <table-wrap-foot>
                  <p>Note.—The dependent variable is 1‐year subscription price. Standard errors are heteroscedastic‐consistent and robust to autocorrelation.</p>
                  <fn id="tb4fna">
                     <label>*</label>
                     <p>Statistically significant at the 5% level.</p>
                  </fn>
               </table-wrap-foot>
            </table-wrap>
         </p>
         <p>Focusing first on the magazine subscription equation and the log‐log functional form results reported in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">table 3</xref>, price has a negative and statistically significant impact on the quantity of subscriptions, indicating a downward‐sloping (direct) demand curve for magazine subscriptions. A 1% increase in subscription price causes the number of subscriptions to decrease by 3.1%, indicating relatively elastic demand.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn18">17</xref>Magazines of purely local distribution have fewer subscriptions. The number of subscriptions is found to increase as the age of a magazine’s readership increases; perhaps age is correlated with an increased interest in magazine content. The genre‐specific dummy variables are all statistically different from zero except for the Business and News genre. The year dummy variables are all statistically insignificant, indicating that the demand for magazines was relatively stable over the span of the data.</p>
         <p>
            <xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">Table 4</xref>reports the estimation results of the subscription price equation. Subscription prices increase with household incomes, more readers per copy, a greater percentage of newsstand sales, and more issues per volume. These results conform to expectations and all parameter estimates, except for that of the quantity of subscriptions sold, are statistically significant at the 5% level.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn19">18</xref>The genre‐specific dummy variables are all statistically different from zero. Finally, we find that the year dummy variables are all statistically significant (but not from each other) in explaining the variation of subscription prices, indicating that, over the time period of our sample, prices of magazine subscriptions were stable.</p>
         <p>The results of the simultaneous estimation of equations<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df1">(1)</xref>and<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df2">(2)</xref>can be combined to investigate how advertising affects the price and quantity of magazine subscriptions. There are two impacts investigated. First, the impact of a 1% increase in advertising content holding the size of the magazine (in pages) constant is considered. The second approach allows for the size of the magazine to change.</p>
         <p>From the results presented in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">tables 3</xref>and<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">4</xref>, it is clear that, if advertising is increased by 1% but the total number of pages in the magazine does not change, thereby reducing the amount of editorial content delivered, the quantity of subscriptions declines, as does the price that publishers can charge for their magazine bundles. Thus, advertising, when included in a magazine bundle as a direct substitute for editorial content, can be characterized as a consumer bad. However, these results are perhaps a bit inconclusive in that we cannot identify if advertising qua advertising reduces the value of the magazine subscription or if advertising is less valued relative to editorial content.</p>
         <p>It is possible, however, for a magazine to increase the amount of advertising and increase the size of the magazine (in pages printed). This would require the level of editorial content to stay the same or perhaps increase along with the number of pages of advertising. Using the statistically superior log‐log form<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df1">equation (1)</xref>, an increase in (the previous volume’s) advertising has a total impact on the quantity of subscriptions as<disp-formula id="df3">
               <graphic xlink:href="df3"
                        mimetype="image"
                        position="float"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
            </disp-formula>where A<sub>
               <italic>i, t</italic>−1</sub>is the number of advertising pages and<italic>E</italic>
            <sub>
               <italic>i, t</italic>−1</sub>is the number of editorial pages published by magazine<italic>i</italic>in the previous volume. The left‐hand side of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">condition (3)</xref>is the percentage of the previous year’s volume that was advertising, and it proxies for the expected percentage of advertising in the current volume of a magazine. We call this percentage the advertising intensity. The right‐hand side of condition<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">(3)</xref>is a function of the parameter estimates of PREVADV (β<sub>2</sub>) and PREVPPS (β<sub>3</sub>), reported in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">table 3</xref>.</p>
         <p>A similar condition can be derived from the statistically superior log‐log form of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df2">equation (2)</xref>to determine advertising’s impact on the price that publishers charge for magazine subscriptions:<disp-formula id="df4">
               <graphic xlink:href="df4"
                        mimetype="image"
                        position="float"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
            </disp-formula>where the left side of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>is the advertising intensity in the previous volume and the right‐hand side is composed of the parameter estimates of PREVADV (δ<sub>2</sub>) and PREVPPS (δ<sub>3</sub>), reported in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">table 4</xref>.</p>
         <p>If conditions<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">(3)</xref>and<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">(4)</xref>are satisfied (not satisfied) simultaneously, the effect of advertising on the value of magazines would correspond to the lower‐right (upper‐left) corner of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">figure 1</xref>, which would support the idea that advertising is an unambiguous good (bad) from the consumer’s point of view. However, it is possible that one condition is satisfied while the other is not, depending on the values of the parameter estimates obtained from the econometric estimation and the amount of advertising and editorial content in a magazine. If<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">condition (3)</xref>is not satisfied but<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>is, corresponding with the upper‐right‐hand corner of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">figure 1</xref>, then advertising is an ambiguous or weak good. Satisfying<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">condition (3)</xref>but not<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>corresponds with the lower‐left‐hand corner of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">figure 1</xref>and would imply that is an ambiguous or weak bad.</p>
         <p>Given the estimation results from our sample, we find that the 95% confidence interval for the right‐hand side of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">condition (3)</xref>is [0.403, 0.417] and the 95% confidence interval for the right‐hand side of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>is calculated as [0.673, 0.686]. It is apparent that those magazines with an advertising intensity of less than 40.3% will satisfy both<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">conditions (3)</xref>and<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">(4)</xref>. Conversely, those magazines with an advertising intensity greater than 68.6% will simultaneously fail to satisfy both conditions, such that both price and quantity of magazine sales will decline. These two possibilities correspond with the diagonal elements in<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">figure 1</xref>.</p>
         <p>Of course, other combinations exist. If the advertising intensity of a magazine falls within the confidence bounds of condition<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">(3)</xref>, the implication is that advertising does not have a statistically significant impact on the quantity of magazine subscriptions but most likely will have a positive impact on price. We characterize advertising as an unambiguous good in this combination. It may also be the case that advertising intensity falls within the confidence bounds of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>, in which case advertising has no statistical impact on the price of subscriptions, although most likely advertising has a negative impact on the quantity of subscriptions sold. We characterize advertising as an unambiguous bad in this combination.</p>
         <p>However, there exists the possibility that a magazine might satisfy<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>, that is, advertising has a positive influence on price, but not<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (3)</xref>, that is, advertising has a negative influence on the quantity of magazine subscriptions sold, corresponding to the upper‐right‐hand corner of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">figure 1</xref>, in which advertising is characterized as a weak bad.</p>
         <p>To determine the impact of advertising on the magazines in our sample, we first calculate the advertising intensity for each observation included in our sample and compare it to the upper bounds of the confidence intervals for<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">conditions (3)</xref>and<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>. In the sample, 46.26% of the observations have advertising intensities that are less than or within the 95% confidence interval of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">condition (3)</xref>, whereas 97.38% of the observations have advertising intensities that are less than or within the 95% confidence of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>. However, to determine if<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">condition (3)</xref>is not satisfied while simultaneously<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>is, the Bonferroni effect must be taken into account; therefore, the confidence intervals are expanded to be 97.5%.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn20">19</xref>Overall, 33.22% of the observations in the sample correspond with the upper‐left‐hand corner of<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">figure 1</xref>, 46.26% with the lower‐right‐hand corner, and 20.52% with the upper‐right‐hand corner (see the last row of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">table 5</xref>). However, the results indicate that, over the time period of our sample, several magazines satisfy both conditions in some years and only one condition in other years.<table-wrap id="tb5" position="float">
               <label>Table 5</label>
               <caption>
                  <title>Advertising as a Good or Bad in Magazine Subscriptions (Sample of 95 Magazines)</title>
               </caption>
               <graphic xlink:href="tb5"
                        position="float"
                        mimetype="image"
                        xlink:type="simple"/>
               <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                              xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                              frame="topbot"
                              colsep="0"
                              rowsep="1"
                              pgwide="1"
                              orient="port">
                  <oasis_0:tgroup cols="5" align="left">
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                     <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="left"
                                          valign="bottom"
                                          morerows="1">Magazine Genre</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                          nameend="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Number of Magazines in Which Advertising Is:</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Unambiguous Good</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Weak Good</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Weak Bad</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="center"
                                          valign="bottom">Unambiguous Bad</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Business and news</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">3</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">8</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Entertainment, general, and travel</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">14</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">5</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">2</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Health, home, food, and leisure</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">10</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">3</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">6</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Sports, cars, and men’s</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">13</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">3</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="0"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">6</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                        <oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top">Women’s, fashion, and parenting</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">5</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">6</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                          colsep="0"
                                          rowsep="1"
                                          align="char"
                                          char="."
                                          valign="bottom">9</oasis_0:entry>
                        </oasis_0:row>
                     </oasis_0:tbody>
                  </oasis_0:tgroup>
               </oasis_0:table>
               <table-wrap-foot>
                  <p>Note.—Advertising is characterized as a good or a bad by comparing the sample‐average advertising intensity of each magazine to the appropriate confidence intervals of the right side of conditions<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">(3)</xref>and<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">(4)</xref>from the text.</p>
               </table-wrap-foot>
            </table-wrap>
         </p>
         <p>Therefore, we calculate the average advertising intensity from 1996 through 1998 for each magazine and compare this average to the appropriate confidence intervals of the right‐hand side of<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">conditions (3)</xref>and<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">(4)</xref>.<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>reports the results of these comparisons by magazine genre. Advertising reduces the price and quantity of subscriptions for 31 magazines, indicating that, in these bundles, advertising is an unambiguous bad. However, advertising is an unambiguous good for 45 magazines in our sample. Therefore, 80% of the magazines in our sample support the hypothesis of Becker and Murphy (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf3">1993</xref>), as opposed to the alternative hypotheses developed in the circulation‐industry literature. The remaining magazines in our sample do not satisfy<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3">condition (3)</xref>but do satisfy<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4">condition (4)</xref>, indicating that advertising in these magazines is an ambiguous or weak good, in the spirit of Thompson (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf31">1989</xref>) and Blair and Romano (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf5">1993</xref>). While some magazines not included in our sample may follow the pattern hypothesized by Abrahamson (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf1">1998</xref>), we find no evidence to support Abrahamson’s contention that advertising reduces the price that consumers are willing to pay for magazine bundles while simultaneously increasing the quantity of magazine subscriptions sold.</p>
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn6">
               <label>5.</label>
               <p>Our sample of 95 magazines consists of 268 useable observations. The data are “unbalanced” because of missing data for some magazines for certain years.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn7">
               <label>6.</label>
               <p>The Audit Bureau of Circulation (ABC) is an independent clearinghouse charged with confirming the circulation data that magazines provide potential and actual advertisers. We are grateful to the ABC for making the data used in this study available.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn8">
               <label>7.</label>
               <p>As mentioned by an anonymous referee, a portion of magazine subscriptions may be repeat buyers, i.e., subscription renewals. We treat each yearly (re)subscription decision as mutually exclusive, although with sufficient data (currently unavailable) it might be possible to test for differences between new and repeat subscribers. A theoretical treatment of the resubscription decision is offered in Coyte and Ryan (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf12">1991</xref>).</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn9">
               <label>8.</label>
               <p>In our sample, the average subscription discounts from the “newsstand price,” by genres, are as follows: business and news, 53.81%; entertainment, general, and travel, 39.90%; health, home, food, and lifestyle, 29.13%; sports, cars, and men’s, 46.45%; and women’s, fashion, and parenting, 44.00%. Round and Bentick (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf27">1997</xref>) offer a preliminary examination of this form of second degree price discrimination in the context of Australian magazines.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn10">
               <label>9.</label>
               <p>It is easily shown that measurement error in the dependent variable does not affect the desirable statistical properties of parameter estimates (see Greene<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf19">2000</xref>, p. 375).</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn11">
               <label>10.</label>
               <p>Examples of how a particular magazine copy might be read by multiple people would include a doctor’s office or hair salon.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn12">
               <label>11.</label>
               <p>It should be noted that the readership characteristics reported by<italic>Media Mark</italic>reflect the readership of both newsstand purchasers and subscribers. We implicitly assume that the characteristics of subscription purchasers closely resemble the characteristics of a magazine’s total readership.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn13">
               <label>12.</label>
               <p>The motivation for grouping magazines by genres follows from Reddaway’s (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1963</xref>) study of English newspapers, Round and Bentick’s (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf27">1997</xref>) analysis of Australian magazines, and Steiner’s (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf28">1952</xref>) approach to U.S. radio broadcasts.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn14">
               <label>13.</label>
               <p>While not an internationally recognized authority, this discount magazine retailer provides a representative delineation of genre.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn15">
               <label>14.</label>
               <p>We note that our estimation is not intended as a hedonic approach (as in Lancaster<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf22">1966</xref>and Rosen<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf25">1974</xref>). We cannot quantify many of the aspects of individual magazines that would facilitate hedonic values of the attributes of magazines, e.g., the quality of editorial content.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn16">
               <label>15.</label>
               <p>In support of this intuition, consider a magazine such as the<italic>Robb Report,</italic>which specializes in advertising very expensive consumer products and services.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn17">
               <label>16.</label>
               <p>The model was estimated using panel data techniques in which groups were defined by magazines and, alternatively, by genres. We note that the results did not differ qualitatively from those reported here, although the fixed effects estimator caused a loss of all time invariant variables. The results of these estimations are available from us on request.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn18">
               <label>17.</label>
               <p>While not a direct test of profit maximization on the part of publishers, the estimated demand elasticity is at least consistent with (traditional) criteria for profit maximization. Moreover, the estimated price elasticity of demand is not consistent with Chaudhri’s (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf9">1998</xref>) hypothesis that publishers may sell magazines (or newspapers) below cost.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn19">
               <label>18.</label>
               <p>The parameter estimate on the quantity of subscriptions sold is positive but statistically insignificant. This insignificant relationship might be explained by the price of subscriptions being essentially fixed over a given year (volume). While publishers may alter the price of subscriptions during the year, the publisher‐reported price is announced once a year. Therefore, one might expect a greater contemporaneous response in the quantity of subscriptions to changes in price than vice versa.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn20">
               <label>19.</label>
               <p>This is due to the Bonferroni effect. Bonferroni (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf6">1936</xref>) shows that type I and type II errors are propagated as multiple hypotheses are tested simultaneously. In general, if α is the desired significance on<italic>k</italic>different hypotheses being rejected simultaneously, each hypothesis should be tested at (approximately) the<inline-formula>
                     <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\alpha / k$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                  </inline-formula>significance level. For example, consider two null hypotheses rejected separately at the 5% level. Both nulls are simultaneously rejected at only the 9.75% level (<inline-formula>
                     <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $1-0.95\times 0.95$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                  </inline-formula>). By increasing the significance level for each hypothesis, the product of type II errors equals the desired significance level of the joint test. Thus, we increase the confidence interval to 97.5% for the weak good and weak bad characterizations presented in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">table 5</xref>.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <label>IV.</label>
         <title>Conclusions</title>
         <p>Research on the markets for magazines and newspapers often assumes that the publisher is a monopolist in both advertising and subscriptions. Further, it has often been assumed that advertising subsidizes consumers through a reduction in cover price despite a lack of corroborating empirical evidence. If advertising reduces cover price, then advertising can be considered a (weak) bad that reduces the overall value of a magazine’s bundle of advertising and editorial content. Some models have developed the positive feedback of advertising on circulation yet have failed to test the value of advertising included in a bundle, as reflected in advertising’s impact on subscriptions and subscription price. An alternative theory offered by Becker and Murphy (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf3">1993</xref>) treats advertising as a choice variable on the part of consumers. As advertising is treated like other consumption decisions, advertising can be either a good or a bad.</p>
         <p>While seemingly benign, the differences between the publisher‐oriented approach used in traditional models of circulation industries and the consumer‐oriented approach of Becker and Murphy have important implications for publishers. If advertising is treated as a valued component of the magazine bundle, then the optimal level of advertising in a given magazine may be greater than predicted by traditional subscription models. Moreover, models that investigate the impact of advertising on the demand for advertised goods ignore any consumer surplus enjoyed from advertising included in the vehicle used to deliver advertising, that is, a magazine.</p>
         <p>This article employs a unique data set describing 95 U.S. magazines for the years 1996–98. A two‐equation system is estimated wherein subscriptions (quantity demanded) and subscription price are endogenous. Using the results from three‐stage least squares, advertising is found to reduce the price and quantity of magazine subscriptions if advertising is substituted for editorial content on a one‐for‐one basis. Whether the decline in subscription revenue caused by increasing advertising intensity has a net negative impact on a publisher’s total revenue (including advertising revenues) is not directly tested.</p>
         <p>Yet, this result alone is not enough to discern the value consumers place on the advertising portion of a magazine bundle, because additional advertising may actually increase the size of the magazine (in pages). Given the functional form of our estimation, the total impact of advertising is related to the percentage of a magazine dedicated to advertising, that is, advertising pages as a ratio of total pages. We show the ambiguity by characterizing advertising as a good or a bad for the magazines in our sample. We find that, for 45 magazines, advertising is an unambiguous good; for 31 magazines, advertising is an unambiguous bad; and for the remaining magazines advertising is a weak good.</p>
         <p>The characterization of advertising as an unambiguous good or bad does not necessarily imply that magazine publishers are behaving inconsistently with profit maximization. A magazine publisher earns profit from two distinct streams of revenue, advertising and magazine sales. Therefore, a publisher may be willing to suffer a decline in subscription revenue that is more than offset by extra revenue from selling advertising. This potentiality is not directly tested here, although it is clearly an avenue for future research.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
   <back>
      <app-group>
         <app id="apa">
            <label>Appendix A</label>
            <title/>
            <sec>
               <title/>
               <p>
                  <table-wrap id="tb6" position="float">
                     <label>Table A1</label>
                     <caption>
                        <title>Magazines in the Sample</title>
                     </caption>
                     <graphic xlink:href="tb6"
                              position="float"
                              mimetype="image"
                              xlink:type="simple"/>
                     <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                    xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                    frame="topbot"
                                    colsep="0"
                                    rowsep="1"
                                    pgwide="1"
                                    orient="port">
                        <oasis_0:tgroup cols="5" align="left">
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="14.81pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="12.63pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="6.60pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="10.03pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">Business and News</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">Entertainment, General, and Travel</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">Health, Home, Food, and Lifestyle</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">Sports, Cars, and Men’s</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top">Women’s, Fashion, and Parenting</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Black Enterprise</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>CondeNastTraveler</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Architectural Digest</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Car &amp; Driver</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Cosmopolitan</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Business Week</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Discover</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Better Homes and Gardens</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Esquire</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Elle</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Entrepreneur</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Ebony</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Bon Appetit</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Family Handyman</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Essence</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Forbes</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Jet</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Consumer’s Digest</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Field and Stream</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Glamour</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Fortune</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Life</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Cooking Light</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Four Wheeler</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Harper’s Bazaar</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Home Office Computing</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>National Enquirer</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Country Living</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Golf Digest</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Ladies Home Journal</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Inc.</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>National Geographic</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Family Circle</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Golf Magazine</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Mademoiselle</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Kiplinger’s</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>National Geographic Traveler</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Good Housekeeping</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>GQ</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>McCall’s</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Money</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <bold>
                                       <italic>New York</italic>
                                    </bold>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Gourmet</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Hot Rod</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Modern Bride</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Newsweek</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <bold>
                                       <italic>The New Yorker</italic>
                                    </bold>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Health</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Men’s Health</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>New Woman</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>PC Computing</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>People</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Home</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Motor Trend</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Parenting</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Time</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Popular Science</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>House Beautiful</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Muscle &amp; Fitness</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Parents</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>U.S. News &amp; World Report</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Premier</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Metropolitan Home</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Outdoor Life</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Redbook</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Reader’s Digest</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Organic Gardening</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Playboy</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Seventeen</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Rolling Stone</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Prevention</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Popular Mechanics</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Teen</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Scientific American</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Shape</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Road and Track</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Vanity Fair</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Smithsonian</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <bold>
                                       <italic>Southern Living</italic>
                                    </bold>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Runner’s World</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Victoria</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <bold>
                                       <italic>Texas Monthly</italic>
                                    </bold>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Sunset</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Ski</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Vogue</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Town and Country</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Weight Watchers</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Sport</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Woman’s Day</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>TV Guide</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Sporting News</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Working Woman</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Yankee</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Sports Afield</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top">
                                    <italic>Sports Illustrated</italic>
                                 </oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top"/>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                           </oasis_0:tbody>
                        </oasis_0:tgroup>
                     </oasis_0:table>
                     <table-wrap-foot>
                        <p>Note.—Bold font indicates that the magazine has local distribution.</p>
                     </table-wrap-foot>
                  </table-wrap>
               </p>
            </sec>
         </app>
         <app id="apb">
            <label>Appendix B</label>
            <title/>
            <sec>
               <title/>
               <p>
                  <table-wrap id="tb7" position="float">
                     <label>Table B1</label>
                     <caption>
                        <title>Descriptive Statistics for Selected Variables by Magazine Genre</title>
                     </caption>
                     <graphic xlink:href="tb7"
                              position="float"
                              mimetype="image"
                              xlink:type="simple"/>
                     <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                    xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                    frame="topbot"
                                    colsep="0"
                                    rowsep="1"
                                    pgwide="1"
                                    orient="port">
                        <oasis_0:tgroup cols="5" align="left">
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="5.50pi"/>
                           <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="left"
                                                valign="bottom">Genre/Variable</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">Mean</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">SD</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">Minimum</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="center"
                                                valign="bottom">Maximum</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Business and news (BN):</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> 1‐year subscription price ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">37.32</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">16.22</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">19.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">60.06</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Subscriptions (1,000s)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">52.79</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">31.55</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">16.60</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">133.27</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising in previous volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">2,249.90</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">1,133.80</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">790.73</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">4,662.83</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Issues per volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">26.72</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">17.36</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">12.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">52.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising per issue</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">103.81</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">56.86</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">40.06</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">249.48</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader age</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">41.50</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">2.69</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">36.90</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">46.70</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader income ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">60,833.50</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">11,819.49</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">32,611.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">81,280.50</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Entertainment, general, and travel (EGT):</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> 1‐year subscription price ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">32.17</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">17.59</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">17.94</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">103.48</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Subscriptions (1,000s)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">157.77</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">279.33</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">7.09</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">1,191.26</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising in previous volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">1,239.28</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">932.75</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">272.26</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">3,998.88</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Issues per volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">22.54</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">17.45</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">6.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">52.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising per issue</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">64.50</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">34.23</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">13.61</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">178.49</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader age</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">41.12</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">5.53</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">27.40</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">51.90</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader income</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">48,430.12</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">12,234.30</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">25,937.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">74,654.79</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Health, home, food, and lifestyle (HHFL):</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> 1‐year subscription price ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">21.84</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">5.52</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">15.97</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">39.95</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Subscriptions (1,000s)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">152.12</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">130.54</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">38.65</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">602.68</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising in previous volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">970.45</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">435.64</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">144.06</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">1,925.26</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Issues per volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">10.64</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">2.81</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">6.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">17.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising per issue</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">88.06</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">29.53</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">24.01</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">160.43</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader age</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">44.06</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">3.62</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">30.70</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">50.20</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader income ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">50,455.79</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">9,428.93</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">34,558.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">77,972.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Sports, cars, and men's (SCM):</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> 1‐year subscription price</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">26.66</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">17.36</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">13.94</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">81.95</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Subscriptions (1,000s)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">77.04</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">47.55</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">9.35</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">219.01</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising in previous volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">976.16</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">532.70</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">379.98</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">2,905.20</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Issues per volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">15.32</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">12.46</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">6.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">55.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising per issue</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">75.79</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">34.79</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">11.89</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">160.93</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader age</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">36.62</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">4.56</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">28.8</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">47.90</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader income ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">48,808.04</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">8,409.84</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">36,124.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">69,201.89</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top">Women’s, fashion, and parenting (WFP):</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom"/>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> 1‐year subscription price ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">19.21</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">4.34</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">11.97</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">28.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Subscriptions (1,000s)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">103.82</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">86.27</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">21.32</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">334.45</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising in previous volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">1,403.24</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">620.57</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">372.29</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">3,018.97</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Issues per volume</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">13.78</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">9.18</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">6.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">52.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Advertising per issue</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">123.50</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">94.59</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">31.02</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">503.16</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="0" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader age</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">35.91</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">5.99</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">27.10</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="0"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">48.40</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:row>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="1" colsep="0" rowsep="1" align="left" valign="top"> Average reader income ($)</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">43,322.87</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">5,606.65</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">30,104.00</oasis_0:entry>
                                 <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                                colsep="0"
                                                rowsep="1"
                                                align="char"
                                                char="."
                                                valign="bottom">58,088.69</oasis_0:entry>
                              </oasis_0:row>
                           </oasis_0:tbody>
                        </oasis_0:tgroup>
                     </oasis_0:table>
                  </table-wrap>
               </p>
            </sec>
         </app>
      </app-group>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="rf1">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Abrahamson, David. 1998. Magazines in the twentieth century. In<italic>History of the mass media in the United States: An encyclopedia</italic>, ed. Margaret Blanchard, pp. 340–42. Chicago: Fitzroy Dearborn.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf2">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Adams, William, and Janet Yellen. 1976. Commodity bundling and the burden of monopoly.<italic>Quarterly Journal of Economics</italic>90, no. 3 (August): 475–98.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf3">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Becker, Gary, and Kevin Murphy. 1993. A simple theory of advertising as a good or a bad.<italic>Quarterly Journal of Economics</italic>108, no. 4 (November): 941–64.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf4">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Benham, Lee. 1972. The effect of advertising on the price of eyeglasses.<italic>Journal of Law and Economics</italic>15, no. 2 (October): 337–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf5">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Blair, Roger, and Richard Romano. 1993. Pricing decisions of the newspaper monopolist.<italic>Southern Economic Journal</italic>59, no. 4 (April): 721–32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf6">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Bonferroni, Carlo Emilio. 1936. Teoria statistica delle classi e calcolo delle probabilità.<italic>Pubblicazioni del R Istituto Superiore di Scienze Economiche e Commerciali di Firenze</italic>8:3–62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf7">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Buchan, Russell, and John Siegfried. 1978. An economic evaluation of the magazine distribution industry.<italic>Antitrust Bulletin</italic>23, no. 1 (Spring): 19–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf8">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Cecchetti, Stephen. 1986. The frequency of price adjustment: A study of the newsstand prices of magazines.<italic>Journal of Econometrics</italic>31, no. 3 (May): 255–74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf9">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Chaudhri, Vivek. 1998. Pricing and efficiency of a circulation industry: The case of newspapers.<italic>Information Economics and Policy</italic>10, no. 1 (March): 59–76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf10">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Corden, W. M. 1953. The maximisation of profit by a newspaper.<italic>Review of Economic Studies</italic>20, no. 3:181–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf11">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Cover, John, Peter Thompson, and Vincent Cohenour. 1931. Newspaper advertising rates and circulation.<italic>Journal of Business</italic>4, no. 2 (April): 115–26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf12">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Coyte, Peter, and David L. Ryan. 1991. Subscribe, cancel, or renew: The economics of reading by subscription.<italic>Canadian Journal of Economics</italic>24, no. 1 (February): 101–23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf13">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Depken, Craig A., II, and Dennis P. Wilson. 2001. The value of advertising in a magazine bundle. In<italic>Advertising and differentiated products,</italic>ed. Michael R. Baye and Jon P. Nelson, pp. 109–28. Advances in Microeconomics, vol. 10. Greenwich, CT: JAI Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf14">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Dertouzos, James, and William Trautman. 1990. Economic effects of media concentration: Estimates from a model of the newspaper firm.<italic>Journal of Industrial Economics</italic>39, no. 1 (September): 1–14.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf15">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Dixit, Avanish, and Victor Norman. 1978. Advertising and welfare.<italic>Bell Journal of Economics</italic>9, no. 1 (Spring): 1–17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf16">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Dorfman, Robert, and Peter Steiner. 1954. Optimal advertising and optimal quality.<italic>American Economic Review</italic>44, no. 5 (December): 826–36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf17">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Emmons, William, III, and Robert Prager. 1997. The effects of market structure and ownership on prices and service offerings in the U.S. cable television industry.<italic>RAND Journal of Economics</italic>28, no. 4 (Winter): 732–50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf18">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Farr, Stephen, Carol Tremblay, and Victor Tremblay. 2001. The welfare effect of advertising restrictions in the U.S. cigarette industry.<italic>Review of Industrial Organization</italic>18, no. 2 (March): 147–60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf19">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Greene, William H. 2000.<italic>Econometric analysis</italic>. 4th ed. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf20">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Grossman, Gene, and Carl Shapiro. 1984. Informative advertising with differentiated products.<italic>Review of Economic Studies</italic>51, no. 1 (January): 63–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf21">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Kaldor, Nicholas. 1951. The economic aspects of advertising.<italic>Review of Economic Studies</italic>18, no. 1:1–27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf22">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Lancaster, Kelvin. 1966. A new approach to consumer theory.<italic>Journal of Political Economy</italic>74, no. 2 (April): 132–57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf23">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">MacKinnon, James, Halbert White, and Russell Davidson. 1983. Tests for model specification in the presence of alternative hypotheses.<italic>Journal of Econometrics</italic>21, no. 1 (January): 53–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf24">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Reddaway, W. 1963. The economics of newspapers.<italic>Economic Journal</italic>74, no. 20 (June): 201–18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf25">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Rosen, Sherwin. 1974. Hedonic prices and implicit markets.<italic>Journal of Political Economy</italic>82, no. 1 (January): 34–55.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf26">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Rosse, James. 1980. Vertical price fixing in newspaper distribution: A per se rule that makes everyone worse off. Studies in Industry Economics, no. 112, Stanford University, Department of Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf27">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Round, David, and Teresita Bentick. 1997. Magazine subscription discounts in Australia.<italic>Review of Industrial Organization</italic>12, no. 4 (August): 555–77.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf28">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Steiner, Peter. 1952. Program patterns and preferences and the workability of competition in radio broadcasting.<italic>Quarterly Journal of Economics</italic>66, no. 2 (May): 194–223.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf29">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Stigler, George. 1968. A note on block booking. In<italic>The organization of industry</italic>, chap. 15, ed. George Stigler. Homewood, IL: Irwin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf30">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Stigler, George, and Gary Becker. 1977. De gustibus non est disputandum.<italic>American Economic Review</italic>67, no. 2 (March): 76–90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf31">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Thompson, R. Stephen. 1989. Circulation versus advertiser appeal in the newspaper industry: An empirical investigation.<italic>Journal of Industrial Economics</italic>37, no. 3 (March): 259–71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf32">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Tremblay, Carol, and Victor Tremblay. 1995. Advertising, price, and welfare: Evidence from the U.S. brewing industry.<italic>Southern Economic Journal</italic>66, no. 2 (October): 367–81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
