<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE INTERNATIONAL</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26562368</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Method for Turbocharging Single-Cylinder, Four-Stroke Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Buchman</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ramanujan</surname>
                  <given-names>Devarajan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Winter</surname>
                  <given-names>Amos G.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>11</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>e26562366</issue-id>
         <fpage>423</fpage>
         <lpage>434</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2018 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26562368"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Turbocharging can provide a low cost means for increasing the power output and fuel economy of an internal combustion engine. Currently, turbocharging is common in multi-cylinder engines, but due to the inconsistent nature of intake air flow, it is not commonly used in single-cylinder engines. In this article, we propose a novel method for turbocharging single-cylinder, four-stroke engines. Our method adds an air capacitor-an additional volume in series with the intake manifold, between the turbocharger compressor and the engine intake-to buffer the output from the turbocharger compressor and deliver pressurized air during the intake stroke. We analyzed the theoretical feasibility of air capacitor-based turbocharging for a single-cylinder engine, focusing on fill time, optimal volume, density gain, and thermal effects due to adiabatic compression of the intake air. Our computational model for air flow through the intake manifold predicted an intake air density gain of 37-60% depending on heat transfer rates; this density translates to a proportional to power gain. An experimental setup was constructed to measure peak power, density gain, and manifold pressure. With an air capacitor seven times the volume of engine capacity, our setup was able to produce 29% more power compared to natural aspiration. These results confirm our approach to be a relatively simple means for increasing power density in single-cylinder engines. Therefore, turbocharging single-cylinder engines using an air capacitor can provide a lower cost alternative for increasing the power-output in diesel-powered machinery such as tractors, generators, and water pumps, when compared to adding an additional cylinder.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords</label> 
            <kwd>Turbocharging</kwd> 
            <kwd>Manifold</kwd> 
            <kwd>Single-cylinder</kwd> 
            <kwd>Air-capacitor</kwd> 
            <kwd>Diesel</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watson, N. and Janota, M., Turbocharging the Internal Combustion Engine (New York, NY: John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1982).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Makartchouk, A., Diesel Engine Engineering: Thermodynamics, Dynamics, Design, and Control (New York, NY: Marcel Dekker, Inc, 2002).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanin, K.V., Wickman, D.D., Montgomery, D.T., Das, S., and Reitz, R.D., “The Influence of Boost Pressure on Emissions and Fuel Consumption of a Heavy-Duty Single-Cylinder D.I. Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0840, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0840.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dominique Petitjean, C.M., Bernardini, L., and Shahed, S.M., “Advanced Gasoline Engine Turbocharging Technology for Fuel Economy Improvements,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01- 0988, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pawar, S., “Farm Mechanization in India,” presented to the Indian Parliament by the Indian Dept. of Agriculture and Cooperation Mechanization and Technology Division, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehta, C.R., “Agriculture Mechanization Strategies in India,” presented to Central Institute of Agricultural Engineering, Bhopal Indian Council of Agricultural Research, New Delhi, India, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhat, P.G., Thipse, S., Marathe, N.V., Pawar, N. et al., “Upgradation of Two Cylinder NA Diesel Genset Engine into TCIC configuration for Achieving Stricter Emission Norms for 19 kW to 75 kW Power Categories,” SAE Technical Paper 2015-26-0097, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-26-0097.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Honeywell Turbo Technologies, Corporate, 2015, http://turbo. honeywell.com/our-technologies/small-wastegate-turbo/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aravand, B. and Simhachalam, J., Conversion with partners at Mahindra and Mahindra Corporation, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiereth, H. and Prenninger, P., Charging the Internal Combustion Engine (Vienna: Springer, 2003).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bisane, R. and Katpatal, D., “Experimental Investigation and Analysis of an Single-Cylinder Four Stroke Twin Charged C.I Engine,” Int. J. Res. Eng. Technol. 205-210, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen H., Hekeem, I., and Martinez-Botas, R.F., “Modelling of a Turbocharger Turbine Under Pulsating Inlet Conditions,” Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. Part J. Power Energy 210(5):397-408, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nakonieczny, K., “Entropy Generation in a Diesel Engine Turbocharging System,” Nadbystrzycka 36(20):1027- 10560, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winter, A.G., “Turbocharged Single-Cylinder Internal Combustion Engine Using an Air Capacitor,” U.S. Patent 20150007560A1, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buchman, M. and Winter, A., “Method for Turbocharging Single-Cylinder Four Stroke Engine,” ASME IDETC &amp; CIE, Buffalo, NY, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">TurboMaster, “Turbocharger Applications,” 2015, http://www.turbomaster.info/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winterbone, D. and Pearson, R., Design Techniques for Engine Manifolds (United Kingdom: Professional Engineering Pub. Limited, 1999).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lermusiaux, P., 2.006 Equation Sheet (MIT, 2012).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chan, S., “Thermodynamics in a Turbocharged Direct Injection Diesel Engine,” Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. Part J. Automob. Eng. 212:10-24, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Co, Y., Yanmar Service Manual (Yanmar, 2015).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wuix Pipor Power Corporation, Kipor Power Operation Manual Version 1 (Kipur, 2010).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Depot, H., “6,500-Watt 10 HP Diesel Generator with Electric Start Battery,” 2015, http://www.homedepot.com/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turbomaster, “Garrett GT1241,” Retail, 2015, http://www.turbosbytm.com/gt1241.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Garrett, “Turbocharger Products,” 2015, http://www.turbobygarrett.com/turbobygarrett/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
