<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465656</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465660</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do Lenders Still Monitor When They Can Securitize Loans?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Yihui</given-names>
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Han</given-names>
                  <surname>Xia</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2354</fpage>
         <lpage>2391</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465660"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We examine how securitization markets affect the role of banks as monitors in corporate lending. We find that banks active in securitization impose looser covenants on borrowers at origination. After origination, these borrowers take on substantially more risk than do borrowers of non-securitization-active banks. We use borrowers' geographic locations to instrument for borrower-lender matching to distinguish the effect of securitization on the banks' ex post monitoring from its effect on ex ante screening. We further investigate direct evidence of banks' monitoring role by examining their actions following covenant violations and find that securitization-active lenders are more likely to grant waivers without changing loan terms. Our results suggest that banks exert less effort on ex post monitoring when they can securitize loans.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d57e263a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e270" publication-type="other">
This practice reflects CLO managers' intentions to generate high returns by turning lower-rated collateral assets
into highly rated securities. Benmelech and Dlugosz (2009) and Griffin and Tang (2012) document this alchemy
of credit ratings in detail.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e283a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e290" publication-type="other">
We use the link file provided by Michael Roberts for the matching. The details of the matching process are in
Chava and Roberts (2008). We thank Michael Roberts for sharing the matching file.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e300a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e307" publication-type="other">
The ABS database is collected and managed by Asset-Backed Alert. It contains the initial terms and origination
information (including underwriting banks) for all rated CDO issues globally. We thank Asset-Backed Alert for
providing this data. See Shivdasani and Wang (2011) for further discussion of this database and the list of major
CDO underwriters.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e323a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e330" publication-type="other">
If multiple lead arrangers are involved, we require all lead arrangers to be securitization active. In our sample,
43.6% of the loans have multiple lead arrangers. Our results are robust to the alternative classification that only
requires at least one of the lead arrangers to be securitization active.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e344a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e351" publication-type="other">
Additionally, our classification of a securitization-active bank varies from year to year for a given bank. This
time-varying classification also helps alleviate the concern that our Securitization active dummy might capture
time-invariant bank characteristics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e364a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e371" publication-type="other">
DealScan records loan terms at the tranche (facility) level rather than at the loan (package) level. Because we are
most interested in Term Loan B, we report terms of this tranche in each loan (package). When the Term Loan B
tranche is missing in the data, we take the characteristics of other term loan tranches (e.g., Term Loan C, D, and
so on). To confirm whether Term Loan B is representative of all of the institutional tranches, we randomly draw
300 deals from our sample and manually check the characteristics of the institutional tranches for each deal.
We find that in over 95% of all cases, all of the institutional tranches in the same deal share common features,
including maturity, the presence of financial covenants, and primary loan purposes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e397a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e404" publication-type="other">
We thank Justin Murfin for generously providing us with his programming codes for calculating the strictness
measure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e414a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e421" publication-type="other">
The mean covenant strictness in Murfin's sample is 22.51%. The higher probability of covenant violations in our
sample reflects the fact that our sample consists of only borrowers with non-investment-grade ratings, whereas
Murfin's sample includes investment-grade firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e434a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e441" publication-type="other">
We recognize that loan covenants are jointly set with prices. The looser covenants we observe, however, are not
likely a result of the trade-off between covenant strictness and loan spreads. Nadauld and Weisbach (2012) find
that securitization leads to lower loan spreads in a similar sample of loans. Based on this finding, the trade-off
theory would predict stricter covenants for securitization-inclined loans, but we find the opposite.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e457a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e464" publication-type="other">
The KMV mcxiel backs out asset volatility from equity volatility in an option theory framework. The KMV model
is widely used in empirical research of both corporate finance and asset pricing literature, including Vassalou
and Xing (2004), Bharath and Shumway (2008), and Drucker and Puri (2009), among others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e478a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e485" publication-type="other">
Specifications analogous to Columns 1 and 2 over the 24- and 36-month windows show a similar pattern in the
DTD change. In the interest of space, we do not tabulate these results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e495a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e502" publication-type="other">
For example, the change in DTD over the one-year window (i.e., the change in DTD from one year before loan
origination to one year after) has a correlation of 0.01 (with a p-value of 0.71) with the logarithm of the total
assets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e515a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e522" publication-type="other">
Although ROA is significant in these regressions, its level is the same in the two groups of borrowers (shown in
Table 1 Panel B). Therefore, the effect of ROA on DTD changes should not bias our results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e532a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e539" publication-type="other">
In our sample, the median year in which a bank initially converts to securitization active is 2004. A majority of
the banks retain their securitization-active status after their initial conversion. Only two banks, ABN Amro and
Credit Suisse, became inactive briefly after their initial conversions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e552a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e559" publication-type="other">
We include both revolving loans and term loans when identifying borrower-lender relationships. When multiple
lead banks are present, we treat the borrower as a repeat borrower if any of the lead banks lends to the borrower
before the bank becomes active in securitization.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e572a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e579" publication-type="other">
Ackerberg and Botticini (2002) similarly use geographic dummies for tenants' locations as instruments to resolve
the endogenous matching between landlords and tenants in agricultural contracts.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e590a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e597" publication-type="other">
One may argue that a firm can still borrow from securitization-active banks across regions without relocating its
headquarters. This argument, however, only weakens the predictability of our instruments on loan securitization
(i.e., the inclusion criteria) but does not affect the exclusion criteria of our instruments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e610a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e617" publication-type="other">
Even though Securitization active is a dichotomous variable, we estimate the first-stage regression by using an
OLS to avoid the inconsistency of estimates from a probit or logit model. See Angrist and Krueger (2001) and
Bennedsen et al. (2007) for more details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e630a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e637" publication-type="other">
In the interest of space, we only report the first-stage regression corresponding to Column 1 in Panel B of Table 6.
All other specifications generate almost identical interpretations and are omitted.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e647a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e654" publication-type="other">
We do not include lead-arranger fixed effects as in Table 2, because they drive out most variations of the
dependent variable in the first stage of the 2SLS (i.e., the Securitization active dummy). Instead, we control for
bank characteristics. We get similar results without controlling for these characteristics.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e667a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e674" publication-type="other">
The Securitization active dummy is not significant in these regressions, suggesting that it captures the effect of
securitization that is unique to the sample of leveraged loans. In addition, the Market CDO is not significant in
this table. This reassures us that although the expansion of the CDO market coincides with the economic boom
preceding the financial crisis of 2008-2009, Market CDO does not capture just the overall corporate risk taking
or the trend of covenant strictness during this boom.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e693a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e700" publication-type="other">
We thank Amir Sufi for providing the data for the research community. Details on the data can be found in
Roberts and Sufi (2009a). To extend the sample period of his data, we write a script to search all 10-K and 10-Q
files during 2008 to 2010 for firms in our sample using the key words listed in Roberts and Sufi (2009a). This
search yields 22,480 hits, many of which are not associated with a real covenant violation. We then read the text
up to ten lines before and after all the hits to identify an actual violation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e720a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e727" publication-type="other">
We also delete loans that are labeled as Debt-in-Possession or whose borrowers have filed for Chapter 11 or
Chapter 7, because restructuring may already have been in process for these firms.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e737a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e744" publication-type="other">
We do not include the interaction of Securitization active dummy with B-rated dummy because of a small sample
size. In our regression sample, 27 loans are from securitization-active banks, seven of which are from the BB-
rated group. In this case, the interaction term compares the likelihood of a waiver among the seven BB-rated
firms to that of the 20 B-rated firms. Therefore, drawing any statistically meaningful inferences is difficult.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e760a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e767" publication-type="other">
We fit the conditional logit model by keeping only the largest lead arranger if multiple lead arrangers are present
in a loan. We lose twenty observations because the Securitization active dummy has no variation over time for
these lead arrangers.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e780a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e787" publication-type="other">
We collect information on the duration of waivers from borrowers' SEC filings. We read 10-Q and 10-K filings
for up to eight quarters following violations that were waived by lenders. We consider that a waiver is effective
until the quarter in which the borrower's financial ratios are in compliance with all covenants; this quarter then
marks the end of the waiver. In three cases, we still cannot verify such compliance by the end of the eighth
quarter following violation and therefore treat the eighth quarter as the end of the waiver.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d57e806a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d57e813" publication-type="other">
We thank Shulan Fang for generously sharing her data with us.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d57e829a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e833" publication-type="other">
Ackerberg, D., and M. Botticini. 2002. Endogenous matching and the empirical determinants of contract form.
Journal of Political Economy 110:564-90.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e847" publication-type="other">
Angrist, J. D., and A. B. Krueger. 2001. Instrumental variables and the search for identification: From supply
and demand to natural experiments. Journal of Economic Perspectives 15:69-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e857a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e861" publication-type="other">
Benmelech, E., and J. Dlugosz. 2009. The alchemy of CDO credit ratings. Journal of Monetary Economics
56:617-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e871a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e875" publication-type="other">
Benmelech, E., J. Dlugosz, and V. Ivashina. 2012. Securitization without adverse selection: The case of CLOs.
Journal of Financial Economics 106:91-113.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e886a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e890" publication-type="other">
Bennedsen, M., K. M. Nielsen, F. Perez-Gonzalez, and D. Wolfenzon. 2007. Inside the family firm: The role of
families in succession decisions and performance. Quarterly Journal of Economics 122:647-91.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e900a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e904" publication-type="other">
Bharath, S. T., S. Dahiya, A. Saunders, and A Srinivasan. 2011. Lending relationships and loan contract terms.
Review of Financial Studies 24:1141-203.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e914a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e918" publication-type="other">
Bharath, S. T., and T. Shumway. 2008. Forecasting default with the Merton distance to default model. Review of
Financial Studies 21:1339-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e928a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e932" publication-type="other">
Bord, V., and J. A. C. Santos. 2011. Did the rise of CLOs lead to risker lending? Working Paper, Federal Reserve
Bank of New York.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e942a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e946" publication-type="other">
Chava, S., and M. Roberts. 2008. How does financing impact investment? The role of debt covenants. Journal
of Finance 63:2085-121.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e956a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e960" publication-type="other">
Crosbie, P., and J. Bohn. 2003. Modeling credit risk. Moody's KMV.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e972" publication-type="other">
Dass, N., and M. Massa. 2011. The impact of a strong bank-firm relationship on the borrowing firm. Review of
Financial Studies 24:1204-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e982a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e986" publication-type="other">
Degryse, H., and S. Ongena. 2005. Distance, lending relationships, and competition. Journal of Finance
60:231-66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e996a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1000" publication-type="other">
DeMarzo, P. 2005. The pooling and tranching of securities: A model of informed intermediation. Review of
Financial Studies 18:1-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1010a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1014" publication-type="other">
Diamond, D. 1984. The choice between bank loans and directly placed debt. Journal of Political Economy
18:689-721.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1024a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1028" publication-type="other">
Drucker, S., and M. Puri. 2009. On loan sales, loan contracting, and lending relationships. Review of Financial
Studies 22:2835-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1038a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1042" publication-type="other">
Fang, S. 2011. State independent contractual adjustment in financial covenants. Working Paper, University of
Rochester.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1053a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1057" publication-type="other">
Fitch Ratings. 2011. Bridging the refinancing cliff. Volume III, Leveraged Finance U.S. Special Report.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1064a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1068" publication-type="other">
Gande, A., and A. Saunders. 2012. Are banks still special when there is a secondary market for loans? Journal
of Finance 67:1649-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1078a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1082" publication-type="other">
Garleanu, N., and J. Zwiebel. 2009. Design and renegotiation of debt covenants. Review of Financial Studies
22:749-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1092a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1096" publication-type="other">
Gorton, G, and G Pennacchi. 1995. Banks and loan sales: Marketing nonmarketable assets. Journal of Monetary
Economics 35:389-411.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1106a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1110" publication-type="other">
Griffin, J., and D. Tang. 2012. Did subjectivity play a role in CDO credit ratings? Journal of Finance 67:1293-328.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1121" publication-type="other">
Guiso, L., P. Sapienza, and L. Zingales. 2004. Does local financial development matter? Quarterly Journal of
Economics 119:929-69.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1132a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1136" publication-type="other">
Ivashina, V., and Z. Sun. 2011. Institutional demand pressure and cost of corporate loans. Journal of Financial
Economics 99:500-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1146a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1150" publication-type="other">
Keys, B., T. Mukheijee, A. Seru, and V. Vig. 2010. Did securitization lead to lax screening? Evidence from
subprime loans. Quarterly Journal of Economics 125:307-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1160a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1164" publication-type="other">
Merton, R. 1974. On the pricing of corporate debt: The risk structure of interest rates. Journal of Finance
46:879-903.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1174a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1178" publication-type="other">
Mian, A., and A. Sufi. 2009. The consequences of mortgage credit expansion: Evidence from the U.S. mortgage
default crisis. Quarterly Journal of Economics 124:1449-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1188a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1192" publication-type="other">
Murfin, J. 2012. The supply-side determinants of loan contract strictness. Journal of Finance 67:1565-601.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1203" publication-type="other">
Nadauld, T., and M. Weisbach. 2012. Did securitization affect the cost of corporate debt? Journal of Financial
Economics 105:332-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1214a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1218" publication-type="other">
Parlour, C., and G Plantin. 2008. Loan sales and relationship banking. Journal of Finance 63:1291-314.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1225a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1229" publication-type="other">
Pennacchi, G 1988. Loan sales and the cost of bank capital. Journal of Finance 43:375-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1236a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1240" publication-type="other">
Petersen, M., and R. Rajan. 2002. Does distance still matter? The information revolution in small business
lending. Journal of Finance 57:2533-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1250a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1254" publication-type="other">
Purnanandam, A. 2010. Originate-to-distribute model and the subprime mortgage crisis. Review of Financial
Studies 24:1881-915.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1264a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1268" publication-type="other">
Rajan, R., and A. Winton. 1995. Covenants and collateral as incentives to monitor. Journal of Finance 50:
1113-46.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1278a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1282" publication-type="other">
Roberts, M. 2012. The role of dynamic renegotiation and asymmetric information in financial contracting.
Working Paper, University of Pennsylvania.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1293a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1297" publication-type="other">
Roberts, M., and A. Sufi. 2009a. Control rights and capital structure: An empirical investigation. Journal of
Finance 64:1657-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1307a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1311" publication-type="other">
. 2009b. Renegotiation of financial contracts: Evidence from private credit agreements. Journal of
Financial Economics 93:159-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1321a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1325" publication-type="other">
Ross, D. 2010. The "dominant bank effect:" How high lender reputation affects the information content and
terms of bank loans. Review of Financial Studies 23:1-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1335a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1339" publication-type="other">
Shivdasani, A., and Y. Wang. 2011. Did structured credit fuel the LBO boom? Journal of Finance 66:1291-328.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d57e1346a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d57e1350" publication-type="other">
Vassalou, M., and Y. Xing. 2004. Default risk in equity returns. Journal of Finance 59:831-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


