<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794419</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Sales Taxes and VATs</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Sales Tax Holidays</article-title>
            <subtitle>Evidence on Incidence</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ross</surname>
                  <given-names>Justin M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lozano-Rojas</surname>
                  <given-names>Felipe</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>34</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794419"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Sales Tax Holidays are temporary suspensions of tax rates applicable to certain types of goods. States frequently employ to realize a variety of objectives, including economic stimulus and arranging financial support to certain types of taxpayers. Critics of these policies often raise the concern that the intended benefits of these policies will be undermined if retailers respond to these policies with increases in pretax prices, but previous research has surprisingly found the opposite to be true and that retailers overshift the tax savings back to consumers. This paper investigates the tax incidence question using a dataset of high frequency scanner data on school supplies from 35,000 retailers across the US from 2006 to 2014. While the overshifting results of previous literature are replicated on a long panel covering 117 sales tax holidays, the richer data allows us to uncover seasonal shifts in the market around school start dates that likely biases the findings into this result. When we focus on cases where this seasonality does not occur the overshifting does not manifest, and pretax prices either increase or stay the same. Ultimately, we conclude that the concern of retailers capturing the tax holiday savings to be unsubstantiated by the data, and that the holidays’ market weighted average effect on pretax prices is zero. However, we use complementary data that demonstrate tax holidays to be poorly targeted if judged by the intention of arranging transfers to low income households or households with children. These findings should be helpful to policymakers in weighing the policy’s trade-offs.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Agarwal, Sumit, Nathan Marwell, and Leslie McGranahan. “Consumption Responses to Temporary Tax Incentives: Evidence from State Sales Tax Holidays.” American Economic Journal: Economic Policy (Forthcoming).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Belsey, Timothy J. and Harvey S. Rosen. 1999. “Sales Taxes and Prices: An Empirical Analysis.” National Tax Journal 52(2): 157-78.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Cole, Adam J. 2009. “Sales Tax Holidays: Timing Behavior and Tax Incidence.” Dissertation, University of Michigan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Correia, Sergio. 2016. “Linear Models with High-Dimensional Fixed Effects: An Efficient and Feasible Estimator.” Working Paper. http://scorreia.com/research/hdfe.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Harper, Richard K., Richard R. Hawkins, Gregory S. Martin, and Richard Sjolander. 2003. “Price Effects Around a Sales Tax Holiday: An Exploratory Study.” Public Budgeting &amp; Finance 23(4): 108-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Hawkins, Richard R. and Mikesell, John L. 2001. “Six Reasons to Hate Your Sales tax Holiday.” State Tax Notes (March 7): 801-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Henchman, Joseph and Liz Malm. 2014. “Sales Tax Holidays: Politically Expedient but Poor Tax Policy.” Tax Foundation Special Report Number 222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Mogab, John W. and Michael J. Pisani. 2007. “Shoppers’ Perceptions of the State Sales Tax Holiday: A Case Study from Texas.” American Journal of Business 22(2): 45-56.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Phillips, Mark D. 2016. “The Welfare Effects of Temporary Tax Cuts and Subsidies: Theory, Estimation, and Applications.” Economic Inquiry 54(1): 612-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Ross, Justin M. (Forthcoming). “Welfare Effects of Selective Taxation: Economic Efficiency as a Normative Principle.” Book Chapter in Taxing More Choice. Edited by Adam Hoffer and Todd Nesbit. Mercatus Center, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Tax Rate Waived in States Implementing Back-to-School Sales Tax Holidays</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Nielsen Product Modules Containing UPCs Categorized as “School Supplies”</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Selected Statistics on Market Composition by Sample</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Regression Results For Tax Holiday Price Effects, 2006-2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Regression Results for Tax Holiday Price Effects by Retailer Type, 2006-2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Regression Results for 8 Weeks Surrounding TN Spring Tax Holiday, 2007 and 2008</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Market Weighted Estimates of Tax Shifting</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Mean Per Unit Price and Total Quantity Sold for School Supplies, 2006 to 2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Mean Per Unit Price and Total Quantity Sold for School Supplies, 2007 &amp; 2008</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Point Estimates and Confidence Intervals for Sales Tax Rate by Channel</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Child Presence Among Households Participating in Tax Holiday, 2006-2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Tax Holiday Savings by Household Income Profiles, 2006-2014</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
