<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="other"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663758</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/380825</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB770109</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Notes</article-title>
            <subtitle>University Schools of Business</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>01</month>
            <year>2004</year>
            <string-date>January 2004</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>77</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2004.77.issue-1</issue-id>
         <fpage>203</fpage>
         <lpage>208</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/380825"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <title>Appointments</title>
         <p>David Aadland, asst. prof., economics and finance, Wyoming, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Yasser Abdih, instructor/ABD, Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Rajesh K. Aggarwal, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Asli Arikan, instructor, strategy and policy, Boston Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Ilgaz Arikan, instructor, strategy and policy, Boston Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Alicia D. Boisnier, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Susan M. Broniarczyk, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Nicholas Capaldi, prof. and chair, ethics, Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2002.</p>
         <p>Amelia Carr, assoc. prof., Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Jooh Chae, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Katherine Chalmers, instructor/ABD, Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Sucharita Chandran, asst. prof., marketing, Boston Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Tailin Chi, assoc. prof., Univ. Kansas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>David D. Cho, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kirsten Daniel, asst. prof., Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Douglas Dayhoff, clinical asst. prof., management, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Carolyn Dehring, asst. prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Erik Devos, asst. prof., Ohio Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Robert O. Edmister, prof. and dean, Bowling Green, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Daniel C. Feldman, prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Juan Jane Feng, asst. prof., Univ. Florida, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Willie E. Gist, prof., accounting, Ohio Univ., July 2003.</p>
         <p>Mark T. Green, asst. prof., Univ. Oregon, Dec. 2002.</p>
         <p>Isin Guler, asst. prof., strategy and policy, Boston Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Levent Guntay. asst. prof, finance, Indiana—Bloomington, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Martin Halek, asst. prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Ira Caldwell Harris, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Nancy Haus, instructor/ABD, Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Carrie M. Heilman, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Michael Highfield, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Vinit K. Jagdish, instructor (full time), Kent State, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Troy D. Janes, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Michelle Johnston, asst. prof., Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Eui Jong, instructor/ABD, Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Nikunj Kapadia, visiting asst. prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kenneth A. Kavajecz, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, May 2003.</p>
         <p>Franz Kellermanns, asst. prof., management, Mississippi State, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Elinda Fishman Kiss, teaching prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Thomas Knox, asst. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Steven Kreft, lecturer, business economics and public policy, Indiana—Bloomington, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Aparna Labroo, instructor, Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>April Legler, lecturer, business administration, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Richard Lester, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Clayton A. Looney, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Hedibert Lopes, asst. prof., Chicago, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Megan MacGarvie, asst. prof., finance and economics, Boston Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Susan Mantel, assoc. prof., marketing, Indiana—Bloomington, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Roger D. Martin, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Sean T. McGann, visiting prof., Ohio Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Adam Mersereau, instructor, Chicago, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Emad Mohd, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Robert Novy‐Marx, asst. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Vincent Onyemah, asst. prof., marketing, Boston Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Francois Ortalo‐Magne, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Hilde Patron, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2002.</p>
         <p>Andrew Pek, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Monika Piazzesi, asst. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Plummer, asst. prof., Univ. North Texas, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>C. Randall Powell, clinical prof. of business administration, Indiana—Bloomington, Mar. 2003.</p>
         <p>David Rakowski, asst. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kendra Reed, visiting asst. prof., Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Z. Justin Ren, asst. prof., operations management, Boston Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Cynthia Rex, asst. clinical prof. of business administration, Indiana—Bloomington, Mar. 2003.</p>
         <p>Javier Reyes, asst. prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>William N. Robinson, assoc. prof., Univ. Oregon, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Kenneth Roskelley, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Christopher Rump, asst. prof., Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>John K. Ryans, Jr., prof., Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Trent C. Sanders, asst. prof., Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Lee Sanning, asst. prof., economics and finance, Wyoming, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Chandra Schorg, visiting asst. prof., Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Tom Schultz, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Scott Shane, prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Marcia Simmering, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Lester Singletary, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Allen Snively, Jr., lecturer in finance, Indiana—Bloomington, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Nathan Stout, instructor/ABD, Bowling Green, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Andrei Strijnev, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Gary Templeton, asst. prof., management, Mississippi State, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Anjan Thakor, John E. Simon Professor, finance, Washington University, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Weiyu Tsai, asst. prof., Univ. Utah, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Stuart Turnbull, Bauer Chaired Professor, finance, Houston, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Stephen Vargo, visiting prof., Maryland, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Miguel Villaneuva, asst. prof., economics and finance, Wyoming, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Charles X. Wang, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Siaoxin Wang, asst. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Andrew J. Ward, asst. prof., Univ. Georgia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Yang Wei, visiting asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Toni M. Whited, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Madison, May 2003.</p>
         <p>Jr‐Ming Yang, asst. prof., Univ. Oregon, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Robert Zeithammer, asst. prof., Chicago, Aug. 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <title>Grants</title>
         <p>Joan Gillman, faculty assoc., Wisconsin—Madison; Oct. 2002 and Jan. 2003; $14,559 and $31,246; U.S. Association for Small Business Entrepreneurship.</p>
         <p>Janice Lawrence, assoc. prof., Nebraska—Lincoln; June 2003; $2,500; Hicks Summer Research Fellowship.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <title>Leaves</title>
         <p>Mukarram Attari, asst. prof., Wisconsin—Madison; Jan. 2003–Dec. 2003; to obtain industry experience and improve teaching and research skills.</p>
         <p>Nicholas Barberis, assoc. prof., Chicago; July 2003–June 2004.</p>
         <p>Sayan Chatterjee, prof., Case Western Reserve; July 2003–Dec. 2003; research and writing.</p>
         <p>David Cooperrider, prof., Case Western Reserve; July 2003–Dec. 2003; research and writing.</p>
         <p>Stephen Davidson, prof., strategy and policy, Boston Univ.; Jan. 2004–Aug. 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Luis Garicano, assoc. prof., Chicago; July 2003–June 2004.</p>
         <p>William Hamlen, assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo; Aug. 2003–Jan. 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Jonathan Hibbard, asst. prof., marketing, Boston Univ.; Jan. 2004–Aug. 2005; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Andrew Hoffman, assoc. prof., organizational behavior, Boston Univ.; Sept. 2003–Aug. 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Christopher Hsee, prof., Chicago; Autumn 2003 and Spring 2004.</p>
         <p>William Kahn, assoc. prof., organizational behavior, Boston Univ.; Jan. 2003–Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>James B. King II, assoc. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale; Aug. 2003–Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Iqbal Mathur, prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale; Aug. 2003–Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Arlyn Melcher, prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale; Aug. 2003–Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Allen Michel, prof., finance and economics, Boston Univ.; Sept. 2003–Aug. 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Linda Pastor, lecturer in business communication, Indiana—Bloomington; 2003–4 academic year.</p>
         <p>Raghuram Rajan, Joseph L. Gidwitz Professor, Chicago; Oct. 2003–Sept. 2004.</p>
         <p>Stephen Rosenthal, prof., operations management, Boston Univ.; Jan. 2004–Aug. 2004; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Linda Ruchala, assoc. prof., Nebraska—Lincoln; Jan. 2004–May 2004.</p>
         <p>Sushil Vachani, assoc. prof., strategy and policy, Boston Univ.; Sept. 2003–Dec. 2003; sabbatical.</p>
         <p>Robert Vishny, Eric J. Gleacher Distinguished Service Professor, Chicago; Sept. 2003–Aug. 2004.</p>
         <p>Kathryn S. Wilson, assoc. prof., Kent State; Aug. 2003–May 2004; faculty professional improvement.</p>
         <p>Virginia R. Young, assoc. prof., Wisconsin—Madison; Aug. 2003–May 2004; visiting Univ. Michigan.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <title>Promotions</title>
         <p>Michael J. Alderson, prof., finance, St. Louis, July 2002.</p>
         <p>Charalambos Aliprantis, distinguished prof., economics, Purdue, Feb. 2003.</p>
         <p>Christopher Anderson, assoc. prof., Univ. Kansas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Lloyd Baird, prof. and chair, organizational behavior, Boston Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Federico Bandi, assoc. prof., Chicago, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Daniel Bens, assoc. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Marianne Bertrand, prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Apostolos Burnetas, assoc. prof. (tenured), Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
         <p>David Cooper, assoc. prof. (tenured), Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Michael Cooper, assoc. prof., Purdue, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Anthony Cox, prof., marketing, Indiana—Indianapolis, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Stanislav Dobrev, assoc. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Michael Ettredge, prof., Univ. Kansas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Amy Farmer, prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Gary Ferrier, prof., Arkansas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Joseph Fisher, prof., accounting, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Uri Gneezy, assoc. prof., Chicago, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Roger C. Graham, prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Mahendra Gupta, prof., accounting, Washington Univ., July 2003.</p>
         <p>Lawrence Hamer, assoc. prof., DePaul, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Barton H. Hamilton, prof., economics, management, and entrepreneurship, Washington Univ., Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Janelle Heineke, assoc. prof. and chair, operations management, Boston Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Andrew Hoffman, assoc. prof., organizational behavior, Boston Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Ping‐Hung Hsieh, assoc. prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Erik Hurst, assoc. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Alison Kirby Jones, assoc. prof. and chair, accounting, Boston Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Jay Kim, faculty director, Asia‐Pacific Executive MBA Program, Boston Univ., Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Adelaide Wilcox King, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Nalin Kulatilaka, Wing Tat Lee Family Professor in Management, Boston Univ., Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Jing Li, assoc. prof., Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Puneet Manchanda, assoc. prof., Chicago, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>James H. McAlexander, prof., Oregon State, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Michael Michalisin, assoc. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Elizabeth Murphy, assoc. prof., DePaul, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Lubos Pastor, assoc. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Erol Pekoz, assoc. prof. (tenured), operations management, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Mark Peterson, assoc. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Joseph Piotroski, assoc. prof., Chicago, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Raghavendra Rau, assoc. prof., Purdue, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Eric Richards, prof., business law, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Dan E. Schendel, Blake Family Endowed Chair in Strategic Management, Purdue, Feb. 2003.</p>
         <p>Benjamin Schultz, lecturer, business communication, Indiana—Bloomington, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>William Schulze, assoc. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Richard Shockley, assoc. prof., finance, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>June Soloman, lecturer, business communication, Indiana—Bloomington, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Ashok Soni, prof., decision sciences, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Geoffrey Sprinkle, assoc. prof., accounting, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>George Valraktarakis, assoc. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Ramesh Venkataraman, assoc. prof., information systems, Indiana—Bloomington, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Barbara Haley Wixom, assoc. prof., commerce, Virginia, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>Aimin Yan, faculty director, International Management Program, Boston Univ., Jan. 2003.</p>
         <p>Youngjin Yoo, assoc. prof., Case Western Reserve, July 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <title>Resignations</title>
         <p>Eric Anderson, asst. prof., Chicago, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Timothy Barnett, assoc. prof., Louisiana Tech, August 16, 2002.</p>
         <p>Danielle Beu, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, July 1, 2002.</p>
         <p>Alison Butler, assoc. prof., Kent State, May 17, 2003.</p>
         <p>Debra Connelley, visiting asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Sept. 1, 2003.</p>
         <p>David Downs, assoc. prof., Univ. Georgia, August 2003.</p>
         <p>Vanessa Druskat, assoc. prof., Case Western Reserve, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Erik Durbin, asst. prof., Washington Univ., June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Richard K. Green, prof., Wisconsin—Madison, Aug. 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Govind Hariharan, visiting asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 14, 2003.</p>
         <p>Thomas Hemmer, assoc. prof., Chicago, Aug. 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Owen Lamont, assoc. prof., Chicago, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Bing Liang, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Brigitte Madrian, assoc. prof., Chicago, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Steve Monahan, asst. prof., Chicago, Aug. 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Evren Ors, asst. prof., Southern Illinois at Carbondale, Aug. 15, 2003.</p>
         <p>Anita Pennathur, asst. prof., Louisiana Tech, Jan. 1, 2003.</p>
         <p>Gil Preuss, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Vaughan Radcliffe, assoc. prof., Case Western Reserve, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Robert Sanborn, visiting assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 14, 2003.</p>
         <p>Jesus Santos, assoc. prof., Chicago, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>D. Paul Scarbrough, visiting assoc. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 14, 2003.</p>
         <p>Rachel Schwartz, assoc. prof., Washington Univ., Aug. 1, 2003.</p>
         <p>John Stephan, asst. prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Sept. 1, 2003.</p>
         <p>Pamela Steurke, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Toby Stuart, Fred G. Steingraber–A. T. Kearney Professor of Organizations and Strategy, Chicago, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Stijn van Osselaer, assoc. prof., Chicago, Sept. 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Rohit Verma, assoc. prof., DePaul, July 2003.</p>
         <p>Chung Woo Young, asst. prof., Case Western Reserve, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Scott Young, prof., Univ. Utah, July 1, 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <title>Retirements</title>
         <p>Boris W. Becker, prof., Oregon State, May 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Rogene Buchholz, prof. and chair, Loyola (New Orleans), Aug. 1, 2002.</p>
         <p>David B. Croll, prof., Virginia, Jan. 15, 2003.</p>
         <p>Gordon Fitch, prof., Univ. Kansas, Aug. 2003.</p>
         <p>David H. Gobeli, prof., Oregon State, May 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Robert Hagerman, prof., SUNY at Buffalo, Aug. 14, 2003.</p>
         <p>Robert Hamada, Edward Eagle Brown Distinguished Service Professor, Chicago, July 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Jonathan B. King, assoc. prof., Oregon State, May 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Tom Means, prof., Louisiana Tech, May 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Randall I. Mount, prof., Kent State, Aug. 1, 2003.</p>
         <p>James F. Nielsen, prof., Oregon State, Dec. 1, 2002.</p>
         <p>Patricia Pattison, prof., Wyoming, May 17, 2003.</p>
         <p>Ganas K. Rakes, prof. and O'Bleness Chair, Ohio Univ., June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Linus Schrage, prof., Chicago, Sept. 2003.</p>
         <p>Donald P. Schwab, prof., Wisconsin—Madison, June 30, 2003.</p>
         <p>Florence C. Sharp, prof., Ohio Univ., Aug. 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>John Shaver, assoc. prof., Louisiana Tech, May 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Maurice Tassin, assoc. prof., Louisiana Tech, May 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>Phillip H. Taylor, prof., Arkansas, May 18, 2003.</p>
         <p>Samuel G. Taylor, prof., Wyoming, May 17, 2003.</p>
         <p>George Tiao, W. Allen Wallace Professor, Chicago, Aug. 31, 2003.</p>
         <p>James S. Trieschmann, prof., Univ. Georgia, June 2003.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <title>Deaths</title>
         <p>Barbara E. Kovach, prof., Rutgers; July 28, 2003; Princeton, NJ.</p>
      </sec>
   </body>
</article>
