<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278299</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Measurement of Equivalence Ratio in a Light-Duty Low Temperature Combustion Diesel Engine by Planar Laser Induced Fluorescence of a Fuel Tracer</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sahoo</surname>
                  <given-names>Dipankar</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Petersen</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miles</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278288</issue-id>
         <fpage>2312</fpage>
         <lpage>2325</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278299"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The spatial distribution of the mixture equivalence ratio within the squish volume is quantified under non-combusting conditions by planar laser induced fluorescence (PLIF) of a fuel tracer (toluene). The measurements were made in a single-cylinder, direct-injection, light-duty diesel engine at conditions matched to an early-injection low temperature combustion mode. A fuel amount corresponding to a low load (3.0 bar indicated mean effective pressure) operating condition was introduced with a single injection. Data were acquired during the mixture preparation period from near the start of injection (−22.5° aTDC) until the crank angle where the start of high-temperature heat release normally occurs (−5° aTDC). Despite the opposing squish flow, the fuel jets penetrate through the squish region to the cylinder bore. Although rapid mixing is observed in the head of each jet, rich regions remain at the head at the start of high-temperature heat release. In contrast, the fuel mixture is generally lean in the clearance volume above the bowl, though near-stoichiometric pockets are observed near the bowl rim. Significant pockets of mixture in the central clearance volume, and between the jets in the squish volume, are sufficiently lean that complete oxidation is unlikely.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I.W., Colban, W.F., Miles, P.C., Park, S.W., Foster, D.E., Reitz, R.D., “Sources of UHC Emissions from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” International Journal of Engines, V118-3, Vol. 2(1), pp 1265-1289, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Colban, W., Miles, P., Park, S. et al., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Dilution-Controlled Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):411-430, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-24-0043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J.E., “An Investigation into Lowest Acceptable Combustion Temperatures for Hydrocarbon Fuels in HCCI Engines,” Proc. of the Combustion Institute, vol. 30, pp.2719-2726, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I.W., Colban, W.F., Miles, P.C., Park, S.W., Foster, D.E., Reitz, R.D., Aronsson, U., Andersson, Ö., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Late-Injection Low Temperature Combustion,” Proceedings of ASME ICEF2009, ICEF2009-14030, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Ekoto, I., Colban, W., and Miles, P., “In-cylinder CO and UHC Imaging in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine during PPCI Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):933-956, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Ekoto, I., and Miles, P., “Optical Investigation of UHC and CO Sources from Biodiesel Blends in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1): 414-434, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0862.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Ekoto, I., and Miles, P., “An Investigation into the Effects of Fuel Properties and Engine Load on UHC and CO Emissions from a Light-Duty Optical Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):38-55, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1470.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koban, W. and Schulz, C., “Toluene Laser-Induced Fluorescence (LIF) Under Engine-Related Pressures, Temperatures and Oxygen Mole Fractions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2091, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2091.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fansler, T., French, D., and Drake, M., “Fuel Distributions in a Firing Direct-Injection Spark-Ignition Engine Using Laser-Induced Fluorescence Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 950110, 1995, doi: 10.4271/950110.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greenhalgh, A.D., Bryce, F.D., Lockett, D. R., and Harding, C. S., “Development of Planar Laser Induced Fluorescence for Fuel: Application to Gas Turbine Combustion,” in AGARD PEP symposium on “Advanced non-intrusive instrumentation for propulsion engines”, Brussels, Belgium, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hentschel, W., Block, B., Hovestadt, T., Meyer, H. et al., “Optical Diagnostics and CFD-Simulations to Support the Combustion Process Development of the Volkswagen FSI® Direct-Injection Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3648, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3648.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L., and Idicheria, C., “End-of-Injection Over-Mixing and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions in Low-Temperature-Combustion Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0907, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., Hultqvist, A., Särner, G. et al., “Simultaneous Formaldehyde and Fuel-Tracer LIF Imaging in a High-Speed Diesel Engine With Optically Accessible Realistic Combustion Chamber,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-24-008, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-24-008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, C., Gronki, J., and Andersson, S., “Multi-Species Laser-Based Imaging Measurements in a Diesel Spray,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1917, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1917.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, T., Beckman, M., Farrell, P., and Ghandhi, J., “Evaporating Spray Concentration Measurements from Small and Medium Bore Diesel Injectors,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0219, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W., Kim, D., Miles, P., Oh, S. et al., “A Detailed Comparison of Emissions and Combustion Performance Between Optical and Metal Single-Cylinder Diesel Engines at Low Temperature Combustion Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):505-519, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scultz, C. and Sick, V., “Tracer-LIF Diagnostics: Quantitative Measurement of Fuel Concentration, Temperature, and A/F Ratio in Practical Combustion Systems,” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci, vol. 31, pp 75-121, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koban, W., Koch, J. D., Hanson, R. K., and Schultz, C., “Absorption and Fluorescence of Toluene Vapor at Elevated Temperatures,” Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 6, pp-2940-2945, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothamer, D., Snyder, J., Hanson, R., and Steeper, R., “Two-Wavelength PLIF Diagnostic for Temperature and Composition,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):520-533, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1067.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wermuth, N. and Sick, V., “Absorption and Fluorescence Data of Acetone, 3-Pentanone, Biacetyl, and Toluene at Engine-Specific Combinations of Temperature and Pressure,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2090, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2090.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Ekoto, I., and Miles, P., “Effect of Fuel properties on UHC and CO Emissions from Partially Premixed Combustion,” Engine Combustion Processes (10th Congress), Leipertz, A. Ed., Haus der Technik, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arai, M., Amagai, K., and Ebara, T., “Attitude Control of a Diesel Spray Under the Coanda Effect,” SAE Technical Paper 941923, 1994, doi: 10.4271/941923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
