<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">21</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830618</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830624</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>NEW TRENDS AND DEVELOPMENTS IN EXPORT CREDIT INSURANCE / NOUVELLES TENDANCES ET DÉVELOPPEMENT DE L'ASSURANCE EXPORT</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Carlo Federico</given-names>
                  <surname>Cattani</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1997</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>317</fpage>
         <lpage>326</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830624"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The business environment and marketplace are evolving rapidly as a result of fundamental changes in the economic and political environment in key regions. The growth in international trade is leading to a greater dependence of importers and exporters upon trade finance institutions. Since the early 1990s, both exporters and importers have benefited from a wide range of possibilities to meet their needs because of the liberalization of financial services. The globalization of the financial institutions is particularly evident in the sector of credit insurance. The unsatisfactory level of past export credit activity, the persistent losses in many areas and the emergence of private insurers has forced export credit agencies to re-examine their export promotion approach and to find ways to balance their operations. As a result of these significant changes, Governments are gradually restructuring their State-sponsored export credit insurance programmes by privatising part of their activities. In particular, the private sector is playing a major role in the short-term export credit insurance. Le monde des affaires et les marchés évoluent rapidement face aux changements économiques et politiques qui ont lieu dans nombreuses régions du monde. La croissance du commerce international augmente la dépendance des importateurs et exportateurs des institutions financières. Depuis les années '90 les exportateurs et les importateurs ont bénéficié de la libéralisation des services financiers qui a apportée des nouveaux moyens et opportunités de financement. La globalisation des institutions financières est particulièrement évidente dans le secteur de l'assurance du crédits export. Le déception à l'égards des activités passées, les pertes persistantes et l'émergence des assureurs privés ont conduit les institutions spécialisées dans l'assurance des exportations a reexaminer leur approche et envisager de nouvelles stratégies pour accomplir leur fonctions. Comme résultat de ces profonds changements, les gouvernements restructurent graduellement leur programmes de soutien à l'assurance export à travers la privatisation d'une partie de leurs activités. En particulier, le secteur privé joue un rôle de plus en plus important dans l'assurance des crédit à court terme.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e107a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e111" publication-type="other">
International Trade Finance: issue No 261,10/May/1996, p:2</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d8e117" publication-type="other">
issue No 252, 15/December/1995, p:11 -13.</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d8e123" publication-type="other">
issue No 251, 1/December/1995, p:5-6.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e130a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e134" publication-type="other">
Le MOCI: issue No 1225, 21-27/March/1996, p:29.</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d8e140" publication-type="other">
issue No 1222, 29/February/1996-6/March/196,p:37.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e147a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e151" publication-type="other">
Officially Supported Export Credits Recent Development and Prospects, World economic and financial surveys,
prepared by Michael G. Khun, Balazs Horvath, Christopher J. Jarvis, IMF Publications, March 1995.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e161a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e165" publication-type="other">
Project and Trade Finance Handbook 1996, Euromoney Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e173a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e177" publication-type="other">
Project and Trade Finance: issue No 155, March 1996, p:17.</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d8e183" publication-type="other">
issue No 154, February 1996, p:35-37.</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d8e189" publication-type="other">
issue No 150, October 1995, p:7-9, 38-41.</mixed-citation>
            <mixed-citation id="d8e195" publication-type="other">
issue No 149, September 1995, p:4-8.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e202a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e206" publication-type="other">
World Trade Report (2nd quarter 1996), Global Economic, The Economist Intelligence Unit (b.U.I) Publications.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


