<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794461</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Financial Reporting for Taxes</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The sources of declining effective tax rates for multinational and domestic firms</article-title>
            <subtitle>Insight from effective tax rate reconciliations</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Drake</surname>
                  <given-names>Katharine</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hamilton</surname>
                  <given-names>Russ</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lusch</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephen J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>62</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794461"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Using a large, hand-collected data set of firms’ effective tax rate (ETR) reconciliation disclosures, we identify the specific items that drive changes in firms’ GAAP ETRs over time. Our data provides insight into the frequency, tax rate benefit, and dollar benefit of specific tax rate reconciliation items as well as the types of firms affected by various provisions of the tax law (e.g., research tax credit, manufacturing deduction, foreign ETR benefits, etc.). We find that the decline in U.S. multinational (MNE) firms’ ETRs over our sample period arises from a combination of higher levels of income outside the U.S. and declining tax rates overseas, as well as a decline in effective state income tax rates as firms recognize higher levels of income outside the jurisdiction of state taxing authorities. Our analysis suggests that the observed decline in domestic firms’ ETRs arises from valuation allowance releases, which do not reflect declining tax burdens, but rather arise because of the exclusion of loss years from the analysis. We also identify industry, growth, and size differences in ETR component trends over time. Our results provide more granular insight into how ETRs have changed over time, as well as provide insight as to the heterogeneous impact of various income tax rules.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Ayers, B. C., C. M. Schwab, and S. Utke. 2015. Noncompliance with mandatory disclosure requirements: The magnitude and determinants of undisclosed permanently reinvested earnings. The Accounting Review 90 (1):59-93.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bauman, C. C., M. P. Bauman, and R. F. Halsey. 2001. Do firms use the deferred tax asset valuation allowance to manage earnings? Journal of the American Taxation Association 23 (s-1):27-48.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Brock, N., R. Clemons, and A. Nowak. 2017. A Reexamination of U.S. Corporate Tax Avoidance over the Past Twenty-Five Years: Estimating Corporate Tax Avoidance with Accounting-Based Measures: Working paper, Eastern Michigan University.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Chychyla, R., D. Falsetta, and S. Ramnath. 2017. Determinants and Consequences of Presentation Format: The Case of ETR Reconciliations: Working paper, University of Miami.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Chyz, J., L. Luna, and H. Smith. 2016. Implicit Taxes of US Domestic and Multinational Firms Over the Past Quarter-Century: Working paper, University of Tennessee.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Dharmapala, D. 2014. What do we know about base erosion and profit shifting? A review of the empirical literature. Fiscal Studies 35 (4):421-448.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Dyreng, S., M. Hanlon, E. Maydew, and J. Thornock. 2017. Changes in Corporate Effective Tax Rates Over the Past 25 Years. Journal of Financial Economics 124 (3):441-463.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Dyreng, S. D., M. Hanlon, and E. L. Maydew. 2008. Long-run corporate tax avoidance. The Accounting Review 83 (1):61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Dyreng, S. D., B. P. Lindsey, and J. R. Thornock. 2013. Exploring the role Delaware plays as a domestic tax haven. Journal of Financial Economics 108 (3):751-772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Edwards, A., A. Kubata, and T. Shevlin. 2017. The Decreasing Trend in Cash Effective Tax Rates: Working paper, University of California at Irvine.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Fox, W. F., and L. Luna. 2005. Do limited liability companies explain declining state corporate tax revenues? Public Finance Review 33 (6):690-720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Gaertner, F., S. K. Laplante, and D. Lynch. 2016. Trends in the Sources of Permanent and Temporary Book-TaxDifferences during the Schedule M-3Era. National Tax Journal 69 (4):785-808.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Graham, J. R., M. Hanlon, T. Shevlin, and N. Shroff. 2013. Incentives for tax planning and avoidance: Evidence from the field. The Accounting Review 89 (3):991-1023.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Gravelle, J. G. 2014. International Corporate Tax Rate Comparisions and Policy Implications (CRS Report R41743). Washington, DC: Congressional Research Service, 1-29.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Gupta, S., and K. Newberry. 1997. Determinants of the variability in corporate effective tax rates: Evidence from longitudinal data. Journal of Accounting and Public Policy 16 (1):1-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Hanlon, M., and S. Heitzman. 2010. A review of tax research. Journal of Accounting and Economics 50 (2):127-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Hanlon, M., L. Mills, and J. Slemrod. 2005. An Empirical Examination of Corporate Tax Noncompliance. In Taxing Corporate Income in the 21st Century, edited by A. Auerbach, J. R. Hines and J. Slemrod. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Heider, F., and A. Ljungqvist. 2015. As certain as debt and taxes: Estimating the tax sensitivity of leverage from state tax changes. Journal of Financial Economics 118 (3):684-712.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">McGill, G. A., and E. Outslay. 2004. Lost in translation: Detecting tax shelter activity in financial statements. National Tax Journal:739-756.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Mills, L., M. M. Erickson, and E. L. Maydew. 1998. Investments in tax planning. Journal of the American Taxation Association 20 (1):1-20.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Minnick, K., and T. Noga. 2010. Do corporate governance characteristics influence tax management? Journal of Corporate Finance 16 (5):703-718.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Omer, T. C., K. H. Molloy, and D. A. Ziebart. 1993. An investigation of the firm size-effective tax rate relation in the 1980s. Journal of Accounting, Auditing &amp; Finance 8 (2):167-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Rego, S. O. 2003. Tax-avoidance activities of US multinational corporations. Contemporary Accounting Research 20 (4):805-833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Shackelford, D., and J. Slemrod. 1998. The revenue consequences of using formula apportionment to calculate US and foreign-source income: a firm-level analysis. International Tax and Public Finance 5 (1):41-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Towery, E. M. 2017. Unintended consequences of linking tax return disclosures to financial reporting for income taxes: Evidence from Schedule UTP. The Accounting Review 92 (5):201-226.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>APPENDIX A:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Example Tax Rate Reconciliation Disclosure</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>ETR by Year, All Firms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>ETR by Year: MNE=1 versus MNE=0</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>ETR excluding the effect of International Operations and State Taxes by Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>ETR excluding the effect of Valuation Allowances by FYear</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Partitioning the International ETR Effect into foreign tax rate differences and percentage of international income differences</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>VA trends for MNE = 0</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Sample Selection</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>ETR Components by Industry</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>ETR Time Trends</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Time Trends in Adjusted ETR</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Partitioning the International ETR Effect into Rate and Income Components</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-14">
            <p>Examining the source of VA ETR effect</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8 –</label>
         <caption id="ca-15">
            <p>ETR Time trends – Cross-sectional analysis</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
