<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">12</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830142</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830146</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>RURAL CREDIT POLICY: DO WE NEED TO TARGET? / LA POLITIQUE DE CRÉDIT RURAL: LES OBJECTIFS SONT-ILS NÉCESSAIRES?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gilberto M.</given-names>
                  <surname>Lianto</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1988</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>145</fpage>
         <lpage>161</lpage>
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830146"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The present market-orientation of Philippine rural credit policy brings a new era to the country's rural finance. Previous years saw the proliferation of selective and highly subsidized credit policy which led to the decline of the formal financial system in the rural areas. The Philippine experiment with loan targeting and subsidized credit was costly; its accomplishment with respect to the desired goal of increasing rural output and farmer incomes is open to question. This paper argues that (a) loan or credit targeting does not work, (b) the government has no comparative advantage in the lending business and should stay out of it and (c) the government should, however, install the appropriate economic and financial environment to induce greater bank lending to the rural economy. It discusses recent developments in Philippine rural financial markets which complement the present market-oriented rural credit policy. It concludes by pointing out that rural development is a general equilibrium problem and is better addressed by a systems approach. L'orientation actuelle de la politique de crédit rural aux Philippines axée sur la valorisation des forces du marché ouvre dans le domaine financier une perspective nouvelle pour les pays en voie de développement. Dans les années précédentes on a pu constater une prolifération de politiques de crédit de nature sélective basée sur l'octroi de très fortes subventions. L'expérience des Philippines de crédit subventionné et de fixation des montants des prêts s'est révélé coûteuse. En outre, elle peut alimenter une certaine perplexité sur les résultats en ce qui concerne l'augmentation de la production rurale et l'amélioration des revenus des exploitations agricoles. L'article met en lumière a) que l'objectif en terme de prêts ou de crédit ne fonctionne pas b) que le gouvernement ne jouit pas d'un avantage comparé dans le secteur des prêts et donc devrait s'abstenir d'intervenir et c) qu'au contraire le gouvernement devrait maintenir un environnement économique et social stimulant les banques en vue d'offrir des prêts à l'économie rurale. L'article, en deuxième lieu, analyse l'évolution la plus récente des marchés financiers aux Philippines qui soutiennent la politique actuelle de crédit rural axée sur le forces du marché. Enfin, on conclut en observant que le développement rural est un problème d'équilibre économique général et qu'il doit être envisagé et traité par une approche de systèmes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e144a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e151" publication-type="other">
Herdt and Gonzalez (1981)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e158a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e165" publication-type="other">
Osuntogun
and Oludimu (1981)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e175a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e182" publication-type="other">
Gilberto M. Llanto, «Report on the Asia and Pacific Regional Agricultural Credit Association Regional
Experts Consultation on the Survey of Self-Help Groups», Agricultural Credit Policy Council August 4, 1987.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e201a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e205" publication-type="other">
Adera, A., «Agricultural Credit and the Mobilization of Resources in Rural Africa», Savings and Development,
XI, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e215a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e219" publication-type="other">
Esguerra, E., The Redistribute Potential of the Masagana-99 Credit Subsidy, unpublished masters thesis, Univer-
sity of the Philippines, 1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e229a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e233" publication-type="other">
Floro, S., «Technical Change and the Structure of Informal Credit Markets*, Occasional Paper No. 1352, The
Ohio State University, May, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e243a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e247" publication-type="other">
Graham, D., «A Review of the Rehabilitation Package for Rural Banks and the Creation of the CALF Fund*,
Occasional Paper, No. 1357, The Ohio State University, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e258a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e262" publication-type="other">
Gonzalez-Vega, C, interest Rate Restrictions and Income Distribution*, American Journal of Agricultural
Economics, Vol. 59, 1977.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e272a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e276" publication-type="other">
Herdt, R. and Gonzales, L., «Reaction to A Study on the Benefits and Costs of Masagana-99 Program*, Paper
presented at the Fifth National Agricultural Credit Workshop, March, 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e286a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e290" publication-type="other">
Lamberte, M. and Lim, J., «Rural Financial Markets: a Review of Literature*, Staff Paper No. 87-02, Philippine
Institute of Development Studies, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e300a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e304" publication-type="other">
Llanto, G.M., «Recent Term Transformation Activity of Commercial Banks: Some Implications for Agricultural
Lending*, Central Bank Review, October, 1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e314a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e318" publication-type="other">
Llanto, G. M., Balance of Payments Crisis, Speculative Attacks and the Collapse of a Fixed Exchange Rate Regime:
An Empirical Analysis, unpublished doctoral dissertation, University of the Philippines, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e328a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e332" publication-type="other">
Llanto, G.M., «Report on the Asian and Pacific Regional Agricultural Credit Association (APRACA) Regional Ex-
perts Consultation on the Survey of Self-Help Groups (SHGs)», Agricultural Credit Policy Council (ACPC),
August 4, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e346a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e350" publication-type="other">
Meyer, R., «Rural Finance in the Philippines: Recent Changes and Priority Issues*, Occasional Paper No. 1358,
The Ohio State University, June, 1987.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e360a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e364" publication-type="other">
Meyer, R., «Financing Rural non-farm Enterprises in Low Income Countries*, Financing Agriculture, 1979.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e371a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e375" publication-type="other">
Neri, P. and Llanto, G., "Agricultural Credit Subsidy*, Central Bank Review, October, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e382a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e386" publication-type="other">
Osuntogun, A. and Oludinu, O., «Extending Agricultural Credit through Public Institutions in Nigeria*, Savings
and Development, V, 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e396a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e400" publication-type="other">
Padmanabhan, K., «Credit Planning for Rural Development: An Approach», Savings and Development, VI, 1982.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e407a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e411" publication-type="other">
Sacay, 0., Agabin, M., and Tanchoco, C, Small Farmer Credit Dilemma, Technical Board for Agricultural Credit,
Manila, 1985.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e422a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e426" publication-type="other">
Takagi, S., «Rediscount Policy and Official Capital Flows», Journal of Money, Credit and Banking, Vol. 18, May,
1986.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e436a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e440" publication-type="other">
Tolentino, V.B.J., «Current Imperatives and Developments in Philippine Agricultural Credit Policy», Occasional
Paper No. 1324, The Ohio State University, March, 1987 (a).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e450a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e454" publication-type="other">
Tolentino, V.B.J., «Thirty Three Facts About Agricultural Credit», Agricultural Credit Policy Council, April, 1987 (b).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e461a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e465" publication-type="other">
Technical Board for Agricultural Credit, «A Study on the Benefits and Costs of the Masagana-99 Program», Manila
1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


