<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284793</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Experimental Investigation of Dual-Fuel Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine by In-Cylinder Blending of Ethanol and Diesel</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Heuser</surname>
                  <given-names>Benedikt</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute for Combustion Engines, RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kremer</surname>
                  <given-names>Florian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute for Combustion Engines, RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pischinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefan</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Institute for Combustion Engines, RWTH Aachen University</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rohs</surname>
                  <given-names>Hans</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Holderbaum</surname>
                  <given-names>Bastian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Körfer</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>FEV GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>11</fpage>
         <lpage>25</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284793"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study investigated dual-fuel operation with a light duty Diesel engine over a wide engine load range. Ethanol was hereby injected into the intake duct, while Diesel was injected directly into the cylinder. At low loads, high ethanol shares are critical in terms of combustion stability and emissions of unburnt hydrocarbons. As the load increases, the rates of heat release become problematic with regard to noise and mechanical stress. At higher loads, an advanced injection of Diesel was found to be beneficial in terms of combustion noise and emissions. For all tests, engine-out NOₓ emissions were kept within the EU-6.1 limit.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bression, G., Soleri, D., Savy, S., Dehoux, S. et al., “A Study of Methods to Lower HC and CO Emissions in Diesel HCCI,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):37-49, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., “Diesel-Fueled HCCI Engines” from “Homogenous Charge Compression Ignition (HCCI) Engines,” SAE International, Warrendale, PA, ISBN 978-0-7680-1123-4, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Operating a Heavy-Duty Direct-Injection Compression-Ignition Engine with Gasoline for Low Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1442, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1442</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P., Schleyer, C., Duffy, K., Hardy, W., et al., “Effects of Fuel Property Changes on Heavy-Duty HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0191, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0191</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J., Benajes, J., García, A., and Monsalve-Serrano, J., “The role of in-cylinder gas temperature and oxygen concentration over low load reactivity controlled compression ignition combustion efficiency,” Energy (2014), http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.energy2014.10.080</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D., Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., and Reitz, R., “Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Heavy-Duty Engine Operation at Mid-and High-Loads with Conventional and Alternative Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0363, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0363.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., Kaddatz, J. et al., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion in Light- and Heavy-Duty Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):360-374, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0357</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Kokjohn, S., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “An Experimental Investigation of Fuel Reactivity Controlled PCCI Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):700-716, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Muether, M., Lamping, M., Kolbeck, A., Cracknell, R. et al., “Advanced Combustion for Low Emissions and High Efficiency Part 1: Impact of Engine Hardware on HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2008- 01-2405, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Muether, M. “Einflüsse alternativer Kraftstoffe auf die dieselmotorische Verbrennung”, Ph.D. Thesis, RWTH Aachen University, 2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Padala, S., Woo, C., Kook, S., and Hawkes, E., “Ethanol utilization in a diesel engine using dual-fuelling technology,” Fuel 109(2013), 597-607, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.03.049</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rodríguez-Fernández, J., Tsolakis, A., Theinnoi, Snowball, J., et al., “Engine performance and emissions from dual-fuelled engine with in-cylinder injected diesel fuels and in-port injected bioethanol,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1853, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1853</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Ekoto, I., Colban, W., and Miles, P., “In-cylinder CO and UHC Imaging in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine during PPCI Low- Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):933-956, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yahyaoui, M., Mathieu, O., Dotoum, D., Chaumeix, N., et al., “Autoignition of a gasoline surrogate containing various blend ratios of ethanol: shock tube experiments and detailed kinetic modeling,” Seventh Mediterranean Combustion Symposium, 11th-13th September 2011, Sardinia, Italy</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saisirirat, P, Togbé, C., Chanchaona, S., Foucher, F., et al., “Autoignition and combustion characteristics in HCCI and JSR using 1-butanol/n-heptane and ethanol/n-heptane blends,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 33 (2011), 3007-3014</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hashimoto, K., “Inhibition Effect of Ethanol on Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition of Heptane,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2504, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2504.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weall, A., Szybist, J., Edwards, K, Foster, M. et al., “HCCI Load Expansion Opportunities Using a Fully Variable HVA Research Engine to Guide Development of a Production Intent Cam-Based VVA Engine: The Low Load Limit,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1149-1162, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhave, A., Kraft, M., Montorsi, L., and Mauss, F., “Sources of CO emissions in an HCCI engine: a numerical analysis,” Combust Flame 2006;144(3):634-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kong S.-C., Reitz R., “Numerical study of premixed HCCI engine combustion and its sensitivity to computational mesh and model uncertainties,” Combustion Theory and Modelling. 2003;7:417-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
