<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue-id>i40186382</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44433891</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>New Features in Shock Absorbers With Inertia Control</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>C. H.</given-names>
                  <surname>Kindl</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1933</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>172</fpage>
         <lpage>176</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44433891"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>MANY improvements in shock-absorbing apparatus have been made during the last two years, the most notable being in dash control and devices for temperature compensation. Two types of hydraulic absorbers, the piston and the vane types, have been in use during this period. Both constructions function around the hydraulic principle of forcing a fluid through an orifice of some type. So-called automatic shock-absorbers were much heard of during 1932. The various kinds of control used are examined herewith to determine whether or not some particular type of velocity-load diagram is most desirable. After describing the inertia-controlled shockabsorber, Mr. Kindl enlarges upon its various features. The equipment used for testing purposes is illustrated. In conclusion, he states that future experimental work undoubtedly will increase the perfection of this type of shock absorber. Present designs result in outstanding improvements in rides, but further improvements must come as a result of lower spring-rates and lighter wheel-suspensions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


