<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24438120</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Should Central Government Seek to Control the Level of Local Authority Expenditures?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>JOHN</given-names>
                  <surname>FENDER</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>PETER A.</given-names>
                  <surname>WATT</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2002</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">23</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24438073</issue-id>
         <fpage>265</fpage>
         <lpage>285</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2002</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24438120"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Should local authorities be free to determine their expenditure, provided they finance changes in spending by changes in local taxation? We set up a theoretical framework to analyse this issue, and discuss three arguments that have been put forward for central control of such spending. The first relates to tax spillovers, the second to distributional effects combined with imperfect local democracy and the third considers self-interested local politicians. While these arguments cannot be entirely dismissed, they are subject to numerous qualifications and, if correct, would imply the desirability of a number of policies other than expenditure capping.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1e144a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e151" publication-type="other">
More strictly, the debate concerns control of what, in the UK, is called local authority self-financed
expenditure (LASFE).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e161a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e168" publication-type="other">
For an account of how capping has operated in the UK, and an attempt to assess its economic consequences,
see, for example, Emmerson, Hall and Windmeijer (1998).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e178a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e185" publication-type="other">
See, for example, the Treasury's evidence to the House of Lords Select Committee on Relations between
Central and Local Government (House of Lords, 1996, vol. II, pp. 280-3 and 308-9).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e195a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e202" publication-type="other">
However, see Bailey (1999, ch. 5) and Jackson (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e210a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e217" publication-type="other">
0ur tax variables should be interpreted as representing net tax receipts — that is, total tax revenue less transfer
payments. Sometimes the spillover effects we discuss have their impact by affecting transfer payments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e227a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e234" publication-type="other">
We hence ignore questions of strategic interaction, which have featured in some of the recent theoretical
literature (for example, Figuieres, Hindriks and Myles (2001)). Such questions may be important in considering
issues relating to fiscal federalism in the European Union, but we consider our approach more relevant for the
analysis of UK local authorities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e250a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e257" publication-type="other">
Such a condition is fairly standard in the literature (see, for example, equation (3) on p. 288 of Case, Hines
and Rosen (1993)).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e267a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e274" publication-type="other">
These are sufficient conditions — the failure of any one of these conditions to hold does not necessarily mean
that there is a case for CG control of LA expenditure. (It might be possible, for example, for LAs to agree
amongst themselves in a Coasian fashion on measures to internalise external effects without necessarily
involving the CG.)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e290a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e297" publication-type="other">
The implications of this scheme are discussed at greater length in Watt and Fender (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e304a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e311" publication-type="other">
These are not unreasonable figures to use for the distortionary costs of taxation. For further discussion of
estimates of these costs, see Ruggeri (1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e322a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e331" publication-type="other">
A complication comes from the fact that £15 (of the £31 increase in spending) is considered 'one-off
expenditure. If we are considering a permanent increase in LA spending, then we would need to convert this
into its annual flow equivalent which, assuming a 10 per cent interest rate, would be £1.50. This means that a
permanent annual increase of £100 in LA spending would raise the CG fiscal deficit by £37.50 annually,
implying the appropriate rate of withdrawal of government grant per £100 increase in LA spending is just
£3.75.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e354a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e361" publication-type="other">
As already noted, much of the extensive recent theoretical literature on local public finance assumes a high or
(sometimes) an infinite degree of mobility of the local tax base. We would point out that many of the
contributors to this literature come from countries (such as the US and Germany) with very different systems of
local taxation, for which an assumption of a high degree of interregional mobility of the tax base is much more
relevant.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e380a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e387" publication-type="other">
0ur companion paper, Watt and Fender (1999), contains some discussion of the actual arrangements whereby
LA capital spending is controlled in the UK, and the government has recently proposed some major changes
(see Department for Transport, Local Government and the Regions (2001b)); here, we are more concerned with
the theoretical arguments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e403a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e410" publication-type="other">
However, it might be argued that if local revenue is raised by a property tax, then expected future increases in
local taxes will be capitalised into property prices, so eliminating the 'mismatch' problem: local taxpayers
cannot shift the cost of local services onto future local residents since the higher future taxes mean lower
current property prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e426a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e435" publication-type="other">
For this reason, it is entirely appropriate that LAs should not be able to control business rates (so the current
system whereby the business rate is set centrally is welcome), since the incidence of such rates probably falls
largely on those outside the LA area. At the moment, although LAs finance only a fraction of their spending by
taxation that they control (about a quarter — see Table 2), it is true to say that at the margin, subject to the
qualification made earlier about council tax benefit, they pay the full cost of any increase in their spending
themselves. We believe it would be desirable for LAs to finance a much greater proportion of their expenditures
by taxes that they control, but discussion of this is beyond the scope of this paper. (For one of the author's
ideas on how this might be done, see Fender (1986).)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e464a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e471" publication-type="other">
We would also point out that if, in spite of our arguments, it is decided that the level of LA spending should
be controlled for this particular reason, there is no need to control each individual LA's spending; it is only
necessary to control the aggregate. A way of doing the latter whilst preserving individual LAs' freedom to set
their own levels of expenditure would be to issue LAs with marketable permits, enabling them to increase their
spending above their Standard Spending Assessments (SSAs). So if one LA wanted to raise its expenditure by a
certain amount above its SSA, and did not have enough permits, it would have to buy such permits from other
LAs, which would thus need to reduce their expenditure. The market for such permits would work in a similar
way to the recently established market in sulphur dioxide emissions allowances in the US. (This argument also
holds if CG seeks to control LA spending for macroeconomic reasons.)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d1e512a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e516" publication-type="other">
Bailey, S. (1999), Local Government Economics, London: MacMillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e523a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e527" publication-type="other">
Barlow, J. (1981), 'The rationale for the control of local government expenditure for the purposes
of macroeconomic management', Local Government Studies, vol. 7, pp. 3-13.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e537a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e541" publication-type="other">
Brennan, G. and Buchanan, J. (1980), The Power to Tax: Analytical Foundations of a Fiscal
Constitution, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e551a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e555" publication-type="other">
Case, A., Hines, J. and Rosen, H. (1993), 'Budget spillovers and fiscal policy interdependence:
evidence from the States', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 52, pp. 285-307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e566a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e570" publication-type="other">
Department for Transport, Local Government and the Regions (2001a), 'Estimated
proportion of council tax yield accounted for by council tax benefit',
www.local.dtlr.gov.uk/finance/ssa/1012/data/ctbslq.xls.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e583a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e587" publication-type="other">
— (2001b), Strong Local Leadership: Quality Public Services, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e594a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e598" publication-type="other">
Department of the Environment, Transport and the Regions (1998), Modern Local Government: In
Touch with the People, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e608a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e612" publication-type="other">
— (1999), The Government's Response to the Environment and Regional Affairs Committee's
Report, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e622a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e626" publication-type="other">
— (2000), Modernising Local Government Finance: A Green Paper, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e633a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e637" publication-type="other">
Dowding, K., John, P. and Biggs, S. (1994), 'Tiebout: a survey of the empirical literature', Urban
Studies, vol. 31, pp. 767-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e648a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e652" publication-type="other">
Edwards, J. and Keen, M. (1996), 'Tax competition and Leviathan', European Economic Review,
vol. 40, pp. 113-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e662a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e666" publication-type="other">
Emmerson, C., Hall, J. and Windmeijer, F. (1998), Impact of Capping on Local Service Provision,
Commentary no. 71, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e676a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e680" publication-type="other">
Fender, J. (1986), 'Local taxation and housing finance: a proposal for reform', Lloyds Bank
Review, no. 162, pp. 17-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e690a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e694" publication-type="other">
Figuieres, C., Hindriks, J. and Myles, G. (2001), 'Revenue sharing versus expenditure sharing',
CORE, Belgium, unpublished paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e704a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e708" publication-type="other">
Gordon, R. H. (1983), 'An optimal taxation approach to fiscal federalism', Quarterly Journal of
Economics, vol. 108, pp. 567-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e718a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e722" publication-type="other">
House of Commons (1999), Local Government Finance, Environment, Transport and Regional
Affairs Committee, Eighth Report, HC 78-1, Session 1998-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e733a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e737" publication-type="other">
House of Lords (1996), House of Lords Select Committee on Relations between Central and Local
Government, (Hunt Committee), three volumes, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e747a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e751" publication-type="other">
Jackman, R. (1982), 'Does central government need to control the total of local government
spending?', Local Government Studies, vol. 8, pp. 75-90.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e761a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e765" publication-type="other">
Jackson, P. (1982), 'The impact of economic theories of local government spending', Local
Government Studies, vol. 8, pp. 21-33.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e775a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e779" publication-type="other">
— (1999), 'Central/local fiscal relations: the macroeconomic dimension'. Public Money and
Management, vol. 19, pp. 11-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e789a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e793" publication-type="other">
Niskanen, W. A. (1971), Bureaucrats and Representative Government, Chicago, IL: Aldine Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e800a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e804" publication-type="other">
Oates, W. (1985), 'Searching for Leviathan: an empirical study', American Economic Review, vol.
75, pp. 748-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e815a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e819" publication-type="other">
— (1999), 'An essay on fiscal federalism', Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 37, pp. 1120-49.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e826a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e830" publication-type="other">
Retail Prices Index Advisory Committee (1993), Treatment of Council Tax and Holidays in the
Retail Prices Index, Cm. 2142, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e840a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e844" publication-type="other">
Ruggeri, G. (1999), 'The marginal cost of public funds in closed and small open economies',
Fiscal Studies, vol. 20, pp. 41-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e854a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e858" publication-type="other">
Tiebout, C. (1956), 'A pure theory of local expenditure', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 64, pp.
416-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e868a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e872" publication-type="other">
Watt, P. A. (1996), Local Government Principles and Practice, London: Witherby.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e879a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e883" publication-type="other">
— and Fender, J. (1999), 'Feasible changes in the UK controls on local government expenditure',
Public Money and Management, vol. 19, pp. 17-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
