<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284945</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Motorcycle Dual Exhaust Muffler Design Improvement to Eliminate Failure Caused by Thermal Stress</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bansode</surname>
                  <given-names>Narendra V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Ganguly</surname>
                  <given-names>Arnab</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Agarwal</surname>
                  <given-names>Vikas Kumar</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Mahindra Two Wheelers Ltd</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>September 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284904</issue-id>
         <fpage>1833</fpage>
         <lpage>1838</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284945"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A single cylinder gasoline engine of a sports bike generates sufficient hot gases to pose great challenge to the designers of exhaust system. The high temperature exhaust gases in muffler creates thermal elongation on the solid parts of exhaust system, which is mounted on the chassis. This arrangement induces thermal stress in exhaust assembly. It is necessary to analyze this thermal stress to ensure the durability of muffler components.</p>
            <p>The exhaust design has a diversion at the header pipe to distribute the flow in two branches. This junction and the branches heated up excessively and showed repeated failure. To analyze the thermal stress, the temperature distribution in the muffler components is obtained from Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) analysis. The complete motorcycle with detailed exhaust system is modelled in the standard wind tunnel using a commercial CFD software. Conjugate heat transfer (CHT) study is done for normal and adverse operating conditions considering transfer of heat between hot exhaust gases passing through muffler assembly, muffler solid components and external air flowing over motorcycle. The heat generation in the catalytic convertor and the radiation between muffler components are also considered.</p>
            <p>Parallelly, complete muffler assembly is modelled in a commercially available FEA code. All the muffler mountings are considered including the bushings and bolted connections. Material properties are defined for each of the muffler components. The temperature distribution obtained from CFD analysis is applied to simulate for thermal expansion, stress and deformation in the exhaust system. Results showed excessive stress on a certain component of the muffler. Design modification is implemented and is validated following similar analysis work flow. Thermal stress is found to have reduced considerably in the modified design as compared to the base design.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, J., Young, B., Uy, B., "Behaviour of high strength structural steel at elevated temperatures, " University of Wollongong-Research Online, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wille, A. and Bonifer, M., "Catalytic Coating for Effective Emission Reduction in a Small Motorcycle Application," SAE Technical Paper 2009-32-0158, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun. Yongling, Xieshuo Wu Guangqiang, “Numarical Simulation of the External Flow Field around a bluff car”, Shanghai : s.n.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gokhale, A. and Karthikeyan, N., "Optimization of Engine Cooling Through Conjugate Heat Transfer Simulation and Analysis of Fins," SAE Technical Paper 2012-32-0054, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-32-0054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joseph, E. S., Charles, R. M., "Mechanical Engineering Design "</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
