<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278220</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>An Efficient Lift Control Technique in Electro-hydraulic Camless Valvetrain Using Variable Speed Hydraulic Pump</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pournazeri</surname>
                  <given-names>Mohammad</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Waterloo</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Khajepour</surname>
                  <given-names>Amir</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Univ of Waterloo</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fazeli</surname>
                  <given-names>Amir</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Waterloo</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1247</fpage>
         <lpage>1259</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278220"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Significant improvement in fuel consumption, torque delivery and emission could be achieved through flexible control of the valve timings, duration and lift. In most existing electro-hydraulic variable valve actuation systems, the desired valve lift within every engine cycle is achieved by accurately controlling of the solenoid-valve opening interval; however, due to slow response time, precision control of these valves is difficult particularly during higher engine speeds. In this paper a new lift control strategy is proposed based on the hydraulic supply pressure and flow control. In this method, in order to control the peak valve lift, the hydraulic pump speed is precisely controlled using a two-input gearbox mechanism. This eliminates the need for precision control of the solenoid valves opening interval within every cycle. To achieve a smooth control signal, it is worthwhile to control the maximum valve lift within few engine cycles rather than every cycle; therefore, instead of using the governing non-linear differential equations of the mechanism, a novel average model of the system is developed based on energy conservation equations. A non-linear sliding mode controller (SMC) is also designed based on the developed average model and the boundary layer method is used to eliminate the chattering problem. The performance of the proposed controller is then examined through some simulations. Moreover, the new lift control technique is implemented experimentally by reconfiguration of the existing electro-hydraulic valve system prototype and empirical results are then compared with those obtained from the simulations.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, L., “Camless Variable Valve Actuation Designs with Two-Spring Pendulum and Electrohydraulic Latching,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-1295, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-1295.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schechter, M. and Levin, M., “Camless Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 960581, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960581.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Misovec, K., Johnson, B., Mansouri, G., Sturman, O. et al., “Digital Valve Technology Applied to the Control of an Hydraulic Valve Actuator,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0825, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni, M., Foschini, L., Postrioti, L., and Cristiani, M., “Development of an Electro-Hydraulic Camless WA System,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0088, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-24-0088.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, M., Tsao, T., and Levin, M., “Adaptive Lift Control for a Camless Electrohydraulic Valvetrain,” SAE Technical Paper 981029, 1998, doi: 10.4271/981029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sun, Zongxuan and Cleary, David, “Dynamics and control of an electro-hydraulic fully flexible valve actuation system,” in Proceedings of the American Control Conference, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, C., Babbitt, G., Balton, C., Raimao, M. et al., “Design and Control of a Two-stage Electro-hydraulic Valve Actuation System,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1265, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1265.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pournazeri, Mohammad, Fazeli, Amir, Khajepour, Amir, “A robust lift control technique in electro-hydraulic camless valves using system average model,” in IMECE2010, Vancouver, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeinali, Meysar and Notash, Leila, “Adaptive sliding mode control with uncertainty estimator for robot manipulator,” Mechanism and Machine Theory, vol. 45, no. 1, pp. 80-90, January 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalil, H K, Nonlinear Systems, 3rd ed.: Prentice-Hall Inc, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slotine, J J and Li, W, Applied non-linear control:. Prentice-Hall Inc, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krstic, Miroslav, Kanellakopoulos, Ioannis, and Kokotovic, Petar V, Nonlinear andAdaptive Control Design By Miroslav Krstic: Wiley-Interscience, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ioannou, P A and Fidan, B, Adaptive Control Tutorial.: Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Norton, Robert L, Cam design and manufacturing handbook.: Industrial Press Inc, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pournazeri, M, Khajepour, A, and Fazeli, A, “A new valve lift control technique in electrohydraulic variable valve actuation systems,” in ASME International Combustion Engine Division ICEF2010, San Antonio, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
