<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">7</issue>
         <issue-id>i24465666</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24465669</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Valuing Private Equity</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Morten</given-names>
                  <surname>Sorensen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Neng</given-names>
                  <surname>Wang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Jinqiang</given-names>
                  <surname>Yang</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>1977</fpage>
         <lpage>2021</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24465669"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We investigate whether the performance of private equity (PE) investments is sufficient to compensate investors (LPs) for risk, long-term illiquidity, management, and incentive fees charged by the general partner (GP). We analyze the LPs' portfolio-choice problem and find that management fees, carried interest, and illiquidity are costly, and GPs must generate substantial alpha to compensate LPs for bearing these costs. Debt is cheap and reduces these costs, potentially explaining the high leverage of buyout transactions. Conventional interpretations of PE performance measures appear optimistic. On average, LPs may just break even, net of management fees, carry, risk, and costs of illiquidity.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e266a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e273" publication-type="other">
See Gompers and Lerner (2002) and Metrick and Yasuda (2010,2011) for detailed discussions of the institutional
features of these investments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e283a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e290" publication-type="other">
In their conclusion, Axelson et al. (2011) state that "the factors that predict capital structure in public companies
have no explanatory power for buyouts. Instead, the main factors that do affect the capital structure of buyouts
are the price and availability of debt; when credit is abundant and cheap, buyouts become more leveraged [...]
Private equity practitioners often state that they use as much leverage as they can to maximize the expected
returns on each deal. The main constraint they face, of course, is the capital market, which limits at any particular
time how much private equity sponsors can borrow for any particular deal."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e313a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e320" publication-type="other">
As explained in the text, the PME is calculated by dividing the present value (PV) of the cash flows distributed
to the LP by the PV of the cash flows paid by the LP, where the PV is calculated using the realized market return
as the discount rate. A PME exceeding one is typically interpreted as outperformance relative to the market.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e333a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e340" publication-type="other">
Kaplan and Schoar (2005) find substantial persistence in the performance of subsequent PE funds managed by the
same PE firm, indicating that PE firms differ in their quality and ability to generate returns. Lerner, Schoar, and
Wongsunwai (2007) find systematic variation in PE performance across LP types, suggesting that LPs differ in
their ability to identify and access high-quality PE firms. Hence, some specific LPs may consistently outperform
(or underperform) the average.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e360a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e367" publication-type="other">
In practice, PE funds have several LPs, which typically share the value of the fund pro rata. We interpret Xq as
the LP's share of the total fund. If the total committed capital to the PE fund is Xq, and a given LP owns the share
s of the fund, then Xo=sX(). Alternatively, we can interpret the LP in the model as representing the aggregate
collection of LPs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e383a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e390" publication-type="other">
We assume that Xq &gt; 0, and that the GP cannot short the investment in the PE fund. Further, we assume that
the LP cannot trade the debt used to leverage the PE asset. The LP would want a short position in this debt to
partially hedge the non-spanned risk.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e403a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e410" publication-type="other">
Our model can also accommodate value created by levering the PE asset with "cheap" debt. In this paper,
however, we only consider debt priced in equilibrium. Ivashina and Kovner (2010) provide empirical evidence
of the use of cheap debt financing in PE transactions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e423a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e430" publication-type="other">
PE funds usually have catch-up rates of n = 100%, leaving nothing for the LP in the catch-up region. For generality,
we allow for n &lt; 100%, even if it is rare in PE partnerships. Real estate partnerships often use a catch-up rate of
n=80%</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e443a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e450" publication-type="other">
Caballero (1991) and Wang (2006) derive explicitly solved optimal consumption rules under incomplete
markets with CARA utility. Miao and Wang (2007) derive the optimal American-style growth option exercising
problems under incomplete markets. Chen, Miao, and Wang (2010) integrate the incomplete-markets real options
framework of Miao and Wang (2007) into Leland (1994) to analyze entrepreneurial default, cash-out, and credit
risk implications.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e469a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e476" publication-type="other">
Technically, the full-spanning case is not a special case of the model in Section 1 with incomplete markets. With
full spanning, we need more traded assets to span the PE risk (see Appendix B). As we show in this section, as
y 0+, the LP's valuation under incomplete markets converges to the valuation under full spanning.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e490a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e497" publication-type="other">
Formally, our model does not allow the LP to be risk neutral (y=0). Since public equity yields a higher expected
rate of return than the risk-free rate, a risk-neutral investor would hold an infinite position in the public market
portfolio. In the limit, as y —&gt;■ 0+, the solution for V(At, t) remains valid, though, and it converges to the valuation
formula for the full-spanning case. We use y Iq=0+ (with subscript "+") to denote the corresponding limit solution.
In this limit, the LP is effectively risk neutral and the cost of illiquidity disappears. Formally, for y= 0+, the PDE
(31) is linear, and the solution is identical to the one from the full-spanning case, given in Section 3.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e520a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e527" publication-type="other">
To some extent, the constant illiquidity discount is also a property of CARA utility, because it lacks wealth effects
and hence an absolute reduction of wealth does not change the certainty-equivalent valuation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e537a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e544" publication-type="other">
We confirm that our numerical solution of the break-even alphas using PDE (31 ) yields the same result as implied
by (64).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e554a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e561" publication-type="other">
The studies include Ljungqvist and Richardson (2003), Kaplan and Schoar (2005), Jegadeesh, Kraussl, and Pollet
(2010), Phalippou and Gottschalg (2009), Korteweg and Sorensen (2010), Metrick and Yasuda (2010), Robinson
and Sensoy (2012), and Stucke (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e587" publication-type="other">
Ang, A., D. Papanikolaou, and M. M. Westerfeld. 2012. Portfolio choice with illiquid assets. Working Paper,
Columbia University, Northwestern University, and University of Washington.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e601" publication-type="other">
Axelson, U., P. Stromberg, and M. Weisbach. 2009. Why are buyouts levered? The Financial Structure of Private
Equity Firms. Journal of Finance 64:1549-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e611a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e615" publication-type="other">
Axelson, U., T. Jenkinson, P. Stromberg, and M. Weisbach. 2011. Borrow cheap, buy high? The determinants of
leverage and pricing in buyouts. Working Paper, Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e625a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e629" publication-type="other">
Berk, J. B., and R. C. Green. 2004. Mutual fund flows and performance in rational markets. Journal of Political
Economy 112:1269-95.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e640a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e644" publication-type="other">
Black, F., and M. Scholes. 1973. The pricing of options and corporate liabilities. Journal of Political Economy
81:637-59.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e654a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e658" publication-type="other">
Caballero, R. J. 1991. Earnings uncertainty and aggregate capital accumulation. American Economic Review
81:859-71.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e672" publication-type="other">
Chen, H., J. Miao, and N. Wang. 2010. Entrepreneurial finance and non-diversifiable risk. Review of Financial
Studies 23:4348-88.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e686" publication-type="other">
Cochrane, J. 2005. The risk and return of venture capital. Journal of Financial Economics 75:3-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e693a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e697" publication-type="other">
Duffle, D., W. Fleming, H. M. Soner, and T. Zariphopoulou. 1997. Hedging in incomplete markets with H ARA
utility. Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control 21:753-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e707a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e711" publication-type="other">
Duffle, D. 2001. Dynamic asset pricing theory, 3rd ed. NJ: University Press, Princeton.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e719a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e723" publication-type="other">
Glode, V., and R. C. Green. 2011. Information spillovers and performance persistence for hedge funds. Journal
of Financial Economics 101:1-17.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e733a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e737" publication-type="other">
Goetzmann, W. N., J. E. Ingersoll, and S. A. Ross. 2003. High-water marks and hedge fund management contracts.
Journal of Finance 58:1685-1718.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e747a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e751" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., A. Kovner, J. Lerner, and D. Scharfstein. 2008. Venture capital investment cycles: The impact of
public markets. Journal of Financial Economics 87:1-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e761a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e765" publication-type="other">
Gompers, P., and J. Lerner. 2002. The venture capital cycle. MA: MIT Press, Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e772a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e776" publication-type="other">
Harris, R. S., T. Jenkinson, and S. N. Kaplan. 2011. Private equity performance: What do we know? Working
Paper, University of Chicago.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e786a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e790" publication-type="other">
Hochberg, Y., A. Ljungqvist, and A. Vissing-Jorgensen. 2010. Informational hold-up and performance persistence
in venture capital. Working Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e801a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e805" publication-type="other">
Ivashina, V., and A. Kovner. 2010. The private equity advantage: Leveraged buyout firms and relationship
banking. Review of Financial Studies 24:2462-98.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e815a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e819" publication-type="other">
Jegadeesh, N., R. Kraussl, and J. M. Pollet. 2010. Risk and expected return of private equity investments:
Evidence based on market prices. Working Paper, Emory University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e829a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e833" publication-type="other">
Kahl, M., J. Liu, and F. A. Longstaff. 2003. Paper millionaires: How valuable is stock to a stockholder who is
restricted from selling it? Journal of Financial Economics 67:385-410.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e843a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e847" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, S., and A. Schoar. 2005. Private equity performance: Returns, persistence, and capital flows. Journal of
Finance 60:1791-1823.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e857a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e861" publication-type="other">
Koo, H. K. 1998. Consumption and portfolio selection with labor income: A continuous time approach.
Mathematical Finance 8:49-65.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e871a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e875" publication-type="other">
Korteweg, A., and M. Sorensen. 2010. Risk and return characteristics of venture capital-backed entrepreneurial
companies. Review of Financial Studies 23:3738-72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e886a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e890" publication-type="other">
Lan, Y., N. Wang, and J. Yang. 2013. The economics of hedge funds. Journal of Financial Economics 110:300-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e897a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e901" publication-type="other">
Leland, H. 1994. Corporate debt value, bond covenants, and optimal capital structure. Journal of Finance
49:1213-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e911a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e915" publication-type="other">
Lerner, J., A. Schoar, and W. Wongsunwai. 2007. Smart institutions, foolish choices: The limited partner
performance puzzle. Journal of Finance 62:731-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e925a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e929" publication-type="other">
Ljungqvist, A., and M. Richardson. 2003. The cash flow, return, and risk characteristics of private equity. Working
Paper, New York University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e943" publication-type="other">
Merton, R. C. 1971. Consumption and portfolio rules in a continuous-time model. Journal of Economic Theory
3:373-413.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e953a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e957" publication-type="other">
Merton, R. C. 1974. On the pricing of corporate debt: The risk structure of interest rates. Journal of Finance
29:449-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e968a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e972" publication-type="other">
Metrick, A., and A. Yasuda. 2010. The economics of private equity funds. Review of Financial Studies 23:2303—41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e979a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e983" publication-type="other">
Metrick, A. and A. Yasuda. 2011. Venture capital and other private equity: A survey. European Financial
Management 17:619-54.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e993a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e997" publication-type="other">
Miao, J., and N. Wang. 2007. Investment, consumption and hedging under incomplete market. Journal of
Financial Economics 86:608—42.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1007a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1011" publication-type="other">
Panageas, S., and M. Westerfield. 2009. High water marks: High risk appetites? Convex compensation, long
horizons, and portfolio choice. Journal of Finance 64:1-36.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1021a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1025" publication-type="other">
Phalippou, L., and O. Gottschalg. 2009. The performance of private equity funds. Review of Financial Studies
22:1747-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1035a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1039" publication-type="other">
Robinson, D., and B. Sensoy. 2012. Cyclically, performance measurement, and cash flow liquidity in private
equity. Working Paper, Duke University and Ohio State University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1050a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1054" publication-type="other">
Stromberg, P. 2007. The new demography of private equity. Working Paper, Stockholm School of Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1061a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1065" publication-type="other">
Stucke, R. 2011. Does private equity underperform or outperform public equity. Working Paper, Oxford
University.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1079" publication-type="other">
Svensson, L., and I. Werner. 1993. Nontraded assets in incomplete markets: Pricing and portfolio choice. European
Economic Review 37:1149-68.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1089a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1093" publication-type="other">
Viceira, L. 2001. Optimal portfolio choice for long-horizon investors with nontradable labor income. Journal of
Finance 56:433-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1103a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1107" publication-type="other">
Wang, C., N. Wang, and J. Yang. 2012. A unified model of entrepreneurship dynamics. Journal of Financial
Economics 106:1-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1117a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1121" publication-type="other">
Wang, N. 2006. Generalizing the permanent-income hypothesis: Revisiting Friedman's conjecture on
consumption. Journal of Monetary Economics 53:737-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


