<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909593</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>C3 Driver, An Army Success Story</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Works</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Paul W. Works, Jr. is the Chief, Methods and Research Office, TRADOC Analysis Center (TRAC), Ft. Leavenworth, KS. He advises Director, TRAC on matters pertaining to advanced methodologies, technologies, and modeling and simulation (M&amp;S) tools. Previously, he served as the C3 Driver Deputy Project Director and as an ORSA within the Network Architecture Directorate and TRAC’s Joint and Combined Operations Directorate. While in the Joint and Combined Operations Directorate, Paul has led various scenario, simulation, and mission thread development activities for the C3 Driver Program and led analyses on various AoA and C4I interoperability studies. He moved to TRACLeavenworth, KS after working for eleven years as a physicist/ORSA for the Weapons and Tactics Analysis Center (WEPTAC) and the Advanced Systems IPT at the Naval Air Warfare Center-Weapons Division (NAWC-WD), China Lake, CA. While assigned to NAWC-WD, he conducted numerous studies investigating air-to-air, strike, and C4I tactics and systems requirements. Mr Works has a B.S. in Physics and Mathematics from Kansas State University.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Mazariegos</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Andrea Mazariegos is a Computer Scientist with the Army Test and Evaluation Command (ATEC), Developmental Test Command (DTC), Electonic Proving Ground (EPG), located on Ft. Huachuca, AZ. Andrea has been a member of the Command, Control, and Communications (C3) Driver team since March 2004 and is also responsible for data reduction and analysis operations at EPG.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Krondak</surname>
                  <given-names>William</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>William J. Krondak serves as the Director of Scenarios and Wargaming for TRADOC Analysis Center, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas. He received a Bachelor of Science degree in Mathematics Education from the University of Nebraska and a Masters degree from the University of Oklahoma. He graduated from the Armed Forces Staff College in Norfolk, VA and the US Army War College at Carlisle Barracks, PA. He has extensive experience in scenario development, modeling and simulation, cost and operational effectiveness analysis, exercise evaluation, operational planning assessment, and surveillance and reconnaissance analysis. Bill has presented papers at the Defense Analysis Seminar (DAS) X, the International Symposia for Military Operations Research (ISMOR), several Military Operations Research Society Symposiums (MORSS), and the Army Operations Research Symposia (AORS). He has authored articles for the Field Artillery Journal and the Military Review.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2007</year>
            <string-date>March 2007</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>40</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909586</issue-id>
         <fpage>7</fpage>
         <lpage>9</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909593"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
