<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440082</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Means Testing and Retirement Choices in Europe: A Comparison of the British and Danish Systems</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
                  <surname>Sefton</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Justin</given-names>
                  <surname>van de Ven</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
                  <surname>Weale</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2005</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">26</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440075</issue-id>
         <fpage>83</fpage>
         <lpage>118</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2005</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440082"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>We develop a simulation model of household behaviour in which both the consumption/saving and labour/leisure choices are endogenous. This model is used to explore the effects of the UK and Danish state tax and benefit systems on the labour supply of workers aged 50 or over. We find that, in broad terms, differences in labour force participation can be accounted for by differences in benefit structures. Furthermore, our simulations suggest that the UK system is preferred by young people while the Danish arrangement – which imposes a larger tax burden and provides larger welfare benefits – is chosen by people of 50 or older. Notably, people older than 60 are in the majority in the simulated population. The Danish system does not promote notably greater equality over the lifetime, but it does underpin a higher level of consumption for people of 50 or older.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d43e293a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e300" publication-type="other">
The authors acknowledge funding from the European Commission under the AGIR project.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e307a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e314" publication-type="other">
These figures are taken from OECD data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e321a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e328" publication-type="other">
Studies typically assume that welfare is derived from income rather than consumption - which is
equivalent to the assumption that all income is consumed in the year in which it is earned - and they do
not give explicit recognition to the utility derived from leisure.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e341a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e348" publication-type="other">
By optimal choices, we mean that individuals derive utility from consumption and leisure and make
their work/leisure and consumption/saving decisions in the light of expected future net earnings if they
decide to work and in the light of benefits if they decide not to work. The optimal choices are represented
as the solutions to an intertemporal optimisation problem (Sefton, 2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e365a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e372" publication-type="other">
The Beveridge Report recommended that the British people should be guaranteed a minimum
standard of living in times of sickness, unemployment and retirement, in return for a weekly contribution
during employment. The value judgements made in the Beveridge Report can, however, be traced to
1536, when English parishes were first authorised to collect money to support the 'impotent poor'. This
embryonic welfare state provided a means of sustenance to the elderly, infirm, blind and
insane. See Fraser (1972) on the evolution of the welfare state in Britain up to 1945. On the
contemporary development of the British welfare state, see Department of Social Security (2000).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e398a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e405" publication-type="other">
Esping-Anderson (1990) distinguishes between the liberal systems that are commonly found in
Anglo-Saxon countries and the social democratic regimes that are typical of Scandinavian countries.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e415a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e422" publication-type="other">
See Appendix A for details regarding the ECHP.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e429a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e436" publication-type="other">
Much of the material presented here is based upon Abrahamson and Wehner (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e443a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e450" publication-type="other">
To be eligible, an individual must have been in residence in Denmark for at least three years, and for
non-nationals 10 years including the five years immediately prior to receiving the pension. The
simulations assume that all citizenship and residency requirements are always satisfied.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e463a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e470" publication-type="other">
It is also compulsory for people who receive daily allowances in case of sickness, birth, adoption or
unemployment. Civil servants are administered under an alternative system. The simulations presented
here do not take into consideration ATP contributions during periods when an individual chooses not to
be employed.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e487a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e494" publication-type="other">
The simulations assume that all individuals who are employed accrue DKK2.684 of ATP
contributions during a given year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e504a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e511" publication-type="other">
Deferrals are not taken into consideration by the simulation model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e518a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e525" publication-type="other">
The simulation model applies the same annuity to SP as to ATP, which extends to the full lifetime.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e532a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e539" publication-type="other">
Bingley and Lanot (2004) report econometric estimates which suggest that Danish occupational
pensions have a small effect on retirement behaviour, relative to the state pension system (although the
effect reported for women is statistically significant).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e552a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e559" publication-type="other">
In principle, an individual must also be a member of an a-kassa (a private insurance fund) for at
least 25 of the preceding 30 years, although there are some exceptions.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e569a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e576" publication-type="other">
See Department for Work and Pensions (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e584a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e591" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Blundell, Meghir and Smith (2002) for empirical evidence.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e598a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e605" publication-type="other">
The total NIC charged is 11 per cent, 2.05 percentage points of which is used to fund the National
Health Service (NHS). Employers are also required to pay NICs above the EET, at a rate of 12.8 per cent
(10.9 percentage points of which is used to fund the BSP).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e618a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e625" publication-type="other">
For example, if an individual earned the equivalent of £40,000 in one year, then they would be
credited with £6,194.02 = 0.46x(l 1,200-4,004) + 0.115x(25,600-11,201) + 0.23x(30,940-25,601).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e635a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e642" publication-type="other">
The 'contracting-out' rebate on NICs.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e649a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e656" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Blake and Orszag (1997, table 12).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e663a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e670" publication-type="other">
See Social Survey Division, Office for National Statistics (2001, volume 1) for the definition of a
household reference person.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e681a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e688" publication-type="other">
An alternative version of the model allows households to work part-time. This option is omitted here
to focus attention upon the issue of retirement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e698a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e705" publication-type="other">
See van de Yen (2004) for details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e712a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e719" publication-type="other">
Data from the ECHP and OECD are adjusted to reflect the fact that involuntary unemployment is
not included in the simulations presented here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e729a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e736" publication-type="other">
The associated survey data were obtained from the Family Expenditure Survey (FES) due to the finer
detail that that survey provides regarding the definition of household income. See Appendix A for details
regarding the FES.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e749a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e756" publication-type="other">
It should be noted that the limited calibrations undertaken for the tax function of the working
lifetime mean that the model fails to capture important labour supply effects at the time of labour market
entry (to age 29 for Denmark).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e769a1310">
            <label>27</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e776" publication-type="other">
See Eurostat (2003) for further details regarding the ECHP.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e784a1310">
            <label>28</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e791" publication-type="other">
Due to the repeated survey methods employed, the most recent wave of the BHPS no longer provides
a representative sample of the UK population. See Taylor (2001) for further details regarding the BHPS.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e801a1310">
            <label>29</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e808" publication-type="other">
There are currently three main sources of wealth data for the UK: the General Household Survey
(primarily for housing wealth), the Family Resources Survey and the British Household Panel Survey. An
alternative source that will provide detailed information for the English population over the age of 50 is
the English Longitudinal Study of Ageing, the first wave of which has yet to be released. Following a
review of these alternative data-sets, the BHPS was identified as the most comprehensive source of
wealth data currently available for the UK.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e831a1310">
            <label>30</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e838" publication-type="other">
For further information, see Social Survey Division, Office for National Statistics (2001).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e845a1310">
            <label>31</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e852" publication-type="other">
The regression was undertaken using the 'Sampsel' procedure in TSP, full details of which can be
obtained from the TSP 4.4 User's Guide (see elsa.berkeley.edu/wp/tsp_user/tspugpdf.htm).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d43e862a1310">
            <label>32</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d43e869" publication-type="other">
All currencies are specified in terms of Purchasing Power Standards (PPS), obtained by dividing the
national currency by the relevant Purchasing Power Parity (PPP). The PPPs used were calculated by
Eurostat and are provided with the ECHP.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d43e891a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e895" publication-type="other">
Abrahamson, P. and Wehner, C. (2003), Pension Reforms in Denmark, Copenhagen:
Department of Sociology, University of Copenhagen.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e905a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e909" publication-type="other">
Barro, R. J. and Becker, G. S. (1989), 'Fertility choice in a model of economic growth',
Econometrica, vol. 57, pp. 481-501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e919a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e923" publication-type="other">
Beveridge, W. H. (1942), Social Insurance and Allied Services, Cmd 6404, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e930a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e934" publication-type="other">
Bingley, P., Gupta, N. and Pedersen, P. (2002), 'The effects of pension programme incentives
on retirement behaviour in Denmark', Centre for Labour Market and Social Research,
Working Paper no. 01-08, www.cls.dk/workingpapers/docftles/93.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e948a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e952" publication-type="other">
— and Lanot, G. (2004), 'Employer pay policies, public transfers and the retirement decisions
of men and women in Denmark', European Economic Review, vol. 48, pp. 181-200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e962a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e966" publication-type="other">
Blake, D. and Orszag, J. M. (1997), Portability and Preservation of Pension Rights in the
UK, Report of the Director-General's Inquiry into Pensions, 3, London: Office of Fair
Trading.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e979a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e983" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R., Meghir, C. and Smith, S. (2002), 'Pension incentives and the pattern of early
retirement', Economic Journal, vol. 112, pp. CI53-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e993a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e997" publication-type="other">
Cardarelli, R., Sefton, J. and Kotlikoff, L. J. (2000), 'Generational accounting in the UK',
Economic Journal, vol. 110, pp. 547-74.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1007a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1011" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions (2003), A Guide to State Pensions, NP46, October.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1018a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1022" publication-type="other">
Department of Social Security (2000), The Changing Welfare State: Social Security
Spending, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1033a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1037" publication-type="other">
Esping-Anderson, G. (1990), The Three Worlds of Welfare Capitalism, Princeton, NJ:
Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1047a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1051" publication-type="other">
Eurostat (2003), ECHP UDB Manual, Waves 1 to 7, Doc. Pan 168/2003-06.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1058a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1062" publication-type="other">
Fraser, D. (1972), Evolution of the British Welfare State, London: Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1069a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1073" publication-type="other">
Gourinchas, P-O. and Parker, J. A. (2002), 'Consumption over the life cycle', Econometrica,
vol. 70, pp. 47-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1083a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1087" publication-type="other">
Gruber, J. and Wise, D. A. (2004), Social Security Programmes and Retirement around the
World: Micro-Estimation, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1097a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1101" publication-type="other">
Nerlove, M., Razin, A. and Sadka, E. (1984), 'Income distribution policies with endogenous
fertility', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 24, pp. 221-30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1112a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1116" publication-type="other">
Pensions Commission (2004), Pensions: Challenges and Choices, London: TSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1123a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1127" publication-type="other">
Rust, J. (1995), 'Structural estimation of Markov decision processes', in R. F. Engle and D.
L. McFadden (eds), Handbook of Econometrics, vol. IV, Amsterdam: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1137a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1141" publication-type="other">
Sefton, J. (2000), 'A solution method for consumption decisions in a dynamic stochastic
general equilibrium model', Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control, vol. 24, pp.
1097-102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1154a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1158" publication-type="other">
— and van de Ven, J. (2004), 'Simulating household savings and labour supply: an
application of dynamic programming', National Institute Economic Review, no. 188, pp.
56-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1171a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1175" publication-type="other">
— and Weale, M. R. (2003), 'State pensions, means testing and public choice', in M. R.
Weale (ed.), Pension Reform: Redistribution and Risk, National Institute Occasional
Paper no. 56, London: National Institute of Economic and Social Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1188a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1192" publication-type="other">
Social Survey Division, Office for National Statistics (2001), Family Expenditure Survey
2000-2001 User Guide, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1203a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1207" publication-type="other">
Stock, J. H. and Wise, D. A. (1990), 'Pensions, the option value of work, and retirement',
Econometrica, vol. 58, pp. 1151-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1217a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1221" publication-type="other">
Taylor, M. F. (2001), British Household Panel Survey User Manual Volume A: Introduction,
Technical Report and Appendices, Colchester: University of Essex,</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d43e1231a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d43e1235" publication-type="other">
van de Ven, J. (2004), 'The distribution of perceived household wealth in the UK',
unpublished manuscript.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
