<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308482</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>CO Emission Model for an Integrated Diesel Engine, Emissions, and Exhaust Aftertreatment System Level Model</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bagal</surname>
                  <given-names>Nilesh L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rutland</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Foster</surname>
                  <given-names>David E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Wisconsin-Madison</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Narayanaswamy</surname>
                  <given-names>Kushal</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors R&amp;D Center</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>He</surname>
                  <given-names>Yongsheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>General Motors R&amp;D Center</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308370</issue-id>
         <fpage>1460</fpage>
         <lpage>1472</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308482"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A kinetic carbon monoxide (CO) emission model is developed to simulate engine out CO emissions for conventional diesel combustion. The model also incorporates physics governing CO emissions for low temperature combustion (LTC). The emission model will be used in an integrated system level model to simulate the operation and interaction of conventional and low temperature diesel combustion with aftertreatment devices. The Integrated System Model consists of component models for the diesel engine, engine-out emissions (such as NOx and Particulate Matter), and aftertreatment devices (such as DOC and DPF). The addition of CO emissions model will enhance the capability of the Integrated System Model to predict major emission species, especially for low temperature combustion.</p>
            <p>In this work a CO emission model is developed based on a two-step global kinetic mechanism [8]. In addition, effect of physical parameters such as start of injection (SOI) and ignition delay are studied and modeled to develop a phenomenological CO emission model. This includes development of a simple spray model to compute amount of fuel missing the bowl in case of PCCI and HCCI type combustion. Results from the spray model are used to simulate the motion of fuel in the cylinder bowl during various stages of combustion. Ignition delay effects are analyzed and modeled to change the activation temperature of CO oxidation reaction to simulate the affect of increasing peak temperatures with advancing SOI. The results from the CO emission model are compared with experimental data from a multi-cylinder conventional diesel engine as well as a single cylinder version of a low temperature combustion diesel engine. For the LTC engine, the start of injection is advanced using two different injection strategies (single and two-step injection). Overall the results show good agreement of the trends between the experiments and model predictions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bayer, J., “Zero-Dimensional Direct Injection Spray and Particulate Emission Modeling,” M.S. thesis, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bayer J., Foster, D.E., “Zero-Dimensional Soot Modeling,” SAE Paper No 2003-01-1070, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., Rutland, C.J., Foster, D.E., He, Y., “A New Approach to System Level Soot Modeling,” SAE Paper No 2005-01-1122, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., “Data Driven System Level Modeling for Diesel Engines,” Ph.D. thesis, Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin- Madison, Madison, WI, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">England, S.B., Rutland, C.J., Foster, D.E., He, Y., “Investigation of the Effect of DPF Loading and Passive Regeneration on Engine Performance and Emissions Using an Integrated System Simulation,” SAE Paper No 2006-01-0263, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rutland, C.J., England, S.B., Foster, D.E., He, Y., “Integrated Engine, Emissions, and Aftertreatment System Level Models to Simulate DPF Regeneration,” SAE Paper No 2007-01-3970, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Greeves, G., Wang, C.H.T., “Origins of Hydrocarbon and Carbon Monoxide Emissions from Diesel Engines,” International Federation of Automobile Techn Eng., 00307642, pp. 779-804, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westbrook, C.K., and Dryer, F.L., “Simplified Reaction Mechanisms for the Oxidation of Hydrocarbon,” Combustion Science and Technology, Vol. 27, pp. 31-43, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S.M., Flowers, D.L., Chen, Y.J., Babajimopoulos, A., “Fast Prediction of HCCI Combustion with an Artificial Neural Network Linked to a Fluid Mechanics Code,” SAE Paper No 2006- 01-3298, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flowers, D., Aceves, S., Frias, J.M., Hessel, R., Dibble, R., “Effect of Mixing on Hydrocarbon and Carbon Monoxide Emissions Prediction for Isooctane HCCI Engine Combustion Using a Multi- Zone Detailed Kinetic Solver,” SAE Paper No 2003- 01-1821, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S.M., Flowers, D.L., “A Detailed Chemical Kinetic Analysis of Low Temperature Non-Sooting Diesel Combustion,” SAE Paper No 2005-01-0923, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aceves, S.M., Flowers, D.L., Westbrook, C.K., Smith, J.R., Pitz, W., Dibble, R., Christensen, M., Johansson, B., “A Multi-Zone Model for Prediction of HCCI Combustion and Emissions,” SAE Paper No 2000-01-0327, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flowers, D.L., Aceves, S.M., Babajimopoulos, A., “Effect of Charge Non-Uniformity on Heat Release and Emissions in PCCI Engine Combustion,” SAE Paper No 2006-01-1363, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Bae, C., Miles, P.C., Choi, D., Bergin, M., Reitz, R.D., “The Effect of Swirl Ratio and Fuel Injection Parameters on CO Emission and Fuel Conversion Efficiency for High-Dilution, Low- Temperature Combustion in an Automotive Diesel Engine,” SAE Paper No 2006-01-0197, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Ra, Y., Gonzalez, M.A.D., Kreiger, R., Reitz, D., Foster, D.E., Durrett, R.P., Siewert, M., “Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., Arai, M., “Structure of Fuel Sprays in Diesel Engines,” SAE Paper No 900475, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siewert, R., “A Phenomenological Engine Model for Direct Injection of Liquid Fuels, Spray Penetration, Vaporization, Ignition Delay, and Combustion,” SAE Paper No 2007-01-0673, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siewert, R., “Spray Angle and Rail Pressure Study for Low NOx Diesel Combustion,” SAE Paper No 2007-01-0122, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adomeit, P., Becker, M., Rohs, H., Pischinger, S., Greis, A., Grunefeld, G., “Potential Soot and CO Reduction for HSDI Diesel Combustion Systems,” SAE Paper No 2006-01-1417, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjoberg, M., Dec, J.E., “An Investigation into Lowest Acceptable temperatures for Hydrocarbon Fuels in HCCI Engines,” Proceedings of Combustion Institute, Vol 30, pp. 2719-2726, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zinola, S., Lavy, J., Voirol, A.J., “Towards CO and HC Aftertreatment Devices for the Next Generation of Diesel Engines,” SAE Paper No 2008-01-1543, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turns, S.R., “An Introduction to Combustion,” McGraw-Hill Book Company, New York, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warnatz, J., Maas, U., Dibble, R.W., Combustion, 4th Edition, Springer, Berlin, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, McGraw-Hill Book Company, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ricardo Inc., WAVE Engine User Manual, WAVE version 7.0, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
