<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909706</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>“Emergent Validation”:</article-title>
            <subtitle>Defensible and Authoritative Modeling, Simulation and Analysis for Complex Adaptive Systems</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Middleton</surname>
                  <given-names>Victor E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Mr Middleton has over 30 years experience developing, implementing, and applying mathematical models and simulations for a wide variety of military and civilian studies and analyses. He has worked extensively in assessment of military chemical and biological defense issues, focusing on balancing operational capability and risk and estimation of human performance in high stress environments. Most recently, he has been supporting Air Force Research Laboratory at Wright Patterson AFB: modeling of the environmental fate of chemical agents; developing crisis and consequence management decision aids; and using agent based simulation to study combat situation awareness as it relates to operations in chemically contaminated environments.</p>
                  <p>From 1990 to 2004, Mr Middleton concentrated on the modeling and analysis of small unit infantry operations. He is one of the principal authors of the US Army’s Integrated Unit Simulation System (IUSS), and served as the Principal Scientist for the evolution of the IUSS into the Infantry Warrior Simulation (IWARS) addressing the joint needs of US Army Natick Soldier Center and the US Army Materiel Systems Analysis Activity (AMSAA). Mr Middleton’s research focused on the need to represent the impact of dynamic changes of individuals’ and units’ psychological and physiological states on battlefield performance.</p>
                  <p>Mr Middleton is the author of numerous technical reports and presentations relating to Warrior Systems modeling and simulation and their application to analysis. His interest in modeling human behavioral representation, especially as affected by the individual’s psycho-physiological state, dates back more than 25 years to computer modeling of emergency aircraft evacuation in the presence of post-crash fire and attendant toxic conditions. His current research focus is on the use of intelligent agent technologies to represent situation awareness and other cognitive aspects of individual combatant behaviors.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2008</year>
            <string-date>March 2008</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>41</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909694</issue-id>
         <fpage>12</fpage>
         <lpage>19</lpage>
         <page-range>12-13, 19</page-range>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2007, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909706"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
</article>
