<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26812250</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Property Taxes: Support for, Relief From, and Collapse</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Use Value Assessment of Rural Land in the United States</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Anderson</surname>
                  <given-names>John E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>England</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">107</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26812141</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>37</lpage>
         <page-range>1, 1-37</page-range>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26812250"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>This paper was prepared for presentation at the annual meetings of the National Tax Association, in the session, “Property Taxes: Support for, Relief from, and Collapse,” Santa Fe, NM, November 15, 2014. This paper draws substantially from Anderson and England (2014). Support for this research was provided by the Lincoln Institute of Land Policy, Cambridge, MA.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Alig, Ralph J., Andrew J. Pantinga, SoEun Ahn, and Jeffrey D. Kline. 2003. Land Use Changes Involving Forestry in the United States: 1952 to 1997, with Projections to 2050.Gen. Tech. Report PNW-GTR-587. Portland, OR: U.S. Forest Service, Pacific Northwest Research Station.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Anderson, John E. 1986. “Property Taxes and the Timing of Urban Land Development.”Regional Science and Urban Economics, Volume 16, pp. 483-492.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Anderson, John E. 1993a. “State Tax Credits and Land Use: Policy Analysis of Circuit Breaker Effects.” Resource and Energy Economics, Volume 15, Number 3 (September) pp. 295-312.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Anderson, John E. 1993b. “Use-Value Property Tax Assessment: Effects on Land Development,” Land Economics 69, no. 3 (August): 263-269.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Anderson, John E. and Richard W. England. 2014. Use-Value Assessment of Rural Land in the United States. Cambridge, MA: Lincoln Institute of Land Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Anderson, John E. and Marlon F. Griffing. 2000a. “Measuring Use-Value Assessment Tax Expenditures.” Assessment Journal (January/February) pp. 35-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Anderson, John E. and Marlon F. Griffing. 2000b. “Use-Value Assessment Tax Expenditures in Urban Areas.” Journal of Urban Economics, Volume 48, Number 3(November) 2000, pp. 443-452.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Anderson, John E. and Marlon F. Griffing. 2012. “Agricultural Use-Value Property Tax Assessment: Estimation and Policy Issues.” Public Budgeting &amp; Finance, Volume 32, Number 4 (Winter) pp. 71-94.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Barnett, Jeffrey L. and Phillip M. Vidal. 2013. “State and Local Government Finances Summary: 2011.” Governments Division Briefs. Washington, DC: United States Census Bureau.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Berry, David, and Thomas Plaut. 1978. “Retaining Agricultural Activities under Urban Pressure: A Review of Land Use Conflicts and Policies,” Policy Sciences 9, no. 2 (April): 153-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Blase, Melvin G., and William J. Staub. 1971. “Real Property Taxes in the Rural-Urban Fringe,” Land Economics 47, no. 2 (May): 168-174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Bowman, Woods, Joseph Cordes, and Lori Metcalf. 2009. “Preferential tax treatment of property used for social purposes: Fiscal impacts and public policy implications.” In Erosion of the property tax base: Trends, causes, and consequences, edited by Nancy Y.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Bowman, John H., Daphne A. Kenyon, Adam Langley, and Bethany P. Paquin. 2009.Property Tax Circuit Breakers: Fair and Cost-Effective Relief for Taxpayers. Policy Focus Report. Cambridge, MA: Lincoln Institute of Land Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Brigham, John. 1980. “The Politics of Tax Preference,” chapter 5 in Property Tax Preferences for Agricultural Land, edited by Neal A. Roberts and H. James Brown. Montclair, NJ: Allanheld, Osmun, and Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Capozza, Dennis R. and Robert W. Helsley. 1989. “The Fundamentals of Land Prices and Urban Growth,” Journal of Urban Economics 26, no. 3 (November): 295-306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Combs, Susan. 2013. Tax Exemptions &amp; Tax Incidence: A Report to the Governor and the 83rd Texas Legislature. Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts. Accessed at http://www.window.state.tx.us/taxinfo/incidence/incidence13/96- 463_Tax_Incidence2013.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Dunford, Richard W., and Douglas C. Marousek. 1981. “Sub-County Property Tax Shifts Attributable to Use-Value Assessments on Farmland,” Land Economics 57, no. 2 (May): 221-229.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Dye, Richard F. and Richard W. England, eds. 2009. Land Value Taxation: Theory, Evidence, and Practice. Cambridge, MA: Lincoln Institute of Land Policy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">England, Richard W., and Robert D. Mohr. 2006. “Land Development and Current Use Assessment.” In Economics and Contemporary Land Use Policy: Development and Conservation at the Rural-Urban Fringe, edited by S.K. Swallow and R.J. Johnston, Chapter 8. Washington, DC: Resources for the Future.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Gloudemans, Robert J. 1974. Use-Value Farmland Assessments: Theory, Practice, and Impact. Chicago: International Association of Assessing Officers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Heimlich, Ralph E., and William D. Anderson. 2001. Development at the Urban Fringe and Beyond: Impacts on Agriculture and Rural Land. USDA Economic Research Service. Agricultural Economic Report No. 803.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Keene, John C., David Berry, Robert E. Coughlin, James Farnum, Eric Kelly, Thomas Plaut, and Ann Louise Strong. 1976. Untaxing Open Space: An Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Differential Assessment on Farms and Open Space. Washington, DC: Council on Environmental Quality.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Morris, Adele C. 1998. “Property Tax Treatment of Farmland: Does Tax Relief Delay Land Development?” In Helen F. Ladd, ed., Local Government Tax and Land Use Policies in the United States, 144-167. Cheltenham, UK: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">National Agricultural Statistics Service. 2014. “State Agriculture Overview: Ohio.” http://www.nass.usda.gov/Statistics_by_State/Ag_Overview/AgOverview_OH.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Ohio Department of Taxation. 2010. “2010 current Agricultural use Value of Land Tables, Explanation of the Calculation of Values for Various Soil Mapping Units for Tax Year 2010.” http://www.tax.ohio.gov/divisions/real_property/documents/CAUV_Memorandum_2010. pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Polyakov, Maksym, and Daowei Zhang. 2008. “Property Tax Policy and Land-Use Change,” Land Economics 84, no. 3: 396-408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Skouras, A. 1978. “The Non-Neutrality of Land Taxation.” Public Finance, Volume 33, Number 1-2, pp. 113-134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Tideman, T. Nicholas. 1982. “A Tax on Land is Neutral.” National Tax Journal 35:109- 111.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Extent of Use Value Assessment Programs in Selected States</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Ohio Current Agricultural Use Value Program, Selected Counties, 2009</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Use Value Assessment Acreage Minima, Selected States</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Farm Income or Sales Requirement for UVA Enrollment, Selected States</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>States with No UVA Development Penalty</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>States with UVA Rollback Penalties</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>States with UVA Conveyance Penalties</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Market and Use Values for Land Parcels around Lincoln and Omaha, Nebraska</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
