<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278185</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Relationship Between Diesel Fuel Spray Vapor Penetration/Dispersion and Local Fuel Mixture Fraction</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Manin</surname>
                  <given-names>Julien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universidad Politecnica de Valencia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Genzale</surname>
                  <given-names>Caroline L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Georgia Institute of Technology</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siebers</surname>
                  <given-names>Dennis L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Musculus</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark P. B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Idicheria</surname>
                  <given-names>Cherian A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>GM R&amp;D Center</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>764</fpage>
         <lpage>799</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278185"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The fuel-ambient mixture in vaporized fuel jets produced by liquid sprays is fundamental to the performance and operation of engines. Unfortunately, experimental difficulties limit the direct measurement of local fuel-ambient mixture, inhibiting quantitative assessment of mixing. On the other hand, measurement of global quantities, such as the jet penetration rate, is relatively straightforward. Simplified models to predict local fuel-ambient mixture have also been developed, based on these global parameters. However, experimental data to validate these models over a range of conditions is needed. In the current work, we perform measurements of jet global quantities such as vapor-phase penetration, liquid-phase penetration, spreading angle, and nozzle flow coefficients over a range of conditions in a high-temperature, high-pressure vessel. Using this data and other quantitative mixing measurements performed by Rayleigh scattering in the vaporized portion of the jet, we compare to an existing variable-radial-profile model for prediction of fuel mixture fraction during the steady period of injection. Results show that spreading angles based on measurement of the most sensitive outer boundary of the jet, by schlieren or Rayleigh-scatter imaging, are needed as inputs to the model to obtain a match between modeled and measured fuel jet penetration rates. By adjusting the model (with spreading angle) to match the measured penetration, the model predictions also produce local mixture fractions that are within the Rayleigh scattering experimental uncertainty. Using this same penetrationmatching technique, accurate model predictions of mixture fraction are achieved for a range of ambient densities, fuel injector nozzle shapes, injection pressures, and types of fuels. Additionally, extrapolation of the mixing measurements suggests that a fuel spray has a smaller spreading angle in the near-field and transitions to a larger angle in the far-field jet.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peters, N. and Weber, J., “The Effects of Spray Formation and Evaporation on Mixing, Auto-ignition and Combustion in Diesel Engines,” THIESEL 2006, Valencia Spain.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baert, R., Frijters, P., Somers, B., Luijten, C., de Boer, W., “Design and Operation of a High Pressure, High Temperature Cell for HD Diesel Spray Diagnostics: Guidelines and Results,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0649, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0649.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J.D. and Siebers, D.L., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1170-1193, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Pickett, L.M., and Musculus, M.P.B., “Influence of Diesel Injection Parameters on End-of-Injection Liquid Length Recession,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1194-1210, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1356.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M.P.B., “Entrainment Waves in Decelerating Transient Turbulent Jets,” J. Fluid. Mech. 638:117-140, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abramovich, G. N., “Chapter 5: Jet of an Incompressible Fluid in a Coflowing External Stream,” The Theory of Turbulent Jets, The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA, USA, 1963.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L., “Scaling Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays Based on Mixing-Limited Vaporization,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0528, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M., Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., and Gimeno, J., “Measurements of Spray Momentum for the Study of Cavitation in Diesel Injection Nozzles,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0703, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0703.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Salvador, F.J., Gimeno, J., and Zapata, L.D., “Diesel Nozzle Geometry Influence on Spray Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Evaporative Conditions,” Fuel 87:1165-1176, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdelghaffar, W. A., Karimi, K., and Heikal, M.R., “Fuel Spray Penetration in High-Pressure Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0066, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Karimi, K., Sazhina, E.M., Abdelghaffar, W.A., Crua, C., Cowell, T., Heikal, M.R., and Gold, M.R., “Developments in Diesel Spray Characterisation and Modelling,” Thermo- and Fluid-Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines: THIESEL, Valencia, Spain, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egermann, J., Göttler, A., and Leipertz, A., “Application of Spontaneous Raman Scattering for Studying the Diesel Mixture Formation Process Under Near-Wall Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3496, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-3496.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hoffman, T., Hottenbach, P., Koss, H.J., Pauls, C., and Grunefeld, G., “Investigation of Mixture Formation in Diesel Sprays Under Quiescent Conditions Using Raman, Mie and LIF Diagnostics,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0945, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0945.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronsson, U., Chartier, C., Andersson, O., Egnell, R., Sjoholm, J., Richter, M., and Alden, M., “Analysis of the Correlation between Engine-Out Particulates and Local Equivalence Ratio in the Lift-Off Region of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Using Raman Spectroscopy,” SAE Int. J. Fuels. Lubr. 2(1):645-660, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, T. and Ghandhi, J.B., “Characterization of Evaporating Diesel Sprays Using Exciplex Laser-Induced Fluorescence Measurements,” Atom. Sprays 13:535-559, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Mixing Process in High Pressure Diesel Jets by Normalized Laser Induced Exciplex Fluorescence Part I: Free Jet,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-2100, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-2100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Pastor, J.V., Pastor, J.M., and Julia, J.E., “Diesel Spray Analysis by Means of Planar Laser-Induced Exciplex Fluorescence,” Int. J. Engine Research 7:77-89, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kosaba, H., Kamimoto, T., “Quantitative Measurement of Fuel Vapor Concentration in an Unsteady Evaporating Spray via a 2-D Mie-Scattering Imaging Technique,” SAE Technical Paper 932653, 1993, doi: 10.4271/932653.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., “Liquid and Vapor Spray Structure in High-Pressure Common Rail Diesel Injection,” Atom. Sprays, 11:533, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Espey, C., Dec, J.E., Litzinger, T.A., and Santavicca, D. A., “Planar Laser Rayleigh Scattering for Quantitative Vapor- Fuel Imaging in a Diesel Jet,” Combust. Flame 109:65-86, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulz, C., Gronki, J., and Andersson, S., “Multi-Species Laser-Based Imaging Measurements in a Diesel Spray,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1917, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1917.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Adam, A., Leick, P., Bittlinger, G., and Schulz, C., “Visualization of the Evaporation of a Diesel Spray using Combined Mie and Rayleigh Scattering Techniques,” Exp. Fluids 47:439-449, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C.A. and Pickett, L.M., “Quantitative Mixing Measurements in a Vaporizing Diesel Spray by Rayleigh Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0647, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network data archive. &lt;http://www.sandia.gov/ECN/&gt;.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abraham, J. and Pickett, L.M., “Computed and Measured Fuel Vapor Distribution in a Diesel Spray,” Atom. Sprays 20:241-250, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Kook, S., and Williams, T.C., Visualization of Diesel Spray Penetration, Cool-Flame, Ignition, High-Temperature Combustion, and Soot Formation Using High-Speed Imaging,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 439-459, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0658.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Settles, G.S., Schlieren and Shadowgraph Techniques, Springer-Verlag, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot in Diesel Fuel Jets: Effects of Ambient Temperature, Ambient Density, and Injection Pressure,” Combust. Flame 138:114-135, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Idicheria, C.A., “Effects of Ambient Temperature and Density on Soot Formation under High EGR Conditions,” Thermo- and Fluid-Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines: THIESEL, Valencia, Spain, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C. A. and Pickett, L.M., “Soot Formation in Diesel Combustion under High-EGR Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3834, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-3834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L. and Higgins, B.S., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Sprays under Quiescent Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0530, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D.L., Higgins, B.S., and Pickett, L.M., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Fuel Jets: Oxygen Concentration Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0890, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Genzale, C.L., Bruneaux, G., Malbec, L.- M., Hermant, L., Christiansen, C.A., and Schramm, J., “Comparison of Diesel Spray Combustion in Different High- Temperature, High-Pressure Facilities,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2): 156-181, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-2106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">d'Errico, J. Inpaint_nans routine. Matlab file exchange, &lt;http://www.mathworks.com/matlabcentral/fileexchange/? term=tag%3A%22inpaint%22&gt;, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dibble, R.W., Hollenbach, R.E., “Laser Rayleigh Thermometry in Turbulent Flames”, Proc. Combust. Inst., 18:1489, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Caton, J.A., Musculus, M.P.B., and Lutz, A.E., “Evaluation of the Equivalence Ratio-Temperature Region of Diesel Soot Precursor Formation using a Two- Stage Lagrangian Model,” Int. J. Engine Res. 7:349-370, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moffat, R.J., “Describing the Uncertainties in Experimental Results,” Exp. Therm. Fluid Science 1:3-17, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blessing, M., König, G., Krüger, C., Michels, U., and Schwarz, V., “Analysis of Flow and Cavitation Phenomena in Diesel Injection Nozzles and its Effects on Spray and Mixture Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1358, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1358.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kastengren, A.L., Powell, C.F., Wang, Y.J., Im, K.S., and Wang, J., “X-Ray Radiography Measurements of Diesel Spray Structure at Engine-Like Ambient Density,” Atom. Sprays 19:1031-1044, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arrègle, J., Pastor, J.V., and Ruiz, S., “The Influence of Injection Parameters on Diesel Spray Characteristics,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0200, 1999, doi: 10.4271/1999-01-0200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Arai, M., “Structures of Fuel Sprays in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 900475, 1990, doi: 10.4271/900475.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Desantes, J.M., and Arrègle, J., “Characterization of DI Diesel Sprays in High Density Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 960774, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960774.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heimgärtner, C. and Leipertz, A., “Investigation of the Primary Spray Breakup Close to the Nozzle of a Common - Rail High Pressure Diesel Injection System,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1799, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1799.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R.D. and Bracco, F.B., “On the Dependence of Spray Angle and Other Spray Parameters on Nozzle Design and Operating Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 790494, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790494.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J., Internal Combustion Engines, McGraw- Hill, New York, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot Formation in Diesel Fuel Jets Near the Lift-Off Length,” Int. J. Engine Res. 7:103-130, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
