<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26939361</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Optimal Tax 1</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Heterogeneity in Talent or in Tastes? Implications for Redistributive Taxation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fillmore</surname>
                  <given-names>Ian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gallen</surname>
                  <given-names>Trevor</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">111</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26939350</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>30</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26939361"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>How much of income heterogeneity is due to taste vs. talent? We use a simple model of human capital accumulation inspired by Neal and Rosen (2005) in which workers are heterogeneous in (i) their ability to accumulate human capital (talent) (ii) their preferences over consumption vs. leisure (taste) and (iii) their initial human capital to estimate the joint distribution of taste and talent. Filtering out idiosyncratic hours shocks from the NLSY79 and focusing on highly-attached prime-age males, we find that even for this group, heterogeneneity in taste plays a large role: 71% of income variation at age 44 is due solely to taste, rather than talent or initial conditions. We find that the moments driving high heterogeneity in taste are the relatively high standard deviation in “permanent” labor hours and the positive correlation between labor hours and earnings that does not strongly decline by age. Finally, we show that exchanging the sources of income variation changes utilitarian optimal tax rates significantly, particularly when heterogeneity is due to differences in the marginal utility of consumption, rather than leisure.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">J M Abowd and D Card. On the Covariance Structure of Earnings and Hours Changes. Econo- metrica, 57(2):411-445, 1989. ISSN 0012-9682. doi: 10.2307/1912561.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Mark Aguiar and Erik Hurst. Measuring trends in leisure: The allocation of time over five decades. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 122(3):969-1006, 2007. ISSN 0033-5533. doi: 10.1162/qjec.122.3.969.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Mark Aguiar, Erik Hurst, and Loukas Karabarbounis. Recent developments in the economics of time use. Annual Review of Economics, 4, 2012. ISSN 1057-9230.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Regis Barnichon and Andrew Figura. Declining Desire to Work and Downward Trends in Un- employment and Participation. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Raymond C Battalio, John H Kagel, and Morgan O Reynolds. Income Distributions in Two Experimental Economies. Journal of Political Economy, 85(6):1259-1271, 1977.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Yoram Ben-Porath. The Production of Human Capital and the Life Cycle of Earnings. Journal of Political Economy, 75(4):352-365, 1967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Adam Blandin. Learning by doing and ben-porath: Life-cycle predictions and policy implica- tions. Working Papers 1604, VCU School of Business, Department of Economics, 2016. URL https://EconPapers.repec.org/RePEc:vcu:wpaper:1604.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Richard Blundell, Luigi Pistaferri, and Itay Saporta-Eksten. Consumption Inequality and Family Labor Supply. American Economic Review, 106(2):387-435, 2016. doi: 10.1257/aer.20121549.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Robin Boadway, Maurice Marchand, Pierre Pestieau, and Maria Del Mar Racionero. Opti- mal Redistribution with Heterogeneous Preferences for Leisure. Journal of Public Economic Theory, 4(4):475-498, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Audra J Bowlus and Chris Robinson. Human Capital Prices, Productivity, and Growth. The American Economic Review, 102(7):3483-3515, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Flavio Cunha and James Heckman. Decomposing Trends in Inequality in Earnings into Fore- castable and Uncertain Components. Journal of Labor Economics, 34(2), 2016.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Peter Gottschalk and Robert Mott. The Rising Instability of U.S. Earnings. Journal of Economic Perspectives, 23(4):3-24, 2009. ISSN 0895-3309. doi: 10.1257/jep.23.4.3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Peter Gottschalk, Robert Mott, Lawrence F Katz, and William T Dickens. The Growth of Earnings Instability in the U . S . Labor Market. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 1994(2):217-272, 1994. ISSN 0007-2303. doi: 10.2307/2534657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Fatih Guvenen, Burhanettin Kuruscu, and Serdar Ozkan. Taxation of Human Capital and Wage Inequality: A Cross-Country Analysis. Review of Economic Studies, 81(2):818-850, 2014. URL https://ideas.repec.org/a/oup/restud/v81y2014i2p818-850.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Jonathan Heathcote, Kjetil Storesletten, and Giovanni L. Violante. Consumption and labor supply with partial insurance: An analytical framework. American Economic Review, 104(7): 2075-2126, 2014. ISSN 00028282. doi: 10.1257/aer.104.7.2075.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">James Heckman, Lance Lochner, and Christopher Taber. Explaining Rising Wage Inequality: Explorations with a Dynamic General Equilibrium Model of Labour Earnings with Heteroge- nous Agents. Review of Economic Dynamics, 1:1-58, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">James J. Heckman. A Life-Cycle Model of Earnings, Learning, and Consumption. Journal of Political Economy, 84(4):S11-S44, 1976a.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">James J. Heckman. Estimates of a Human Capital Production Function Embedded in a Life-Cycle Model of Labor Supply. 1976b. ISBN 0870145150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Mark Huggett, Gustavo Ventura, and Amir Yaron. Sources of lifetime inequality. American Economic Review, 101(7):2923-2954, 2011. ISSN 00028282. doi: 10.1257/aer.101.7.2923.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Daniel Kahneman. Thinking, Fast and Slow. Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 2011. ISBN 1429969350.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Michael P. Keane and Kenneth I. Wolpin. The Role of Labor and Marriage Markets, Preference Heterogeneity, and the Welfare System in the Life Cycle Decisions of Black, Hispanic, and White Women. International Economic Review, 51(3):851-892, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">J Kennan. A Note on Discrete Approximations of Continuous Distributions. Mimeo, 1 (September), 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Robert G. King, Charles I. Plosser, and Sergio T. Rebelo. Production, Growth and Business Cycles. Journal of Monetary Economics, 21:195-232, 1988. ISSN 03043932. doi: 10.1016/0304–3932(88)90034-7.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Donghoon Lee and Kenneth I Wolpin. Intersectoral Labor Mobility and the Growth of the Service Sector. Econometrica, 74(1):1-46, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Donghoon Lee and Kenneth I. Wolpin. Accounting for wage and employment changes in the US from 1968-2000: A dynamic model of labor market equilibrium. Journal of Econometrics, 156(1):68-85, 2010. ISSN 03044076. doi: 10.1016/j.jeconom.2009.09.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Benjamin B. Lockwood and Matthew Weinzierl. De Gustibus non est Taxandum: Heterogeneity in preferences and optimal redistribution. Journal of Public Economics, 124:74-80, apr 2015. ISSN 00472727. doi: 10.1016/j.jpubeco.2015.01.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Thomas E. MaCurdy. An Empirical Model of Labor Supply in a Life-Cycle Setting. Journal of Political Economy, 89(6):1059-1085, 1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Rodolfo E Manuelli, Ananth Seshadri, and Yongseok Shin. Lifetime Labor Supply and Human Capital Investment. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">J. A. Mirrlees. An Exploration in the Theory of Optimal Income Taxation. The Review of Economic Studies, 38(2):175-208, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Derek Neal and Sherwin Rosen. Theories of the Distribution of Earnings BT - Handbook of Income Distribution, Volume 1. In A B Atkinson and F Bourguignon, editors, Handbook of Income Distribution, Volume 1, volume 1, pages 379-427. Elsevier Science, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Paolo Giovanni Piacquadio. A Fairness Justification of Utilitarianism. Econometrica, 85(4): 1261-1276, 2017. ISSN 0012-9682. doi: 10.3982/ECTA14151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Solomon W Polachek, Tirthatanmoy Das, and Rewat Thamma-Apiroam. Micro- and Macroeconomic Implications of Heterogeneity in the Production of Human Capital. Journal of Political Economy, 123(6):1410-1455, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Martin Ravallion. Inequality when Eort Matters. jul 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Emmanuel Saez and Stefanie Stantcheva. Generalized Social Marginal Welfare Weights for Optimal Tax Theory. American Economic Review, 106(1):24-45, 2016. ISSN 0002-8282. doi: 10.1257/aer.20141362.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Stefanie Stantcheva. Learning and (or) Doing: Human Capital Investments and Optimal Taxa- tion. jul 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>This figure depicts three comparison paths: a baseline path (black lines), a low-distaste for labor path (blue lines), and a high-ability path (red lines). Importantly, while the two counterfactual paths display similar hourly wages, an increase in talent decreases total labor hours while a decrease in distaste increases total labor hours. As a consequence, increasing earnings with higher ability typically lowers the correlation between hours and earnings, increasing earnings with a lower distaste for labor increases the correlation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>This figure depicts the six sets of empirical moments from the NLSY79 (red line) and model fits (black line) that describe the joint distribution of labor hours and earnings by age.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Directly-Calibrated Parameters</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>This figure depicts the joint distribution of talent A<sub>i</sub>, taste ψ<sub>i</sub>, and initial human capital at age 30 (interpreted as an hourly wage) RK<sub>i</sub>. Importantly for our results, our model moments put our fit to include people who work many hours (have a low distaste for labor) but are relatively untalented (have a reactively low wage), while there are people with high talent and high initial wage who work relatively little.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>This figure summarizes our main decomposition results, depicting the three elasticities from equation 21. Each of the three visible lines (the residual category, a measure of how bad our linear approximation is, is not visible) indicates how much earnings variance at each age falls if variance in the corresponding parameter falls by 1%. These values are normalized by the total fall in earnings variance at each age.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>This figure depicts the change in the proportion of earnings variation at age 44 attributable to talent, taste and initial human capital for various level changes in the correlation between earnings and labor hours. Each elasticity is calculated using the elasticities of equation 21. As we increase the level of the correlation between hours and earnings throughout agents lifetimes, so that people who earn more typically work more, our model puts more emphasis on taste as the driving force behind earnings variation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>This figure depicts the change in the proportion of earnings variation at age 44 attributable to talent, taste and initial human capital for various level changes in the standard deviation of labor hours. Each elasticity is calculated using the elasticities of equation 21. As we increase the “permanent” variation in hours worked, so that there exist some people working many hours and some working few, our model puts more emphasis on taste as the driving force behind earnings variation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>This figure depicts the equivalent variation of changing the tax rate from its optimum in our baseline setup and when we exchange sources of variation from talent to taste, keeping income variation at age 44 constant, with α = 0.5 (heterogeneity on both consumption and labor preferences). The black line depicts the utility loss from changing the tax rate and resultant transfer (measured by the total change in utility of all agents, converted into dollars using the average marginal utility of money at the optimum). The red line depicts the same exercise after reducing population variation in talent and increasing it in taste. The shift from the black line's apex to the red line's apex shows the change in optimal taxation caused by changes in the sources of income variation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>This figure depicts the two optimal tax rates as a function of α, which controls where heterogeneity in preference lies. When α = 0, the heterogeneous term multiplies consumption preferences, and all heterogeneity lies on consumption. When α = 1, heterogeneity shifts to labor preferences. When heterogeneity lies on labor preferences, the two tax rates are both higher and highly similar. When heterogeneity lies on consumption preferences, the impetus for redistributive taxation is lower, and the optimal tax rate is more sensitive (both in percentage and absolute terms) to the sources of income variation.</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
