<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2/3</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000402</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40007732</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Multilingual Generation: The Role of Telicity in Lexical Choice and Syntactic Realization</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Bonnie J.</given-names>
                  <surname>Dorr</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mari Broman</given-names>
                  <surname>Olsen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1996</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>37</fpage>
         <lpage>74</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1996 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40007732"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>Multilingual generation in machine translation (MT) requires a knowledge organization that facilitates the task of "lexical choice", i.e. selection of lexical units to be used in the generation of a target-language sentence. This paper investigates the extent to which "lexicalization patterns" involving the "lexical aspect" feature [+telic] may be used for translating events and states among languages. Telicity has been correlated syntactically with both transitivity and unaccusativity, and semantically with Talmy's 'path' of a motion event, the representation of which characterizes languages parametrically. Taking as our starting point the syntactic/semantic classification in Levin's "English Verb Classes and Alternations," we examine the relation between telicity and the syntactic contexts, or "alternations," outlined in this work, identifying systematic relations between the lexical aspect features and the semantic components that potentiate these alternations. Representing lexical aspect-particularly telicity - is therefore crucial for the tasks of lexical choice and syntactic realization. Having enriched the data in Levin (by correlating the syntactic alternations (Part I) and semantic verb classes (Part II) and marking them for telicity) we assign to verbs "lexical semantic templates" (LSTs). We then demonstrate that it is possible from these templates to build a large-scale repository for "lexical conceptual structures" which encode meaning components that correspond to different values of the telicity feature. The LST framework preserves both "semantic content" and "semantic structure" (following Grimshaw during the processes of lexical choice and syntactic realization. Application of this model identifies precisely where the Knowledge Representation component may profitably augment our rules of composition, to identify cases where the interlingua underlying the source language sentence must be either reduced or modified in order to produce an appropriate target language sentence.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>syntax-semantics interface</kwd>
            <kwd>syntactic alternations</kwd>
            <kwd>semantic classes</kwd>
            <kwd>(a)telicity</kwd>
            <kwd>multilingual generation</kwd>
            <kwd>interlingua</kwd>
            <kwd>lexical conceptual structure</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>Notes</title>
            <ref id="d3000081e197a1310">
               <label>2</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e204" publication-type="other">
[45, p. 66],</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e211a1310">
               <label>4</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e218" publication-type="other">
[45, p. 57].</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e225a1310">
               <label>6</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e232" publication-type="other">
[33, p. 268].</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e239a1310">
               <label>10</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e246" publication-type="other">
[45, p. 12]</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e254a1310">
               <label>14</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e261" publication-type="other">
Ullman [68, p. 161],</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e268a1310">
               <label>15</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e275" publication-type="other">
Olsen [47]</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e282a1310">
               <label>24</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e289" publication-type="other">
Dorr and Voss [18];</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e296a1310">
               <label>34</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e303" publication-type="other">
Search (2.11)</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d3000081e319a1310">
               <label>1</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e326" publication-type="other">
S. Ali and S. Shapiro: 1993, Natural Language Processing Using a Propositional Semantic
Network with Structured Variables, International Journal of Minds and Machines 3, 421-451.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e336a1310">
               <label>2</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e343" publication-type="other">
J. Anderson: 1971, The Grammar of Case: Towards a Localist Theory. Cambridge University
Press, Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e353a1310">
               <label>3</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e360" publication-type="other">
J.D. Apresjan: 1973, Regular Polysemy, Linguistics 142, 5-32.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e367a1310">
               <label>4</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e374" publication-type="other">
Edmond Bach: 1986, The Algebra of Events, Linguistics and Philosophy 9, 5-16.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e382a1310">
               <label>5</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e389" publication-type="other">
Douglas A. Behrend: 1990, The Development of Verb Concepts: Children's Use of Verbs to
Label Familiar and Novel Events, Child Development 61, 681-696.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e399a1310">
               <label>6</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e406" publication-type="other">
Douglas A. Behrend, L. Lynn Harris, and Kelly B. Cartwright: 1995, Morphological Cues to
Verb Meaning: Verb Inflections and the Initial Mapping of Verb Meanings, Journal of Child
Language 22, 89-106.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e419a1310">
               <label>7</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e426" publication-type="other">
Laurel J. Brinton: 1988, The Development of English Aspectual Systems: Aspectualizers and
Post-Verbal Particles. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e436a1310">
               <label>8</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e443" publication-type="other">
D. Alan Cruse: 1995, Polysemy and Related Phenomena from a Cognitive Linguistic Viewpoint,
in P. Saint-Dizier and E. Viegas (eds), Computational Lexical Semantics, pp. 33-49. Cambridge
University Press, Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e456a1310">
               <label>9</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e463" publication-type="other">
Chrysanne DiMarco, Graeme Hirst, and Manfred Stede: 1993, The Semantic and Stylistic Differ-
entiation of Synonyms and Near-Synonyms. In Working Notes for the AAAI Spring Symposium on
Building Lexicons for Machine Translation, Technical Report SS-93-02, pp. 114-121, Stanford
University, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e479a1310">
               <label>10</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e486" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr: 1992, A Parameterized Approach to Integrating Aspect with Lexical-Semantics
for Machine Translation, in Proceedings of the 30th Annual Meeting of the Association for
Computational Linguistics, pp. 257-264, University of Delaware, Newark, DE.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e500a1310">
               <label>11</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e507" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr: 1993, Machine Translation: A View from the Lexicon. The MIT Press, Cambridge,
MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e517a1310">
               <label>12</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e524" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr, Joseph Garman, and Amy Weinberg: 1995, From Syntactic Encodings to The-
matic Roles: Building Lexical Entries for Interlingual MT, Machine Translation 9, 71-100.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e534a1310">
               <label>13</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e541" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr and Doug Jones: 1996, Role of Word Sense Disambiguation in Lexical Acquisi-
tion: Predicting Semantics from Syntactic Cues, in Coling 96 Proceedings of the International
Conference on Computational Linguistics, Copenhagen, Denmark, pp. 322-333.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e554a1310">
               <label>14</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e561" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr and Doug Jones: 1996, Use of Syntactic and Semantic Filters for Lexical Acqui-
sition: Using WordNet to Increase Precision, in Proceedings of the Workshop on Predicative
Forms in Natural Language and Lexical Knowledge Bases, Toulouse, France, pp. 81-88.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e574a1310">
               <label>15</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e581" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr, Dekang Lin, Jye hoon Lee, and Sungki Suh: 1995, Efficient Parsing for Korean
and English: A Parameterized Message Passing Approach, Computational Linguistics 21, 255-
263.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e594a1310">
               <label>16</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e601" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr and Martha Palmer: 1995, Building a LCS-Based Lexicon in TAGs, in Proceedings
of the AAAI-95 Spring Symposium Series, Representation and Acquisition of Lexical Knowledge:
Polysemy, Ambiguity, and Generativity, Stanford, CA, pp. 33-38.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e615a1310">
               <label>17</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e622" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr and Clare Voss: 1993, Machine Translation of Spatial Expressions: Denning
the Relation between an Interlingua and a Knowledge Representation System, in Proceedings of
Twelfth Conference of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence, 374-379, Washington,
DC.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e638a1310">
               <label>18</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e645" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr and Clare Voss: 1996, A Multi-Level Approach to Interlingual MT: Defining the
Interface between Representational Languages, International Journal of Expert Systems.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e655a1310">
               <label>19</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e662" publication-type="other">
Bonnie J. Dorr, Clare Voss, Eric Peterson, and Michael Kiker: 1994, Concept Based Lexical
Selection, in AAAI 1994 Fall Symposium on Knowledge Representation for Natural Language
Processing in Implemented Systems, New Orleans, LA, pp. 21-30.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e675a1310">
               <label>20</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e682" publication-type="other">
David Dowty: 1979, Word Meaning in Montague Grammar, D. Reidel, Dordrecht.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e689a1310">
               <label>21</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e696" publication-type="other">
David Dowty: 1977, Toward a Semantic Analysis of Verb Aspect and the English 'Imperfective'
Progressive, Linguistics and Philosophy 1, 45-77.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e706a1310">
               <label>22</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e713" publication-type="other">
Howard B. Garey: 1957, Verbal Aspect in French, Language 33, 91-110.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e721a1310">
               <label>23</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e728" publication-type="other">
Dedre Gentner: 1978, On Relational Meaning: The Acquisition of Verb Meaning, Child Devel-
opment 49, 988-998.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e738a1310">
               <label>24</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e745" publication-type="other">
Jane Grimshaw: 1993, Semantic Structure and Semantic Content in Lexical Representation,
unpublished ms., Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e755a1310">
               <label>25</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e762" publication-type="other">
Jess Gropen, Steven Pinker, Michelle Hollander, and Richard Goldberg: 1991, Syntax and Seman-
tics in the Acquisition of Locative Verbs, Journal of Child Language 18, 115-151.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e772a1310">
               <label>26</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e779" publication-type="other">
Jeffrey S. Gruber: 1967, Look and See, Language 43, 937-947.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e786a1310">
               <label>27</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e793" publication-type="other">
Mohamed Guerssel, Kenneth Hale, Mary Laughren, Beth Levin, and Josie White Eagle: 1985,
A Cross-linguistic Study of Transitivity Alternations, in W. H. Eilfort, P. D. Kroeber, and K. L.
Peterson (eds), CLS 21, Part 2, The Chicago Linguistic Society, Chicago, pp. 48-63.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e806a1310">
               <label>28</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e813" publication-type="other">
B. Heine, U. Claudi, and F. Huennemeyer: 1991, Grammaticalization: A Conceptual Framework.
University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e824a1310">
               <label>29</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e831" publication-type="other">
Graeme Hirst: 1988, Resolving Lexical Ambiguity Computationally with Spreading Activation
and Polaroid Words, in S.I. Small, G.W. Cottrell, and M.K. Tanenhaus (eds), Lexical Ambiguity
Resolution. Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, CA, pp. 73-107.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e844a1310">
               <label>30</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e851" publication-type="other">
Lucja Iwanska: 1993, Logical Reasoning in Natural Language: It is All about Knowledge,
International Journal of Minds and Machines 3, 475-510.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e861a1310">
               <label>31</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e868" publication-type="other">
Ray Jackendoff: 1983, Semantics and Cognition. The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e875a1310">
               <label>32</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e882" publication-type="other">
Ray Jackendoff: 1990, Semantic Structures. The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e889a1310">
               <label>33</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e896" publication-type="other">
Suzanne Kemmer, ed.: 1993, The Middle Voice. John Benjamins, Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e903a1310">
               <label>34</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e910" publication-type="other">
Anthony Kenny: 1963, Action, Emotion and Will. Routledge and Kegan-Paul, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e918a1310">
               <label>35</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e925" publication-type="other">
Adam Kilgarriff: 1995, Inheriting Polysemy. In P. Saint-Dizier and E. Viegas (eds), Computa-
tional Lexical Semantics. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, pp. 319-335.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e935a1310">
               <label>36</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e942" publication-type="other">
R. Langacker: 1987, Foundations of Cognitive Grammar, Vol. 1: Theoretical Prerequisites.
Stanford University Press, Stanford, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e952a1310">
               <label>37</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e959" publication-type="other">
BethLevin: 1993, English Verb Classes and Alternations: A Preliminary Investigation. University
of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e969a1310">
               <label>38</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e976" publication-type="other">
Beth Levin and Malka Rappaport Hovav: 1995, The Elasticity of Verb Meaning, in Proceedings
of the Tenth Annual Conference of the Israel Association for Theoretical Linguistics and the
Workshop on the Syntax-Semantics Interface, Bar Ilan University, Israel.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e989a1310">
               <label>39</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e996" publication-type="other">
Beth Levin and Malka Rappaport Hovav: 1995, Unaccusativity: At the Syntax-Lexical Semantics
Interface. The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1006a1310">
               <label>40</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1013" publication-type="other">
Lori Levin and Sergei Nirenburg: 1993, Principles and Idiosyncracies in MT Lexicons, in Working
Notes for the AAAI Spring Symposium on Building Lexicons for Machine Translation, pp. 122-
131, Stanford University, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1027a1310">
               <label>41</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1034" publication-type="other">
Talke Macfarland: 1995, Cognate Objects and the Argument/Adjunct Distinction in English. PhD
thesis, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1044a1310">
               <label>42</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1051" publication-type="other">
A. Mourelatos: 1981, Events, Processes, and States, in P. Tedeschi and A. Zaenen (eds), Syntax
and Semantics 14: Tense and Aspect, pp. 191-212. Academic Press, New York, NY. Originally
published in Linguistics and Philosophy 2, 415-434, (1978).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1064a1310">
               <label>43</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1071" publication-type="other">
Sergei Nirenburg, Jaime Carbonell, Masaru Tomita, and Kenneth Goodman: 1992, Machine
Translation: A Knowledge-Based Approach. Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1081a1310">
               <label>44</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1088" publication-type="other">
Mari Broman Olsen: 1991, Lexical Semantic Typology of Motion Verbs: Insight from Translation,
in M. Alexander and M. Dressier (eds), Papers from the Second Annual Meeting of the Formal
Linguistic Society of Mid-America, pp. 255-271. University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1101a1310">
               <label>45</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1108" publication-type="other">
Mari Broman Olsen: 1994, The Semantics and Pragmatics of Lexical and Grammatical Aspect.
PhD thesis, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1118a1310">
               <label>46</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1125" publication-type="other">
Mari Broman Olsen: 1994, The Semantics and Pragmatics of Lexical Aspect Features, in Proceed-
ings of the Formal Linguistic Society ofMidamerica V, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign,
Studies in the Linguistic Sciences, 24.2, pp. 361-375.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1139a1310">
               <label>47</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1146" publication-type="other">
Mari Broman Olsen: 1996, Telicity and English Verb Classes and Alternations: An Overview,
Umiacs TR 96-15, CS TR 3607, University of Maryland, College Park, MD.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1156a1310">
               <label>48</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1163" publication-type="other">
Martha Palmer and Zhibao Wu: 1995, Verb Semantics for English-Chinese Translation, Machine
Translation 10, 59-92.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1173a1310">
               <label>49</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1180" publication-type="other">
Terence Parsons: 1990, Events in the Semantics of English. The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1187a1310">
               <label>50</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1194" publication-type="other">
Steven Pinker: 1989, Learnability and Cognition. The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1201a1310">
               <label>51</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1208" publication-type="other">
Stanley Porter: 1989, Verbal Aspect in the Greek of the New Testament, with Reference to Tense
and Mood, in D.A. Carson (ed.), Studies in Biblical Greek, Vol. 1. Peter Lang, New York.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1218a1310">
               <label>52</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1225" publication-type="other">
F. Pugeault, P. Saint-Dizier, and M.G. Monteil: 1994, Knowledge Extraction From Texts: A
Method For Extracting Predicate-Argument Structures From Texts, in Proceedings of Fifteenth
International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Kyoto, Japan, pp. 1039-1043.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1239a1310">
               <label>53</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1246" publication-type="other">
James Pustejovsky: 1991, The Syntax of Event Structure, in Beth Levin and Steven Pinker (eds),
Lexical and Conceptual Semantics. Blackwell, Cambridge, MA, pp. 47-81.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1256a1310">
               <label>54</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1263" publication-type="other">
James Pustejovsky: 1995, The Generative Lexicon. The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1270a1310">
               <label>55</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1277" publication-type="other">
J.J. Quantz and B. Schmitz: 1994, Knowledge-Based Disambiguation for Machine Translation,
International Journal of Minds and Machines 4, 39-57.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1287a1310">
               <label>56</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1294" publication-type="other">
Roger C. Schank: 1975, Conceptual Information Processing. Elsevier Science Publishers, Ams-
terdam.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1304a1310">
               <label>57</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1311" publication-type="other">
Leonard Schubert: 1991, Semantic Nets are in the Eye of the Beholder, in J. Sowa (ed.), Principles
of Semantic Networks, Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, CA, pp. 95-107.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1321a1310">
               <label>58</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1328" publication-type="other">
Dan I. Slobin: (to appear), Typology and Rhetoric: Verbs of Motion in English and Spanish, in
M. Shibatani and S. A. Thompson (eds), Grammatical Constructions: Their Form and Meaning.
Oxford University Press, Oxford.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1342a1310">
               <label>59</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1349" publication-type="other">
Dan I. Slobin and Aura Bocaz: 1988, Learning to Talk about Movement through Time and Space:
The Development of Narrative Abilities in Spanish and English, Lenguas Modernas 15, 5-24.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1359a1310">
               <label>60</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1366" publication-type="other">
Carlota Smith: 1991, The Parameter oj Aspect. Kluwer, Dordrecht.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1373a1310">
               <label>61</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1380" publication-type="other">
J. Sowa: 1991, Toward the Expressive Power of Natural Language, In J. Sowa (ed.), Principles
of Semantic Networks, pp. 157-189. Morgan Kaufmann, San Mateo, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1390a1310">
               <label>62</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1397" publication-type="other">
Leonard Talmy: 1975, Semantics and Syntax of Motion, In J.P. Kimball (ed.), Syntax and
Semantics 4, pp. 181-238. Academic Press, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1407a1310">
               <label>63</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1414" publication-type="other">
Leonard Talmy: 1985, Lexicalization Patterns: Semantic Structure in Lexical Forms, in T. Shopen
(ed.), Language Typology and Syntactic Description 3: Grammatical Categories and the Lexicon.
University Press, Cambridge, pp. 57-149.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1427a1310">
               <label>64</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1434" publication-type="other">
Leonard Talmy: 1991, Path to Realization: A Typology of Event Conflation, Technical Report
Buffalo Papers in Linguistics, Vol. 91-01, State University of New York, Buffalo, NY.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1445a1310">
               <label>65</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1452" publication-type="other">
Carol Tenny: 1992, The Aspectual Interface Hypothesis, in LA. Sag and A. Szabolcsi (eds),
Lexical Matters. CSLI Publications, Stanford, CA, pp. 1-27.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1462a1310">
               <label>66</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1469" publication-type="other">
Carol Tenny: 1994, Aspectual Roles and the Syntax-Semantics Interface. Kluwer, Dordrecht.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1476a1310">
               <label>67</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1483" publication-type="other">
Carol Tenny: 1996, Review of Verkuyl's A Theory of Aspectuality. Language 72, 121-126.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1490a1310">
               <label>68</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1497" publication-type="other">
Stephen Ullmann: 1962, Semantics: An Introduction to the Science of Meaning. Harper and Row,
New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1507a1310">
               <label>69</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1514" publication-type="other">
Angehek Van Hout: (to appear), Projection Based on Event Structure, in P. Coopmans, Mar-
tin Everaert and Jane Grimshaw (eds), Lexical Specification and Lexical Insertion, Lawrence
Erlbaum Associates, Hillsdale, NJ.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1527a1310">
               <label>70</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1534" publication-type="other">
Robert D. van Valin, Jr: 1993, A Synopsis of Role and Reference Grammar, in Robert D.
van Valin, Jr. (ed), Advances in Role and Reference Grammar, pp. 1-164. John Benjamins,
Amsterdam.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1548a1310">
               <label>71</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1555" publication-type="other">
Zeno Vendler: 1957, Verbs and Times, Philosophical Review 56, 143-160. Reprinted in Linguis-
tics in Philosophy, 1967, pp. 97-121, Cornell University Press, Ithaca, NY.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1565a1310">
               <label>72</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1572" publication-type="other">
Henk Verkuyl: 1972, On the Compositional Nature of the Aspects. D. Reidel, Dordrecht.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1579a1310">
               <label>73</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1586" publication-type="other">
Henk Verkuyl: 1993, A Theory ofAspectuality: The Interaction between Temporal andAtemporal
Structure. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1596a1310">
               <label>74</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1603" publication-type="other">
G. Vernère: 1994, Manuel d'utihsation de la structure lexicale conceptuelle (LCS) pour
representer des phrases en francais. Researc note, IRIT, Université Paul Sabatier, Toulouse,
France.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d3000081e1616a1310">
               <label>75</label>
               
               <mixed-citation id="d3000081e1623" publication-type="other">
Uriel Weinreich: 1964, Webster's Third: A Critique of its Semantics, International Journal of
American Linguistics 30, 405-409.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
