<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277739</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Influence of the Washcoat Structure in the Performance of Automotive Three Way Catalysts</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Santos</surname>
                  <given-names>Helder</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Instituto Politécnico de Leiria</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pires</surname>
                  <given-names>João</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Instituto Politécnico de Leiria</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Costa</surname>
                  <given-names>Mário</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Instituto Superior Tecnico</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>September 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277710</issue-id>
         <fpage>1846</fpage>
         <lpage>1854</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277739"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Transport limitations inside the porous washcoat layer have an important influence in the light-off and overall conversions even in the case of relatively thin layers used in automotive three way catalysts (TWC). The porous structure of the washcoat layer is controlled at two levels: i) at the level of mesoporous structure, which can be determined by the use of specific synthesis techniques (<italic>e.g.</italic>, sol-gel or pore-templating method), and ii) at the level of macroporous structure, which is influenced by the particle size distribution of mesoporous in a slurry that has undergone a specific thermal treatment. This paper investigates the influence of the washcoat structure in the performance of automotive TWC. Furthermore, the article presents a method that allows to quantify the magnitude of the reaction resistance (chemical kinetics), internal mass transfer resistance (washcoat diffusion), and external mass transfer resistance on the TWC conversions. From experimental data gathered at different operating temperatures (from light-off to 1100 K) and applying the developed methodology for resistances quantification, it was found that the internal mass transfer limitations play a major role in the TWC conversions. The main conclusions from this study are: i) the effective diffusivity strongly depends on the washcoat layer structure, which in turn depends on its preparation process; ii) the resistance quantification analysis reveals that the lower effective diffusivity interval is more adequate for the TWC used in the present investigation, which also indicates that the TWC washcoat has a low percentage of macropores; and iii) to decrease the relevance of the internal mass transfer limitation requires an increase in the effective diffusivity and/or a thinner washcoat layer.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Avila, P., Montes, M., and Miró, E., “Monolithic Reactors for Environmental Applications a Review on Preparation Technologies”, Chemical Engineering Journal, 109, 11-36, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meille, V., “Review on Methods to Deposit Catalysts on Structured Surfaces”, Applied Catalysis A: General, 315, 1-17, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kočí, P., Štěpánek, F., Kubíček, M., and Marek, M., “Meso-Scale Modelimg of CO Oxidation in Digitally Reconstructed Porous Pt/γ- Al2O3 Catalyst”, Chemical Engineering Science, 61, 3240-3249, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kočí, P., Kubíček, M., and Marek, M., “Modeling of Three-Way Catalyst Monolith Converters with Microkinetics and Diffusion in the Washcoat”, Industrial Engineering Chemistry Research, 43, 4503-4510, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Santos, H., and Costa, M., “The Relative Importance of External and Internal Transport Phenomena in Three Way Catalysts”, International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer, 51, 1409-1422, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, F., Hayes, R., and Kolaczkowski, S., “A New Technique to Measure the Effective Diffusivity in the Washcoat of a Monolith Reactor”, Chemical Engineering Research and Design, 82, 481-489, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hayes, R., Kolaczkowski, S., Li, P., and Awdry, S., “Evaluating the Effective Diffusivity of Methane in the Washcoat of a Honeycomb Monolith”, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental, 25, 93-104, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Starý, T., Šolcová, O., Schneider, P., and Marek, M., “Effective Diffusivities and Pore-transport Characteristics of Washcoated Ceramic Monolith for Automotive Catalytic Converter”, Chemical Engineering Science, 61, 5934-5943, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kato, S., Ozeki, H., Yamada, H., Tagawa, T., Takahashi, N., and Shinjoh, H., “Direct Measurements of gas Diffusivity in a Washcoat Layer Under Steady State Conditions at Ambient Temperature”, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, 19(3), 835-840, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolaczkowski, S., “Measurement of Effective Diffusivity in Catalyst- Coated Monoliths”, Catalysis Today, 83, 85-95, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Joshi, S., Harold, M., and Balakotaiah, V., “Overall Mass Transfer Coefficients and Controlling Regimes in Catalytic Monoliths”, Chem. Eng. Sci., 65, 1729-1747, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
