<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440098</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Keeping up or Falling behind? The Impact of Benefit and Tax Uprating on Incomes and Poverty</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Holly</given-names>
                  <surname>Sutherland</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Ruth</given-names>
                  <surname>Hancock</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Hills</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Francesca</given-names>
                  <surname>Zantomio</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2008</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">29</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440094</issue-id>
         <fpage>467</fpage>
         <lpage>498</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 2008</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440098"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Each year, the government decides how much to raise benefits and tax allowances. In the UK, the basis for these upratings is rarely debated, yet has major long-term consequences for the relative living standards of different groups as well as for the public finances. This paper considers the medium-term implications of present uprating policies, which vary across parameters of the tax–benefit system. Continuing these policies for 20 years, other things staying the same, would result in a near doubling of the child poverty rate alongside a substantial gain to the public finances. At the same time, pensioners are largely protected by the earnings indexation of pensioner benefits including, in time, the basic state pension. We show how difficult it will be to meet the UK child poverty targets unless the greater inequality inherent in the current regime for uprating payments and allowances is redressed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d1e260a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e267" publication-type="other">
Submitted May 2008.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e274a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e281" publication-type="other">
Those unfamiliar with the UK tax and benefit systems can find descriptions of them available online
on the IFS website in Adam and Browne (2006) and O'Dea, Phillips and Vink (2007). A detailed
description of the UK pension system can be found in Pensions Policy Institute (2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e294a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e301" publication-type="other">
Since 1977, when the Rooker-Wise amendment to the Finance Act made increasing personal tax
allowances in line with inflation a statutory commitment, indexation with prices (at least) has occurred in
most years. This did not happen in 1981-82, 1993-94, 1994-95 or 2003-04, when the main single
allowance was frozen.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e317a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e324" publication-type="other">
HM Revenue &amp; Customs, http://www.hmrc.gov.uk/stats/t_expenditures/menu.htm, table 2.7.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e332a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e339" publication-type="other">
Future cash amounts are adjusted back to 2006-07 values by expected future growth in real average
earnings (taken as 2 per cent annually, in line with UK government projections). In Sections V and VI,
where we look at the impacts of the future systems as if they had been in force in 2006-07, the adjusted
tax and benefit parameters are applied to the population distribution of other gross incomes as they
actually were in 2006-07.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e358a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e365" publication-type="other">
It should be noted that uprating the savings credit threshold by earnings rather than prices results in a
less generous payment than if the reverse were the case.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e375a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e382" publication-type="other">
While there is some expectation in policy circles that earnings uprating will be extended for a longer
period, there is no stated policy on this so we retain price uprating as the default.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e392a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e399" publication-type="other">
The main features of these Budget announcements were the abolition of the initial 10 per cent income
tax band (in 2008); the reduction in the basic rate of income tax from 22 to 20 per cent (in 2008); an
increase in the upper earnings limit for National Insurance contributions to equal the threshold for
payment of income tax at 40 per cent (by 2009), with the latter threshold increased by more than inflation
(in 2009); above-inflation increases in values of child tax credit (CTC) and working tax credit (WTC)
thresholds (in 2008) and maximum CTC child element (in 2008) and in the age allowances for income tax
(in 2008 and 2011); an increase in the CTC and WTC taper from 37 per cent to 39 per cent (in 2008); and
a slightly greater increase in the universal child benefit for the first child than implied by price indexation
alone (by 2010). See Sutherland et al. (2008) for more details.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e431a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e438" publication-type="other">
Note that these estimates do not include the effect of continuing to index the thresholds for employer
National Insurance contributions (NICs) with prices. It is likely that in practice these would move
consistently with employee NIC thresholds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e451a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e458" publication-type="other">
income support (IS), housing benefit (HB), council tax benefit (CTB), pension credit (PC), child tax
credit (CTC) and working tax credit (WTC).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e469a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e476" publication-type="other">
The proportions are not exactly the same at the starting point and after 20 years because of the way
the pension savings credit is uprated - see the appendix. Note that, as explained in Section III, this is not a
forecast of how many pensioners would be receiving pension credit in 2026-27, as it takes no account of
factors such as the changing composition of pensioner income or the ageing of the population. As before,
the comparisons isolate the impact of indexation processes by themselves.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e495a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e502" publication-type="other">
METRs are calculated as the proportion of gross earnings on an additional hour of work per week
taken in tax, contributions, and benefit and credit withdrawal.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e512a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e519" publication-type="other">
Not including employer NIC thresholds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e526a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e533" publication-type="other">
The proportion is calculated to correspond to the amount of revenue attributable to fiscal drag alone,
but this should not be taken to suggest that the revenue from fiscal drag should (or indeed could) be ring-
fenced in this way: we simply take this proportion of the total revenue in order to provide some sense of
scale to an otherwise arbitrary choice.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e549a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e556" publication-type="other">
indeed, the UK Treasury's long-term fiscal projections assume a constant tax-to-GDP ratio (HM
Treasury, 2008, p. 31), although benefits are generally assumed to be linked to prices.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e566a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e573" publication-type="other">
As explained later, these figures are not directly comparable with the poverty rates in the previous
sections or indeed with the official Households Below Average Income statistics. It is the comparison
across age groups which is important to note at this point. For further discussion, see Sutherland et al.
(2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e590a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e597" publication-type="other">
A decline in income across the age groups would also be observed if those on higher incomes died
younger than those on lower incomes. Since all the evidence suggests the opposite - richer people live
longer than poorer people - this is unlikely to be an explanation. Rather, the fall in income across the ages
would be more marked if there were less difference in life expectancy between rich and poor.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e613a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e620" publication-type="other">
if anything, this is likely to overestimate the increase in these sources of income that pensioners
receive in practice. Defined benefit private pensions tend to increase by at most price inflation and many
pensioners drawing annuity-based pensions opt for annuities that remain at the same nominal level
throughout retirement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e636a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e643" publication-type="other">
This is equivalent to assuming that pensioners consume all the income from their capital but do not
deplete the original capital sum. No allowance is made for windfall increases in capital, e.g. from
inheritances.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e656a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e663" publication-type="other">
0f course, if the revenue gain from fiscal drag and benefit erosion were spent on public services, for
example, rather than income transfers, the distribution of benefits from these services would need to be
taken into account.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e676a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e683" publication-type="other">
Where ranges of take-up proportions are published, the midpoint is used.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e690a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e697" publication-type="other">
See Redmond, Sutherland and Wilson (1998) for more information.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e705a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e712" publication-type="other">
The index of annual change up to the previous September is used and this is what is assumed by HM
Treasury in the price indices shown in Table A2.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d1e722a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d1e729" publication-type="other">
http://www.statistics.gov.uk/StatBase/tsdataset.asp?vlnk=392&amp;Pos=l &amp;ColRank= 1 &amp;Rank=-1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d1e745a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e749" publication-type="other">
Adam, S. and Browne, J. (2006), A Survey of the UK Tax System, Briefing Note no. 9,
London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/bns/bn09.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e759a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e763" publication-type="other">
Bradshaw, J. and Lynes, T. (1995), Benefit Uprating Policy and Living Standards, Social
Policy Report no. 1, York: Social Policy Research Unit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e773a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e777" publication-type="other">
Brewer, M., Goodman, A., Muriel, A. and Sibieta, L. (2007), Poverty and Inequality in the
UK: 2007, Briefing Note no. 73, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies
(http://www.ifs. org. uk/bns/bn73.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e790a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e794" publication-type="other">
Department for Work and Pensions (2006), Security in Retirement: Towards a New Pensions
System, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e805a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e809" publication-type="other">
— (2007a), Abstract of Statistics for Benefits, National Insurance Contributions, and Indices
of Prices and Earnings: 2006 Edition (http://www.dwp.gov.uk/asd/asdl/abstract/
Abstract2006.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e822a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e826" publication-type="other">
— (2007b), Households below Average Income 1994/95-2005/06, London: DWP.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e833a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e837" publication-type="other">
— (2007c), Income Related Benefits Estimates of Take-Up in 2005/2006, London: DWP.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e844a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e848" publication-type="other">
Evans, M. and Scarborough, J. (2006), Can Current Policy End Child Poverty by 2020?,
York: Joseph Rowntree Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e858a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e862" publication-type="other">
Glennerster, H., Hills, J., Piachaud, D. and Webb, J. (2004), One Hundred Years of Poverty
and Policy, York: Joseph Rowntree Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e872a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e876" publication-type="other">
Hancock, R., Wittenberg, R., Pickard, L., Comas-Herrera, A., Juarez-Garcia, A., King, D. and
Malley, J. (2007), 'Paying for long-term care for older people in the UK: modelling the
costs and distributional effects of a range of options', Personal Social Services Research
Unit, Discussion Paper no. 2336/2 (http://www.pssru.ac.uk/pdf/dp2336_2.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e893a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e897" publication-type="other">
Hills, J. (2004), Inequality and the State, Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e904a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e908" publication-type="other">
Hirsch, D. (2006), What would it Take to End Child Poverty? Firing on All Cylinders, York:
Joseph Rowntree Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e918a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e922" publication-type="other">
HM Revenue &amp; Customs (2007), Child Tax Credit and Working Tax Credit Take-Up Rates
2004-05, London: HMRC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e932a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e936" publication-type="other">
HM Treasury (2007), Financial Statement and Budget Report, London (http://www.hm-
treasury.gov.uk/bud_budget07_repindex.htm).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e946a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e950" publication-type="other">
— (2008), Long-Term Public Finance Report: An Analysis of Fiscal Sustainability, London
(http://www.hm-treasury.gov.Uk/d/bud08_longterm_586.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e960a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e964" publication-type="other">
O'Dea, C., Phillips, D. and Vink, A. (2007), A Survey of the UK Benefit System, Briefing
Note no. 13, London: Institute for Fiscal Studies (http://www.ifs.org.uk/bns/bnl3.pdf).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e975a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e979" publication-type="other">
Pensions Commission (2005), A New Pensions Settlement for the Twenty-First Century,
Second Report of the Pensions Commission, London: Stationery Office.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e989a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e993" publication-type="other">
Pensions Policy Institute (2008), The Pensions Primer, London: PPI.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1000a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1004" publication-type="other">
Redmond, G., Sutherland, H. and Wilson, M. (1998), The Arithmetic of Tax and Social Security
Reform: A User's Guide to Microsimulation Methods and Analysis, Cambridge: Cambridge
University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1017a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1021" publication-type="other">
Sutherland, H., Evans, M., Hancock, R., Hills, J. and Zantomio, F. (2008), The Impact of Benefit
and Tax Uprating on Incomes and Poverty, York: Joseph Rowntree Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d1e1031a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d1e1035" publication-type="other">
—, Sefton, T. and Piachaud, D. (2003), Poverty in Britain: The Impact of Government Policy
since 1997, York: Joseph Rowntree Foundation.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
