<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26794426</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Public policy in European Regions</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Regional Resources and Democratic Secessionism</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gehring</surname>
                  <given-names>Kai</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schneider</surname>
                  <given-names>Stephan A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">110</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26794387</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>43</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26794426"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>We argue that region-specific resources are crucial politico-economic factors explaining the success of democratic secessionist movements. Exploiting oil discoveries off the Scottish coast as a natural experiment, we estimate the causal effect of regional resources in a difference-in-differences design with Wales as the counterfactual. Based on constituency-level election results from 1945 to 2001, we show that each additional giant oil discovery has a significant positive effect on the Scottish National Party’s vote share of about 2 percentage points. A triple-differences design using changes in world oil prices as additional exogenous variation supports the causal interpretation of this finding.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Alesina, Alberto, &amp; Spolaore, Enrico. 1997. On the Number and Size of Nations. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 112(4), 1027–1056. 1, 5, 6</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Alesina, Alberto, Perotti, Roberto, &amp; Spolaore, Enrico. 1995. Togetheror Separately? Issues on the Costs and Benefits of Political and Fiscal Unions. European Economic Review, 39(3), 751–758. 6</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Arezki, Rabah, &amp; Brückner, Markus. 2011. Oil Rents, Corruption, and State Stability: Evidence from Panel Data Regressions. European Economic Review, 55(7), 955–963. 1, 34</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Arezki, Rabah, &amp; Brückner, Markus. 2012. Commodity Windfalls, Democracy and External Debt. The Economic Journal, 122(561), 848–866. 1, 34</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Arezki, Rabah, Ramey, Valerie A., &amp; Sheng, Liugang. forthcoming. News Shocks in Open Economies: Evidence from Giant Oil Discoveries. Quarterly Journal of Economics. 18, 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Ashbrook, John, &amp; Ashbrook, John E. 2008. Buying and Selling the Istrian Goat: Istrian Regionalism, Croatian Nationalism, and EU Enlargement. Peter Lang. 10</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bamberg, James. 2000. British Petroleum and Global Oil 1950-1975: The Challenge of Nationalism. Vol. 3. Cambridge University Press. 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Baum, Christopher F., Schaffer, Mark E., &amp; Stillman, Steven. 2010. Ivreg2: Stata Module for Extended Instrumental Variables/2SLS and GMM Estimation. http://ideas.repec.org/c/boc/bocode/s425401.html. 25</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Baumeister, Christiane, &amp; Peersman, Gert. 2013. The Role of Time-Varying Price Elasticities in Accounting for Volatility Changes in the Crude Oil Market. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 28(7), 1087–1109. 19</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Bélanger, Éric, &amp; Meguid, Bonnie M. 2008. Issue Salience, Issue Ownership, and Issue-based Vote Choice. Electoral Studies, 27(3), 477–491. 32</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Berman, Nicolas, Couttenier, Mathieu, &amp; Rohner, Dominic. 2017. This Mine is Mine! How Minerals Fuel Conflicts in Africa. American Economic Review, 107(6), 1564–1610. 1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Boffa, Federico, Piolatto, Amedeo, &amp; Ponzetto, Giacomo A. M. 2016. Political Centralization and Government Accountability. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 131(1), 381–422. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Bolton, Patrick, &amp; Roland, Gerard. 1997. The Breakup of Nations: A Political Economy Analysis. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 112(4), 1057–1090. 5, 6</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Bordignon, Massimo, &amp; Brusco, Sandro. 2001. Optimal Secession Rules. European Economic Review, 45(10), 1811. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Brancati, Dawn M. 2015. Global Elections Database. http://www.globalelectionsdatabase.com. 17</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Brand, Jack, Mitchell, James, &amp; Surridge, Paula. 1994. Social Constituency and Ideological Profile: Scottish Nationalism in the 1990s. Political Studies, 42(4), 616. 17, 37</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Brender, Adi, &amp; Drazen, Allan. 2008. How Do Budget Deficits and Economic Growth Affect Reelection Prospects? Evidence from a Large Panel of Countries. The American Economic Review, 98(5), 2203–2220. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Brocklehurst, Steven. 2013. Who Has a Right to Claim North Sea Oil? BBC Scotland News, http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-20042070. 13, 14</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Brown, J. Gordon. 1975. The Red Paper on Scotland. Edinburgh: EUSPB. 16</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Bryant, Christopher G. A. 2006. The Nations of Britain. 1. publ. edn. Oxford: Oxford Univ. Press. 13, 20, 23</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Buchanan, James M., &amp; Faith, Roger L. 1987. Secession and the Limits of Taxation: Toward a Theory of Internal Exit. The American Economic Review, 77(5), 1023. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Cameron, A. Colin, &amp; Miller, Douglas L. 2015. A Practitioners Guide to Cluster-Robust Inference. Journal of Human Resources, 50(2), 317–372. 33</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Carreri, Maria, &amp; Dube, Oeindrila. 2017. Do Natural Resources Influence Who Comes to Power, and How? The Journal of Politics, 79(2), 502–518. 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Caselli, Francesco, Morelli, Massimo, &amp; Rohner, Dominic. 2015. The Geography of Interstate Resource Wars. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 130(1), 267–315. 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Casertano, Stefano. 2013. Natural Resources and the Question of Ethnic Nationalisms. Pages 253–267 of: Our Land, Our Oil! Wiesbaden: Springer. 3, 4, 9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Cento Bull, Anna, &amp; Gilbert, Mark. 2001. The Lega Nord and the Northern Question in Italian Politics. Palgrave. 10</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Collier, Paul. 2010. The Political Economy of Natural Resources. Social Research, 77(4), 1105–1132. 1, 36</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Collier, Paul, &amp; Hoeffler, Anke. 2004. Greed and Grievance in Civil War. Oxford Economic Papers, 56(4), 563–595. 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Collier, Paul, &amp; Hoeffler, Anke. 2006. The Political Economy of Secession. Pages 37–59 of: Hannum, Hurst, &amp; Babbitt, Eileen (eds), Negotiating Self-Determination. Lanham, Maryland: Lexington Books. 2, 4, 9, 15, 16, 21, 24</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Dehdari, Sirus, &amp; Gehring, Kai. 2016. The Origins of Common Identity: Division, Homogenization Policies and Identity Formation in Alsace-Lorraine. Center for Comperative and International Studies (CIS), Working paper. 8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Dixit, Avinash, &amp; Londregan, John. 1998. Fiscal Federalism and Redistributive Politics. Journal of Public Economics, 68(2), 153–180. 1, 7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Dreher, Axel, Eichenauer, Vera Z., &amp; Gehring, Kai. 2016. Geopolitics, Aid, and Growth: the Impact of UN Security Council Membership on the Effectiveness of Aid. The World Bank Economic Review. 34</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Eerola, Essi, Määttänen, Niku, &amp; Poutvaara, Panu. 2004. Citizens should Vote on Secession. Topics in Economic Analysis &amp; Policy, 4(1). 6</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Ferraz, Claudio, &amp; Monteiro, Joana. 2014. Learning to Punish: Resource Windfalls and Political Accountability in Brazil. Working Paper. 1, 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Fusaro, Anthony. 1979. Two Faces of British Nationalism: The Scottish National Party &amp; Plaid Cymru Compared. Polity, 11(3), 362–386. 22, 23</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Gehring, Kai, &amp; Schneider, Stephan A. forthcoming. Towards the Greater Good? EU Commissioners’ Nationality and Budget Allocation in the European Union. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy. 7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Gourevitch, Peter A. 1979. The Reemergence of “Peripheral Nationalisms”: Some Comparative Speculations on the Spatial Distribution of Political Leadership and Economic Growth. Comparative Studies in Society and History, 21(3), 303–322. 13</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Goyal, Sanjeev, &amp; Staal, Klaas. 2004. The Political Economy of Regionalism. European Economic Review, 48(3), 563. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Harvie, Christopher. 1995. Scotland and Nationalism. 2. ed., repr. edn. London: Routledge. 2, 17</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Heald, David. 1994. Territorial Public Expenditure in the United Kingdom. Public Administration London, 72, 147–147. 20</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Hechter, Michael. 1992. The Dynamics of Secession. Acta Sociologica, 35(4), 267–283. 9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Holitscher, Marc, &amp;Suter, Roy. 1999. The Paradox of Economic Globalisation and Political Fragmentation: Secessionist Movements in Quebec and Scotland. Global Society: Journal of Interdisciplinary International Relations, 13(3), 257–286. 2, 13</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Horowitz, Leah S. 2004. Toward a Viable Independence? The Koniambo Project and the Political Economy of Mining in New Caledonia. The Contemporary Pacific, 16(2), 287–319. 11</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Ivanhoe, L. F. Buz, &amp; Leckie, George G. 1993. Global Oil, Gas Fields, Sizes Tallied, Analyzed. Oil &amp; Gas Journal, 91(7), 87–91. 18</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Jolly, Seth K. 2007. The Europhile Fringe? European Union Politics, 8(1), 109–130. 15, 16, 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Jolly, Seth K. 2014. Voting forNation or State: Determinants of Independence Support in Scotland &amp; Catalonia. APSA 2014 Annual Meeting Paper. 8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Jones, Richard W., &amp; Scully, Roger. 2006. Devolution and Electoral Politics in Scotland and Wales. The Journal of Federalism, 36(1), 115–134. 17</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Jordahl, Henrik. 2006. An Economic Analysis of Voting in Sweden. Public Choice, 127(3/4), 251–273. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Kemp, Alexander G., &amp; Stephen, Linda. 2000. Expenditures in and Revenues from the UKCS: Estimating the Hypothetical Scottish Shares. North Sea Study Occasional Paper No. 70. 13, 15</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Kemp, Alexander G., Hallwood, C. Paul, &amp; Wood, Peter W. 1983. The Benefits of North Sea Oil. Energy Policy, 11(2), 119–130. 15</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Kilian, Lutz, &amp; Park, Cheolbeom. 2009. The Impact of Oil Price Shocks on the US Stock Market. International Economic Review, 50(4), 1267–1287. 34</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Kuklinski, James H., &amp; West, Darrell M. 1981. Economic Expectations and Voting Behavior in United States House and Senate Elections. American Political Science Review, 75(2), 436–447. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Lee, Clive H. 1995. Scotland and the United Kingdom: The Economy and the Union in the Twentieth Century. Manchester: Manchester Univ. Press. 15, 20, 23</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Lee, Geoffrey W. 1976. North Sea Oil and Scottish Nationalism. Political Quarterly, 47(3), 307–317. 15, 24</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Lei, Yu-Hsiang, &amp; Michaels, Guy. 2014. Do Giant Oilfield Discoveries Fuel Internal Armed Conflicts? Journal of Development Economics, 110, 139–157. 3, 18, 21, 27, 29</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">Levy, Roger. 1995. Finding a Place in the World-Economy. Party Strategy and Party Vote: The Regionalization of SNP and Plaid Cymru Support, 1979-92. Political Geography, 14(3), 295. 2, 22, 24</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Lewis, M. Paul, Simons, Gary F., &amp; Fennig, Charles D. 2009. Ethnologue: Languages of the World. Vol. 16. SIL International Dallas, TX. 12</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Lewis-Beck, Michael S., &amp; Stegmaier, Mary. 2000. Economic Determinants of Electoral Outcomes. Annual Review of Political Science, 3, 183–219. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Lynch, Peter. 2003. Marriage versus Divorce: Political Parties and the Costs and Benefits of Secession and Union in Scotland. Canadian Political Science Association Annual Meeting, Dalhousie University, Halifax. 2, 7, 15, 16, 20</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">MacKay, Donald I., &amp; Mackay, George A. 1975. The Political Economy of North Sea Oil. London: Robertson. 2, 13, 15, 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">McCrone, David. 1992. Understanding Scotland. 1. publ. edn. International Library of Sociology. London: Routledge. 13</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">McGuinness, Feargal, Cracknell, Richard, &amp; Taylor, Mark. 2012. UK Election Statistics: 1918-2012. Commons Briefing Papers No. RP 12-43. 2, 16, 17</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Miller, William L. 1981. The End of British Politics? Oxford: Clarendon Press. 16</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Miller, William L., Sarlvik, Bo, Crewe, Ivor, &amp; Alt, Jim. 1977. The Connection Between SNP Voting and the Demand for Scottish Self-Government. European Journal of Political Research, 5(1), 83–102. 16, 17</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Mitchell, Brian R. 1988. British Historical Statistics. 1. publ. edn. Cambridge: Cambridge Univ. Press. 19</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Mitchell, James, Bennie, Lynn, &amp; Johns, Rob. 2012. The Scottish National Party: Transition to Power. Oxford: Oxford Univ. Press. 16, 17, 22</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">Mnookin, Robert, &amp; Verbeke, Alain. 2009. Persistent Nonviolent Conflict with no Reconciliation: The Flemish and Walloons in Belgium. Law and Contemporary Problems, 72(2), 151–186. 12</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">Morelli, Massimo, &amp; Rohner, Dominic. 2015. Resource Concentration and Civil Wars. Journal of Development Economics. 3, 4, 6, 35</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">Nagel, Klaus-Jürgen. 2004. Transcending theNational/ Asserting theNational: How StatelessNations like Scotland, Wales and Catalonia React to European Integration. Australian Journal of Politics &amp; History, 50(1), 57–74. 7, 23</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Outlaw, Ian. 2012. UK General Election Results 1992. http://www.politicsresources.net/area/uk/ge92/ge92index.htm. 17</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">Paquin, Stéphane. 2002. Globalization, European Integration and the Rise of Neo-Nationalism in Scotland. Nationalism and Ethnic Politics, 8(1), 55–80. 7, 13, 16</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">Perez-Sebastian, Fidel, &amp; Raveh, Ohad. 2016. Natural Resources, Decentralization, and Risk Sharing: Can Resource Booms Unify Nations? Journal of Development Economics, 121, 38–55. 7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r73">
            <mixed-citation id="c73">Persson, Torsten, &amp; Tabellini, Guido. 1996. Federal Fiscal Constitutions: Risk Sharing and Redistribution. Journal of Political Economy, 979–1009. 1, 7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r74">
            <mixed-citation id="c74">Persson, Torsten, &amp; Tabellini, Guido Enrico. 2002. Political Economics: Explaining Economic Policy. MIT Press. 1, 8</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r75">
            <mixed-citation id="c75">Ploeg, Frederick. 2011. Natural Resources. Journal of Economic Literature, 49(2), 366–420. 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r76">
            <mixed-citation id="c76">Popiden, Sandra. 2011. Globalization, Natural Resources, and SeparatistWars. http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1919919. 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r77">
            <mixed-citation id="c77">Powell, G. Bingham, &amp; Whitten, Guy D. 1993. A Cross-National Analysis of Economic Voting: Taking Account of the Political Context. American Journal of Political Science, 37(2), 391–414. 5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r78">
            <mixed-citation id="c78">Ross, Michael L. 2004a. How Do Natural Resources Influence Civil War? Evidence from Thirteen Cases. International Organization, 58(1), 35–67. 1, 4, 36</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r79">
            <mixed-citation id="c79">Ross, Michael L. 2004b. What Do We Know about Natural Resources and Civil War? Journal of Peace Research, 41(3), 337–356. 3, 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r80">
            <mixed-citation id="c80">Rosser, Andrew. 2006. The Political Economy of the Resource Curse: A Literature Survey. IDS Working Paper No. 268. 1, 3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r81">
            <mixed-citation id="c81">Scott, Peter. 2004. Regional Development and Policy. Pages 332–367 of: Floud, Roderick, &amp; Johnson, Paul (eds), The Cambridge Economic History of Modern Britain – Structural Change and Growth, 1939 - 2000, 1. publ. edn., vol. 3. Cambridge: Cambridge Univ. Press. 15, 19, 20</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r82">
            <mixed-citation id="c82">Sorens, Jason. 2004. Globalization, Secessionism, and Autonomy. Electoral Studies, 23(4), 727–752. 7, 16</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r83">
            <mixed-citation id="c83">Sorens, Jason. 2005. The Cross-Sectional Determinants of Secessionism in Advanced Democracies. Comparative Political Studies, 38(3), 304. 5, 8, 9, 16, 17, 23, 37</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r84">
            <mixed-citation id="c84">Tufte, Edward R. 1978. Political Control of the Economy. 2. print. edn. Princeton, NJ: Princeton Univ. Press. 4</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r85">
            <mixed-citation id="c85">UK Statistics Authority. 2013. Official Statistics in the Context of the Referendum on Scottish Independence. Monitoring Report No. 6. 14, 15</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r86">
            <mixed-citation id="c86">Van Houten, Pieter. 2007. Regionalist Challenges to European States: A Quantitative Assessment. Ethnopolitics, 6(4), 545–568. 7, 37</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r87">
            <mixed-citation id="c87">Whaley, Jane. 2010. The First UK Giant Oil Field. GeoExPro, 7(3), 76–80. 13, 21</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r88">
            <mixed-citation id="c88">Wood, John R. 1981. Secession: A Comparative Analytical Framework. Canadian Journal of Political Science, 14(1), 107–134. 5, 9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r89">
            <mixed-citation id="c89">Wooldridge, Jeffrey M. 2010. Econometric Analysis of Cross Section and Panel Data. 2. ed. edn. Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press. 22, 24</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r90">
            <mixed-citation id="c90">Young, Robert. 2014. Transition Costs in Secessions, with a Brief Application to Scotland. Oxford Review of Economic Policy, 30(2), 392–405. 7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r91">
            <mixed-citation id="c91">Zirakzadeh, Cyrus Ernesto. 1989. Economic Changes and Surges in Micro-Nationalist Voting in Scotland and the Basque Region of Spain. Comparative Studies in Society and History, 31(2), 318–339. 19</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Oil Fields</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Election Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Distribution of Oil Discoveries over Time</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Descriptive Statistics</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Linear Pre-Trends</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Regional Versus National Identity</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Regression Results – Sum and Average Number of Oil Discoveries</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Regression Results – Amount of New Oil Reserves</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Figure 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>Effect of the Sum of Giant Discoveries and Giant Discoveries per Year</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>Regression Results</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Regression Results – Triple-Differences with World Oil Price</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Pre- and Post-1970 Effect of the Oil Price</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
