<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24909543</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Six-Sigma &amp; Simulation:</article-title>
            <subtitle>A Yin-Yang Approach to Better</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wong</surname>
                  <given-names>Ernest Y.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>MAJ Ernest Wong is an Analyst with the Operations Research Center of Excellence located at the United States Military Academy. As a Military Intelligence officer, he has served in a variety of command and staff positions at Fort Hood, Texas, and throughout the Republic of Korea. He holds a B.S. in Economics from USMA, a M.S. in Management Science &amp; Engineering from Stanford University, and a M.A. in Education from Stanford University.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2006</year>
            <string-date>September 2006</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>39</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e24909534</issue-id>
         <fpage>12</fpage>
         <lpage>14</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2006, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24909543"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>The Chinese constructed the Yin-Yang to represent how things work. The interaction between the Yin (black) and the Yang (white) causes everything to happen. But just as most things in life are not completely black and white, the Yin contains a small white circle and the Yang contains a small black circle. Consequently, the ancient Chinese believed that both must co-exist and the world achieves equilibrium when both are balanced. As Operations Research practitioners, we know the goals of Six-Sigma and simulation tend to be at odds with one another: Six-Sigma is an exacting optimization tool that aims for reducing defects, while simulation is a dynamic enabling instrument that aims for enhancing discovery. However, despite their differences, both Six-Sigma and simulation do provide us with the means of achieving better solutions. In this article, I examine how these two seemingly contradictory applications can work together in our pursuit of better.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rudolf Ritsema &amp; Shantena Sabbadini (trans.). 2005. The Complete I Ching Oracle—the Pure and Complete Texts With Concordance Translated under the auspices of the Eranos Foundation. Watkins Publishing, London.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Patricia Ebrey. 1993. Chinese Civilization: ASourcebook, 2d ed. Free Press, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allen Tsai. 2005. Where Does the Yin- Yang Symbol Come From? URL: http://www.chinesefortunecalendar.co m/yinyang.htm, accessed 28 December 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ebrey.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jeff Brooks. 2003. Yin, Yang Mind: Esoteric Thoughts on Kata. URL: http://www.fightingarts.com/reading/article.php?id=357, accessed 28 much attention on just doing the right things (e.g. relying only on simulation capabilities) can lead an organization to a disconnect trap that prevents it from effectively communicating and actually implementing a coherent and achievable plan. By maintaining a balanced outlook on doing things right and doing the right things, an organization can execute process improvements that complement its longterm vision. Furthermore, Six-Sigma and simulation can also augment one another. Just as doctors use x-rays and MRIs concurrently to gain a more complete picture of their patients, Six-Sigma and simulation can be used synergistically to develop a better assessment of an organization. Together, the tools can help determine where an organization can become more efficient and help identify where it can become more effective. Leveraging Six-Sigma and simulation jointly can help an organization attain a perpetual state of continual improvement. Doing so allows an organization to develop appropriate strategy and implement suitable tactics for achieving long-term success. Summary The Yin-Yang approach manifests itself in numerous aspects of daily life. Physical fitness requires both proper diet as well as appropriate exercise. Financial wisdom suggests diversification in both the safety of bonds as well as the growth potential of stocks. Undergraduate education in America promotes the development of students who are well-rounded in the sciences as well as the humanities. Leading design companies infuse both form and function into their creations. Even in the military, Army leaders call for us to simultaneously “transform to win the war today, [as well as] prepare for future challenges.”10 Six- Sigma and simulation, while useful in their own right, become even more powerful tools for driving organizational efficiency and effectiveness when utilized together. The Bible tells us, “Any enterprise is built by wise planning, becomes strong through common sense, and profits wonderfully by keeping abreast of the facts.”11 To thrive and flourish in this new century of rapid change and breakthrough advances, our military must have the right December 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Peter Patel-Schneider &amp; Jermone Simeon. 2002. The Yin/Yang Web: XMLSyntax and RDF Semantics. Proceedings of the WWW2002 Conference, Honolulu, Hawaii, 7-11 May 02, URL: http://www2002.org/CDROM/refereed/231/, accessed on 28 December 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">iSixSigma Homepage. 2000-2006. URL: http://www.isixsigma.com/, accessed 18 Jan. 06.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wayne Hughes (Ed.). 1997. Military Modeling for Decision Making, 3rd ed. Military Operations Research Society, Alexandria, VA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Averill Law and W. Kelton. 2000. Simulation Modeling and Analysis, 3rd ed. McGraw Hill Companies, Boston.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Francis Harvey, Kenneth Preston, and Peter Schoomaker, AMessage from the Army Leadership, 2006 Soldiers Almanac, Jan. 06, Vol. 1, No. 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Living Bible. 1976. Proverbs 24:3-4. Tyndale House Publishers, Carol Stream, Illinois.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
