<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">27</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466820</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466857</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Complex Securities and Underwriter Reputation: Do Reputable Underwriters Produce Better Securities?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Griffin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
                  <surname>Lowery</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alessio</given-names>
                  <surname>Saretto</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2872</fpage>
         <lpage>2925</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466857"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Conventional wisdom suggests that high-reputation banks will generally produce good securities to maintain their long-run reputation. We show with a simple model that, when securities are complex a high-reputation bank may produce assets that underperform during market downturns. We examine this possibility using a unique sample of $10.1 trillion of CLO, MBS, ABS, and CDOs. Contrary to the conventional view, securities issued by more reputable banks did not outperform but, rather, had higher proportions of capital in default.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d8e284a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e291" publication-type="other">
He, Qian, and Strahan (2014) found that large issuers had to offer higher yields than did small issuers, suggesting
that the market was aware that these large MBS issuers received more inflated ratings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e301a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e308" publication-type="other">
Our results will also hold with a more microfounded model of security design, but we take the reduced-form
approach described here to keep the analysis simple and to focus on the role of reputation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e318a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e325" publication-type="other">
As is standard in models of over-the-counter trading, we assume the investor is not holding a fully diversified
portfolio of all assets in the economy and thus faces some risk associated with the particular security he is
purchasing. We represent this with a quadratic cost for securities.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e338a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e345" publication-type="other">
Some investors in structured products (like hedge funds) may also be sophisticated modelers, but they are
typically not able to access the same level of detailed underlying asset information available to the underwriter.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e356a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e363" publication-type="other">
We note here that having the price set by the commitment type will in effect pin down the price charged for all
securities. Therefore, prices will in a sense not respond to investors' equilibrium beliefs about the behavior of
strategic players or the fraction of commitment types in the economy. Our main results are robust to an alternative
setting in which commitment types adjust their behavior to reflect the ex ante expected payoff from dealing with
a reputable underwriter relative to a low-reputation underwriter.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e382a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e389" publication-type="other">
Similar predictions can be generated with a more complex model, which was analyzed in a previous version of
the paper, where no commitment types are assumed and low-reputation underwriters focus on short-term profits
whereas high-reputation underwriters focus on long-term profits.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e402a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e409" publication-type="other">
The investor has access to information that allows him to observe both 0 and w or, equivalently, can perform a
counterfactual analysis of the payoffs that would have occurred in the state that was not realized.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e419a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e426" publication-type="other">
In the white region near the y-axis, multiple equilibria hold over part of the region; details are in the Internet
Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e436a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e443" publication-type="other">
Proposition 7 in the Internet Appendix formalizes the comparative static argument described here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e450a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e457" publication-type="other">
Some of the student loans that are found in the collateral pool of student loan ABS in fact carry a guarantee by
the Department of Education, which was enforced through various government related entities (Sallie Mae being
one of them). Because the guarantee was not for 100% of the value of the loan, and because of the difficulty in
distinguishing between securities backed by loans issued under FFELP and private loans, we leave student loans
ABS in the sample.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e477a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e484" publication-type="other">
We have collected industry classification information for each underwriter from Bloomberg. Bloomberg
classifies financial institution into ten main categories: Commercial Banks, Commercial Services, Diversified
Operations, Finance-Commercial, Finance-Investment Banking, Institutional Brokerage, Advisory Services,
Investment Management, Life Insurance, and Wealth Management. We classify Finance-Investment Banking
and Institutional Brokerage as investment banks. This list includes Goldman Sachs, JP Morgan, Lehman Brothers
and other smaller shops, for example, Warburg Dillon Read and William R. Hough. Examples of institutions that
are not classified as investment bank are Chase Manhattan Bank, Citigroup, Commerzbank, Credit Lyonnais and
others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e513a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e520" publication-type="other">
Because we average the reputation score through the sample, we consider in this table even deals produced by
a bank for which we do not have a reputation score for the year in which the deal was issued. Therefore not
all deals that appear in this table are necessarily used in all of the empirical analyses. The table is largely for
expositional purposes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e536a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e543" publication-type="other">
Internet Appendix Figure A.3 shows the distribution of issuances within the two groups: low-reputation
underwriters issue proportionally less in the ABS market and more in the CDO market.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e553a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e560" publication-type="other">
The total does not correspond to the number reported in Table 1 because there are underwriters with an IPO
reputation score that do not appear in the League Tables.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e570a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e577" publication-type="other">
In additional analyses reported in the Internet Appendix, we use a secondary measure of performance based on
the deal rating, which is constructed by calculating a value-weighted average rating score of all the tranches that
belong to each particular deal. We compute the difference between the rating deal as of December 2010 and the
rating deal at issuance. This measure has the advantage of being continuous and capturing minor events that may
not lead to default and the disadvantage of depending on the initial rating of the securities at issuance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e596a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e603" publication-type="other">
Often, rating agencies interrupt the rating service by effectively withdrawing the rating. This might happen for
two reasons: the security might be in default and the deal manager thus stopped paying the rating fee, or the
deal is fully repaid. If the final balance of the security (which is also available through Bloomberg) reports both
a positive outstanding value and losses, and all ratings are withdrawn, then we consider the security to be in
default. If the balance is zero and there are no reported losses, we consider the security to be repaid in full with
a rating equal to the last known rating.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e627a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e634" publication-type="other">
Cordell, Huang, and Williams (2011) estimate that 65% of the CDO principal was lost with 70% of these losses
having occurred as of March 2011. Because our numbers are for default and do not include recovery, they are
comparable to a sample of 727 structured finance ABS CDOs analyzed by Cordell, Huang, and Williams (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e647a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e654" publication-type="other">
We start tracking the performance of assets issued during the year at the beginning of the next year.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e661a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e668" publication-type="other">
We randomly assign each low-reputation deal to a high-reputation deal with the same characteristics: collateral
type, issue amount, calendar quarter of issuance, issuance rating (within one notch), proportion of tranches in
default (within 10%), synthetic composition of the collateral, type of bank (investment versus commercial), and
credit enhancements. We repeat the random assignment 5,000 times with replacement.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e684a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e691" publication-type="other">
The break points for the grouping are chosen so that all the groups other than the first one have approximately
the same amount of capital issued.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e701a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e708" publication-type="other">
Results are similar if we exclude CMBS from this analysis.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e715a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e722" publication-type="other">
We use currency of deal denomination because country of issuance is often missing in the data.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e730a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e737" publication-type="other">
A large fraction of the securities have floating rates in the form of a spread to LIBOR. For those securities we
compute the yield by first finding the comparable swap rate (fix to LIBOR). We then add back the spread and
subtract LIBOR. For fixed rate securities, we compute yields in the traditional way and then subtract LIBOR.
We then compute a principal weighted average to determine a yield spread at the deal level.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e753a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e760" publication-type="other">
We report in Table A.9 of the Internet Appendix some analyses based on subsamples for which issuance market
yields could be computed for tranches with an initial rating lower than AAA. We do not find any statistically
significant relation between the underwriter reputation and issuance yields for lower- rated tranches.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e773a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e780" publication-type="other">
ABSNet data includes most of the universe of nonagency loans securitized from 2002 through 2008. We thank
Gonzalo Maturana for constructing and sharing the relevant variables.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e790a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e797" publication-type="other">
Nadauld, Sherlund, and Vorkink (2011) finds that the concentration of housing collateral and loans in California
varies widely across MBS deals and can explain substantial cross-sectional differences in MBS performance.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e807a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e814" publication-type="other">
It is possible that the impact of reputation on deal performance can be uniquely ascribed to the deal structure.
The proportion of senior to junior tranches and the waterfall might mechanically determine different percentage
of deal in default for deals with similar losses in the collateral pool.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e827a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e834" publication-type="other">
Because rating agencies are more likely to make positive adjustments on deals with a lower proportion of model
generated AAA (Griffin and Tang 2012), it would make more sense for an issuer to take a weak deal structure
(which deserves a smaller amount of AAA) and work for an upward positive adjustment. This might leave the
issue's proportion of AAA similar to other deals.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e851a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e858" publication-type="other">
More announcements surrounding RMBS from the rating agencies followed in March. A notable quote (Mitchell
2007) on March 3, 2007 states that, "the legs that powered the CDO machine for the last three years have fallen
off."</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e871a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e878" publication-type="other">
Because we do not want to lose any data, especially around 2006 and 2007, for this part of the analysis we
consider all bank year observations regardless of whether there is an IPO ranking measure in any particular year.
In the table we report all these deals and pair them with the reputation measure that is available to us.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d8e891a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e898" publication-type="other">
A popular story described by the media and industry is that, in response to troubling signs in the market in late
2006, JP Morgan largely backed out of structured finance security issuance (Barr 2008; Wilson and Kerr 2009).
In contrast to this description, we see only a small decrease in volume for JP Morgan in 2007.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d8e920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e924" publication-type="other">
Ashcraft, A., P. Goldsmith-Pinkham, and J. Vickery. 2010. MBS ratings and the mortgage credit boom. Federal
Reserve Bank of New York Staff Reports, no 449.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e934a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e938" publication-type="other">
Barr, A. 2008. Dimon's tactics help JP Morgan weather crisis. Dow Jones News Service.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e945a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e949" publication-type="other">
Beatty, R. P., and J. R. Ritter. 1986. Investment banking, reputation, and the underpricing of initial public offerings.
Journal of Financial Economics 15:213-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e959a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e963" publication-type="other">
Booth, J., and R. Smith. 1986. Capital raising, underwriting and the certification hypothesis. Journal of Financial
Economics 15:261-81.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e974a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e978" publication-type="other">
Carter, R., and S. Manaster. 1990. Initial public offerings and underwriter reputation. Journal of Finance
45:1045-67.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e988a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e992" publication-type="other">
Chemmanur, T. J., and P. Fulghieri. 1994. Reputation, renegotiation, and the choice between bank loans and
publicly traded debt. Review of Financial Studies 7:475-506.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1002a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1006" publication-type="other">
Chen, Z., A. Morrison, and W. Wilhelm. 2012. Traders vs. relationship managers: Reputational conflicts in
full-service investment banking. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1016a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1020" publication-type="other">
. 2014. Investment bank reputation and "star" cultures. Review of Corporate Finance Studies 2:129-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1027a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1031" publication-type="other">
Chernenko, S., S. Hanson, and A. Sunderam. 2014. The rise and fall of securitization. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1038a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1042" publication-type="other">
Cordell, L., Y. Huang, and M. Williams. 2011. Collateral damage: Sizing and assessing the subprime CDO crisis
Working Paper, Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia, no. 11-30.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1053a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1057" publication-type="other">
Demyanyk, Y., and O. Van Hemert. 2011. Understanding the subprime mortgage crisis. Review of Financial
Studies 24:1848-80.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1067a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1071" publication-type="other">
Endlich, L. 1999. Goldman sacks: The culture of success. New York: A.A. Knopf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1078a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1082" publication-type="other">
Erel, I., T. D. Nadauld, and R. M. Stulz. 2014. Why did U.S. banks invest in highly-rated securitization tranches?
Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1092a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1096" publication-type="other">
Fang, L. H. 2005. Investment bank reputation and the price and quality of underwriting services. Journal of
Finance 60:2729-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1106a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1110" publication-type="other">
Fitch Ratings. 2006. 2007 global structured finance outlook: Economic and sector-by-sector analysis. Available
at www.securitization.net/pdf/Fitch/SFOutlook07_l lDec06.pdf.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1120a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1124" publication-type="other">
Fulghieri, P., G Strobl, and H. Xia. 2014. The economics of solicited and unsolicited credit ratings. Review of
Financial Studies 27:484-518.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1135a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1139" publication-type="other">
Furfine, C. 2014. Complexity and loan performance: Evidence from the decuritization of commercial mortgages.
Review of Corporate Finance Studies 2:154-87.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1149a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1153" publication-type="other">
Ghent, A. C., W. N. Torous, and R. I. Valkanov. 2013. Complexity in structured finance: Financial wizardry or
smoke and mirrors? Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1163a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1167" publication-type="other">
Golubov, A., D. Petmezas, and N. G Travlos. 2012. When it pays to pay your investment banker: New evidence
on the role of financial advisors in M&amp;As. Journal of Finance 67:271-312.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1177a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1181" publication-type="other">
Griffin, J. M., and G Maturana. Forthcoming. Who facilitated misreporting in securitized loans? Journal of
Finance.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1191a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1195" publication-type="other">
Griffin, J. M., and D. Y. Tang. 2012. Did subjectivity play a role in CDO credit ratings? Journal of Finance
67:1293-328.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1205a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1209" publication-type="other">
Hartman-Glaser, B. 2012. Reputation and signaling. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1217a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1221" publication-type="other">
He, J., J. Qian, and P. E. Strahan. 2014. Are all ratings created equal? The impact of issuer size on the pricing of
mortgage-backed securities. Journal of Finance 67:2097-137.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1231a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1235" publication-type="other">
Ivashina, V., and Z. Sun. 2011. Institutional demand pressure and the cost of corporate loans. Journal of Financial
Economics 99:500-22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1245a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1249" publication-type="other">
Keys, B. J., T. Mukheijee, A. Seru, and V. Vig. 2010. Did securitization lead to lax screening? Evidence from
subprime loans. Quarterly Journal of Economics 125:307-62.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1259a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1263" publication-type="other">
Keys, B. J., A. Seru, and V. Vig. 2012. Lender screening and the role of securitization: Evidence from prime and
subprime mortgage markets. Review of Financial Studies 25:2071-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1273a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1277" publication-type="other">
Kreps, D., P. Milgrom, J. Roberts, and R. Wilson. 1982. Rational cooperation in the finitely repeated prisoners'
dilemma. Journal of Economic Theory 27:245-2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1287a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1291" publication-type="other">
Lewellen, K. 2006. Risk, reputation, and IPO price support. Journal of Finance 61:613-53.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1299a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1303" publication-type="other">
Liu, Q. 2011. Information acquisition and reputation dynamics. Review of Economic Studies 78:1400-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1310a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1314" publication-type="other">
Mailath, G J., and L. Samuelson. 2006. Repeated games and reputations: Long-run relationships. Oxford:
Oxford UP.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1324a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1328" publication-type="other">
Mathis, J., J. McAndrews, and J.-C. Rochet. 2009. Rating the raters: Are reputation concerns powerful enough
to discipline rating agencies? Journal of Monetary Economics 56:657-74.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1338a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1342" publication-type="other">
Mayer, C., K. Pence, and S. M. Sherlund. 2009. The rise in mortgage defaults. Journal of Economic Perspectives
23:27-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1352a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1356" publication-type="other">
Milgrom, P., and J. Roberts. 1982. Prédation, reputation, and entry deterrence. Journal of Economic Theory
27:280-312.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1366a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1370" publication-type="other">
Mitchell, D. 2007. Wider 'AAA' subprime levels weaken nearterm rebound hopes. Asset Securitization
Report 7:4.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1381a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1385" publication-type="other">
Morrison, A., and W. Wilhelm. 2004. Parternship firms, reputation and human capital. American Economic
Review 94:1682-92.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1395a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1399" publication-type="other">
. 2007. Investment banking: Institutions, politics, and law. Oxford: Oxford UP.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1406a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1410" publication-type="other">
. 2008. The demise of investment banking partnerships: Theory and evidence. Journal of Finance
63:311-50.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1420a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1424" publication-type="other">
Nadauld, T. D., and S. M. Sherlund. 2013. The impact of securitization on the expansion of subprime credit.
Journal of Financial Economics 107:454-76.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1434a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1438" publication-type="other">
Nadauld, T. D., S. M. Sherlund, and K. Vorkink. 2011. Correlated collateral. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1445a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1449" publication-type="other">
Nadauld, T. D., and M. S. Weisbach. 2012. Did securitization affect the cost of corporate debt? Journal of financial
economics 105:332-52.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1460a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1464" publication-type="other">
Piskorski, T., A. Seru, and J. Witkin. 2013. Asset quality misrepresentation by financial intermediaries: Evidence
from RMBS market. Working Paper.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1474a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1478" publication-type="other">
Purnanandam, A. 2011. Originate-to-distribute model and the subprime mortgage crisis. Review of Financial
Studies 24:1881-915.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1488a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1492" publication-type="other">
Ross, D. G 2010. The 'dominant bank effect:' How high lender reputation affects the information content and
terms of bank loans. Review of Financial Studies 23:2730-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1502a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1506" publication-type="other">
Shenn, J. 2007. Subprime mortgages bonds to get earlier S&amp;P warnings. Bloomberg,
w ww.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=21070001 &amp;sid=atjfuTokS5Lg.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1516a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1520" publication-type="other">
Tennant, J. 2006. Moody's rating actions, reviews, and outlooks: Quarterly update, fourth quarter 2006. Moody's
Investor Service.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1530a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1534" publication-type="other">
Titman, S., and S. Tsyplakov. 2010. Originator performance, CMBS structures, and the risk of commercial
mortgages. Review of Financial Studies 23:3558-94.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1545a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1549" publication-type="other">
Wilson, H., and D. Kerr. 2009. Is JP Morgan now the best bank in the world? Financial News.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d8e1556a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d8e1560" publication-type="other">
Yoon, A. 2004. UBS says mobile home prices, securities may rise by year-end. Bloomberg.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


