<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">machtran</journal-id>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="jstor">j50000036</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Machine Translation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">09226567</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15730573</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <volume xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">10</volume>
         <issue xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i40000451</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">40008412</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Towards a Cross-Linguistically Valid Classification of Spatial Prepositions</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Arturo</given-names>
                  <surname>Trujillo</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>93</fpage>
         <lpage>141</lpage>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1995 Kluwer Academic Publishers</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40008412"/>
         
         
         <abstract>
            <p>This article proposes a classification for a subset of English spatial prepositions which is argued to have cross-linguistic validity by using it to classify a subset of Spanish spatial prepositions. The classification consists of a hierarchy of spatial relations where each node in the hierarchy satisfies a series of syntactic and semantic tests. These tests define properties which are then inherited uniformly throughout. Prepositions are assigned values from the lower nodes in the hierarchy either in the lexicon or through lexical rules. Similarities and differences between the spatial system of different languages can be described by appealing to the relations and lexical rules that the language allows. It is shown how the hierarchy is used for building a lexicon for the machine translation of spatial prepositions in a transfer-based system.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <kwd>spatial prepositions</kwd>
            <kwd>spanish grammar</kwd>
            <kwd>type hierarchy</kwd>
            <kwd>bilingual lexicography</kwd>
            <kwd>bilingual lexical Rules</kwd>
            <kwd>contrastive linguistics</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      
         <ref-list>
            <title>References</title>
            <ref id="d908416e292a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e296" publication-type="other">
Alshawi, H., D. Carter, B. Gambäck, and M. Rayner. 1992. Swedish-English
QLF Translation. In H. Alshawi, editor, The Core Language Engine. MIT Press,
Cambridge, MA, chapter 14, pages 277-309.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e309a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e313" publication-type="other">
Asher, N. 1993. Reference to Abstract Objects in Discourse. Kluwer Academic
Publishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e323a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e327" publication-type="other">
Asher, N. and P. Sablayrolles. forthcoming. A Typology and Discourse Semantics
for Motion Verbs and Spatial PPs in French. Journal of Semantics.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e337a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e341" publication-type="other">
Aske, J. 1989. Path Predicates in English and Spanish: A Closer Look. In Pro-
ceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Berkeley Linguistics Society 15th. Bekeley
Linguistics Society, Berkeley, CA, pages 1-14.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e355a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e359" publication-type="other">
Beaven, J.L. 1992. Lexicalist Unification Based Machine Translation. Ph.D. thesis,
Department of Artificial Intelligence, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e369a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e373" publication-type="other">
Bennett, D.C. 1975. Spatial and Temporal Uses of English Prepositions-An Essay
in Stratificational Semantics. Library of Linguistics. Longman, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e383a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e387" publication-type="other">
Bowerman, M. 1989. Learning a Semantic System-What Role do Cognitive Pre-
dispositions Play. In M.L. Rice and R.L. Schiefelbusch, editors, The Teachability
of Language. Paul H. Brookes Co., Inc., Baltimore, Maryland, chapter 4, pages
133-69.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e403a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e407" publication-type="other">
Bowerman, M. forthcoming. Learning How to Structure Space for Language-A
Crosslinguistic Perspective. In P. Bloom, M. Peterson, L. Nadel, and M. Garrett,
editors, Language and Space. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e420a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e424" publication-type="other">
Brown, P.F., S.A. Delia Pietra, V.J. Della Pietra, and R.L. Mercer. 1993. The
Mathematics of Statistical Machine Translation. Computational Linguistics,
19(2):263-312, June.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e437a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e441" publication-type="other">
Butt, J. and C. Benjamin. 1994. A New Reference Grammar of Modern Spanish.
Edward Arnold, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e452a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e456" publication-type="other">
Carpenter, R. 1992. The Logic of Typed Feature Structures. Tracts in Theoretical
Computer Science. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, UK.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e466a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e470" publication-type="other">
Clark, H.H. 1973. Space, Time, Semantics, and the Child. In T.E. Moore, editor,
Cognitive Development and the Acquisition of Language. Academic Press, New
York, pages 65-110.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e483a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e487" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A. 1993. Defaults in Lexical Representation. In E. Briscoe, A. Copes-
take, and V. de Paiva, editors, Inheritance, Defaults and the Lexicon. Cambridge
University Press, Cambridge, UK, chapter 12, pages 223-45.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e500a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e504" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A. and E.J. Briscoe. 1995. Semi-Productive Polysemy and Sense Ex-
tension. Journal of Semantics, 12:15-67.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e514a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e518" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A., T. Briscoe, P. Vossen, A. Ageno, I. Castellon, F. Ribas, G. Rigau,
H. Rodríguez, and A. Samiotou. 1995. Acquisition of Lexical Translation Rela-
tions from MRDs. Machine Translation, 9(3-4).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e531a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e535" publication-type="other">
Copestake, A., A. Sanfilippo, E. Briscoe, and V. de Paiva. 1993. The ACQUILEX
LKB: An Introduction. In E. Briscoe, A. Copestake, and V. de Paiva, editors,
Inheritance, Defaults and the Lexicon. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge,
UK, chapter 9, pages 148-63.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e552a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e556" publication-type="other">
Cresswell, M.J., 1985. Adverbial Modification-Interval Semantics and Its Rivals,
volume 28 of Studies in Linguistics and Philosophy, chapter IV: Prepositions and
Points of View, pages 97-141. D. Reidel, Dordrecht, Holland. Reprinted from
Linguistics and Philosophy Vol. 2 (1978) pp. 1-41.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e572a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e576" publication-type="other">
Dorr, B.J. 1992. The Use of Lexical Semantics in Interlingual Machine Translation.
Machine Translation, 7(3): 135-93.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e586a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e590" publication-type="other">
Dowty, D.R. 1979. Word Meaning and Montague Grammar: The Semantics of
Verbs and Times in Generative Semantics and in Montague's PTQ, volume 7 of
Synthese Language Library. D. Reidel, Dordrecht, The Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e603a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e607" publication-type="other">
Emele, M., U. Heid, S. Momma, and R. Zajac. 1992. Interaction between Linguistic
Constraints: Procedural vs. Declarative Approaches. Machine Translation, 7(1-
2):61-98.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e620a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e624" publication-type="other">
Fillmore, C.J. 1971. Some problems for Case Grammar. In R.J. O'Brien, editor,
Report of the Twenty-Second Annual Round Table Meeting in Linguistics and
Language Studies, volume 24 of Monograph Series on Languages and Linguistics.
Georgetown University Press, Washington DC, pages 35-56.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e640a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e644" publication-type="other">
García-Pelayo, R. 1988. Larousse Gran Diccionario Español-Inglés English-
Spanish. Larousse, México DF, México.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e655a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e659" publication-type="other">
Grimaud, M. 1988. Toponyms, Prepositions and Cognitive Maps in English and
French. Journal of the American Society of Geolinguistics, 14:54-76.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e669a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e673" publication-type="other">
Hawkins, B.W. 1988. The Natural Category MEDIUM: An Alternative to Selec-
tion Restrictions and Similar Constructs. In B. Rudzka-Ostyn, editor, Topics in
Cognitive Linguistics, number 50 in Current Issues in Linguistic Theory. John
Benjamin, Amsterdam, pages 231-70.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e689a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e693" publication-type="other">
Herskovits, A. 1986. Language and Spatial Cognition: An Interdisciplinary Study of
the Prepositions in English. Studies in Natural Language Processing. Cambridge
University Press, Cambridge, UK.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e706a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e710" publication-type="other">
Hjelmslev, L. 1935. La Catégorie des Cas. Étude de Grammaire Générale. Acta
Jutlandica, VII(l).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e720a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e724" publication-type="other">
Hutchins, W.J. and H.L. Somers. 1992. An Introduction to Machine Translation.
Academic Press, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e734a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e738" publication-type="other">
Ioerger, T.R. 1994. The Manipulation of Images to Handle Indeterminacy in
Spatial Reasoning. Cognitive Science, 18(4):551-93, Oct-Dec.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e749a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e753" publication-type="other">
Jackendoff, R. 1983. Semantics and Cognition. The MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e760a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e764" publication-type="other">
Japkowicz, N. and J.M. Wiebe. 1991. A System for Translating Locative Preposi-
tions from English into French. In Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of
the ACL, pages 153-60, Berkeley, CA, June.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e777a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e781" publication-type="other">
Kameyama, M., R. Ochitani, and S. Peters. 1991. Resolving Translation Mis-
matches with Information Flow. In Proceedings 29th Annual Conference of the
ACL, pages 193-200, Berkeley, CA, June.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e794a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e798" publication-type="other">
Kaplan, R.M. and J. Wedekind. 1993. Restriction and Correspondence-based
Translation. In Proceedings of the Sixth Conference of the European Chapter
of the ACL, pages 193-202, The Netherlands, April. OTS, Utrecht University.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e811a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e815" publication-type="other">
Kawasaki, Z., F. Yamano, and N. Yamasaki. 1992. Translator Knowledge Base for
Machine Translation Systems. Machine Translation, 6(4):265-78.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e825a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e829" publication-type="other">
Kay, M., J.M. Gawron, and P. Norvig. 1994. Verbmobil: A Translation System
for Face-to-Face Dialog. Number 33 in Lecture Notes. Centre for the Study of
Language and Information, Stanford, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e843a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e847" publication-type="other">
Leech, G.N. 1969. Towards a Semantic Description of English. Linguistics Library.
Longman, London.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e857a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e861" publication-type="other">
Levinson, S.C. 1991. Relativity in Spatial Conception and Description. Tech-
nical Report WP 1, Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics, Nijmegen, The
Netherlands, October. (To appear in J. J. Gumperz and S. C. Levinson (Eds.),
Rethinking Linguistics Relativity, Cambridge University Press, UK).</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e877a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e881" publication-type="other">
Olivier, P. and J. Tsujii. 1994. Quantitative Perceptual Representation of Preposi-
tional Semantics. Artificial Intelligence Review, 8(2-3):147-158. Special Issue on
Integration of Natural Language and Vision Processing.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e894a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e898" publication-type="other">
Parsons, T. 1990. Events in the Semantics of English: A Study in Subatomic
Semantics. Number 19 in Current Studies in Linguistics. MIT Press, Cambridge,
MA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e911a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e915" publication-type="other">
Pollard, C. and I. Sag. 1987. Information Based Syntax and Semantics: Vol. 1.
Lecture Notes. CSLI, Stanford, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e925a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e929" publication-type="other">
Procter, P., editor. 1978. Longman Dictionary of Contemporary English. Longman,
Harlow, Essex, England.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e940a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e944" publication-type="other">
Pustejovsky, J. 1991. The Generative Lexicon. Computational Linguistics,
17(4):409-441.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e954a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e958" publication-type="other">
Regier, T. forthcoming. A Model of the Human Capacity for Categorizing Spatial
Relations. Cognitive Linguistics.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e968a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e972" publication-type="other">
Reyero-Sans, I. and J. Tsujii. 1994. A Cognitive Approach to an Interlingua Repre-
sentation of Spatial Descriptions. In Proceedings of the Workshop on Integration
of Natural Language and Vision Processing, pages 122-30, Seattle, WA, July-
August. Twelfth National Conference on Artificial Intelligence.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e988a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e992" publication-type="other">
Sanfilippo, A., E. Briscoe, A. Copestake, M. Marti, M. Taule, and A. Alonge. 1992.
Translation Equivalence and Lexicalization in the ACQUILEX LKB. In Proceed-
ings of the Fourth International Conference on Theoretical and Methodological
Issues in Machine Translation-TMI-92, pages 1-11, Montreal, Canada, June.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1008a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1012" publication-type="other">
Sato, S. and M. Nagao. 1990. Towards Memory Based Translation. In Proceedings
of COLING '90, Helsinki, Finland, August.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1022a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1026" publication-type="other">
Shieber, S.M. 1986. An Introduction to Unification-based Approaches to Grammar,
volume 4 of CSLI Lecture Notes. CSLI, Stanford, CA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1037a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1041" publication-type="other">
Sjöström, S. 1990. Spatial Relations: Towards a Theory of Spatial Verbs, Preposi-
tions and Pronominal Adverbs in Swedish. Ph.D. thesis, Department of Linguis-
tics, University of Götenborg, Sweden.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1054a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1058" publication-type="other">
Sondheimer, N.K. 1978. A Semantic Analysis of Reference to Spatial Properties.
Linguistics and Philosophy, 2(2):235-80.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1068a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1072" publication-type="other">
Talmy, L. 1975. Semantics and Syntax of Motion. In J.P. Kimball, editor, Syntax
and Semantics, volume 4. Academic Press, New York, NY, pages 181-238.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1082a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1086" publication-type="other">
Talmy, L. 1983. How Language Structures Space. In H.L. Pick, Jr. and
L.P. Acredolo, editors, Spatial Orientation-Theory, Research, and Application.
Plenum Press, New York, pages 225-282.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1099a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1103" publication-type="other">
Talmy, L. 1985. Lexicalization Patterns: Semantic Structure in Lexical Forms. In
T. Shopen, editor, Language Typology and Syntactic Description Vol. III: Gram-
matical Categories and the Lexicon. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, UK,
chapter 2, pages 57-149.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1119a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1123" publication-type="other">
Trujillo, A. 1992a. Locations in the Machine Translation of Prepositional Phrases.
In Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Theoretical and Method-
ological Issues in Machine Translation-TMI-92, pages 13-20, Montreal, Canada,
June.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1140a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1144" publication-type="other">
Trujillo, A. 1992b. Spatial Lexicalization in the Translation of Prepositional
Phrases. In Proceedings of the 30th Annual Conference of the ACL, Student
Session, pages 306-08, Newark, Delaware, July.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1157a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1161" publication-type="other">
Trujillo, A. 1995. Bi-Lexical Rules for Multi-Lexeme Translation in Lexicalist
MT. In Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference on Theoretical and
Methodological Issues in Machine Translation-TMI-95, Leuven, Belgium, July.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1174a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1178" publication-type="other">
Vendler, Z. 1967. Linguistics in Philosophy. Cornell University Press, Ithaca, NY,
USA.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
            <ref id="d908416e1188a1310">
               
               <mixed-citation id="d908416e1192" publication-type="other">
Whitelock, P. 1992. Shake-and-Bake Translation. In Proceedings of the 14th COL-
ING, pages 784-91, Nantes, France, August.</mixed-citation>
            </ref>
         </ref-list>
      
   </back>
</article>
