<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24910728</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURE</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Do You SEE What I’m SAYING??</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Matos</surname>
                  <given-names>Rafael E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Dr. Rafael Matos is a retired naval officer with over 20 years of service in US Navy. He served as a Surface Warfare Officer, as an operations research analyst at the Pentagon, and as master instructor of mathematics at the US Naval Academy. He obtained a master’s of science degree in operations research from the Naval Postgraduate School and a doctor of philosophy in organizational psychology from Walden University, with a concentration on cognitive decision making. He is a recognized leader in operations research with his areas of expertise in statistical analysis, optimization, modeling and simulation, decision analysis, effective visual presentations, psychometrics, organizational change management, and organizational decision support facilitation. Dr. Matos has been a member of the MORS Board of Directors for the last six years and most recently served MORS as its 49th President, from June 2014 to June 2015.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>September 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>48</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e24910718</issue-id>
         <fpage>19</fpage>
         <lpage>24</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2015, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24910728"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anscombe, F. J. 1973. Graphs in statistical analysis, American Statistician, Vol 27 (February), 17–21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Card, S., Mackinlay J. D., and Shneiderman B. 1999. Readings in Information Visualization: Using Vision to Think. Morgan Kaufmann Publishers, San Francisco.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomas, J. J., and Cook K. A., eds. 2005. Illuminating the Path: The R&amp;D Agenda for Visual Analytics. National Visualization and Analytics Center, 4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ware, C. 2004. Information Visualization, 2nd ed. Morgan Kaufmann Publishers, xxi.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>Resources</title>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Visual Display of Quantitative Information, Edward R. Tufte, Graphics Press, 1983. “A tour de force.” The baseline and initial standard for this topic.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Information Dashboard Design: The Effective Visual Communication of Data, Stephen Few, O’Reilly Media, 2006. This book addresses the visual design of dashboards. Written by one of the foremost experts in the field of data visualization.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Show Me the Numbers: Designing Tables and Graphs to Enlighten, Stephen Few, Analytics Press, 2004. The first book to pr ovide practical and comprehensive instruction in the design of business tables and graphs. Compared with Tufte’s book on charting, Few is more applied and provides more explicit guidelines for everyday datasets. Also, Few emphasizes business information, whereas Tufte emphasizes scientific datasets.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turning Numbers into Knowledge: Mastering the Art of Problem Solving, Jonathan G. Koomey, PhD, Analytics Press, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Information Visualization: Perception for Design, Second Edition, Colin Ware, Morgan Kaufmann, 2004. This book combines a strictly scientific approach to human perception with a practical concern for the rules governing the effective visual presentation of information.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A Field Guide to Digital Color, Maureen Stone, A. K. Peters, 2003. Perhaps no aspect of information display is as commonly misunderstood and misapplied as color. This book explains how color works, both physically and perceptually, and applies this knowledge to multiple fields and technologies, including computer-based information display.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perceptual Edge Website. Visual Business Intelligence for enlightening analysis and communication, http://www.perceptualedge.com. Website dedicated to topics on visual presentations. There is a large library of whitepapers and other brief publications on the subject.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
