<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169299</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Assessment of Compressive Thoracolumbar Injury Potential and Influence of Seat Cushions on Vertical Impact Loading of a Seated Occupant</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Winkel</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Toomey</surname>
                  <given-names>Daniel E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Taylor</surname>
                  <given-names>Robert</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Design Research Engineering</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169292</issue-id>
         <fpage>81</fpage>
         <lpage>91</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169299"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Thoracolumbar vertebral fractures are most commonly due to compressive loading modes and associated with falls from height. Two injury metrics are generally referenced for assessing the potential for compressive thoracolumbar injury; the Dynamic Response Index (DRI) and the compressive load measured between the pelvis and lumbar spine using the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) title 49 part 572 subpart B anthropomorphic test device (ATD).</p>
            <p>This study utilizes an ATD to investigate the injury mitigation potential of a variety of seat cushions during vertical impact in an unrestrained seated posture. ATD responses and DRI are reported for 65 vertical impacts with and without cushions from heights between 4 and 80 inches. The cushions investigated reduced ATD peak pelvic acceleration 63 +/− 11% and compressive lumbar load 42 +/− 9% on average. Results indicate a drop height of approximately 19 inches onto a rigid surface will generate ATD lumbar loads of 1500 lbs, whereas drop heights of 42 +/− 10 inches were required to produce equivalent lumbar loads with a cushion present. Conversely, the presence of a cushion had little or no influence on the resulting DRI. A 40 inch drop onto a rigid surface resulted in a DRI of 20.3 and drops of 40 inches onto a cushion resulted in DRI of 20.5 +/− 1.3. ATD lumbar load is a superior tool for qualitative comparative purposes. Neither metric has been correlated to human tolerance during unrestrained vertical impacts. Further research is required to better define their relationships to injury potential.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">National Spinal Cord Injury Statistical Center (NSCISC), “Complete Public Version of The 2012 Annual Statistical Report for the Spinal Cord Injury Model Systems,” https://www.nscisc.uab.edu/PublicDocuments/reports/pdf/2012%20NSCISC%20Annual%20Statistical%20Report%20 -%20Complete%20Public%20Version.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leucht, P., Fischer, K., Nuhr, G., and Mueller, E., “Epidemiology of Traumatic Spine Fractures,” Injury 40:166-172, 2009, doi:10.1016/j. injury.2008.06.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jansson, K., Blomqvist, P., Svedmark, P., Granath, F. et al., “Thoracolumbar Vertebral Fractures in Sweden: an analysis of 13,496 Patients Admitted to Hospital,” Eur J Epidemiol 25:431-437, 2010, doi:10.1007/s10654-010-9461-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H., Zhang, Y., Xiang, Q., Wang, W. et al., “Epidemiology of Traumatic Spinal Fractures: Experience from Medical University - Affiliated Hospitals in Chongqing, China, 2001-2010,” J Neurosurg Spine 17:459-468, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pintar, F., Yoganandan, N., Maiman, D., Scarboro, M. et al., “Thoracolumbar Spine Fractures in Frontal Impact Crashes,” presented at 56th AAAM Annual Conference, CAN, October 14-17, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gertzbein, S., Khoury, D., Bullington, A., StJohn, T. et al., “Thoracic and Lumbar Fractures Associated with Skiing and Snowboarding Injuries According to the AO Comprehensive Classification,” Am J Sports Med 40(8):1750-1754, 2012, doi:10.1177/0363546512449814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Latch, R. and Fiser, D., “The Increasing Threat of Personal Watercraft Injuries,” Clin Pediatr 43(4):309-311, 2004, doi:10.1177/000992280404300401.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haan, J., Kramer, M., and Scalea, T., “Pattern of Injury from Personal Watercraft,” Am Surg 68(7):624-627, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kikuike, K., Uemura, S., Miyamoto, K., Horiya, Y. et al., “Upper Lumbar Burst Fractures Due to Recreational High Jumping into a River: Report of Five Cases,” Arch Orthop and Trauma Surg 129(1):87-90, 2009, doi:10.1007/s00402-008-0698-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ragel, B., Allred, C., Brevard, S., Davis, R. et al., “Fractures of the Thoracolumbar Spine Sustained by Soldiers in Vehicles Attacked by Improvised Explosive Devices”, Spine 34(22):2400-2405, 2009, doi:10.1097/BRS.0b013e3181b7e585.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lehman Jr., R., Paik, H., Eckel, T., Helgeson, M. et al., “Low Lumbar Burst Fractures: A Unique Fracture Mechanism Sustained in Our Overseas Conflicts,” Spine J 12(9):784-790, 2012, doi:10.1016/j. spinee.2011.09.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eiband M, “Human Tolerance to Rapidly Applied Accelerations: A Summary of the Literature”, Lewis Research Center, Cleveland, OH, NASA Memorandum, Washington, June 1959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ewing C., King A. and Prasad P., “Structural Considerations of the Human Vertebral Column Under +Gz Impact Acceleration”, Naval Aerospace Medical Research Laboratory, Pensacola, FL, NAMRL-1178, 1972.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hearon, B. and Brinkley, B., “Effect of Seat Cushions on Human Response to +Gz Impact,” Aviat Space Environ Med 57(2):113-121, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brinkley, J., Dearing, E. and Rauterkus, L., “Evaluation of the Effects of Selected Egress System Design Parameters During +Gz Acceleration,” Aerospace Medical Research Laboratory, Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, OH, AMRL-TR-69-51, 1969.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruff S, “Brief Acceleration: Less Than One Second”, German Aviation Medicine in World War II, Vol. I, Chapter VI-C, Department of the Air Force, 1950.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payne, P. and Stech E., “Dynamic Models of the Human Body”, Frost Engineering Development Corp, Englewood CO: AMRL-TR-66-157, 1969.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coermann R., “The Mechanical Impedance of the Human Body in Sitting and Standing Positions at Low Frequencies”, Aerospace Medical Research Laboratory, Aeronautical Systems Division, Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, OH, ASD TR 61-492, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Perey O, “Fracture of the Vertebral End-Plate in the Lumbar Spine; An Experimental Biomechanical Investigation,” Acta Orthop Scand Suppl. 25:1-101, 1957.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NATO Science and Technology Organisation, “Test Methodology for Protection of Vehicle Occupants Against Anti-Vehicular Landmine Effects,” RTO-TR-HFM-090, ISBN 978-92-837-0068-5, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chandler, R., “Human Injury Criteria Relative to Civil Aircraft Seat and Restraint Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 851847, 1985, doi:10.4271/851847.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brinkley J. and Shaffer J., “Dynamic Simulation Techniques for the Design of Escape Systems: Current Applications and Future Air Force Requirements”, Aerospace Medical Research Laboratory, Wright - Patterson Air Force Base, OH, AMRL-TR-71-29, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laananen, D., “Biomechanically Based Performance Criteria for Crashworthy Aircraft Seats,” presented at 7th International IRCOBI Conference on the Biomechanics of Impact, DEU, September 8-10, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Code of Federal Regulations, “Subpart B - 50th Percentile Male”, 49 CFR Ch. V, Part 572, 10-1-2012 Edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Code of Federal Regulations, “Emergency Landing Dynamic Conditions,” 14 CFR Ch I, Part 25.562, 1-1-2012 Edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stemper, B., Storvik, S., Yoganandan, N., Baisden, J., et al., “A New PMHS Model for Lumbar Spine Injuries During Vertical Acceleration,” J Biomech Eng, 133(8):081002, 2011, doi:10.1115/1.4004655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
