<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440181</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Proposal to Improve the VAT Treatment of Housing in the European Union</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Sijbren</given-names>
                  <surname>Cnossen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">32</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440179</issue-id>
         <fpage>455</fpage>
         <lpage>481</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2011 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440181"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>The treatment of housing is one of the most difficult issues under the VATs in the EU. Ideally, rents and rental values should be taxed just like other consumer goods and services, but doing so would present formidable practical and political difficulties. Under a second-best approach, the value of newly created residential (and other) property is taxed as a proxy for the VAT that should be payable on the flow of housing (building) services. This implies, however, that future increases (and decreases) in the value of the exempt property are left out of the VAT base. To remedy this defect, this paper recommends taxing the increases (refunding the tax related to decreases) realised at the time of sale of the exempt used property. This VAT should replace the current transfer, registration and stamp duties, which are highly distortionary. Beyond that, the VATs in various member states can be improved by limiting the exemption for all used immovable property to housing, by taxing land and by applying the standard rate more widely than is currently the case.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d8e132a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e139" publication-type="other">
Submitted September 2010.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e146a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e153" publication-type="other">
Unless otherwise indicated, references to increases in property values should be understood to include
decreases, which would involve VAT refunds.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e163a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e170" publication-type="other">
Unless the context requires otherwise, references to transfer duty include registration and stamp duties
levied on the same base.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e180a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e187" publication-type="other">
See European Commission (2010a), as well as the accompanying Commission Staff Working
Document (European Commission, 2010b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e198a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e205" publication-type="other">
The following paragraphs draw on Cnossen (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e212a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e219" publication-type="other">
It is quite another matter that land is not a produced input - that its supply is fixed (except perhaps in
Holland), so that taxing land ownership is taxing an economic rent (Mirrlees et al., 2011, chapter 16).
Accordingly, the tax would be capitalised in the value of the land without any effect on economic activity.
But this feature calls for a separate land or land value tax, not a VAT. Under a VAT, the tax on land
would be washed out if the land is used for taxable activities by taxable persons, but not if used or owned
by non-taxable persons.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e242a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e249" publication-type="other">
The rationale for taxing rental values under the income tax runs parallel to that under a pure VAT.
Rather than earning a return on his house in the market, on which he would be taxed, the owner-occupier
offers the return to himself as investor, which should be included in his income tax assessment. Taxing
this return under the income tax as well as the VAT is not a form of double taxation, just as the
application of the VAT to the consumption of a market-earned rental charge, on which income tax has
been paid, is not considered double taxation. The application of both taxes arises because owner-occupied
houses are an investment as well as a consumption good.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e275a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e282" publication-type="other">
In this respect, the treatment of immovable property differs from the treatment of other consumer
durables, such as new cars, which are taxed in full if purchased by a consumer (just like newly built
residential property), but whose lease is also taxed (unlike housing rentals).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e295a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e302" publication-type="other">
Poddar (2010) contains a numerical illustration of the equivalence between a VAT on the present
discounted value of rents and rental values and its 'prepayment' through a VAT on the value of newly
constructed residential premises.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e315a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e322" publication-type="other">
in Italy, duplication and non-transparency have reached such proportions that the government has
legislated a replacement tax (see Table 2), purportedly in lieu of the registration duty, stamp duty,
mortgage tax, cadastral tax and the duty on official concessions for medium- and long-term loans.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e336a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e343" publication-type="other">
Elsewhere, the Australian states impose stamp duty on the transfer of immovable property,
differentiated by state, property category (principal residences may attract reduced rates) and purchase
price. There is no link between the federal VAT and the state stamp duty. A study by the Property
Council of Australia (2003) concluded that the abolition of stamp duty on leases would be highly
desirable. In Canada, most provinces impose land transfer taxes, often at graduated rates. New Zealand
does not levy transfer or stamp duties.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e366a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e373" publication-type="other">
For the taxation of land in New Zealand, see Harley (2007); for the treatment of immovable property
in New Zealand, see Smith (2007). Australia's goods and services tax (GST) treatment of immovable
property is reviewed by Evans (2007). The situations in both countries are compared by Millar (2010),
who holds a view contrary to the one held in this paper.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e389a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e396" publication-type="other">
Note that both methods would have the same effect if all registered persons opted for taxation of non-
residential property under the exemption approach.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e406a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e415" publication-type="other">
These schemes enable farmers to charge VAT on their sales at a rate approximately equivalent to
their average total input tax as a percentage of turnover, obviating the need for filing and payment of tax
(Germany), or they provide for a presumptive tax credit to purchasers of farm output, again
approximately equivalent to the VAT on farmers' inputs (the Netherlands). For more on these schemes,
see Cnossen (1998, chapter 9).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e434a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e441" publication-type="other">
The issue has to be reviewed in light of the VAT rebate schemes for public bodies that various
member states have introduced in recent years. For a general treatment, see Gendron (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e451a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e458" publication-type="other">
The Australian GST margin scheme was reviewed in 2010. See Australian Treasury (2010a and
2010b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e469a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e476" publication-type="other">
Conrad (2010) believes that VAT should be levied on the selling price and that a credit should be
allowed for the inflation-adjusted VAT on the purchase price, but this appears difficult to reconcile with
the cash-flow nature of the VAT. For more details on this 'S-tax' ('s' for 'stock'), see Conrad and Grozav
(2008).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e492a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e499" publication-type="other">
These valuations are also used for income tax, municipal property tax and inheritance tax purposes.
The rental value of owner-occupied property is subject to the progressive income tax, but effective rates
are low because taxable rental values are computed using lower percentages applied to rated values than
would accord with arm's-length rates. Since mortgage interest is fully deductible, the income tax
treatment of rental values results in a sizeable net subsidy to homeowners.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d8e527a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e531" publication-type="other">
Australian Treasury (2010a), Consultation Paper on the Review of the Margin Scheme,
http://www.treasurv.gov.au/documents/1528/PDF/GST Margin Scheme Review.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e541a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e545" publication-type="other">
— (2010b), 'Implementation of the recommendations of Treasury's review of the GST
margin scheme', Discussion Paper, 10 December, http://www.treasurv.gov.au/documents/
1915/PDF/discussion paper margin scheme.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e558a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e562" publication-type="other">
Cnossen, S. (1996), 'VAT treatment of immovable property', in V. Thuronyi (ed.), Tax Law
Design and Drafting, Washington, DC: International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e572a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e576" publication-type="other">
— (1998), Value-Added Taxes in Central and Eastern European Countries: A Comparative
Survey and Evaluation, Paris: OECD.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e587a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e591" publication-type="other">
— (2010), 'Vervang overdrachtsbelasting door BTW over waardevermeerdering huis'
(Replace transfer tax by VAT on increase in value of house), 3 Me Judice, 28 December
2010. Also published in Weekblad Fiscaal Recht, no. 6889, 20 January 2011, pp. 47-54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e604a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e608" publication-type="other">
— and Badenhorst, G. (2008), South Africa: VAT, Transfer Duty, and Stamp Duty on Fixed
Property, report prepared for the Tax Policy Unit, National Treasury of South Africa, and
the South African Revenue Service, June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e621a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e625" publication-type="other">
Conrad, R. F. (2010), 'Commentary [on S. Poddar, "Taxation of housing under a VAT"]', Tax
Law Review, vol. 63, pp. 471-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e635a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e639" publication-type="other">
— and Grozav, A. (2008), 'Immovable property and VAT', in R. Krever (ed.), VAT in Africa,
Pretoria: Pretoria University Law Press (PULP).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e649a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e653" publication-type="other">
Council Directive (2006), 'Council Directive 2006/112/EC of 28 November 2006 on the
common system of value added tax', Official Journal of the European Union, I, L 347/1,
11 December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e666a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e670" publication-type="other">
Ebrill, L., Keen, M., Bodin, J-P. and Summers, V. (2001), The Modern VAT, Washington,
DC: International Monetary Fund.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e681a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e685" publication-type="other">
European Commission (2010a), Green Paper on the Future of VAT: Towards a Simpler,
More Robust and Efficient VAT System, COM(2010) 695 final, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e695a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e699" publication-type="other">
— (2010b), Commission Staff Working Document, accompanying document to Green Paper
on the Future of VAT: Towards a Simpler, More Robust and Efficient VAT System,
SEC(2010) 1455 final, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e712a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e716" publication-type="other">
Evans, M. (2007), 'The value added tax treatment of immovable property: an Antipodean
context', in R. Krever and D. White (eds), GST in Retrospect and Prospect, Wellington:
Thomson/Bookers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e729a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e733" publication-type="other">
Gendron, P-P. (2010), 'How should the United States treat government entities, nonprofit
organizations, and other tax-exempt bodies under a VAT?', Tax Law Review, vol. 63, pp.
477-516.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e746a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e750" publication-type="other">
Harley, G. J. (2007), 'Dilemma for GST tax policy designers: land transactions', in R. Krever
and D. White (eds), GST in Retrospect and Prospect, Wellington: Thomson/Bookers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e760a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e766" publication-type="other">
Millar, R. (2010), 'VAT treatment of immovable property revisited', paper presented at a
conference on VAT Exemptions: Consequences and Design Alternatives, organised by
the Centre for Business Taxation, University of Oxford, and the Fiscal Institute, Tilburg
University, held at Worcester College, Oxford, 15-16 April.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e783a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e787" publication-type="other">
Mirrlees, J., Adam, S., Besley, T., Blundell, R., Bond, S., Chote, R., Gammie, M., Johnson,
P., Myles, G. and Poterba, J. (2011), Tax by Design: The Mirrlees Review, London:
Oxford University Press for the Institute for Fiscal Studies (available at http://
www.ifs.org.uk/mirrleesReview).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e803a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e807" publication-type="other">
Poddar, S. (2010), 'Taxation of housing under a VAT', Tax Law Review, vol. 63, pp. 443-70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e814a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e818" publication-type="other">
Property Council of Australia (2003), The Case for Abolishing Stamp Duty on Commercial
Leases, June.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e828a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e832" publication-type="other">
Smith, M. (2007), 'GST and immovable property transactions in New Zealand: some
interpretative issues', in R. Krever and D. White (eds), GST in Retrospect and Prospect,
Wellington: Thomson/Bookers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
