<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">61</volume>
         <issue-id>i40190886</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44553230</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>PLASTIC PROTOTYPES Revolutionize Preparation for Manufacture</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Wallace A.</given-names>
                  <surname>Stanley</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1953</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>67</fpage>
         <lpage>80</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1953, Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44553230"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>ONE plastic model is worth 40 lb of blueprints and 40 hr of the explaining that goes along with the prints, according to engineers who have worked with the new plastic "toys" which can serve as perfectly scaled miniatures for virtually every phase of automobile design and manufacture. The extensive benefits occasioned by this revolution in methods may be summarized thus: 1. Shortens design development time by providing a third-dimension evolvement of structure and form. 2. Used in advance discussions for compromising engineering and manufacturing problems, showing construction so clearly that troublesome problems are foreseen; thus enabling clear-cut, reliable decisions with a minimized chance of encountering major revisions 3. Show in one minute what could not be found on prints for hours, saving time over any other methods, while generating valuable counterproposals reducing costs, operations, man-hours, and so forth. 4. Parts can be made in plastic faster than drawings with detailed dimensions. 5. Duplicates can be obtained in a matter of minutes. 6. Used for processing, reducing manufacturing operations; in standardization. 7. Gives entire tooling programs a start months ahead of ordinary procedures, saving thousands of hours of tool and fixture design, and build time.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


