<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278247</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>PIV Measurements in the Swirl-Plane of a Motored Light-Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Petersen</surname>
                  <given-names>Benjamin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Miles</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1623</fpage>
         <lpage>1641</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278247"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Particle image velocimetry (PIV) is used to investigate the structure and evolution of the mean velocity field in the swirl (<italic>r-θ</italic>) plane of a motored, optically accessible diesel engine with a typical production combustion chamber geometry under motoring conditions (no fuel injection). Instantaneous velocities were measured were made at three swirl-plane heights (3 mm, 10 mm and 18 mm below the firedeck) and three swirl ratios (2.2, 3.5 and 4.5) over a range of crank angles in the compression and expansion strokes. The data allow for a direct analysis of the structures within the ensemble mean flow field, the in-cylinder swirl ratio, and the radial profile of the tangential velocity. At all three swirl ratios, the ensemble mean velocity field contains a single dominant swirl flow structure that is tilted with respect to the cylinder axis. The axis of this structure precesses about the cylinder axis in a manner that is largely insensitive to swirl ratio. Higher swirl ratios reduce the cycle-to-cycle variability in the orientation of this structure. The tangential velocity profiles are well represented by the Bessel function profile often used to initialize the tangential velocity in CFD codes. A value of 2.2 is recommended for the value of the parameter<italic>α</italic>which controls the shape of the Bessel function profile. During the compression stroke, the measured in-cylinder swirl ratios were similar to those determined from steady-state flow bench measurements. The swirl ratios decreased significantly after TDC, and continued to decline during the expansion stroke.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals: McGraw-Hill, Inc., 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P.C., “In-Cylinder Turbulent Flow Structure in Direct-Injection, Swirl-Supported Diesel Engines,” Ch. 4 in Flow and Combustion in Reciprocating Engines, Arcoumanis, C. and Kamimoto, T., eds. Springer-Verlag, Berlin-Heidelberg, pp 173-256, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuss, D., Kuo, T., Khalighi, B., Haworth, D. et al., “Particle Image Velocimetry Measurements in a High-Swirl Engine Used for Evaluation of Computational Fluid Dynamics Calculations,” SAE Technical Paper 952381, 1995, doi: 10.4271/952381.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reuss, D., “Cyclic Variability of Large-Scale Turbulent Structures in Directed and Undirected IC Engine Flows,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0246, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nordgren, H., Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., Dahlén, L. et al., “Comparison Between In-Cylinder PIV Measurements, CFD Simulations and Steady-Flow Impulse Torque Swirl Meter Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3147, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deslandes, W., Dupont, A., Baby, X., Charnay, G. et al., “PIV Measurements of Internal Aerodynamic of Diesel Combustion Chamber,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3083, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-3083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Deslandes, W., Dumont, P., Dupont, A., Baby, X. et al., “Airflow Cyclic Variations Analysis in Diesel Combustion Chamber by PIV Measurements,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1410, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Van den Heuvel, B., Willems, W., Karvounis, E., Schulte, H., “In-Cylinder Flow Characterization of Modern HSDI Diesel Engines - Numerical and Experimental Evaluation of Current Practices,” THIESEL, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blechstein, A., Behnk, K., Deepe, R., Donath, S. et al., “Effects of Charge Motion Characteristics on Engine Variables such as Emission Behavior and Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0640, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0640.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Funk, C., Sick, V., Reuss, D., and Dahm, W., “Turbulence Properties of High and Low Swirl In-Cylinder Flows,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-2841, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-2841.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W., Ekoto, I., Kim, D., and Miles, P. C., “In- Cylinder PIV Measurements in an Optical Light-Duty Diesel at LTC Conditions,” THIESEL, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Hultqvist, A., and Miles, P. C., “The Effect of Swirl and Injection Phasing on Flow Structures and Mixing in an HSDI Diesel Engine,” THIESEL, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P. C., Collin, R., Hildingsson, A., Hultqvist, A., and Andersson, O., “Combined Measurements of Flow Structure, Partially Oxidized Fuel, and Soot in a High-Speed Direct-Injection Diesel Engine,” Proc. Combust. Inst, vol. 31, pp. 2963-2970, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P. C., Hildingsson, L., and Hultqvist, A., “The Influence of Fuel Injection and Heat Release on Bulk Flow Structures in a Direct-Injection, Swirl-Supported Diesel Engine,” 13th Symposium on Applications of Laser Techniques to Fluid Mechanics, Lisbon, Portugal, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I. W., Colban, W. F., Miles, P. C., Aronsson, U., Andersson, O., Park, S. W., Foster, D. E., and Reitz, R. D., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Late-Injection Low Temperature Combustion,” ASME International Combustion Engine Division 2009 Fall Technical Conference, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Colban, W., Miles, P., Park, S. et al., “Sources of UHC Emissions from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1265-1289, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ekoto, I., Colban, W., Miles, P., Park, S. et al., “UHC and CO Emissions Sources from a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Undergoing Dilution-Controlled Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):411-430, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-24-0043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Amsden, A. A., O'Rourke, P. J., and Butler, T. D., KIVA II: A Computer Program for Chemically Reactive Flows with Sprays: Los Alamos National Laboratory, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wahiduzzaman, S. and Ferguson, C. R., “Convective Heat Transfer from a Decaying Swirling Flow within a Cylinder,” Proceedings of the International Heat Transfer Conference, 86-IHTC-253, pp. 987-992, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnston, S., Robinson, C., Rorke, W., Smith, J. et al., “Application of Laser Diagnostics to an Injected Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 790092, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790092.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Ekoto, I., and Miles, P., “Optical Investigation of UHC and CO Sources from Biodiesel Blends in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1): 414-434, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0862.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Petersen, B., Ekoto, I., and Miles, P., “An Investigation into the Effects of Fuel Properties and Engine Load on UHC and CO Emissions from a Light-Duty Optical Diesel Engine Operating in a Partially Premixed Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(2):38-55, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1470.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W., Miles, P., and Oh, S., “Effect of Intake Pressure on Performance and Emissions in an Automotive Diesel Engine Operating in Low Temperature Combustion Regimes,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4063, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-4063.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colban, W., Kim, D., Miles, P., Oh, S. et al., “A Detailed Comparison of Emissions and Combustion Performance Between Optical and Metal Single-Cylinder Diesel Engines at Low Temperature Combustion Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):505-519, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1066.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, C. H. and Penney, D. E., Differential Equations and Linear Algebra: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miles, P., Megerle, M., Sick, V., Richards, K. et al., “The Evolution of Flow Structures and Turbulence in a Fired HSDI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3501, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-3501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
