<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277974</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Lift-Off Length in an Optical Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lequien</surname>
                  <given-names>Guillaume</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Zheming</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Oivind</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Richter</surname>
                  <given-names>Mattias</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Lund Univ.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>635</fpage>
         <lpage>646</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277974"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>High-speed OH chemiluminescence imaging is used to measure the lift-off length of diesel sprays in an optical heavy-duty diesel engine of 2 L displacement operated at 1200 rpm and 5 bar IMEP. Stereoscopic images are acquired at two different wavelengths (310 and 330 nm). Subtraction of pairwise images helps reducing the background coming from natural soot incandescence in the OH chemiluminescence images. Intake air temperature (343 to 403 K), motored top dead center density (18 to 22 kg/m³), fuel injection pressure (150 to 250 MPa), intake oxygen concentration (17 to 21 %vol) and nozzle diameter (0.1 and 0.14 mm) are varied and a nonlinear regression model is derived from the experimental results to describe stabilized lift-off length as function of the experimental factors. The lift-off length follows the general trends that are known from spray vessel investigations, but the strength of the dependence on certain variables deviates strongly from those studies. The experimental correlation obtained for the lift-off length in the aforementioned ambient conditions has the following form: H = AT<sub>bulk</sub>
               <sup>−1.43</sup>ρ<sub>bulk</sub>
               <sup>−0.83</sup>d<sup>0.41</sup>U<sup>0.48</sup>Z<sub>st</sub>
               <sup>−0.75</sup>
            </p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chomiak, J. and Karlsson, A., “Flame Lift-Off in Diesel Sprays,” Symposium (International) on Combustion 26(2):2557-2564, 1996, doi:10.1016/S0082-0784(96)80088-9.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot Formation in Diesel Fuel Jets Near the Lift-Off Length,” International Journal of Engine Research 7(2):103-130, 2006, doi:10.1243/146808705X57793.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and Siebers, D., “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004- 01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chartier, C., Aronsson, U., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R. et al., “Analysis of Smokeless Spray Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine by Combined Simultaneous Optical Diagnostics,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1353, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1353.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot in diesel fuel jets: Effects of ambient temperature, ambient density, and injection pressure”, Combustion and Flame 138(1-2):114-135, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2004.04.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C. and Pickett, L., “Soot Formation in Diesel Combustion under High-EGR Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3834, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3834.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D., “Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D. and Higgins, B., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Sprays Under Quiescent Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01- 0530, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., Higgins, B., and Pickett, L., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct- Injection Diesel Fuel Jets: Oxygen Concentration Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0890, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, Y., Huang, R., Liu, Y., Leick, M. et al., “Effect of Ambient Temperature on Flame Lift-off and Soot Formation of Biodiesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0606, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0606.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ito, T., Kitamura, T., Ueda, M., Matsumoto, T. et al., “Effects of Flame Lift-Off and Flame Temperature on Soot Formation in Oxygenated Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0073, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003- 01-0073.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, W., Tian, J., and Nishida, K., “Effects of Nozzle Hole Diameter and Injection Pressure on Flame Lift-Off and Soot Formation in D.I. Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1813, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1813.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Picket, L.M. and Siebers, D.L. “Orifice diameter effects on diesel fuel jet flame structure,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 127(1):187-196, 2005, doi:10.1115/1.1760525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., and Idicheria, C., “Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Engine Combustion Network, http://www.sandia.gov/ECN/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chartier, C., Aronsson, U., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R. et al., “Influence of Jet-Jet Interactions on the Lift-Off Length in an Optical Heavy- Duty DI Diesel Engine,” Fuel 112:311-318, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2013.05.021.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and López, J., “Jet-Wall Interaction Effects on Diesel Combustion and Soot Formation,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0921, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0921.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson, Ö., “Experiment!: Planning, Implementing and Interpreting,” Wiley, UK, 2012, page 165, ISBN:978-0-470-68825-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronsson, U., Solaka, H., Chartier, C., Andersson, O. et al., “Impact of Mechanical Deformation due to Pressure, Mass, and Thermal Forces on the In-Cylinder Volume Trace in Optical Engines of Bowditch Design,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-26-0082, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-26-0082.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., Siebers, D., and Aradi, A., “Diesel-Spray Ignition and Premixed-Burn Behavior,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0940, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lequien, G., Berrocal, E., Gallo, Y., Themudo e Mello, A. et al., “Effect of Jet-Jet Interactions on the Liquid Fuel Penetration in an Optical Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1615, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., “Effects of the In-Cylinder Environment on Diffusion Flame Lift-Off in a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01- 0074, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polonowski, C., Mueller, C., Gehrke, C., Bazyn, T. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-Cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):51-77, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The National Institute of Standards and Technology, http://webbook.nist. gov/chemistry/fluid/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M., Kook, S., Persson, H. and Andersson, Ö., “Diesel fuel jet lift-off stabilization in the presence of laser-induced plasma ignition,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 32(II):2793-2800, 2009, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2008.06.082.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
