<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284820</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Unique Needs of Motorcycle and Scooter Lubricants and Proposed Solutions for More Effective Performance Evaluation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Marcella</surname>
                  <given-names>Mike</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Michlberger</surname>
                  <given-names>Alex</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>The Lubrizol Corporation</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>374</fpage>
         <lpage>378</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284820"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The operating conditions of a typical motorcycle are considerably different than those of a typical passenger car and thus require an oil capable of handling the unique demands. One primary difference, wet clutch lubrication, is already addressed by the current JASO four-stroke motorcycle engine oil specification (JASO T 903:2011). Another challenge for the oil is gear box lubrication, which may be addressed in part with the addition of a gear protection test in a future revision to the JASO specification. A third major difference between a motorcycle oil and passenger car oil is the more severe conditions an oil is subjected to within a motorcycle engine, due to higher temperatures, engine speeds and power densities.</p>
            <p>Scooters, utilizing a transmission not lubricated by the crankcase oil, also place higher demands on an engine oil, once again due to higher temperatures, engine speeds and power densities. However, because scooter oils do not need to lubricate a wet clutch or protect gears, scooter oils can provide more fuel economy benefits than motorcycle oils, when properly formulated.</p>
            <p>First, this study compares the piston deposit performance of motorcycle oils and passenger car oils in the API Sequence III Test and in a fired-engine motorcycle piston deposit evaluation. While the API Sequence III Test is certainly an effective tool for ensuring passenger car motor oil piston deposit performance, the results show that some oils formulated to meet the performance requirements of the Sequence III test do not match the performance of motorcycle-specific oils in a motorcycle piston deposit evaluation.</p>
            <p>Second, this study compares the performance of different oils in the JASO clutch friction test (SAE#2) and in a fired-engine Scooter Fuel Economy Test. The results indicate that JASO MB performance, as determined by the SAE#2 clutch friction test, is not necessarily a predictor of real fuel economy benefit.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuhn, M., Chambers, J., Anderson, B. Twitchell, J., et al., “Support for Long Range Scenario Planning: Motorcycle Engines and Transmissions,” prepared for The Lubrizol Corporation, Jan. 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Japanese Automobile Standard, “JASO T903:2011 Motorcycles - Four stroke cycles gasoline engine oil specification,” (2011).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM Standard Test Method, “Evaluation of Automotive Engine Oils in the Sequence IIIF, Spark-Ignition Engine,” ASTM Standard D6984 - 14a, Rev. Oct. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM Standard Specification, “Performance of Active API Service Category Engine Oils,” ASTM Standard D4485 - 14, Rev. Jan. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM Standard Test Method, “Measurement of Effects of Automotive Engine Oils on Fuel Economy of Passenger Cars and Light-Duty Trucks in Sequence VID Spark Ignition Engine,” ASTM Standard D7589 - 15, Rev. Feb. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wall, J.C., “Influence of Crankcase Lubricant Viscosity on Fuel Consumption in a Medium-Speed Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 1982-02-01, 1982, doi:10.4271/821148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sorab, J., Korcek, S., McCollum, C., and Schriewer, K., “Sequence VIB Engine Test for Evaluation of Fuel Efficiency of Engine Oils - Part II. Stage Selection and Time Factor Determination,” SAE Technical Paper 982624, 1998, doi:10.4271/982624.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
