<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275446</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Hybrid 2-Zone Diesel Combustion Model for NO Formation</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Oppenauer</surname>
                  <given-names>Klaus S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>del Re</surname>
                  <given-names>Luigi</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Institute for Design and Control of Mechatronical Systems, Johannes Kepler University Linz</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>584</fpage>
         <lpage>596</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275446"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This paper presents a methodology which is able to calculate emissions over crank angle (CA) using the measured cylinder pressure. The models are based on a 2-zone Diesel combustion process calculation combined with data based methods to fulfill the objective of a wide operating range, for a later possible use in transients – differently from the standard methods, which usually work accurate only in a small range. The resulting hybrid or grey box oriented model structure offers many advantages when purely physical modeling is too complicated and the combination with data based methods allow to obtain better results. The workflow of CA based emission models on the basis of a 2-zone calculation is presented. The focus of this paper is to explain the development process of a nitric oxide (NO) formation model, which is accurate over a wide operating range. For future similar data based particulate matter (PM) models the shown workflow could be used too.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alberer, D. and Del Re, L., "Fast Oxygen Based Transient Diesel Engine Operation," SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):405-413, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alberer D., Del Re L., Winkler S. and Langthaler P., Virtual Sensor Design of Particulate and Nitric Oxide Emissions in a DI Diesel Engine. SAE Paper 2005- 24-063, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heider G., Woschni G. and Zeillinger K. (1998). 2- Zonen Rechenmodell zur Vorausberechnung der NO-Emissionen. MTZ, 59: p. 770-775.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merker G.P., Hohlbaum B. and Rauscher M., Two- Zone Model for Calculation of Nitrogen-Oxide Formation in Direct-Injection Diesel Engines. SAE Paper 932454, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zillmer M., Stickoxid- und Rußbildung bei der Dieselmotorischen Verbrennung. 1998: Shaker Verlag.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersson M., Johannsson B. and Hultqvist A., A Real Time NOx Model for Conventional and Partially Premixed Diesel Combustion. SAE Paper 2006-01- 0195, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kozuch P., Ein phänomenologisches Modell zur kombinierten Stickoxid- und Rußberechnung bei direkteinspritzdenden Dieselmotoren. Stuttgart Dissertation, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kraßnig G., Die Berechnung der Stickoxidbildung im Dieselmotor. TU Graz, Habilitation, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grill M., Objektorientierte Prozessrechnung von Verbrennungsmotoren. Stuttgart, Dissertation, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeldovich Y.B. (1946). The Oxidation of Nitrogen in Combustion and Explosions. Acta Physiochimica, 21.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirsch M., Alberer D. and Del Re L., Grey-Box Control Oriented Emission Models. 17th IFAC World Congress, Seoul, Korea, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hirsch M. and Del Re L., Adapted D-Optimal Experimental Design for Transient Emission Models of Diesel Engines. SAE Paper 2009-01-0621 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hottel H.G. and Broughten F.P. (1932). Determination of true temperature and total radiation from luminous gas flames. Industrial and Engineering Chemistry: Analytical Edition, 4-2: p. 166-174.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schubinger R.A., Untersuchungen zur Russbildung und -oxidation in der dieselmotorischen Verbrennung: Thermodynamische Kenngrössen, Verbrennungsanalyse und Mehrfarbenspektroskopie. ETH Zürich, Dissertation, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mohammad L.S. and Borman G.L., Measurement of Soot and Flame Temperature Along Three Directions in the Cylinder of a Direct Injection Diesel. SAE Paper 910728, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li X. and Wallace J.S., In-Cylinder Measurement of Temperature and Soot Concentration Using the Two- Color Method. SAE Paper 950848, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cavalloni C., Wolfer P., Karst D., Hentschel W., Kallmeyer F., Kunte S. and Boulouchos K., Optische Indizierung an Verbrennungsmotoren mit kleinsten Sensoren. 10. Tagung "Der Arbeitsprozess des Verbrennungsmotors" Graz, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pischinger R., Klell M. and Sams T., Thermodynamik der Verbrennungskraftmaschine. 2002: Springer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hohenberg G., Experimentelle Erfassung der Wandwärme von Kolbenmotoren. TU Graz, Habilitation, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Berner H.-J., Chiodi M. and Bargende M., Berücksichtigung der Kalorik des Krafstoffs Erdgas in der Prozessrechnung. 9.Tagung "Der Arbeitsprozess des Verbrennungsmotors" Graz, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bargende M., Ein Gleichungsansatz zur Berechnung der instationären Wandwäremverluste im Hochdruckteil von Ottomotoren. Darmstadt, Dissertation, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barba C., Erarbeitung von Verbrennungskennwerten aus Indizierdaten zur verbesserten Prognose und rechnerischen Simulation des Verbrennungsablaufes bei PKW-DE-Dieselmotoren mit Common-Rail- Einspritzung. ETH Zürich, Dissertation, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lavoie G.A., Heywood J.B. and Keck J.C. (1970). Experimental and Theoretical Study of Nitric Oxide Formation in Internal Combustion Engines. Combustion Science and Technology, 1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urlaub A., Verfahrenstheorie. Verbrennungsmotoren. Vol. 2. 1989: Springer.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vanhaelst R., Optische und thermodynamische Methoden zur Untersuchung der teilhomogenen Dieselverbrennung. Otto-von-Guericke-Universität Magdeburg, Dissertation, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiozaki T., Nakajima H., Kudo Y., Miyashita A. and Aoyagi Y., The Analysis of Combustion Flame Under EGR Conditions in a Dl Diesel Engine. SAE Paper 960323, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
