<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169216</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Statistical Considerations for Evaluating Biofidelity, Repeatability, and Reproducibility of ATDs</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Nusholtz</surname>
                  <given-names>Guy S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Aoun</surname>
                  <given-names>Zine</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Di Domenico</surname>
                  <given-names>Laura</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hsu</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gracián</surname>
                  <given-names>Manuel A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Prado</surname>
                  <given-names>Jesús A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Chrysler Group LLC</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169200</issue-id>
         <fpage>200</fpage>
         <lpage>218</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169216"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Reliable testing of a mechanical system requires the procedures used for the evaluation to be repeatable and reproducible. However, it is never possible to exactly repeat or reproduce the tests that are used for evaluation. To overcome this limitation, a statistical evaluation procedure can generally be used. However, most of the statistical procedures use scalar values as input without the ability to handle vectors or time-histories. To overcome these limitations, two numerical/statistical methods for determining if the impact time-history response of a mechanical system is repeatable or reproducible are evaluated and elaborated upon. Such a system could be a vehicle, a biological human surrogate, an Anthropometric Test Device (ATD or dummy), etc. The responses could be sets of time-histories of accelerations, forces, moments, etc., of a component or of the system. The example system evaluated is the BioRID II rear impact dummy. The evaluation begins by transforming the sets of time-histories into sets of relative-shapes and magnitudes of those response time histories. The two statistical procedures use the t and T2-tests. One uses a statistical comparison between the average time history of a set (Representative Curve (RC)) and the individual time histories of that set or other sets. The other procedure uses a statistical comparison of sets of time histories.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. BORTENSCHLAGER, K., HARTLIEB, M., HIRTH, A., KRAMBERGER, D., and STAHLSCHMIDT, S. (2009). Detailed Analysis of BioRID-II Response Variations in Hardware and Simulation. 21st International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Stuttgart, Germany. Paper Number 09-0492</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. CASELLA, G. and BERGER, R. L. (2001). Statistical Inference. Duxbury Press, Second edition.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. Dodd W.G., Eilbeck J.C., Gibbon J.D., and Morris H.C. Solition and Nonlinear Wave Equations. Academic Press, London, 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. GEHRE, C., GADES, H., and WERNICKE, P. (2009). Objective Rating of Signals Using Test and Simulation Responses. 21st International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Stuttgart, Germany. Paper Number 09-0407.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. HUMMEL, T. J., and SLIGO, J. (1971). Empirical Comparison of Univariate and Multivariate Analysis of Variance Procedures. Psychological Bulletin, 76, 49-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. RENCHER A.C., (1995) Methods of Multivariate Analysis, New York Wiley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. McGill, R., TUKEY, J. W., and LAREN, W. A. (1978). Variations of Box Plots. The American Statistician, Vol. 32, No. 1, pp. 12-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. NUSHOLTZ, G. S., HSU, T. P., and BYERS, L. C (2007). A Proposed Side Impact ATD Bio-Fidelity Evaluation Scheme Using Cross- Correlation Approach. 20th International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Lyon, France. Paper Number 07-0399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. NUSHOLTZ, G. S., HSU, T. P., SHI, Y., BABAII KOCHEKSERAII, S., and GRACIAN LUNA, M. A. (2009). Creating Representative Curves from Multiple Time Histories of Vehicle, ATD and Biomechanics Tests. 21st International Technical Conference on the Enhanced Safety of Vehicles (ESV), Stuttgart, Germany. Paper Number 09-0249</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. MALTESE, M. R.; EPPINGER, R. H.; RHULE, H. H.; DONNELLY, B. R.; PINTAR, F. A.; YOGANANDAN, N. (2002) Response corridors of human surrogates in lateral impacts. NHTSA, Washington, D.C./ Wisconsin Medical College, Milwaukee/Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Milwaukee, Wisc. 31 p.Stapp Car Crash Journal, Vol. 46, Nov. 2002, p. 321-351.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. NUSHOLTZ, G. S., HSH, T. P., GRACIAN LUNA, M. A., DI DOMENICO, L., and BABAII KOCHEKSERAII, S. (2010). The Consequence of Average Curve Generation: Implications for Biomechanics Data. Stapp Car Crash Journal, Vol. 54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">. Xu, L., Agaram, V., Rouhana, S., Hultman, R. et al., “Repeatability Evaluation of the Pre-Prototype NHTSA Advanced Dummy Compared to the Hybrid III,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0165, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0165.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
