<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278178</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Diesel Exhaust Aerosol Measurements Using Air-Ejector and Porous Wall Dilution Techniques</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Swanson</surname>
                  <given-names>Jacob John</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Watts</surname>
                  <given-names>Winthrop</given-names>
                  <suffix>Jr.</suffix>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kittelson</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ. of Minnesota</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>667</fpage>
         <lpage>676</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278178"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The objective of this work is to improve the understanding of variables like dilution and sampling conditions that contribute to particle-based emission measurements by assessing and comparing the nucleation tendency of Diesel aerosols when diluted with a porous wall dilutor or an air ejector in a laboratory setting. An air-ejector dilutor and typical dilution conditions were used to establish the baseline sensitivity to dilution conditions for the given engine operating condition. A porous tube dilutor was designed and special attention was given to integrating the dilutor with the exhaust pipe and residence time chamber. Results from this system were compared with the ejector dilutor. Exhaust aerosols were generated by a Deere 4045 Diesel engine running at low speed (1400 rpm) and low load (50 Nm, ∼10% of rated). Primary dilution parameters that were varied included dilution air temperature (25 and 47°C) and dilution ratio (5, 14, and 55). Particle measurements were made at 0.3, 0.75, and 1.0 s to evaluate particle growth in the residence time chamber.</p>
            <p>Exhaust size distribution measurements made using the ejector dilutor were bimodal with high concentrations of nucleation mode particles. Varying the dilution ratio from 5 to 55:1 (with a dilution air temperature of 25 °C and residence time of 1 s) led to the greatest change in the particle number concentration (4 × 10⁸ to 4 × 10<sup>10</sup>particles/cm³) compared to changes in the other variables. Particle concentration was lower with higher dilution air temperatures and particles were larger in size. Size distributions downstream of the porous tube and ejector dilutor were qualitatively similar in shape. Using a simple dilution model and equations for particle growth in the free molecular regime, particle growth in the two residence time chambers was compared. Model results suggest that dilution in the porous tube dilution system occurs more slowly than in the ejector dilutor. This is consistent with the findings that the particle number concentrations were consistently higher and the geometric mean diameter was generally 1 to 5 nm larger downstream of the porous tube dilutor.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burtscher, H. Physical Characterization of Particulate Emissions from Diesel Engines: A Review; J. Aerosol Sci. 2005, 36, 896-932.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hall, D. E.; Stradling, R. J.; Rickeard, D. J.; Martini, G.; Meco-Morato, A.; Hagemann, R.; Szendefi, J.; Rantanen, L., Measurement of the number and mass weighted size distributions of exhaust particles emitted from European heavy duty engines. CONCAWE report, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, G. Z.; Ford, D. C.; Vasys, V. N.; Chan, D-R.; Johnson, T. R. Influence of engine operating conditions on diesel particulate matter emissions in relation to transient and steady-state conditions. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2007, 41, 4593-4599.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kasper, M., “Sampling and Measurement of Nanoparticle Emissions for Type Approval and Field Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-26-013, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-26-013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdul-Khalek, I.S., Kittelson, D.B., Graskow, B.R., Wei, Q. et al., “Diesel Exhaust Particle Size: Measurement Issues and Trends,” SAE Technical Paper 980525, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980525.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A., Spears, M., and Charmley, W., “Particle Size Distribution from a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine: Steady-State and Transient Emission Measurement Using Two Dilution Systems and Two Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0285, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A., Kittelson, D.B., and Brear, F., “Nanoparticle Growth During Dilution and Cooling of Diesel Exhaust: Experimental Investigation and Theoretical Assessment,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0515, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0515.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khalek, I.A., Kittelson, D.B., and Brear, F., “Nanoparticle Growth During Dilution and Cooling of Diesel Exhaust: Experimental Investigation and Theoretical Assessment,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0515, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0515.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B., Watts, W.F., &amp; Johnson, J.P. (2002). Diesel aerosol sampling methodology. CRC E-42 final report.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D.B.; Watts, W.F.; Johnson, J.P.; Ragatz, A. C. New Method for the Real-Time Measurement of Diesel Aerosol. Contract Final Report for Grant 1 R01 OH8676-01, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D. B.; Watts, W. F.; Johnson, J. P. On-road and laboratory evaluation of combustion aerosols-Part1: Summary of diesel engine results. J. Aerosol Sci. 2006a, 37, 913-930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mayer, A., Czerwinski, J., Matter, U., Wyser, M. et al., “VERT: Diesel Nano-Particulate Emissions: Properties and Reduction Strategies,” SAE Technical Paper 980539, 1998, doi: 10.4271/980539.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mikkanen, P., Moisio, M., Keskinen, J., Ristimäki, J. et al., “Sampling Method for Particle Measurements of Vehicle Exhaust,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0219, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0219.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mohr, M.; Lehmann, U.; Rutter, J. Comparison of massbased and non-mass-based particle measurement systems for ultra-low emissions from automotive sources. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2005, 39, 2229-2238.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newton, G. J.; Carpenter, R. L.; Yeh, H-C.; Peele, E. R. Respirable aerosols from fluidized bed coal combustion. 1. Sampling methodology for an 18-inch experimental fluidized bed coal combustor. Environ. Sci. Technol. 1980, 14, 849-853.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ntziachristos, L., Giechaskiel, B., Pistikopoulos, P., Samaras, Z. et al., “Performance Evaluation of a Novel Sampling and Measurement System for Exhaust Particle Characterization,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1439, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1439.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ntziachristos, L., Tzamkiozis, T., Mamakos, A., and Samaras, Z., “A New Constant Dilution Ratio Concept for Vehicle and Engine Exhaust Particle Sampling,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):491-500, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pyykönen, J.; Miettinen, M.; Sippula, O.; Leskinen, A.; Raunemaa, T.; Jokiniemi, J. Nucleation in a perforated tube dilutor. J. Aerosol Sci. 2007, 38, 172-191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakurai, H.; Tobias, H.J.; Park, K.; Zarling, D.; Docherty, K.S.; Kittelson, D.B.; McMurry, P.H.; Ziemann, P.J. On-line Measurements of Diesel Nanoparticle Composition and Volatility; Atmos. Environ. 2003, 37, 1199-1210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swanson, J.; Kittelson, D.B.; Pui, D. Y. H.; Watts, W.; Alternatives to the gravimetric method for quantification of Diesel particulate matter near the lower level of detection. In press, Journal of Air and Waste Management Association, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tobias, H.J.; Beving, D.E.; Ziemann, P.J.; Sakurai, H.; Zuk, M.; McMurry, P.H.; Zarling, D.; Waytulonis, R.; Kittelson, D.B. Chemical Analysis of Diesel Engine Nanoparticles Using a Nano-DMA/Thermal Desorption Particle Beam Mass Spectrometer; Environ. Sci. Technol. 2001, 35, 2233-2243.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, Q., Kittelson, D.B., and Watts, W.F., “Single-Stage Dilution Tunnel Design,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0207, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wei, Q., Kittelson, D.B., and Watts, W.F., “Single-Stage Dilution Tunnel Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0201, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vouitsis, E.; Ntziachristos, L.; Samaras, Z. Particulate matter mass measurements for low emitting diesel powered vehicles: What's Next?” Progr. Energy Combust. Sci. 2003, 29, 635-672.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
