<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">25771531</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">91</volume>
         <issue-id>i40193606</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/44634422</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Manned Remote Work Stations - Machines to Enhance Man's Space Presence</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>C. Allan</given-names>
                  <surname>Nathan</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1982</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>4224</fpage>
         <lpage>4236</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 1983 Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44634422"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The introduction of the Space Transportation System provides opportunities for improved space operations, reliability and cost effectiveness by taking advantage of man's presence. The astronaut with the proper machines can augment the Shuttle to an extent that tasks never performed in space, such as maintenance and repair of satellites and the construction of large structures can now be done. This paper addresses an evolution of one of these machines, the Manned Remote Work Station (MRWS). The MRWS is a series of EVA platforms and crew cabins that perform roles which are common on the ground such as cherry pickers, crane turrets, emergency repair vehicles and short haul transporters. Concepts and their space applications will be delineated for near term applications in support of the Space Shuttle and future applications in support of the Space Station. Results of man-in-the-loop simulations that demonstrate man's role in maintaining satellites will also be discussed as will test results on the use of manipulators, a key element of the MRWS. These test results demonstrate man's ability to perform useful roles in space and provide a foundation for the development of more ambitious roles in the future.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


