<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007450</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">prancotamamnta</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Proceedings. Annual Conference on Taxation and Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the National Tax Association</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15497542</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23775661</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26816563</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Multinational M&amp;A and Incorporations (International)</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Effective Income Tax Experience of Decentered Multinationals</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Allen</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric J.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Morse</surname>
                  <given-names>Susan C.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">109</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26816497</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>58</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26816563"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>In this paper, we examine how the choice to incorporate a parent corporation outside of the United States affects the effective income tax rates of global firms. We are interested in “decentered” firms (Desai (2009)), by which we mean firms that have material business in the U.S. and a parent firm incorporated outside the U.S. Some of these firms are inversion firms, but inversion transactions are not our focus.</p>
            <p>We find that for profit firm years, decentered firms have lower effective tax rates compared to multinationals with U.S. parent corporations, including book effective tax rates lower by 5 percentage points. However, decentered firms record smaller tax benefits in loss firm years, which can be translated to a book effective tax rate that is greater by 2 percentage points. Firms with a tax haven parent show the strongest results, while firms with a Canadian parent show the weakest results.</p>
            <p>Additional testing suggests that the better performance of decentered firms in profit firm years is due to earnings stripping. For loss firm years, we find some evidence that firms with U.S. parent corporations can record greater negative tax expense due to the worldwide U.S. tax law system. We also find suggestive evidence that valuation allowance practice contributes to the recording of larger negative tax expense by firms with U.S. parent corporations in loss firm years.</p>
            <p>There is no statistically significant difference for decentered firms that have experienced an inversion transaction. This suggests that tax policies should address the challenge of decentered firms broadly, rather than narrowly targeting inverted firms.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">Ahern, Kenneth R., Daniele Daminelli, and Cesare Fracassi, [2015]. “Lost in Translation? The Effect of Cultural Values on Mergers Around the World.” Journal of Financial Economics, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Allen, Eric J., 2015. “The Information Content of the Deferred Tax Valuation Allowance: Evidence From Venture Capital Backed IPO Firms.” Working paper, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Allen, Eric J. and Susan C. Morse, 2013. “Tax-Haven Incorporation for U.S.-Centered Firms: No Exodus Yet.” National Tax Journal 66 (2), 395-420.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Altshuler, Rosanne, and Harry Grubert, 2002. “Repatriation Taxes, Repatriation Strategies and Multinational Financial Policy.” Journal of Public Economics 87 (1), 73-107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Armstrong, Christopher S., Jennifer L. Blouin, Alan D. Jagolinzer &amp; David F. Larcker, Corporate Governance, Incentives, and Tax Avoidance (2015) 60(1) J. Acct’g &amp; Econ. 1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Armstrong, Christopher S., Jennifer L. Blouin, and David F. Larcker, 2012. “The Incentives for Tax Planning.” Journal of Accounting and Economics 53 (__) 391-411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Bebchuk, Lucian A., and Alma Cohen, 2003. “Firms’ Decisions Where to Incorporate.” Journal of Law and Economics 46 (2), 383-425.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Bird, Andrew, Alexander Edwards and Terry Shevlin, 2014. “Does Earnings Lockout Make U.S. Multinationals Attractive to Foreign Acquirers?” working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Blouin, Jennifer L., Linda K. Krull and Leslie A. Robinson, 2014 “The Location, Composition, and Investment Implications of Permanently Reinvested Earnings.” Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Broughman, Brian J., Jesse M. Fried and Darian M. Ibrahim, 2014. “Delaware Law as Lingua Franca: Theory and Evidence” forthcoming, Journal of Law and Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Clausing, Kimberly A., 2009. “Multinational Firm Tax Avoidance and Tax Policy.” National Tax Journal 52 (4), 703-725.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Cloyd, C. Brian, Lillian F. Mills, and Connie D. Weaver, 2003. “Firm Valuation Effects of the Expatriation of U.S. Corporations to Tax Haven Countries.” Journal of the American Taxation Association 25 (1), 87-109.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">De Simone, Lisa, 2016. “Does a Common Set of Accounting Standards Affect Tax-Motivated Income Shifting for Multinational Firms?” Journal of Accounting and Economics 61(__)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">De Simone, Lisa, Kenneth J. Klassen, and Jeri K. Seidman, 2015 “Unprofitable Affiliates and Income Shifting Behavior” working paper</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Desai, Mihir A., 2009. “The Decentering of the Global Firm.” The World Economy 32 (9), 1271-1290.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Desai, Mihir A., and Dhammika Dharmapala, 2010. “Do Strong Fences Make Strong Neighbors?” National Tax Journal 54 (4),</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Desai, Mihir A., and James R. Hines Jr., 2002. “Expectations and Expatriations: Tracing the Causes and Consequences of Corporate Inversions.” National Tax Journal 55 (3), 409-440.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Dharmapala, Dhammika., 2014. “What do we know about base erosion and profit shifting? A review of the empirical literature.” CESifo Working Paper, No. 4612.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Dharmapala, Dhammika, and James R. Hines Jr., 2009. “Which Countries Become Tax Havens?” Journal of Public Economics 93 (9-10), 1058-1068.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Dharmapala &amp; Riedel (2012). Earnings Shocks and tax-motivated income shifting: Evidence from European MNCs. Journal of Public Economics.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Dhaliwal, D.S., Kaplan, S.E., Laux, R.C., and Weisbrod, E. 2013. The information content of tax expense for firms reporting losses. Journal of Accounting Research.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Dowd, Tim, Paul Landefeld, and Anne Moore, 2015. “Profit Shifting of U.S. Multinationals” (working paper)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Dyreng, Scott D., Michelle Hanlon, and Edward L. Maydew, 2008. “Long-Run Corporate Tax Avoidance.” The Accounting Review 83 (1), 61-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Dyreng, Scott D., Michelle Hanlon, Edward L. Maydew, and Jacob R. Thornock, 2014. “Changes in Corporate Effective Tax Rates Over the Past Twenty-Five Years.” Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Dyreng, Scott D. and Bradley P. Lindsey, 2009. “Using Financial Accounting Data to Examine the Effect of Foreign Operations Located in Tax Havens and Other Countries on U.S. Multinational Firms’ Tax Rates.” Journal of Accounting Research 47 (5), 1283-1316.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Fleming, J. Clifton Jr., Robert J. Peroni, and Stephen E. Shay, 2009. “Worse Than Exemption.” Emory Law Journal 59 (1), 79-149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Financial Accounting Standards Board, 2008. Financial Accounting Standard Number 131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Financial Accounting Standards Board, 2009. Accounting Standards Codification 740: Tax Provisions.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Frankel, Jeffrey A. and David Romer, 1999. “Does Trade Cause Growth?” American Economic Review 89 (3), 379-399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Graham, John R., Michelle Hanlon and Terry Shevlin, 2010a. “Barriers to Mobility: The Lockout Effect of U.S. Taxation of Worldwide Corporate Profits.” National Tax Journal 63 (4), 1111-1114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Graham, J.R., Hanlon, M., Shevlin, T. 2010b. Real Effects of Accounting Rules: Evidence from Multinational Firms’ Investment Location and Profit Repatriation Decisions. Journal of Accounting Research. Survey result says that three fourths of all foreign earnings are PRE</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Gravelle, Jennifer, 2012. “Who Will Benefit From a Territorial Tax? Characteristics of Multinational Firms.” National Tax Association Proceedings, 105th Annual Conference on Taxation, available at http://www.ntanet.org/images/stories/pdf/proceedings/12/15_gravelle.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Grubert, Harry, 2012. “Foreign Taxes and the Growing Share of U.S. Multinational Company Income Abroad: Profits, Not Sales, Are Being Globalized.” National Tax Journal 65 (2), 247- 282.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Grubert, Harry, and Rosanne Altshuler, 2008. “Corporate Taxes in the World Economy: Reforming the Taxation of Cross-Border Income.” In Diamond, John W. and George R. Zodrow (eds.), Fundamental Tax Reform: Issues, Choices, and Implications, 319-354. MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Grubert, Harry, Timothy Goodspeed &amp; Deborah L. Swenson, 1993. “Explaining the Low Taxable Income of Foreign-Controlled Companies in the United States.” In Giovannini, Alberto, R. Glen Hubbard and Joel Slemrod (eds), Studies in International Taxation, 237-276. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Hines Jr., James R., and Eric M. Rice, 1994. “Fiscal Paradise: Foreign Tax Havens and American Business.” Quarterly Journal of Economics 109 (1), 149-182.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Huizinga, H.P. and Voget, J. 2009. International Taxation and the Direction and Volume of Cross-Broder M&amp;As. Journal of FInance</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Hurt, Christine, 2006. “Regulating Public Morals and Private Markets: Online Securities Trading, Internet Gambling, and the Speculation Paradox.” Boston University Law Review 86 (_), 371-___.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Kane, Mitchell A., and Edward B. Rock, 2008. “Corporate Taxation and International Charter Competition.” Michigan Law Review 106 (7), 1229-1283.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Klassen, Kenneth J. and Stacie K. LaPlante, 2012. “Are U.S. Multinational Corporations Becoming More Aggressive Income Shifters?” Journal of Accounting Research 50 (5), 1245- 1285.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Klassen, Kenneth J., Petro Lisowsky &amp; Devan Mescall, 2016. “Transfer Pricing: Strategies, Practices and Tax Minimization.” Contemporary Accounting Research __ (__), 1-39.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Kleinbard, Edward A., 2014. “Competitiveness’ Has Nothing to Do With It.’” Tax Notes 144 ( ), 1055-___.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Kleinbard, Edward A., 2011. “Stateless Income.” Florida Tax Review 11 (9), 699-774.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">KPMG (2012)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Krull, L.K. 2004. Permanently Reinvested Foreign Earnings, Taxes, and Earnings Management. The accounting Review. 280 of her 417 sample firms disclose PRE</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Litvak, Kate, 2007. “The Effect of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act on Non-U.S. Companies Cross-Listed in the U.S.” Journal of Corporate Finance 13 (2), 195-228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Lokken, Lawrence, 2005. “Whatever Happened to Subpart F?” Florida Tax Review 7 (__), 185-___.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Markle, Kevin S., 2016. “A Comparison of the Tax-Motivated Income Shifting of Multinationals in Territorial and Worldwide Countries.” Contemporary Accounting Research 33(1), 7-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Markle, Kevin S. and Douglas A. Shackelford, 2014. “The Impact of Headquarter and Subsidiary Locations on Multinationals’ Effective Tax Rates.” Tax Policy and the Economy 28 (1), 33-62.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r50">
            <mixed-citation id="c50">Markle, Kevin S. and Douglas A. Shackelford, 2012. “Cross-Country Comparisons of Corporate Income Taxes.” National Tax Journal 65 (3), 493-528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r51">
            <mixed-citation id="c51">Marples, Donald J. and Jane G. Gravelle, 2014. “Corporate Expatriation, Inversions, and Mergers: Tax Issues.” Congressional Research Service Report dated May 27, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r52">
            <mixed-citation id="c52">Mider, Zachary R. &amp; Jesse Drucker, 2016. “Tax Inversion: How U.S. Companies Buy Tax Breaks,” Bloomberg News, updated April 6, 2016, available at http://www.bloombergview.com/quicktake/tax-inversion (last visited April 22, 2016).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r53">
            <mixed-citation id="c53">Mills, Lillian &amp; Kaye J. Newberry, 2004. “Do Foreign Multinationals’ Tax Incentives Influence Their U.S. Income Reporting and Debt Policy?” National Tax Journal 67 (1), 89-107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r54">
            <mixed-citation id="c54">Morse, Susan C., 2013a. “A Corporate Offshore Profits Transition Tax.” North Carolina Law Review 91 (2), 549-605.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r55">
            <mixed-citation id="c55">Morse, Susan C., 2013b. “Startup Ltd.: Tax Planning and Initial Incorporation Location.” Florida Tax Review 14 (8), 219-360.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r56">
            <mixed-citation id="c56">OECD, 2013. Action Plan on Base Erosion and Profit Shifting.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r57">
            <mixed-citation id="c57">Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development, 2000. Towards Global Tax Cooperation: Progress in Identifying and Eliminating Harmful Tax Competition. OECD, Paris, France.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r58">
            <mixed-citation id="c58">Rego, Sonia Olhoft, 2003. “Tax-Avoidance Activities of U.S. Multinational Corporations.” Contemporary Accounting Research 20 (4), 805-833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r59">
            <mixed-citation id="c59">Scholes, Myron S., Mark A. Wolfson, Merle M. Erickson, Michelle L. Hanlon, Edward L. Maydew, and Terrence J. Shevlin, 2014. Taxes and Business Strategy: A Planning Approach.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r60">
            <mixed-citation id="c60">Seida, Jim A., and William F. Wempe, 2004. “Effective Tax Rate Changes and Earnings Stripping Following Corporate Inversions.” National Tax Journal 57 (4), 805-828.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r61">
            <mixed-citation id="c61">Shaviro, Daniel, 2011. “The Rising Tax Electivity of Corporate Residence.” Tax Law Review 64 (3), 377-430.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r62">
            <mixed-citation id="c62">Shay, Stephen E., 2014. “Mr. Secretary, Take the Tax Juice Out of Corporate Expatriations.” Tax Notes [144 ( )], 473-478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r63">
            <mixed-citation id="c63">Shay, Stephen E., 2004. “Exploring Alternatives to Subpart F.” Taxes 82 (__), 29-38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r64">
            <mixed-citation id="c64">Talley, Eric L., 2015. “Corporate Inversions and the Unbundling of Regulatory Competition.” Virginia Law Review 101 (6), 1649-___.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r65">
            <mixed-citation id="c65">Thomas, J. and Zhang, F. 2014. Valuation of Tax Expense. Review of Accounting Studies</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r66">
            <mixed-citation id="c66">Slemrod, Joel, 2004. “The Economics of Corporate Tax Selfishness.” National Tax Journal 57 (4), 877-899.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r67">
            <mixed-citation id="c67">U.S. Department of the Treasury, 2007. Report to the Congress on Earnings Stripping, Transfer Pricing and U.S. Income Tax Treaties. U.S. Department of the Treasury, Office of Tax Policy, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r68">
            <mixed-citation id="c68">U.S. Department of the Treasury, 2002. Corporate Inversion Transactions: Tax Policy Implications. U.S. Department of the Treasury, Office of Tax Policy, Washington D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r69">
            <mixed-citation id="c69">VanderWolk, Jefferson P., 2010. “Inversions Under Section 7874 of the Internal Revenue Code: Flawed Legislation, Flawed Guidance.” Northwestern Journal of International Law and Business 30 (3), 699-719.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r70">
            <mixed-citation id="c70">Voget, Johannes, 2011. “Relocation of Headquarters and International Taxation” J. Pub. Econ. 95 (2011), 1067-1081.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r71">
            <mixed-citation id="c71">Wells, Bret, 2010. “What Corporate Inversions Teach About International Tax Reform” Tax Notes __ (__), 1345-1367.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r72">
            <mixed-citation id="c72">White House and U.S. Department of the Treasury, 2012. The President’s Framework for Business Tax Reform. White House and U.S. Department of the Treasury, Washington, D.C.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Appendix 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Non-U.S. Firm and U.S. Firm Diagram</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1:</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2:</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Sample Construction</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3:</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Incorporation Location</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4:</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Total Sample Breakdown by 2-digit SIC Code</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5:</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Comparison of Mean Values between U.S. Firms and Non-U.S.Firms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6:</label>
         <caption id="ca-7">
            <p>Correlation Matrix</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 7:</label>
         <caption id="ca-8">
            <p>Main Results: Test of Hypotheses 1 and 2. OLS regression of effective tax rate measures for Non-U.S. Firms compared to U.S. Firms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 8:</label>
         <caption id="ca-9">
            <p>Comparison of Mean Values: Other Non-U.S. Firms and Inversion Firms and Geographic Subgroups of Non-U.S. Firms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 9:</label>
         <caption id="ca-10">
            <p>OLS Regression of Effective Tax Rate Measures on Non-U.S. Firm and Inversion Firm Status</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 10:</label>
         <caption id="ca-11">
            <p>OLS Regression on Geographic Subgroup of Non-U.S. Firm</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 11:</label>
         <caption id="ca-12">
            <p>Profit Firm Years: Mechanism for Lower ETRs for Non-U.S. Firms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 12:</label>
         <caption id="ca-13">
            <p>Loss Firm Years: Mechanisms for Different ETR Results for Non-U.S. Firms</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
