<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285083</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Study of Air Flow Interaction with Pilot Injections in a Diesel Engine by Means of PIV Measurements</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Garcia-Oliver</surname>
                  <given-names>Jose M</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Garcia</surname>
                  <given-names>Antonio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Gil</surname>
                  <given-names>Antonio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Pachano</surname>
                  <given-names>Leonardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Universitat Politecnica de Valencia</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>June 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285080</issue-id>
         <fpage>740</fpage>
         <lpage>751</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285083"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>With ever-demanding emission legislations in Compression Ignition (CI) engines, new premixed combustion strategies have been developed in recent years seeking both, emissions and performance improvements. Since it has been shown that in-cylinder air flow affects the combustion process, and hence the overall engine performance, the study of swirling structures and its interaction with fuel injection are of great interest. In this regard, possible Turbulent Kinetic Energy (TKE) distribution changes after fuel injection may be a key parameter for achieving performance improvements by reducing in-cylinder heat transfer. Consequently, this paper aims to gain an insight into spray-swirl interaction through the analysis of in-cylinder velocity fields measured by Particle Image Velocimetry (PIV) when PCCI conditions are proposed. Experiments are carried out in a single cylinder optical Diesel engine with bowl-in-piston geometry. A standard 2D PIV system is used for measuring instantaneous velocity fields in a cross section (swirl-plane) inside the combustion chamber. The test matrix is based on an advanced single pilot injection with energizing time and injection pressure sweeps at different crank-angles. Results show that swirl ratio decreases with the increase of injected fuel mass. The decrease in swirl ratio also comes with a homogenization of the flow field. This homogenization along with lower swirl ratios might decrease heat transfer to cylinder walls.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa, A.J., Broatch, A., García, A., and Mónico, L.F., “Sensitivity of combustion noise and NOx and soot emissions to pilot injection in PCCI diesel engines”, Applied Energy 104:149-157, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2012.11.040.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kiplimo, R., Tomita, E., Kawahara, N., and Yokobe, S., “Effects of spray impingement, injection parameters, and EGR on the combustion and emission characteristics of a PCCI diesel engine”, Applied Thermal Engineering 37:165-175, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2011.11.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda, T., Hakozaki, T., Uchimoto, T., Hatano, J. et al., "PCCI Operation with Early Injection of Conventional Diesel Fuel," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0378, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Neely, G., Sasaki, S., and Leet, J., "Experimental Investigation of PCCIDI Combustion on Emissions in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0121, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0121.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zha, K., Busch, S., Miles, P., Wijeyakulasuriya, S. et al., "Characterization of Flow Asymmetry During the Compression Stroke Using Swirl-Plane PIV in a Light-Duty Optical Diesel Engine with the Re-entrant Piston Bowl Geometry," SAE Int. J. Engines 8(4):1837-1855, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1699.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Desantes, J.M., and Pastor, J.V., “LDV measurements of the flow inside the combustion chamber of a 4-valve D.I. Diesel engine with axisymmetric piston-bowls”, Experiments in Fluids 22(2):118-128, 1996, doi:10.1007/s003480050029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zegers, R.P.C., Luijten, C.C.M., Dam, N.J., and Goey, L.P.H. de, “Preand post-injection flow characterization in a heavy-duty diesel engine using high-speed PIV”, Experiments in Fluids 53(3):731-746, 2012, doi:10.1007/s00348-012-1323-3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Valentino, G., Allocca, L., and Marchitto, L., "PIV Investigation of High Swirl Flow on Spray Structure and its Effect on Emissions in a Diesel-Like Environment," SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-1286, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1286.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dembinski, H.W., “The effects of injection pressure and swirl on incylinder flow pattern and combustion in a compression-ignition engine”, International Journal of Engine Research 15(4):444-459, 2013, doi: 10.1177/1468087413491262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dembinski, H. and Angstrom, H., "Swirl and Injection Pressure Impact on After-Oxidation in Diesel Combustion, Examined with Simultaneous Combustion Image Velocimetry and Two Colour Optical Method," SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-0913, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0913.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tanov, S., Wang, Z., Wang, H., Richter, M. et al., "Effects of Injection Strategies on Fluid Flow and Turbulence in Partially Premixed Combustion (PPC) in a Light Duty Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2015- 24-2455, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-24-2455.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bowditch, F., "A New Tool for Combustion Research A Quartz Piston Engine," SAE Technical Paper 610002, 1961, doi:10.4271/610002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benajes, J., Olmeda, P., Martín, J. and Carreño, R., “A new methodology for uncertainties characterization in combustion diagnosis and thermodynamic modelling”, Applied Thermal Engineering 71:389-399, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2014.07.010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri F., Olmeda P., Martín J., García, Antonio. “A complete 0D thermodynamic predictive model for direct injection diesel engines”, Applied Energy (88) (2011) 4632-4641. doi:10.1016/j.apenergy.2011.06.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Galindo, J., Martín, J., and Arnau, F., "A Simple Model for Predicting the Trapped Mass in a DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0494, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0494.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapuerta M, Armas O, Hernández JJ. “Diagnosis of DI Diesel combustion from in- cylinder pressure signal by estimation of mean thermodynamic properties of the gas”. Appl Thermal Eng 1999; 19(5):513-29. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1359-4311(98)00075-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri F, Molina S, Martín J, Armas O. “Influence of measurement errors and estimated parameters on combustion diagnosis”. Appl Thermal Eng 2006; 26(2-3):226-3, http://dx.doi.o10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2005.05.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, F., Margot, X., Gil, A., and Martin, J., "Computational Study of Heat Transfer to the Walls of a DI Diesel Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0210, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0210.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aronsson, U., Solaka, H., Lequien, G., Andersson, O. et al., "Analysis of Errors in Heat Release Calculations Due to Distortion of the In-Cylinder Volume Trace from Mechanical Deformation in Optical Diesel Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 5(4):1561-1570, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1604.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murakami, A., Arai, M., and Hiroyasu, H., "Swirl Measurements and Modeling in Direct Injection Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 880385, 1988, doi:10.4271/880385.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tropea, C., Yarin, A. L. and Foss, J. F., “Springer Handbook of Experimental Fluid Mechanics”, (Berlin Heidelberg, Springer Verlag, 2007), p289, ISBN-13: 978-3-540-25141-5.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dannemann, J., Pielhop, K., Klaas, M., and Schröder, W., “Cycle resolved multi-planar flow measurements in a four-valve combustion engine,” Experiments in Fluids 50(4):961-976, 2010, doi: 10.1007/s00348-010-0963-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schubert, C., Wimmer, A., and Chmela, F., "Advanced Heat Transfer Model for CI Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0695, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0695.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
