<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830266</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830269</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>AN ANALYSIS OF THE ROLE OF PAWNSHOPS IN THE PHILIPPINE FINANCIAL SYSTEM</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Mario B.</given-names>
                  <surname>Lamberte</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1991</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>229</fpage>
         <lpage>245</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830269"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Pawnshops have recently become a permanent fixture in the lives of ordinary Filipinos. Jewelries, appliances and other properties are pawned everyday to temporarily augment the expenses of those who otherwise can not borrow from banks and other financial institutions. In fact, some of these pawnshops have expanded into the provinces thus taking a new role as exponents of development. But despite its popularity, very little importance has been given to the study of pawnshops. Thus, this paper tries to fill this void by presenting in a new light some facts associated with the pawnshops' continued existence in the financial system. To do this, a review was made regarding the regulatory framework by which pawnshops in the Philippines operate. It then discusses the role of pawnshops in the financial system. This is followed by an analysis of the performance of pawnshops with special emphasis on the following: a) sources and uses of funds, b) interest rates on loans, c) profitability and operating efficiency of pawnshops, and d) linkages between pawnshops and banks. In order to know whether pawnshops can still improve their competitive advantage by increasing their size, tests were made on the economies of scale. In short, what all the analyses and results point to is that pawnshops can and will be a good alternative source of credit for small borrowers and society, in general.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d15e217a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e224" publication-type="other">
Lamberte and Bunda (1988)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e231a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e238" publication-type="other">
Lamberte and Balbosa (1988)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e254a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e258" publication-type="other">
Lamberte, Mario B. and Ma. Theresa Bunda, "The Financial Markets in Low-Income Urban Communities: The
Case of the Sapang Palay." Philippine Institute for Development Studies (PIDS) Working Paper Series
No. 88-05 (March 1988).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e271a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e275" publication-type="other">
Lamberte, Mario B. and Joven Z. Balbosa, "Informal Savings and Credit Institutions in the Urban Areas: The
Case of Cooperative Credit Unions." Philippine Institute for Development Studies (PIDS) Working Paper
Series No. 88-06.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e292" publication-type="other">
Padilla, Jaime T., "A Pawnshop Takes on a Development Role." Countryside Banking, Vol. XI, No. 3 (June 1985).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


