<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26168981</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Methodology for Assessment of Alternative Hybrid Electric Vehicle Powertrain System Architectures</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zaremba</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexander T.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Soto</surname>
                  <given-names>Ciro</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Jennings</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Ford Motor Co.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>June 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26168958</issue-id>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26168981"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Hybrid electric vehicle (HEV) systems offer significant improvements in vehicle fuel economy and reductions in vehicle generated greenhouse gas emissions. The widely accepted power-split HEV system configuration couples together an internal combustion engine with two electric machines (a motor and a generator) through a planetary gear set. This paper describes a methodology for analysis and optimization of alternative HEV power-split configurations defined by alternative connections between power sources and transaxle. The alternative configurations are identified by a matrix of kinematic equations for connected power sources. Based on the universal kinematic matrix, a generic method for automatically formulating dynamic models is developed. Screening and optimization of alternative configurations involves verification of a set of design requirements which reflect: vehicle continuous operation, e.g. grade test; and vehicle dynamic operation such as acceleration and drivability. Only the former are consider in this paper. The method automatically defines a design parameter space for each configuration which eventually would allow configuration evaluation and optimization, e.g. sizing of power sources or optimization of transaxle gear ratios.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chasse, A., and Sciarretta, A., “Supervisory control of hybrid powertrains: An experimental benchmark of offline optimization and online energy management,” Control Engineering Practice, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J., “Modeling, configuration and control optimization of powersplit hybrid vehicles,” Ph.D. thesis, University of Michigan, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rizzoni, G., Guzzella, L., Baumann, B., “Unified Modeling of Hybrid Electric Vehicle Drivetrains,” IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics, Vol. 4, No. 3, pp. 246-257, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J., Peng, H., Filipi, Z., “Modeling and Control Analysis of Toyota Hybrid Systems”, International Conference on Advanced Intelligent Mechatronics, Monterey, CA Jul. 24-28, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Katsargyri, G.-E., Kolmanovsky, I., Michelini, J., Kuang, M. L., Phillips, A. M., Rinehart, M., Dahleh, M., “Optimally Controlling Hybrid Electric Vehicles using Path Forecasting,” American Control Conference, June 10-12, 2009, pp.4613-4617.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Achtenová, G. and Svoboda, J., “Computer-Aided Calculation of Planetary Gear Sets,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0129, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-0129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Conlon, B., “Comparative Analysis of Single and Combined Hybrid Electrically Variable Transmission Operating Modes,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1162, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-1162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benford, H. and Leising, M., “The Lever Analogy: A New Tool in Transmission Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 810102, 1981, doi: 10.4271/810102.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klages, B., Woermann, R., and Theuerkauf, H., “An Improved Real- Time Model of a Planetary Gear Train,” SAE Technical Paper 970970, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">del Castillo, J.M., “The analytcial expression of the efficiency of planetary gear trains,” Mechanism and Machine Theory Journal, 37, pp. 197-217, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kahraman, A., Ligata, H., Kienzle, K., Zini, D.M., “A Kinematics and Power Flow Analysis Methodology for Automatic Transmission Planetary Gear Trains,” ASME Journal of Mechanical Design, Vol. 126, pp. 1071-1081, November 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J., Peng, H., “Modeling and Control of a Power-Split Hybrid Vehicle,” IEEE Transactions of Control Systems Technology, Vol. 16, No. 6, November 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J., Peng, H., “A systematic design approach for two planetary gear split hybrid vehicles,” Vehicle System Dynamics Journal, 48: 11, pp. 1395-1412, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lynwander, P., 1983, Gear Drive Systems: Design and Application. Marcel Dekker, New York.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arnold, V.I., “Mathematical Methods of Classical Mechanics,” 2nd ed. Translated by Vogtmann, K. and Weinstein, A.. New York: Springer- Verlag, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
