<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284892</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Investigation of Two-Phase Flow Evolution of In- and Near-Nozzle Regions of a Gasoline Direct Injection Engine During Needle Transients</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Saha</surname>
                  <given-names>Kaushik</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Som</surname>
                  <given-names>Sibendu</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Argonne National Laboratory</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Battistoni</surname>
                  <given-names>Michele</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Universita degli Studi di Perugia</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Li</surname>
                  <given-names>Yanheng</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Convergent Science Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pomraning</surname>
                  <given-names>Eric</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Convergent Science Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Senecal</surname>
                  <given-names>P. K.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Convergent Science Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>June 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284847</issue-id>
         <fpage>1230</fpage>
         <lpage>1240</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284892"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This work involves modeling internal and near-nozzle flows of a gasoline direct injection (GDI) nozzle. The Engine Combustion Network (ECN) Spray G condition has been considered for these simulations using the nominal geometry of the Spray G injector. First, best practices for numerical simulation of the two-phase flow evolution inside and the near-nozzle regions of the Spray G injector are presented for the peak needle lift. The mass flow rate prediction for peak needle lift was in reasonable agreement with experimental data available in the ECN database. Liquid plume targeting angle and liquid penetration estimates showed promising agreement with experimental observations. The capability to assess the influence of different thermodynamic conditions on the two-phase flow nature was established by predicting non-flashing and flashing phenomena. Mild vapor formation inside the holes of the injector was predicted for flashing and non-flashing conditions, which suggests that there was sufficient depressurization of liquid fuel in a GDI nozzle. Outlet domain size and alignment of spray plumes with a grid were observed to be critically important to avoid numerical errors. Finally, to represent the real-world scenario of a moving needle in a GDI nozzle, simulations were carried out at different fixed needle lifts to provide insight to flow development inside a GDI nozzle, from opening to closing of the needle. Predictions indicated that flow patterns, and thus vapor formation characteristics, are considerably affected at very low needle lifts, for both flashing and non-flashing scenarios.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montanaro, A. and Allocca, L., "Flash Boiling Evidences of a Multi-Hole GDI Spray under Engine Conditions by Mie-Scattering Measurements," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1945, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1945.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weber D. and Leick P., "Structure and Velocity Field of Individual Plumes of Flashing Gasoline Direct Injection Sprays," in ILASS-Europe 2014, 26^th Annual Conference on Liquid Atomiation and Spray Systems, Bremen, Germany, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VanderwegeB. A. and Hochgreb S., "The Effect of Fuel Volatility on Sprays from High-Pressure Swirl -njectors," in International Symposium on Combustion, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng W., Xu M., Zhang G., Zhang Y., and Cleary D. J., "Atomization and Vaporization for Flash-Boiling Multi-hole Sprays with Alcohol Fuels," Fuel, vol. 95, pp. 287-297, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xu, M., Zhang, Y., Zeng, W., Zhang, G. et al., "Flash Boiling: Easy and Better Way to Generate Ideal Sprays than the High Injection Pressure," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):137-148, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BlinkovV. N., Jones O. C., and Nigmatulia B. I., "Nucleation and Flashing in Nozzles - 2. Comparison with Experiments Using a Five- Equation Model for Vapor Void Development," International Journal of Mulitphase Flow, vol. 19, no. 6, pp. 965-986, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ChangD. L. and Lee C. F., "Preliminary Computational Studies of Flash Boiling for Fuel Injectors in Gasoline Direct Injection Automotive Engines," in Proceedings of Inter-society Energy Conversion Engineering Conference, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawano, D., Goto, Y., Odaka, M., and Senda, J., "Modeling Atomization and Vaporization Processes of Flash-Boiling Spray," SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0534, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeng Y. and Lee C. F., "An Atomization Model for Flash Boiling Sprays," Combustion Science and Technology, vol. 169, pp. 45-67, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zuo B., Gomes A. M., and Rutland C. J., "Modelling Superheated Fuel Sprays and Vaporization," International Journal of Engine Research, vol. 1, pp. 321-336, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu N., Reveillon J., Meslem Y., and Demoulin F., "Modelling Cavitation and Flash Atomization," in ASME 2014 4th Joint US-European Fluids Engineering Division Summer Meeting, Chicago, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henry R. and Fauske H., "The Two-Phase Critical Flow of One Component Mixtures in Nozzles, Orifices and Short Tubes," ASME Journal of Heat Transfer, vol. 93, pp. 179-187, 1971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bilicki Z. and Kestin J., "Physical Aspects of the Relaxation Model in Two-Phase Flows," Proceedings of Royal Society London A, vol. 428, pp. 379-397, 1990.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Downar-Zaploski P., Bilicki Z., Bolle L., and Franco J., "The Nonequilibrium Relaxation Model for One-Dimensional Flashing Liquid Flow," International Journal of Multiphase Flow, vol. 22, no. 3, pp. 473-483, June 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">SchmidtD. P., Gopalakrishnan S., and Jasak H., "Multidimensional Simulation of Thermal Non-equilibrium Channel Flow," International Journal of Multiphase Flow, vol. 36, pp. 284-292, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NeroorkarK. D., Modeling of Flash Boiling Flows in Injectors with Gasoline-Ethanol Fuel Blends, Ph. D. Thesis, University of Massachusetts Amherst, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, G., Negro, S., Forte, C., Cazzoli, G. et al., "The Prediction of Flash Atomization in GDI Multi-Hole Injectors," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1501, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1501.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">BrennenC. E., Cavitation and Bubble Dynamics, Oxford University Press, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gopalakrishnan, S. and Schmidt, D., "A Computational Study of Flashing Flow in Fuel Injector Nozzles," SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):160- 170, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0141.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moulai, M., Grover, R., Parrish, S., and Schmidt, D., "Internal and Near-Nozzle Flow in a Multi-Hole Gasoline Injector Under Flashing and Non-Flashing Conditions," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-0944, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-0944.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saha K., Som S., Battistoni M., Li Y., Quan S., and Senecal P. K., "Modeling of Internal and Near-nozzle Flow for a GDI Fuel Injector," in Proceedings of the ASME 2015 ICED Fall Technical Conference, ICEF2015-1112, Houston, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spray G ECN, Sandia National Laboratory, http://www.sandia.gov/ecn/G/targetcondition/sprayG.php, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">RichardsK. J., Senecal P. K., and Pomraning E., CONVERGE v2.2 Documentation, Convergent Sciences, Inc., 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni, M., Xue, Q., Som, S., and Pomraning, E., "Effect of Off-Axis Needle Motion on Internal Nozzle and Near Exit Flow in a Multi- Hole Diesel Injector," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(1):167-182, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-1426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Xue Q., Battistoni M., Powell C. F., Longman D. E., Quan S. P., Pomraning E., Senecal P. K., Schmidt D. P., and Som S., "An Eulerian CFD Model and X-ray Radiography for Coupled Nozzle Flow and Spray in Internal Combustion Engines," International Journal of Multiphase Flow, vol. 70, pp. 77-88, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhao H., Quan S., Dai M., Pomraning E., Senecal P., Xue Q., Battistoni M., and Som S., "Validation of a Three-Dimensional Internal Nozzle Flow Model Including Automatic Mesh Generation and Cavitation Effects," in ASME 2013 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, Dearborn, Michigan, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni M., Som S., and Longman D. E., "Comparison of Mixture and Multi-fluid Models for In-Nozzle Cavitation Prediction," ASME Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbuines and Power, vol. 136, no. 6, pp. (061506)1-12, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Battistoni M., Duke D. J., Swantek A. B., Tilocco F. Z., Powell C. F., and Som S., "Effects of Non-condensable Gas on Cavitating Nozzles," Atomization and Sprays, vol. 25, no. 6, pp. 453-483, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DymondJ. H., Glen N. F., and Isdale J. D., "Transport Properties of Nonelectrolyte Liquid Mixtures vii. Viscosity Coefficients for Isooctane and for Equimolar Mixtures of Isooctane + N-Octane and Isooctane + N-Dodecane from 25 to 100 at Pressures up to 500 mpa or to the Freezing Pressure," International Journal of Thermophysics, vol. 6, no. 3, pp. 233-250, 1985.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Som S., Wang Z., Pei Y., Senecal P. K., and Pomraning E., "LES of Vaporizing Gasoline Sprays Considering Multi-injection Averaging And Grid-convergent Mesh Resolution," in Proceedings of the ASME 2015 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Technical Conference, ICEF2015-1003, Houston, Texas, 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manin, J., Jung, Y., Skeen, S., Pickett, L. et al., "Experimental Characterization of DI Gasoline Injection Processes," SAE Technical Paper 2015-01-1894, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015-01-1894.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
