<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26285049</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Lifetime Assessment of Cylinder Heads for Efficient Heavy Duty Engines Part I</article-title>
            <subtitle>A Discussion on Thermomechanical and High-Cycle Fatigue as Well as Thermophysical Properties of Lamellar Graphite Cast Iron GJL250 and Vermicular Graphite Cast Iron GJV450</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Seifert</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Offenburg University of Applied Sciences</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>von Hartrott</surname>
                  <given-names>Philipp</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Fraunhofer IWM</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Boss</surname>
                  <given-names>Kristopher</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>John Deere Engine Works</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Wynthein</surname>
                  <given-names>Paul</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>John Deere Engine Works</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>April 2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>10</volume>
         <issue>2</issue>
         <issue-id>e26285020</issue-id>
         <fpage>359</fpage>
         <lpage>365</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2017 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26285049"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Cast iron materials are used as materials for cylinder heads for heavy duty internal combustion engines. These components must withstand severe cyclic mechanical and thermal loads throughout their service life. While high-cycle fatigue (HCF) is dominant for the material in the water jacket region, the combination of thermal transients with mechanical load cycles results in thermomechanical fatigue (TMF) of the material in the fire deck region, even including superimposed TMF and HCF loads. Increasing the efficiency of the engines directly leads to increasing combustion pressure and temperature and, thus, lower safety margins for the currently used cast iron materials or alternatively the need for superior cast iron materials. In this paper (Part I), the TMF properties of the lamellar graphite cast iron GJL250 and the vermicular graphite cast iron GJV450 are characterized in uniaxial tests and a mechanism-based model for TMF life prediction is developed for both materials. The model can be used to estimate the fatigue life of components by means of finite-element calculations (Part II of the paper) and supports engineers in finding the appropriate material and design. Furthermore, the effect of the elastic, plastic and creep properties of the materials on the fatigue life can be evaluated with the model. However, for a material selection also the thermophysical properties, controlling to a high level the thermal stresses in the component, must be considered. Hence, the need for integral concepts for material characterization and selection from a multitude of existing and soon-to-be developed cast iron materials is discussed.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bürgel, R., “Handbook high temperature materials engineering” (in German), 3rd edition, Vieweg &amp; Sohn Verlag, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seifert, T. and Riedel, H., “Mechanism-based thermomechanical fatigue life prediction of cast iron. Part I: Models“, International Journal of Fatigue 32, 2010, 1358-1367, doi:10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2010.02.004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seifert, T., Maier, G., Uihlein, A., Lang, K.-H. and Riedel, H., “Mechanism-based thermomechanical fatigue life prediction of cast iron. Part II: Comparison of model predictions with experiments”, International Journal of Fatigue 32, 2010, 1368-1377, doi:10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2010.02.005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schweizer, C., Seifert, T., Nieweg, B., von Hartrott, P. and Riedel, H., “Mechanisms and modelling of fatigue crack growth under combined low and high cycle fatigue loading”, International Journal of Fatigue 33, 2011, 194-202, doi:10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2010.08.008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Metzger, M., Nieweg, B., Schweizer, C. and Seifert, T., “Lifetime prediction of cast iron materials under combined Thermomechanical fatigue and high cycle fatigue loading using a mechanism-based model”, International Journal of Fatigue 53, 2013, 58-66, doi:10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2012.02.007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seifert, T., “A complex LCF test program for fast and cost-saving identification of material properties” (in German), in conference proceedings “Werkstoffprüfung 2006”, Borsutzki M., Geisler S. (Eds.), Bad Neuenahr, 2006, 409-414</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shih, C.F., “Tables of Hutchinson-Rice-Rosengren singular field quantities”, Tech. rep. Brown University Report MRL E-147, 1983</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newman, J.C., “A crack opening stress equation for fatigue crack growth”, International Journal of Fracture 24, 1984, 131-135, doi:10.1007/BF00020751</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schweizer, C., “Physics-based models for fatigue crack growth and fatigue life under thermal and mechanical loadings” (in German), Phdthesis, Karlsruhe Institute for Technology (KIT), 2013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label> 
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Metzger, M., “Microstructure- and mechanism-based models for the description of deformation and lifetime of thermomechanically loaded cast iron components” (in German), Phd-thesis, Karlsruhe Institute for Technology (KIT), 2016</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
