<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277625</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Optical Investigation of the Reduction of Unburned Hydrocarbons Using Close-Coupled Post Injections at LTC Conditions in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>O'Connor</surname>
                  <given-names>Jacqueline</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Musculus</surname>
                  <given-names>Mark</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>379</fpage>
         <lpage>399</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277625"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Partially premixed low-temperature combustion (LTC) using exhaust-gas recirculation (EGR) has the potential to reduce engine-out NOₓ and soot emissions, but increased unburned hydrocarbon (UHC) emissions need to be addressed. In this study, we investigate close-coupled post injections for reducing UHC emissions. By injecting small amounts of fuel soon after the end of the main injection, fuel-lean mixtures near the injector that suffer incomplete combustion can be enriched with post-injection fuel and burned to completion. The goal of this work is to understand the in-cylinder mechanisms affecting the post-injection efficacy and to quantify its sensitivity to operational parameters including post-injection duration, injection dwell, load, and ignition delay time of the post-injection mixture. Three optical diagnostics - planar laser induced fluorescence of OH radicals, planar laser induced fluorescence of formaldehyde, and high-speed imaging of natural combustion luminescence - complement measurements of engine-out UHC with parametric variations of main- and post-injection timing and duration. Across all conditions tested, each at 1200 RPM, the optimal post-injection command duration for UHC reduction was approximately 400 microseconds (2.9 °CA). Also, conditions with shorter (3.4 °CA) post-injection ignition delays were over twice as effective on a percentage basis at reducing engine-out UHC as those with longer (5.5 °CA) post-injection ignition delays. Optical data at the post-injection “sweet-spot,” where UHC emissions are minimized, indicate that the post injection promotes transition to second-stage ignition in the near-injector region, most likely by enriching the overly fuel-lean mixtures in the wake of the main injection.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alriksson, M., Rente, T., and Denbratt, I., “Low Soot, Low NOx in a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Using High Levels of EGR,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3836, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tree D R and Svensson K I, “Soot processes in compression ignition engines” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 33(3):272-309 (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Keeler, B. and Shayler, P., “Constraints on Fuel Injection and EGR Strategies for Diesel PCCI-Type Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1327, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1327.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hardy, W. and Reitz, R., “A Study of the Effects of High EGR, High Equivalence Ratio, and Mixing Time on Emissions Levels in a Heavy- Duty Diesel Engine for PCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0026, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kanda, T., Hakozaki, T., Uchimoto, T., Hatano, J. et al., “PCCI Operation with Fuel Injection Timing Set Close to TDC,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0920, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0920.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus M P B, Miles P C, Pickett L M, “Conceptual models for partially premixed low-temperature diesel combustion” Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. (in press) (2012)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S. et al., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Kitahara, Y., and Aiyoshizawa, E., “Ultra-Clean Combustion Technology Combining a Low-Temperature and Premixed Combustion Concept for Meeting Future Emission Standards,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0200, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0200.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Ojeda, W., Zoldak, P., Espinosa, R., and Kumar, R., “Development of a Fuel Injection Strategy for Diesel LTC,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0057, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han M, Assanis D N, Bohac S V, “Sources of hydrocarbon emissions from low-temperature premixed compression ignition combustion from a common rail direct injection diesel engine” Combust. Sci. Technol. 181(3):496-517 (2009)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lachaux T and Musculus M P B, “In-cylinder unburned hydrocarbon visualization during low-temperature compression-ignition engine combustion using formaldehyde PLIF” Proc. Combust. Inst. 31(2): 2921-2929 (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., Lachaux, T., Pickett, L., and Idicheria, C., “End-of- Injection Over-Mixing and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emissions in Low- Temperature-Combustion Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0907, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-0907.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Ekoto, I., Colban, W., and Miles, P., “In-cylinder CO and UHC Imaging in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine during PPCI Low-Temperature Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):933-956, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1602.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koci, C., Ra, Y., Krieger, R., Andrie, M. et al., “Detailed Unburned Hydrocarbon Investigations in a Highly-Dilute Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Regime,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):858-879, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0928.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Persson, H., Johansson, B., Collin, R. et al., “Optical Diagnostics of HCCI and Low-Temperature Diesel Using Simultaneous 2-D PLIF of OH and Formaldehyde,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2949, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-2949.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chartier, C., Andersson, O., Johansson, B., Musculus, M. et al., “Effects of Post-Injection Strategies on Near-Injector Over-Lean Mixtures and Unburned Hydrocarbon Emission in a Heavy-Duty Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):1978-1992, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bobba, M., Genzale, C., and Musculus, M., “Effect of Ignition Delay on In-Cylinder Soot Characteristics of a Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Operating at Low Temperature Conditions,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 911-924, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0946.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Espey, C. and Dec, J., “Diesel Engine Combustion Studies in a Newly Designed Optical-Access Engine Using High-Speed Visualization and 2-D Laser Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 930971, 1993, doi: 10.4271/930971.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J., “A Conceptual Model of DI Diesel Combustion Based on Laser- Sheet Imaging,” SAE Technical Paper 970873, 1997, doi: 10.4271/970873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murphy M J, Taylor J D, McCormick R L, “Compendium of Experimental Cetane Number Data” N.R.E. Laboratory NREL/SR-540-36805. (2004)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood J B, Internal combustion engine fundamentals, McGraw-Hill, New York, NY (1988)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
