<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275480</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Water Cooled Exhaust Manifold and Full Load EGR Technology Applied to a Downsized Direct Injection Spark Ignition Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Taylor</surname>
                  <given-names>James</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Mahle Powertrain Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fraser</surname>
                  <given-names>Neil</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Mahle Powertrain Ltd.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wieske</surname>
                  <given-names>Peter</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Mahle International GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>225</fpage>
         <lpage>240</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275480"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Gasoline engine downsizing is one of the main technologies being used to reduce automotive fleet CO ₂ emissions. However, the shift in operating point to higher loads which goes with aggressive downsizing means that real world fuel economy can be affected by the amount of over-fuelling required to maintain exhaust gas temperatures within acceptable limits. In addition there is a drive to lower the exhaust gas temperature limit in order to reduce the material costs required for high temperature operation.</p>
            <p>A water-cooled exhaust manifold is one technology, which can be used to minimize the over-fuelling region. This paper investigates the effects of this technology applied to a twin-charger 1.4-litre gasoline direct injection engine. Data is presented which quantifies the benefits in conjunction with other downsizing technologies including cooled EGR and variable geometry turbochargers. The thermal and combustion phasing benefits are found to provide significant advantages over a wide operating region on this highly boosted engine. The downside of the approach is the requirement for increased heat rejection from the coolant and this is also quantified.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Louis, J.J.J., “Well-To-Wheel Energy Use and Greenhouse Gas Emissions for Various Vehicle Technologies,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1343, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ito, N., Ohta, T., Kono, R., Arikawa, S. et al., “Development of a 4-Cylinder Gasoline Engine with a Variable Flow Turbo-charger,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0263, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A., Blaxill, H., and Irlam, G., “Exhaust Gas Recirculation for Improved Part and Full Load Fuel Economy in a Turbocharged Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0047, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns, A., Fraser, N., and Blaxill, H., “Pre Versus Post Compressor Supply of Cooled EGR for Full Load Fuel Economy in Turbocharged Gasoline Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0425, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borrmann D, Kuhlbach K, Friedfeldt R, Mehring J, Fritsche R: “Cylinder Head Integrated Exhaust Manifold IEM Applied to Gasoline Downsizing Concepts”, 17th Aachen Motorenkolloquium (2008)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuhlbach K, Mehring J, Borrmann D, Friedfeldt R: “Cylinder Head with Integrated Exhaust Manifold for Downsizing Concepts”, MTZ 04\2009 Volume 70</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kapus P, Guenter F, Prevedel K and Fuerhapter A: “GDI Turbo - The Next Steps” JSAE Paper 398-20075355 (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraidl G, Kapus P, Prevedel K, Fürhapter A: “GDI Turbo: The next Steps”, Vienna Symposium 2007 (2007)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grandin, B. and Ångström H:-E., “Replacing Fuel Enrichment in a Turbo Charged SI Engine: Lean Burn or Cooled EGR,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3505, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroshi M, Makoto K, Yuichi O, Tetsunori S, Shinji K: “The Potential of Lean Boost Combustion” JSAE F2004V219</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stokes, J., Lake, T.H., and Osborne, R.J., “A Gasoline Engine Concept for Improved Fuel Economy -The Lean Boost System,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-2902, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lake, T., Stokes, J., Murphy, R., Osborne, R. et al., “Turbocharging Concepts for Downsized DI Gasoline Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0036, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Turner, J.W.G., Pearson, R.J., Curtis, R. and Holland, B., “Improving Fuel Economy in a Turbocharged DISI Engine Already Employing Integrated Exhaust Manifold Technology and Variable Valve Timing,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2449, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cairns A, Fraser N, Blaxill H: “EGR Boosted Direct Injection Gasoline Engines” Advanced direct injection combustion engine technologies and development Volume 1: Gasoline and gas engines (2009). Woodhead Pulishing Ltd, Cambridge, ISBN 978-1-84569-389-3</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Steiner A, Hofstetter M, Kerkau M, Beer M, Ronneburger R, Knirsch S: “Die variable Turbinengeometrie für die ottomotorische Anwendung beim neuen 3,6 l Biturbo - Motor des Porsche 911 Turbo”, Aufladetechnische Konferenz (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gabriel H, Lingenaube R, Ramb T: “Der Turbolader mit variabler Turbinengeometrie (VTG) für den neuen Porsche 911 Turbo - Ein Meilenstein in der Ottomotorenaufladung”, Aufladetechnische Konferenz (2006)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Andersen, J., Karlsson, E., and Gawell, A. “Variable Turbine Geometry on SI Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0020, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">London Metal Exchange. www.lme.com (September 2009)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Coltman, D., Turner, J.W.G., Curtis, R., Blake, D. et al., “Project Sabre: A Close-Spaced Direct Injection 3-Cylinder Engine with Synergistic Technologies to Achieve Low CO2Output,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):129-146, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lake T, Stokes J, Osborne R, Murphy R, Keenan M: “The lean boost combustion system for improved fuel economy”, Advanced direct Injection combustion engine technologies and development Volume 1: Gasoline and gas engines (2009)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wieske P, Lüddecke B, Ewert S, Elsäßer A, Hoffman H, Rückauf J, Taylor J, Fraser N: “New Concepts for Optimising Transient Torque Response and Fuel Economy of Turbocharged Gasoline Engines”, 18th Aachen Motorenkolloquium (2009)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
