<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">calicojournal</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50011907</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>CALICO Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Equinox Publishing Ltd.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">07427778</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">20569017</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">90014697</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Article</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>New CALL-SLA Research Interfaces for the 21st Century</article-title>
            <subtitle>Towards Equitable Multilingualism</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Ortega</surname>
                  <given-names>Lourdes</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Department of Linguistics, Georgetown University, Washington, DC.</aff>
               <bio>
                  <p>Lourdes Ortega is Professor in the Department of Linguistics at Georgetown University. She studies second language acquisition in adult classroom settings from usage-based, bilingual, and educational perspectives. Her publications include Understanding Second Language Acquisition (2009, Routledge), Technology-mediated TBLT (2014, John Benjamins), and The Usage-based Study of Language Learning and Multilingualism (2016, Georgetown University Press).</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2017</year>
            <string-date>2017</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>34</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e90014695</issue-id>
         <fpage>283</fpage>
         <lpage>316</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>©2017, EQUINOX PUBLISHING</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/90014697"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>Abstract</label>
            <p>The majority of the world is multilingual, but inequitably multilingual, and much of the world is also technologized, but inequitably so. Thus, researchers in the fields of computer-assisted language learning (CALL) and second language acquisition (SLA) would profit from considering multilingualism and social justice when envisioning new CALL-SLA interfaces for the future. I first explain the connection I see among multilingualism, digital literacy, and social justice, and I characterize contemporary SLA as transformed by a social turn that is now complete, a bilingual turn slowly underway, and a social justice turn emerging on the horizon. I then review empirical evidence that suggests digital communication encourages multilingual practices, helps users appreciate the open nature of language resources, and perhaps even supports positive multilingual ideologies. Next I offer some illustrations of possible new research questions and CALL-SLA studies that would focus on embracing and exploiting the openness of language resources in language learning, and on doing multilingual learning. Finally, I examine what we know about the digital divide that is relevant to CALL-SLA researchers. I close with a checklist for researchers interested in contributing to these new research interfaces in support of equitable multilingualism in online and offline language learning and teaching.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Keywords:</label>
            <kwd>CALL</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>SLA</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>multilingualism</kwd>
            <x>, </x>
            <kwd>social justice</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akiyama, Y., &amp; Cunningham, J. D. (forthcoming). Synthesizing the practice of SCMCbased telecollaboration: A scoping review. CALICO Journal.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Albirini, A. (2016). Chapter 8: Digital media and language use. In A. Albarini, Modern Arabic sociolinguistics: Diglossia, variation, codeswitching, attitudes, and identity (pp. 258–295). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">American Councils for International Education. (2017). The National K–12 Foreign Language Enrollment Survey, 2017. American Councils for International Education American Councils for International Education, American Council for the Teaching of Foreign Languages, &amp; Center for Applied Linguistics. Retrieved from: https://www.americancouncils.org/content/national-k-16-foreign-language-enrollment-survey-report</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Anderson, J. A. E., Mak, L., Chahi, A. K., &amp; Bialystok, E. (2017). The language and social background questionnaire: Assessing degree of bilingualism in a diverse population. Behavior Research Methods. https://doi.org/10.3758/s13428-017-0867-9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Androutsopoulos, J. (2015). Networked multilingualism: Some language practices on Facebook and their implications. International Journal of Bilingualism, 19(2), 185–205. https://doi.org/10.1177/1367006913489198</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, D. (Ed.) (2011). Alternative approaches to second language acquisition. New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bedford, R., Saez de Urabain, I. R., Cheung, C. H., Karmiloff-Smith, A., &amp; Smith, T. J. (2016). Toddlers’ fine motor milestone achievement is associated with early touchscreen scrolling. Frontiers in Psychology, 7, art. 1108. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.01108</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bianchi, R. (2015). 3arabizi, Greeklish, and SMSki: The hybrid making of language in the age of the internet and mobile technology. Tasmeem, 1, 1–4. https://doi.org/10.5339/tasmeem.2015.1 Retrieved from: http://www.qscience.com/doi/abs/10.5339/tasmeem.2015.1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bigelow, M., &amp; Tarone, E. (2004). The role of literacy level in second language acquisition: Doesn’t who we study determine what we know? TESOL Quarterly, 38(4), 689–700. https://doi.org/10.2307/3588285</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Block, D. (2003). The social turn in second language acquisition. Washington, DC: Georgetown University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blyth, C. (1995). Redefining the boundaries of language use: The foreign language classroom as a multilingual speech community. In C. Kramsch (Ed.), Redefining the boundaries of foreign language (pp. 145–182). Boston: Heinle &amp; Heinle.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blyth, C., &amp; Dalola, A. (2016). Translingualism as an open educational language practice: Raising critical language awareness on Facebook. Alsic, 19(1). https://doi.org/10.4000/alsic.2962 Retrieved from: http://alsic.revues.org/2962</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Briggs, C., &amp; Makice, K. (2011). Digital fluency: Building success in the digital age. Retrieved from: http://www.socialens.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/downloads/2012/01/SociaLens_ Digital_Fluency_Sample1.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brotcorne, P., Damhuis, L., Laurent, V., Valenduc, G., &amp; Vendramin, P. (2010). The second order digital divide: Synthesis of the research report. Fondation Travail-Université (Namur). Retrieved from: http://www.ftu-namur.org/fichiers/FTU-Second_order_digital_divide-Synthesis.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buendgens-Kosten, J. (2014). The effects and functions of speaker status in CALL-oriented communities. In S. Jager, L. Bradley, E. J. Meima, &amp; S. Thouësny (Eds.), CALL design: Principles and practice. Proceedings of the 2014 EUROCALL Conference, Groningen, The Netherlands (pp. 29–34). Dublin: Researchpublishing.net. https://doi.org/10.14705/rpnet.2014.000190</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caws, C., &amp; Hamel, M.-J. (Eds.). (2016). Language-learner computer interactions: Theory, methodology and CALL applications. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cenoz, J. (2013). Defining multilingualism. Annual Review of Applied Linguistics, 33, 3–18. https://doi.org/10.1017/S026719051300007X</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapelle, C. A. (1997). CALL in the year 2000: Still in search of research paradigms? Language Learning &amp; Technology, 1(1), 19–43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapelle, C. A. (2007). Technology and second language acquisition. Annual Review of Applied Linguistics, 27, 98–114. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0267190508070050</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chapelle, C. A. (2016). CALL in the year 2000: Looking back from 2016. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 20(2), 159–161. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/issues/june2016/chapelle.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chen, M. H., Tseng, W. T., &amp; Hsiao, T. Y. (2016). The effectiveness of digital game‐based vocabulary learning: A framework‐based view of meta‐analysis. British Journal of Educational Technology. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjet.12526</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chun, D. M. (2016). The role of technology in SLA research. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 20(2), 98–115. Retrieved from http://llt.msu.edu/issues/june2016/chun.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chun, D., Kern, R., &amp; Smith, B. (2016). Technology in language use, language teaching, and language learning. Modern Language Journal, 100(S1), 64–80. https://doi.org/10.1111/modl.12302</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cook, V. J. (1992). Evidence for multicompetence. Language Learning, 42(4), 557–591. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-1770.1992.tb01044.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Courtois, C., &amp; Verdegem, P. (2016). With a little help from my friends: An analysis of the role of social support in digital inequalities. New Media &amp; Society, 18(8), 1508–1527. https://doi.org/10.1177/1461444814562162</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">de Costa, P. I. (Ed.) (2016). Ethics in applied linguistics. New York: Routledge. De Houwer, A. (2015). Harmonious bilingual development: Young families’ well-being in language contact situations. International Journal of Bilingualism, 19(2), 169–184. https://doi.org/10.1177/1367006913489202</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Devlin, K. (July 13, 2015). Learning a foreign language a ‘must’ in Europe, not so in America. Pew Research Center. Retrieved from: http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2015/07/13/learning-a-foreign-language-a-must-in-europe-not-so-in-america/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dooly, M. (2011). Divergent perceptions of telecollaborative language learning tasks: Taskas-workplan vs. task-as-process. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 15(2), 69–91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ellis, E. (2013). The ESL teacher as plurilingual: An Australian perspective. TESOL Quarterly, 47(3), 446–471. https://doi.org/10.1002/tesq.120</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Festman, J., Poarch, G. J., &amp; Dewaele, J.-M. (2017). Raising multilingual children. Bristol: Multilingual Matters.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Firth, A., &amp; Wagner, J. (1997). On discourse, communication, and (some) fundamental concepts in SLA research. Modern Language Journal, 81(3), 285–300. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.1997.tb05480.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Galla, C. K. (2016). Indigenous language revitalization, promotion, and education: Function of digital technology. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 29(7), 1137–1151. https:// doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2016.1166137</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">García, O., &amp; Li Wei (2014). Translanguaging: Language, bilingualism and education. Basingstoke: Palgrave Macmillan.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gonzales, A. L. (2015). The contemporary US digital divide: From initial access to technology maintenance. Information, Communication &amp; Society, 19(2), 234–248. https://doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2015.1050438</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gonzales, A. L. (2017). Disadvantaged minorities’ use of the Internet to expand their social networks. Communication Research, 44(4), 467–486. https://doi.org/10.1177/0093650214565925</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">González-Lloret, M. (2014). The need for needs analysis in technology-mediated TBLT. In M. González-Lloret &amp; L. Ortega (Eds.), Technology-mediated TBLT: Researching technology and tasks (pp. 23–50). Amsterdam: John Benjamins.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gonzalez, C., &amp; Katz, V. S. (2016). Transnational family communication as a driver of technology adoption. International Journal of Communication, 10, 2683–2703. Retrieved from: http://ijoc.org/index.php/ijoc/article/view/5321</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Han, H. (2013). Individual grassroots multilingualism in Africa Town in Guangzhou: The role of states in globalization. International Multilingual Research Journal, 7(1), 83–97. https://doi.org/10.1080/19313152.2013.746803</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hargittai, E. (2010). Digital na(t)ives? Variation in Internet skills and uses among members of the “Net Generation”. Sociological Inquiry, 80(1), 92–113. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1475-682X.2009.00317.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harney, N. (2013). Precarity, affect and problem solving with mobile phones by asylum seekers, refugees and migrants in Naples, Italy. Journal of Refugee Studies, 26(4), 541–557. https://doi.org/10.1093/jrs/fet017</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harrington, M., &amp; Levy, M. (2001). CALL begins with a “C”: Interaction in computer-mediated language learning. System, 29(1), 15–26. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0346-251X(00)00043-9</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harris, K. (2015). Integrating digital literacy into English language instruction: Issue brief. Washington, DC: Literacy and Information Communication Systems ESL Pro Issue Brief of the American Institutes for Research. Retrieved from: https://lincs.ed.gov/sites/default/files/ELL_Digital_Literacy_508.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hazan, J. (May 30, 2016). Don’t read this article si t’es pas bilingue: Le world’s premier-ever de son kind. MTL Blog. Retrieved from: https://www.mtlblog.com/lifestyle/dont-readthis-article-si-tes-pas-bilingue</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helm, F. (2015). The practices and challenges of telecollaboration in higher education in Europe. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 19(2), 197–217.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Helsper, E. (2011). The emergence of a digital underclass: Digital policies in the UK and evidence for inclusion. London: Department of Media and Communications, London School of Economics and Political Science. Retrieved from: http://eprints.lse.ac.uk/38615/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hilbert, M. (2016). The bad news is that the digital access divide is here to stay: Domestically installed bandwidths among 172 countries for 1986–2014. Telecommunications Policy, 40(6), 567–581. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.telpol.2016.01.006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horst, H. A., &amp; Taylor, E. B. (2014). The role of mobile phones in the mediation of border crossings: A study of Haiti and the Dominican Republic. Australian Journal of Anthropology, 25, 155–170. https://doi.org/10.1111/taja.12086</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hua, Z., &amp; Kramsch, C. (2016). Symbolic power and conversational inequality in intercultural communication: An introduction. Applied Linguistics Review, 7(4), 375–383. https://doi.org/10.1515/applirev-2016-0016</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubbard, P. (2008). Twenty-five years of theory in the CALICO Journal. CALICO Journal, 25(3), 387–399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hubbard, P., &amp; Levy, M. (2016). Theory in computer-assisted language learning research and practice. In F. Farr &amp; L. Murray (Eds.), The Routledge handbook of language learning and technology (pp. 24–38). London: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hulstijn, J. H., Young, R. F., Ortega, L., Bigelow, M., DeKeyser, R., Ellis, N. C., Lantolf, J.P., Mackey, A., &amp; Talmy, S. (2014). Bridging the Gap: Cognitive and social approaches to research in second language learning and teaching. Studies in Second Language Acquisition, 36(3), 361–421. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0272263114000035</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hult, F. M. (2014). Covert bilingualism and symbolic competence: Analytical reflections on negotiating insider/outsider positionality in Swedish speech situations. Applied Linguistics, 35(1), 63–81. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/amt003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Internet World Stats. (2017). Usage and population statistics. http://www.internetworldstats.com/stats.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jarvis, S., &amp; Pavlenko, A. (2008). Crosslinguistic influence in language and cognition. New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jenkins, H., with Purushotma, R., Weigel, M., Clinton, K., &amp; Robison, A. J. (2009). Confronting the challenges of participatory culture: Media education for the 21st century. Cambridge, MA: The MIT Press. Retrieved from: https://www.macfound.org/media/article_pdfs/JENKINS_WHITE_PAPER.PDF</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ke, I. C., &amp; Cahyani, H. (2014). Learning to become users of English as a Lingua Franca (ELF): How ELF online communication affects Taiwanese learners’ beliefs of English. System, 46, 28–38. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2014.07.008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kroll, J. F., Bobb, S. C., &amp; Hoshino, N. (2014). Two languages in mind: Bilingualism as a tool to investigate language, cognition, and the brain. Current Directions in Psychological Science, 23(3), 159–163. https://doi.org/10.1177/0963721414528511</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kusyk, M. (2017). The development of complexity, accuracy and fluency in L2 written production through informal participation in online activities. CALICO Journal, 34(1), 75–96. https://doi.org/10.1558/cj.29513</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, C. (2016). Multilingual resources and practices in digital communication. In A. Georgakopoulou &amp; T. Spilioti (Eds.), The Routledge handbook of language and digital communication (pp. 118–132). London: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leppänen, S., &amp; Peuronen, S. (2012). Multilingualism and the internet. In M. Martin-Jones, A. Blackledge, &amp; A. Creese (Eds.), The Routledge handbook of multilingualism (pp. 384–402). London: Routledge. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781405198431.wbeal0805</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levy, M. (1997). Computer-assisted language learning: Context and conceptualisation. Oxford: Clarendon Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levy, M. (2000). Scope, goals and methods in CALL research: Questions of coherence and autonomy. ReCALL, 12(2), 170–195. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0958344000000525</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levy, M., &amp; Stockwell, G. (2006). CALL Dimensions: Options and issues in computer-assisted language learning. Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li Wei. (2017). Translanguaging TESOL. TED Talk presented at the TESOL World Summit on the Future of the TESOL Profession. Athens, Greece, 7–9 February. Recording available at: http://www.tesol.org/summit-2017/themes/english-in-multiculturalism-recordedsessions</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lissitsa, S., &amp; Chachashvili-Bolotin, S. (2014). Use of the Internet in capital enhancing ways—Ethnic differences in Israel and the role of language proficiency. International Journal of Internet Science, 9(1), 9–30.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lo Bianco, J. (2017). Multilingualism in education: Equity and social cohesion: Considerations for TESOL. Report on the World Summit on the Future of the TESOL Profession, Athens, Greece, 7–11 February 2017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">MacSwan, J. (2017). A multilingual perspective on translanguaging. American Educational Research Journal, 54(1), 167–201. https://doi.org/10.3102/0002831216683935</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marsh, J. (2016). The digital literacy skills and competences of children of pre-school age. Media Education, 7(2), 197–214. https://doi.org/10.14605/MED721603</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Marwick, A. E., &amp; boyd, d. (2011). I tweet honestly, I tweet passionately: Twitter users, context collapse, and the imagined audience. New Media &amp; Society, 13(1), 114–133. https://doi.org/10.1177/1461444810365313</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newell, B. C., Gomez, R., &amp; Guajardo, V. E. (2016). Information seeking, technology use, and vulnerability among migrants at the United States–Mexico border. The Information Society, 32(3), 176–191. https://doi.org/10.1080/01972243.2016.1153013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ochs, E. (2012). Experiencing language. Anthropological Theory, 12, 142–160. https://doi.org/10.1177/1463499612454088</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortega, L. (2005). For what and for whom is our research? The ethical as transformative lens in instructed SLA. Modern Language Journal, 89(3), 427–443. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-4781.2005.00315.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortega, L. (2009). Understanding second language acquisition. New York: Routledge. Ortega, L. (2012). Epistemological diversity and moral ends of research in instructed SLA. Language Teaching Research, 16(2), 206–226. https://doi.org/10.1177/0267658311431373</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortega, L. (2013). SLA for the 21st century: Disciplinary progress, transdisciplinary relevance, and the bi/multilingual turn. Language Learning, 63(s1), 1–24. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9922.2012.00735.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortega, L. (2014). Ways forward for a bi/multilingual turn in SLA. In S. May (Ed.), The multilingual turn: Implications for SLA, TESOL, and bilingual education (pp. 32–53). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortega, L. (2016). Multi-competence in second language acquisition: Inroads into the mainstream? In V. Cook &amp; Li Wei (Eds.), The Cambridge handbook of linguistic multicompetence (pp. 50–76). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781107425965.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortega, L., &amp; Zyzik, E. (2008). Online interactions and L2 learning: Some ethical challenges for L2 researchers. In S. Magnan (Ed.), Mediating discourse online (pp. 331–355). Amsterdam: John Benjamins. https://doi.org/10.1075/aals.3.19ort</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pavlenko, A., &amp; Lantolf, J. P. (2000). Second language learning as participation and the (re) construction of selves. In J. P. Lantolf (Ed.), Sociocultural theory and second language learning (pp. 155–177). Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piantadosi, S. T., Tily, H., &amp; Gibson, E. (2012). The communicative function of ambiguity in language. Cognition, 122, 280–291. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2011.10.004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Piller, I. (2016). Linguistic diversity and social justice: An introduction to applied sociolinguistics. New York: Oxford University Press. https://doi.org/10.1093/acprof:oso/9780199937240.001.0001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Plonksy, L., &amp; Ziegler, N. (2016). The CALL-SLA interface: Insights from a second-order synthesis. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 20(2), 17–37. http://llt.msu.edu/issues/june2016/plonskyziegler.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pomerantz, A. (2010). Speaking Spanish outside the foreign language classroom: An analysis of learner narratives. Critical Inquiry in Language Studies, 7(1), 1–27. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15427580903523565</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Porto, M., Houghton, S. A., &amp; Byram, M. (2017). Intercultural citizenship in the (foreign) language classroom. Language Teaching Research. https://doi.org/10.1177/1362168817718580</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reershemius, G. (2017). Autochthonous heritage languages and social media: Writing and bilingual practices in Low German on Facebook. Journal of Multilingual and Multicultural Development, 38(1), 35–49. https://doi.org/10.1080/01434632.2016.1151434</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ritzhaupt, A. D., Liu, F., Dawson, K., &amp; Barron, A. E. (2013). Differences in student information and communication technology literacy based on socio-economic status, ethnicity, and gender: Evidence of a digital divide in Florida schools. Journal of Research on Technology in Education, 45(4), 291–307. https://doi.org/10.1080/15391523.2013.10782607</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Salaberry, R. (1999). CALL in the year 2000: Still developing the research agenda. Language Learning &amp; Technology, 3(1), 104–107.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauro, S. (2017). Online fan practices and CALL. CALICO Journal, 34(2), 131–146. https://doi.org/10.1558/cj.33077</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref88">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulze, M., &amp; Smith, B. (2015). Editorial: In theory—We could be better. CALICO Journal, 32(1), i–vi. doi: 10.1558/calico.v32i1.26142</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref89">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schulze, M., &amp; Smith, B. (2016). The first L of CALL—Language. CALICO Journal, 33(3), i–iii. https://doi.org/10.1558/cj.v33i3.31602</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref90">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Simons, G. F., &amp; Fennig, C. D. (Eds.). (2017). Ethnologue: Languages of the world (20th ed.). Dallas, TX: SIL International.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref91">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Slabakova, R. (2016). Second language acquisition. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref92">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sockett, G. (2014). The online informal learning of English. New York: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1057/9781137414885</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref93">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sterling, S., Winke, P., &amp; Gass, S. (2016). Training in research ethics among applied linguistics and SLA researchers. In P. I. de Costa (Ed.), Ethics in applied linguistics research: Language researcher narratives (pp. 15–37). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref94">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stier, S. (2017). Internet diffusion and regime type: Temporal patterns in technology adoption. Telecommunications Policy, 41(1), 25–34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.telpol.2016.10.005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref95">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sundqvist, P., &amp; Sylvén, L. K. (2016). Extramural English in teaching and learning: From theory and research to practice. New York: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1057/978-1-137-46048-6</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref96">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sylvén, L. K., &amp; Sundqvist, P. (Eds.). (2017). Special issue: Computer-assisted language learning (CALL) in extracurricular/extramural contexts. CALICO Journal, 34(1).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref97">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Douglas Fir Group (2016). A transdisciplinary framework for SLA in a multilingual world. Modern Language Journal, 100 (Supplement 1, Centenary Anniversary), 19–47. https://doi.org/10.1111/modl.12301</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref98">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thomas, M. (2009). Review article: Ethical issues in the study of second language acquisition: Resources for researchers. Second Language Research, 25(4), 493–511. https://doi.org/10.1177/0267658309349676</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref99">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., Sauro, S., &amp; Smith, B. (2015). Technologies, identities, and expressive activity. Annual Review of Applied Linguistics, 35, 215–233. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0267190514000257</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref100">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thorne, S. L., &amp; Smith, B. (2011). Second language development theories and technologymediated language learning. CALICO Journal, 28(2), 268–277. https://doi.org/10.11139/cj.28.2.268-277</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref101">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tudini, V. (2016). Repair and codeswitching for learning in online intercultural talk. System, 62, 15–25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.system.2016.06.011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref102">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">UNESCO. (2016). UNESCO 2015. Retrieved from: http://unesdoc.unesco.org/images/0024/002448/244834e.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref103">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vahedi, V. S., Ghonsooly, B., &amp; Pishghadam, R. (2016). Vocabulary glossing: A metaanalysis of the relative effectiveness of different gloss types on L2 vocabulary acquisition. Teaching English with Technology, 16(1), 3–25. Retrieved from: http://www.tewtjournal.org</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref104">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Compernolle, R. A. (2016). Are multilingualism, tolerance of ambiguity, and attitudes toward linguistic variation related? International Journal of Multilingualism, 13(1), 61–73. https://doi.org/10.1080/14790718.2015.1071821</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref105">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">VanPatten, B., &amp; Williams, J. (Eds.). (2015). Theories in second language acquisition (2nd ed.). New York: Routledge.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref106">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Verboord, M. (2017). Internet usage and cosmopolitanism in Europe: A multilevel analysis. Information, Communication &amp; Society, 20(3), 460–481. https://doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2016.1187193</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref107">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wall, M., Otis Campbell, M., &amp; Janbek, D. (2015). Syrian refugees and information precarity. New Media &amp; Society, 19(2), 240–254. https://doi.org/10.1177/1461444815591967</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref108">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Warschauer, M., Knobel, M., &amp; Stone, L. (2004). Technology and equity in schooling: Deconstructing the digital divide. Educational Policy, 18(4), 562–588. https://doi.org/10.1177/0895904804266469</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref109">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">World Economic Forum. (2017). The global risks report, 2017 (12th ed.). Geneva: World Economic Forum. Retrieved from: http://www3.weforum.org/docs/GRR17_Report_web.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref110">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young-Scholten, M. (2013). Low-educated immigrants and the social relevance of second language acquisition research. Second Language Research, 29(4), 441–454. https://doi.org/10.1177/0267658313491266</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref111">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young-Scholten, M. (2015). Who are adolescents and adults who develop literacy for the first time in an L2, and why are they of research interest? Writing Systems Research, 7(1), 1–3. https://doi.org/10.1080/17586801.2015.998443</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref112">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zillien, N., &amp; Hargittai, E. (2009). Digital distinction: Status-specific types of Internet usage. Social Science Quarterly, 90(2), 274–291. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-6237.2009.00617.x</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
