<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277973</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Ignition Quality Effects on Lift-Off Stabilization of Synthetic Fuels</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lequien</surname>
                  <given-names>Guillaume</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Skeen</surname>
                  <given-names>Scott</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Manin</surname>
                  <given-names>Julien</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pickett</surname>
                  <given-names>Lyle M</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Sandia National Laboratories</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Andersson</surname>
                  <given-names>Oivind</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Lund Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>April 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277951</issue-id>
         <fpage>625</fpage>
         <lpage>634</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277973"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The ignition and flame stabilization characteristics of two synthetic fuels, having significantly different cetane numbers, are investigated in a constant volume combustion vessel over a range of ambient conditions representative of a compression ignition engine operating at variable loads. The synthetic fuel with a cetane number of 63 (S-1) is characterized by ignition delays that are only moderately longer than n-dodecane (cetane number of 87) over a range of ambient conditions. By comparison, the synthetic fuel with a cetane number of 17 (S-2) requires temperatures approximately 300 K higher to achieve the same ignition delays. The much different ignition characteristics and operating temperature range present a scenario where the lift-off stabilization may be substantially different. At temperatures below 1000 K, the S-2 fuel undergoes a long transient stabilization phase during which the lift-off location moves as much as 15 mm upstream (i.e., toward the injector orifice) after the ignition of the first flame kernel. This behavior is much different than S-1, n-dodecane, or with conventional diesel, in which past research shows that the lift-off location stabilizes very close to the ignition location shortly after the premixed burn. The longer ignition delays for S-2 frequently result in fuel-lean mixtures at the ignition location where the spray becomes over-mixed (i.e., too fuel-lean) and the high-temperature ignition event is noticeably less robust (i.e., smaller and less intense ignition kernels) as observed by high-speed chemiluminescence imaging. High-speed chemiluminescence imaging and pressure measurements show strong evidence of cool-flame (i.e., first-stage or low-temperature) reactions prior to high-temperature ignition for S-1 while they are less evident for S-2.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NATO Logistics Handbook, “Senior NATO Logisticians' Conference Secretariat NATO Headquarters Brussels,” http://www.nato.int/docu/logi-en/1997/lo-1511.htm, Third Edition, October 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, D., Martz, J. and Violi, A., “A surrogate for emulating the physical and chemical properties of conventional jet fuel,” Combustion and Flame 161 (6):1489-1498, June 2014, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2013.12.015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colket, M., Edwards, T., Williams, S., Cernansky, N.P. et al., “Development of an experimental database and kinetic models for surrogate jet fuels,” 45th AIAA Aerospace Sciences Meeting 14:9446- 9466, 2007, ISBN: 1563478900; 978-156347890-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Violi, A., Yan, S., Eddings, E.G., Sarofim, A.F. et al., “Experimental formulation and kinetic model for JP-8 surrogate mixture,” Combustion Science and Technology 174(11-12):399-417, 2002, doi:10.1080/00102200215080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dooley, S., Won, S.H., Chaos, M., Heyne, J. et al., “A jet fuel surrogate formulated by real fuel properties,” Combustion and Flame 157(12):2333-2339, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2010.07.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dooley, S., Won, S.H., Heyne, J., Farouk, T.L. et al., “The experimental evaluation of a methodology for surrogate fuel formulation to emulate gas phase combustion kinetic phenomena,” Combustion and Flame 159(4):1444-1466, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2011.11.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huber, M.L., Lemmon, E.W. and Bruno, T.J., “Surrogate mixture models for the thermophysical properties of aviation fuel Jet-A,” Energy and Fuels 24(6):3565-3571, 2010, doi:10.1021/ef100208c.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dryer, F.L., Jahangirian, S., Dooley, S., Won, S.H. et al., “Emulating the Combustion Behavior of Real Jet Aviation Fuels by Surrogate Mixtures of hydrocarbon Fluid Blends: Implications for Science and Engineering,” Energy and Fuels 28(5):3474-3485, 2014, doi:10.1021/ef500284x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gill, S.S., Tsolakis, A., Dearn, K.D. and Rodríguez-Fernández, J., “Combustion characteristics and emissions of Fischer-Tropsch diesel fuel in IC Engines,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 37(4):503-523, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2010.09.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Muzzell, P., Sattler, E., Terry, A., McKay, B. et al., “Properties of Fischer-Tropsch (FT) Blends for Use in Military Equipment,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0702, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gowdagiri, S., Cesari, X.M., Huang, M. and Oehlschlaeger, M.A., “A diesel engine study of conventional and alternative diesel and jet fuels: Ignition and emissions characteristics,” Fuel 136(15):253-260, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2014.07.056.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gokulakrishnan, P., Klassen, M.S. and Roby, R.J., “Ignition characteristics of a fischer-tropsch synthetic jet fuel,” Proceedings of the ASME Turbo Expo 3(PART B):921-929, 2008, doi:10.1115/GT2008- 51211.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schihl, P., Hoogterp-Decker, L., and Gingrich, E., “The Ignition Behavior of a Coal to Liquid Fischer-Tropsch Jet Fuel in a Military Relevant Single Cylinder Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):785-802, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1197.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., “Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi:10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., Siebers, D., and Aradi, A., “Diesel-Spray Ignition and Premixed-Burn Behavior,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0940, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-0940.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lillo, P., Pickett, L., Persson, H., Andersson, O. et al., “Diesel Spray Ignition Detection and Spatial/Temporal Correction,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):1330-1346, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network, http://www.sandia.gov/ecn</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manin, J., Bardi, M. and Pickett, L.M., “Evaluation of the liquid length via diffused back-illumination imaging in vaporizing diesel sprays,” Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Modeling and Diagnostics for Advanced Engine Systems, COMODIA:665-673, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D., “Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caton, P.A., Hamilton, L.J. and Cowart, J.S., “Understanding Ignition Delay Effects With Pure Component Fuels in a Single-Cylinder Diesel Engine,” Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 133(3):032803, 2011, doi:10.1115/1.4001943.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Murphy, M.J., Taylor, J.D., and McCormick, R.L., “Compendium of Experimental Cetane Number Data,” NREL/SR-540-36805, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bardi, M., Payri, R., Malbec, L.M., Bruneaux, G. et al., “Engine combustion network: Comparison of spray development, vaporization, and combustion in different combustion vessels,” Atomization and Sprays 22(10):807-842, 2012, doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2013005837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M. and Kattke, K., “Entrainment Waves in Diesel Jets,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1170-1193, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1355.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Manin, J., Genzale, C., Siebers, D. et al., “Relationship Between Diesel Fuel Spray Vapor Penetration/Dispersion and Local Fuel Mixture Fraction,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):764-799, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0686.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manin, J., Skeen, S., Pickett, L., Kurtz, E. et al., “Effects of Oxygenated Fuels on Combustion and Soot Formation/Oxidation Processes,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 7(3):704-717, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-2657.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria, C. and Pickett, L., “Formaldehyde Visualization Near Lift-off Location in a Diesel Jet,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3434, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-3434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and Siebers, D., “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004- 01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haynes, B.S. and Wagner, H.G., “Soot Formation,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science 7(4):229-273, 1981, doi:10.1016/0360-1285(81)90001-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
