<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278114</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Nanostructure Analysis of In-flame Soot Particles under the Influence of Jet-Jet Interactions in a Light-Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>YiLong</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Zhang</surname>
                  <given-names>Renlin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kook</surname>
                  <given-names>Sanghoon</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>The University of New South Wales</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>11</month>
            <year>2015</year>
            <string-date>November 2015</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278095</issue-id>
         <fpage>2213</fpage>
         <lpage>2226</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278114"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Some soot particles emitted from common-rail diesel engines are so small that can penetrate deep into the human pulmonary system, causing serious health issues. The analysis of nano-scale internal structure of these soot particles sampled from the engine tailpipe has provided useful information about their reactivity and toxicity. However, the variations of carbon fringe structures during complex soot formation/oxidation processes occurring inside the engine cylinder are not fully understood. To fill this gap, this paper presents experimental methods for direct sampling and nanostructure analysis of in-flame soot particles in a working diesel engine. The soot particles are collected onto a lacey carbon-coated grid and then imaged in a high-resolution transmission electron microscope (HRTEM). The HR-TEM images are post-processed using a Matlab-based code to obtain key nanostructure parameters such as carbon fringe length, fringe-to-fringe separation distance, and fringe tortuosity. Of particular interest is how jet-jet interactions impact the soot nanostructures because a wall-jet head merging with a neighbouring jet head is well known to cause high soot formation due to rich mixtures. The soot sampling was conducted for three different jet configurations including two single jets (Jet A and Jet B) and a double jet (Jet A&amp;B). Results show that soot primary particles from all the jet configurations are comprised of two distinctively different structures of multiple amorphous cores and concentrically-oriented carbon-layer shells. From about 5000 carbon fringes processed for each jet configuration, the Jet A and Jet B samples show nearly identical mean values for the fringe length, separation distance, and fringe tortuosity of 0.955∼0.962 nm, 0.398∼0.399 nm, and 1.22, respectively. This suggests that jet-to-jet (or hole-to-hole) variations make a minimal impact on the soot nanostructures. The Jet A&amp;B sample also displays similar tortuosity; however, 4% higher fringe separation distance (0.415 nm), which is well outside of the error range, and the increased proportion of highly reactive short carbon fringes suggest that soot particles formed in the jet-jet interaction region are more pre-mature and reactive than those formed in the single-jet head region.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knecht, W., “Diesel Engine Development in View of Reduced Emission Standards,” Energy 33(2):264-271, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.energy.2007.10.003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, “Health and Environmental Effects of Particular Matter,” http://www.epa.gov/region7/air/quality/pmhealth.htm, accessed Mar. 2015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and Siebers, D., “Non-Sooting, Low Flame Temperature Mixing-Controlled DI Diesel Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2004- 01-1399, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-1399.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shi, J.P., Mark, D., and Harrison, R.M., “Characterization of Particles from a Current Technology Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” Environmental Science and Technology 34(5):748-755, 2000, doi:10.1021/es990530z.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, K., Kittelson, D.B., and McMurry, P.H., “Structural Properties of Diesel Exhaust Particles Measured by Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM): Relationships to Particle Mass and Mobility,” Aerosol Science and Technology 38(9):881-889, 2004, doi:10.1080/027868290505189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mathis, U., Mohr, M., Kaegi, R., Bertola, A. et al., “Influence of Diesel Engine Combustion Parameters on Primary Soot Particle Diameter,” Environmental Science and Technology 39(6):1887-1892, 2005, doi:10.1021/es049578p.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Su, D.S., Serafino, A., Müller, J.O., Jentoft, R.E. et al., “Cytotoxicity and Inflammatory Potential of Soot Particles of Low-Emission Diesel Engines,” Environmental Science and Technology 42(5):1761-1765, 2008, doi:10.1021/es0716554.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Frank, B., Schlögl, R., and Su, D.S., “Diesel Soot Toxification,” Environmental Science and Technology 47(7):3026-3027, 2013, doi:10.1021/es003873.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yehliu, K., Vander Wal, R.L., Armas, O., and Boehman, A.L., “Impact of Fuel Formulation on the Nanostructure and Reactivity of Diesel Soot,” Combustion and Flame 159(12):3597-3606, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2012.07.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vander Wal, R., “Soot Nanostructure: Definition, Quantification and Implications,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0964, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0964.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vander Wal, R.L. and Tomasek, A.J., “Soot Oxidation: Dependence upon Initial Nanostructure,” Combustion and Flame 134(1-2):1-9, 2003, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(03)00084-1.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Qurashi, K. and Boehman, A.L, “Impact of Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) on the Oxidative Reactivity of Diesel Engine Soot,” Combustion and Flame 155(4):675-695, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2008.06.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jaramillo, I.C., Gaddam, C.K., Vander Wal, R.L., and Lighty, J.S., “Effect of Nanostructure, Oxidative Pressure and Extent of Oxidation on Model Carbon Reactivity,” Combustion and Flame 162(5):1848-1856, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2014.12.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, D., Ma, Y., and Zhu, M., “Nanostructure and Oxidative Properties of Soot from a Compression Ignition Engine: the Effect of a Homogeneous Combustion Catalyst,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 34(1):1869-1876, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2012.05.096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vander Wal, R.L. and Mueller. C.J., “Initial Investigation of Effects of Fuel Oxygenation on Nanostructure of Soot from a Direct- Injection Diesel Engine,” Energy and Fuels 20(6):2364-2369, 2006, doi:10.1021/ef060201+.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yehliu, K., Vander Wal, R.L., and Boehman, A.L., “Development of an HRTEM Image Analysis Method to Quantify Carbon Nanostructure,” Combustion and Flame 158(9):1837-1851, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2011.01.009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vander Wal, R.L., Tomasek, A.J., Pamphlet, M.I., Taylor, C.D. et al., “Analysis of HRTEM Images for Carbon Nanostructure Quantification,” Journal of Nanoparticle Research 6(6):555-568, 2005, doi:10.1007/s11051-004-3724-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sakai, M., Iguma, H., Kondo, K., and Aizawa, T., “Nanostructure Analysis of Primary Soot Particles Directly Sampled in Diesel Spray Flame via HRTEM,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1722, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1722.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, Z., Song, C., Song, J., Lv, G. et al., “Evolution of the Nanostructure, Fractal Dimension and Size of in-Cylinder Soot during Diesel Combustion Process,” Combustion and Flame 158(8):1624-1630, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2010.12.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Song, J., Song, C., Tao, Y., Lv, G. et al., “Diesel Soot Oxidation during the Late Combustion Phase,” Combustion and Flame 158(3):446-451, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2010.09.017.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okabe, K., Sakai, M., Mizutani, Y., and Aizawa, T., “Aromatic Additive Effect on Soot Formation and Oxidation in Fischer-Tropsch Diesel (FTD) Spray Flame-Morphology and Nanostructure Analysis of In- Flame Soot Particles via HRTEM-,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(3):807- 816, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Genzale, C., Reitz, R., and Musculus, M., “Effects of Piston Bowl Geometry on Mixture Development and Late-Injection Low- Temperature Combustion in a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 1(1):913-937, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pasunurthi, S.S., Hawkes, E.R., Joelsson, T., Rusly, A.M. et al., “Numerical simulation of sprays and combustion in an automotive-size diesel engine under non-reacting and reacting conditions,” presented at ASPACC 2013, ROK, May 19-22, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mueller, C., Pitz, W., Pickett, L., Martin, G. et al., “Effects of Oxygenates on Soot Processes in DI Diesel Engines: Experiments and Numerical Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1791, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-1791.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rusly, A.M., Le, M.K., Kook, S., and Hawkes, E.R., “The Shortening of Lift-off Length Associated with Jet-Wall and Jet-Jet Interaction in a Small-Bore Optical Diesel Engine,” Fuel 125:1-14, 2014, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2014.02.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lequien, G., Berrocal, E., Gallo, Y., Themudo e Mello, A. et al., “Effect of Jet-Jet Interactions on the Liquid Fuel Penetration in an Optical Heavy-Duty DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2013-01-1615, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-1615.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malbec, L. and Bruneaux, G., “Study of Air Entrainment of Multi-hole Diesel Injection by Particle Image Velocimetry - Effect of Neighboring Jets Interaction and Transient Behavior After End of Injection.,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):107-123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abraham, J., Khan, A., and Magi, V., “Jet-Jet and Jet-Wall Interactions of Transient Jets from Multi-Hole Injectors,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0513, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0513.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., Zhang, R., Szeto, K., Pickett, L. et al., “In-Flame Soot Sampling and Particle Analysis in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(1):80-97, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-0912.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, R., Szeto, K., and Kook, S., “Size Distribution and Structure of Wall-Deposited Soot Particles in an Automotive-Size Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 6(3):605-614, 2013, doi:10.4271/2013-01-2534.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, R. and Kook, S., “Influence of Fuel Injection Timing and Pressure on in-Flame Soot Particles in an Automotive-Size Diesel Engine,” Environmental Science and Technology 48(14):8243-8250, 2014, doi:10.1021/es500661w.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polonowski, C., Mueller, C., Gehrke, C., Bazyn, T. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-Cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):51-77, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shim, H.-S., Hurt, R.H., and Yang, N.Y.C., “A Methodology for Analysis of 002 Lattice Fringe Images and Its Application to Combustion- Derived Carbons,” Carbon 38(1):29-45, 2000, doi:10.1016/S0008- 6223(99)00096-2.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L.M. and Siebers, D.L., “Soot in Diesel Fuel Jets: Effects of Ambient Temperature, Ambient Density, and Injection Pressure,” Combustion and Flame 138(1-2):114-135, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2004.04.006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yehliu, K., Armas, O., Vander Wal, R. L., and Boehman, A. L., “Impact of Engine Operating Modes and Combustion Phasing on the Reactivity of Diesel Soot,” Combustion and Flame 160(3):682-691, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2012.11.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Renlin, Z. and Sanghoon, K., “Structural Evolution of Soot Particles during Diesel Combustion in a Single-Cylinder Light-Duty Engine,” Combustion and Flame 162(6):2720-2728, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2015.04.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishiguro, T., Takatori, Y., and Akihama, K., “Microstructure of Diesel Soot Particles Probed by Electron Microscopy: First Observation of Inner Core and Outer Shell,” Combustion and Flame 108(1-2):231-234, 1997, doi:10.1016/S0010-2180(96)00206-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hurt, R.H., Crawford, G.P., and Shim, H.-S., “Equilibrium Nanostructure of Primary Soot Particles,” Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 28(2):2539-2546, 2000, doi:10.1016/S0082- 0784(00)80670-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lu, T., Cheung, C.S., and Huang, Z., “Effects of Engine Operating Conditions on the Size and Nanostructure of Diesel Particles,” Journal of Aerosol Science 47:27-38, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.jaerosci.2011.12.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
