<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26272338</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Engine Scavenging Tuning for In-Field Product Expectations of a 45cc Stratified Two-Stroke Power Head</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bergman</surname>
                  <given-names>M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sundkvist</surname>
                  <given-names>R.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Husqvarna AB</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>12</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>December 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26272316</issue-id>
         <fpage>2122</fpage>
         <lpage>2132</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright @2013 SAE Japan and Copyright @ 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26272338"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Because of todays new emissions legislation, a new 45cc Husqvarna trimmer/clearing saw power head was needed.</p>
            <p>When reducing emissions in a conventional two-stroke engine or a stratified scavenged engine, it is important that the tuning and basic scavenging characteristics of the standard engine are maintained. A dual charge intake system is necessary for the stratified engine but it also creates air fuel delivery issues compared to a standard two stroke engine. With increasing trapping efficiency more spent gases mixes with the fresh charge, creating less favorable combustion properties and thermal loading on the engine. On top of this the sequential stratified scavenging technology introduces a spatial inhomogeneous mix problem between scavenging fresh air, new mixture and spent gases. This all add sensitivity to long term stability due to deposits of carbon both in combustion chamber and exhaust duct, resulting in a change in engine parameters due to aging.</p>
            <p>There is of course a limit of what can be done in aspects of fuel trapping versus product performance with a simple two-stroke power head design when relying of a standard type mechanical carburettor fuel system. When optimizing the engine aspiration by tuning of intake and scavenging ducts geometry in dependens with static piston port timing.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zahn Wolfgang, Rosskamp Heiko and Schlossarczyk Jörg, “Low emission technologies for high-performance handheld outdoor products, SAE paper No. 2001-01-0896</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zahn Wolfgang, Rosskamp Heiko, Raffenberg Michael and Klimmek Axel, “Analysis of a stratified charging consept for high-performance two-stroke engines” SAE paper No. 2000-01-0900</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergman, M. and Berneklev, J., “A Novel Method of Tuning a Stratified Scavenged Two-Stroke Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-32-0055</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kenny, R.G. Thornhill, D.J. Cunningham, G. Blair, G.P. “Reducing exhaust hydrocarbon emissions from a low cost two-stroke engine”, SAE Paper No. 982013</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sawada Toshiharu, Wada Minoru, Noguchi Masanori, Kobayashi Buhei, “Development of a low emission two.stroke cycle engine”, SAE paper No. 980761</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergman, M. Gustafsson R.U.K., Jonsson B.I.R, “Scavenging System Layout of at 25 cc Two-Stroke Engine Intended for Stratified Scavenging”, SAE paper No. 2002-32-1840</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bergman, M. Gustafsson R.U.K., Jonsson B.I.R, “Emission and Performance Evaluation of a 25cc Stratified Scavenging Two-stroke Engine”, SAE paper No. 2003-32-0047</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sawada Toshiharu, Wada Minoru, Noguchi Masanori, Kobayashi Buhei, “Stratified scavenging two-cycle engine” European patent application EP 0 971 110 A1</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosskamp, H. Klimmek, A. Pretzsch P. and Mugele, M. “Scavenge loss mechanisms and their driving forces in loop-scavenged highperformance two-stroke engines”, SAE paper No. 2001-01-1826/4247</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blair G.P, “Design and simulations of two-stroke engines”, SAE R-161, 1996, ISBN 1-56091-685-0</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J.B. Sher, E. “The two-stroke cycle engine”, SAE R-267, 1999, ISBN 0-7680-0323-7</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Saxena Mukesh, Mathur, H. B. Radzimirski, S. “A stratified charging two-stroke engine for reduction of scavenged-through losses”, SAE paper No. 891805</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Buhei, K. Masanori, N. Toshiharu, S., “Stratified scavenging two-cycle engine” Figure 4, Patent JP11107761</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
