<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">revifinastud</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100802</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>The Review of Financial Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">08939454</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14657368</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">28</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">8</issue>
         <issue-id>i24466874</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24466882</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>House Prices, Home Equity Borrowing, and Entrepreneurship</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Stefano</given-names>
                  <surname>Corradin</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
                  <surname>Popov</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>8</month>
            <year>2015</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2399</fpage>
         <lpage>2428</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 The Society for Financial Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24466882"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper shows that housing wealth helps alleviate credit constraints for potential entrepreneurs by enabling home owners to extract equity from their property and invest it in their business. Using a large U.S. individual-level survey dataset for the 1996–2006 period, we find that a 10% increase in home equity raises the share of individuals who transition into self-employment each year from 1% to 1.07%. Our results persist when we use proxies for aggregate housing demand shocks and for the topological elasticity of housing supply to generate variation in home equity that is orthogonal to entrepreneurial choice.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d623274e217a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e224" publication-type="other">
For important contributions, see Evans and Jovanovic (1989), Evans and Leighton ( 1989), Holtz-Eakin, Joulfain,
and Rosen (1994), Blanchflower and Oswald (1998), and Wang, Wang, and Yang (2012), among others. See Kerr
and Nanda (2009b) for a thorough review of the literature.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e237a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e244" publication-type="other">
The SIPP oversamples individuals from areas with high poverty concentrations. We perform robustness checks
to make sure that our main results are not affected by this feature of the survey.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e254a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e261" publication-type="other">
We have assigned a value of $ 1,000,000 to the home exemption in states in which the homestead exemption is
unlimited.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e271a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e278" publication-type="other">
All of these state-level variables are time varying.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e286a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e293" publication-type="other">
Corradin and Popov (2013) formulate a simple model of career choice with homeownership in the presence
of borrowing constraints to motivate this hypothesis. In their model, agents start out as fixed-wage workers
and can choose to become entrepreneurs in each following period. Their value function in each period depends
on own wealth (as in Quadrini 2000; Cagetti and De Nardi 2006; and Buera 2009), but also on house prices
through two channels. The first is that the current level of house prices affects the equity value they can extract
from their home, increasing their mortgage balance. The housing stock thus has a collateral value component
beyond the value derived from the direct consumption of housing services, due to prospects of limits on the
amount of borrowing. The second channel results from the interaction between the first channel and the cost
of external financing available to the potential entrepreneur. As in Quadrini (2000), the entrepreneur can take
external financing through a business loan up to an amount that corresponds to the difference between the
maximum permitted level of capital investment and total net wealth. The model thus predicts that agents are
more likely to become entrepreneurs when the value of their home equity is high. It also predicts that on average,
new entrepreneurs increase their mortgage balance and rely more on external financing.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e338a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e345" publication-type="other">
In the same vein, Hamilton (2000) shows that most entrepreneurs enter and persist in business, although they have
both lower initial earnings and lower income growth than paid employees. Moskowitz and Vissing-Jorgensen
(2002) show that the returns on private equity are no higher than the returns on public equity, even though
entrepreneurial investment is poorly diversified. Both papers thus suggest that there are important nonpecuniary
benefits of entrepreneurship.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e364a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e371" publication-type="other">
The results from these tests are reported in the Internet Appendix.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e378a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e385" publication-type="other">
Other recent papers to pursue identification of changes in collateral values using the local topological elasticity
of housing supply include Chaney, Sraer, and Thesmar (2012), Adelino, Schoar, and Severino (Forthcoming),
and Cvijanovic (2014), among others.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e398a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e405" publication-type="other">
The original data in Saiz (2010) are at the MSA level. We calculate state-level elasticities by averaging the
MSA-level elasticities for all MSAs in the state, weighted by the MSA's population.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e415a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e422" publication-type="other">
The SIPP stopped reporting the MSA field starting with the 2004-2006 wave.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e430a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e437" publication-type="other">
The estimates in Columns (1) and (2) are directly comparable to the marginal effects reported in Table 4.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e444a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e451" publication-type="other">
The omitted year category is the 1997 dummy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d623274e458a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d623274e465" publication-type="other">
This effect is directly comparable to Schmalz, Sraer, and Thesmar (2013), who find that going from the 25th to
the 75th percentile of past house price growth increases the probability of firm creation by homeowners, relative
to renters, by up to 13%.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d623274e487a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e491" publication-type="other">
Adelino, M., A. Schoar, and F. Severino. Forthcoming. House prices, collateral, and self-employment. Journal
of Financial Economics.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e501a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e505" publication-type="other">
Berkowitz, J., and M. White. 2004. Bankruptcy and small firms' access to credit. RAND Journal of Economics
35:69-84.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e515a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e519" publication-type="other">
Bernanke, B., and C. Lown. 1991. The credit crunch. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity 22:205-48.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e526a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e530" publication-type="other">
Black, S., and P. Strahan. 2002. Entrepreneurship and bank credit availability. Journal of Finance 57:2807-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e538a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e542" publication-type="other">
Blanchflower, D., and A. Oswald. 1998. What makes an entrepreneur? Journal of Labor Economics 16:26-60.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e549a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e553" publication-type="other">
Buera, F. 2009. A dynamic model of entrepreneurship with borrowing constraints: Theory and evidence. Annals
of Finance 5:443-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e563a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e567" publication-type="other">
Cagetti, M., and M. De Nardi. 2006. Entrepreneurship, frictions, and wealth. Journal of Political Economy
114:835-70.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e577a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e581" publication-type="other">
Cetorelli, N., and P. Strahan. 2006. Finance as a barrier to entry: Bank competition and industry structure in local
U.S. markets. Journal of Finance 61:437-61.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e591a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e595" publication-type="other">
Chaney, T., D. Sraer, and D. Thesmar. 2012. The collateral channel: How real estate shocks affect corporate
investment. American Economic Review 102:2381-409.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e605a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e609" publication-type="other">
Chetty, R., and A. Szeidl. 2010. The Effect of housing on portfolio choice. NBER Working Papers 15998.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e617a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e621" publication-type="other">
Corradin, S. 2014. Household leverage. Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 46:567-613.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e628a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e632" publication-type="other">
Corradin, S., and A. Popov. 2013. House prices, home equity, and entrepreneurship. ECB Working Paper 1544</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e639a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e643" publication-type="other">
Cvijanovic, D. 2014. Real estate prices and firm capital structure. Review of Financial Studies 27:2690-735.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e650a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e654" publication-type="other">
Duca, J., J. Mullbauer, and A. Murphy. 2011. House prices and credit constraints: Making sense of the U.S.
experience. Economic Journal 121:533-51.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e664a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e668" publication-type="other">
Evans, D., and B. Jovanovic. 1989. An estimated model of entrepreneurial choice under liquidity constraints.
Journal of Political Economy 97:808-27.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e678a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e682" publication-type="other">
Evans, D., and L. Leighton. 1989. Some empirical aspects of entrepreneurship. American Economic Review
79:519-35.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e693a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e697" publication-type="other">
Fairlie, R. 1999. The absence of the African-American owned business: An analysis of the dynamics of self-
employment. Journal of Labor Economics 17:80-108.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e707a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e711" publication-type="other">
2013. Entrepreneurship, economic conditions, and the Great Recession. Journal of Economics and
Management Strategy 22:207-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e721a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e725" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, B. 2000. Does entrepreneurship pay? An empirical analysis of the returns to self-employment. Journal
of Political Economy 108:604-31.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e735a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e739" publication-type="other">
Holtz-Eakin, D., D. Joulfaian, and H. Rosen. 1994. Sticking it out: Entrepreneurial survival and liquidity
constraints. Journal of Political Economy 102:53-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e749a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e753" publication-type="other">
Hurst, E., and A. Lusardi. 2004. Liquidity constraints, household wealth, and entrepreneurship. Journal of
Political Economy 112:319-47.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e763a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e767" publication-type="other">
Hurst, E., and F. Stafford. 2004. Home is where the equity is: Liquidity constraints, refinancing and consumption.
Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking 36:985-1014.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e778a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e782" publication-type="other">
Kerr, W., and R. Nanda. 2009a. Democratizing entry: Banking deregulation, financing constraints, and
entrepreneurship. Journal of Financial Economics 94:124-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e792a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e796" publication-type="other">
. 2009b. Financing constraints and entrepreneurship. NBER Working Paper 15498.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e803a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e807" publication-type="other">
Loutskina, E., and P. Strahan. 2015. Financial integration, housing, and economic volatility. Journal of Financial
Economics 115:25-41.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e817a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e821" publication-type="other">
Mian, A., and A. Sufi. 2009. The consequences of mortgage credit expansion: Evidence from the U.S. mortgage
default crisis. Quarterly Journal of Economics 124:1449-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e831a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e835" publication-type="other">
. 2011. House prices, home equity-based borrowing, and the U.S. household leverage crisis. American
Economic Review 101:2132-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e845a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e849" publication-type="other">
Mian, A., K. Rao, and A. Sufi. 2013. Household balance sheets, consumption, and the economic slump. Quarterly
Journal of Economics 128:1687-726.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e860a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e864" publication-type="other">
Midrigan, V., and T. Philippon. 2011. Household leverage and the recession. NBER Working Papers 16965.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e871a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e875" publication-type="other">
Moskowitz, T., and A. Vissing-Jorgensen. 2002. The returns to entrepreneurial investment: A private equity
premium puzzle? American Economic Review 92:745-78.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e885a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e889" publication-type="other">
Neyman, J., and E. Scott. 1948. Consistent estimates based on partially consistent observations. Econometrica
16:1-32.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e899a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e903" publication-type="other">
Quadrini, V. 1999. The importance of entrepreneurship for wealth concentration and mobility. Review of Income
and Wealth 45:1-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e913a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e917" publication-type="other">
. 2000. Entrepreneurship, saving, and social mobility. Review of Economic Dynamics 3 :1-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e924a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e928" publication-type="other">
Robb, A., and D. Robinson. 2014. The capital structure decisions of new firms. Review of Financial Studies
27:153-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e939a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e943" publication-type="other">
Saiz, A. 2010. The geographic determinants of housing supply. Quarterly Journal of Economics 125:1253-96.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e950a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e954" publication-type="other">
Schmalz, M., D. Sraer, and D. Thesmar. 2013. Housing collateral and entrepreneurship. NBER Working Paper
19680.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e964a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e968" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R. 2007. Understanding recent trends in house prices and home ownership. Proceedings- Economic
Policy Symposium - Jackson Hole, Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City: 89.123.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e978a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e982" publication-type="other">
Stock, J., and M. Yogo. 2005. Testing for weak instruments in IV regressions. In Identification and inference for
econometric models: Essays in honor of Thomas Rothenberg, 80-108. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e992a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e996" publication-type="other">
U.S. Census. 2010. The United States Census Bureau.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d623274e1003a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d623274e1007" publication-type="other">
Wang, C., N. Wang, and J. Yang. 2012. A unified model of entrepreneurship dynamics. Journal of Financial
Economics 106:1-23.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


