<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26349722</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>Forum: Pedagogical Tools in Public Finance</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>USING THE TWO-PERIOD MODEL TO UNDERSTAND INVESTMENT IN HUMAN CAPITAL</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>M. Daniele</given-names>
                  <surname>Paserman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">70</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26349711</issue-id>
         <fpage>185</fpage>
         <lpage>204</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 National Tax Association-Tax Institute of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26349722"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>In many textbooks, the decision to invest in human capital is presented in terms of the present discounted value of the lifetime stream of costs and benefits associated with the investment. I argue that this approach, while delivering some useful insights, also conflates subjective discount rates and market interest rates, obfuscates the role of credit market imperfections, and makes difficult the analysis of policy interventions and the effects of external shocks on human capital investment. I show instead how a simple two-period model can deliver the main insights about investment in human capital and is flexible enough to be used to model a wide variety of policy interventions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d992e217a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e224" publication-type="other">
Potential confusion between different concepts of the discount rate appears also in other areas in economics.
Most prominent is the debate in climate policy about how much weight should be given to the utility of
future generations, and whether the market interest rate provides good guidance for this parameter (Stem,
2008; Nordhaus, 2007); see Kaplow, Moyer, and Weisbach (2010) for a general discussion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e240a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e247" publication-type="other">
Somewhat more generally, costs may be incurred for more than just the initial year. The same discount
rate can then be used to calculate the present value of costs, PV(C), in which case NPV- PV(B) - PV{C).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e257a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e264" publication-type="other">
Any reasonable estimate of the costs and benefits of college shows that the NPV is large and positive,
and has been growing over time (Avery and Turner, 2012). This of course would be a good place also
to point out some of the caveats with this analysis: (1) the simple comparison of earnings between high
school graduates and college graduates does not necessarily imply that the relationship is causal; (2) the
calculation only shows information on average returns and ignores the substantial heterogeneity across
the population; and (3) as every good investment prospectus reminds us, "past performance is no guar-
antee of future performance." The online Appendix is available at http://people.bu.edu/paserman/papers/
Paserman_UsingTwoPeriodModel_NTJ2017_SupplementaryMaterials.zip.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e293a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e300" publication-type="other">
Other textbooks also fail to make the distinction between market interest rates and subjective discount
rates. Hyclak, Johnes, and Thornton (2013) equate the discount rate to the market interest rate, with no
discussion at all about subjective impatience. Laing (2011) does the same, even though he devotes one
whole section to imperfect capital markets and how they affect the investment decision. In his exposition,
heterogeneity in investment derives from heterogeneity in borrowing costs, not in rates of time preference.
McConnell, Brue, and Macpherson (2013) equate the discount rate to the market interest rate, but do discuss
time preferences in a footnote, arguing present-oriented individuals effectively use a high interest rate to
discount future flows of earnings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e330a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e337" publication-type="other">
A more plausible scenario is that low socioeconomic status individuals have less access to borrowing,
and therefore are offered loans with higher interest rates. But remember that in the present value formula,
the discount rate represents the rate of return on alternative investments. In the following section we will
introduce the possibility that the interest rates for borrowers and for lenders differ.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e353a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e360" publication-type="other">
In principle, one could modify the NPV formula to allow for borrowing, but the formula becomes
quickly quite cumbersome. Specifically, assume that a student takes on %D of debt, at interest rate
rg, which must be repaid within TD periods, starting from period 1. Then, the NPV formula becomes
NPV = -(C - D) + X * (B, - p) / (1 + r)' + £ ^ Β, I ( 1 + r)', where ρ = r,D / [l - (1 + r, ) - TD ] is the
constant repayment amount. As in the traditional calculation, the question about the appropriate discount
rate r remains unresolved.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e383a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e390" publication-type="other">
For more advanced students, it may be useful here to discuss the additively separable utility function that
is used pervasively in economics: t/(C0,C,) = u(C0) + «(C,)/ (1 + p). This explicit formulation is useful
because it clearly shows how the subjective discount rate ρ is a parameter of the utility function.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e403a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e410" publication-type="other">
As of the writing of this article (October 2016), the interest rate on checking and savings account is less
than 0.1 percent, the interest rate on three-month Treasury bills is 0.32 percent, the interest rate on 15-year
mortgages is about 3.0 percent, the interest rate on subsidized undergraduate loans is 4.66 percent, and the
interest rate on credit card debt varies between 15 and 22 percent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e426a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e433" publication-type="other">
More precisely, on any vertical line that crosses both indifference curves, the slope of B's indifference
curve is steeper than the slope of A's indifference curve.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e443a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e450" publication-type="other">
The difficulty that one sometimes encounters with Question 2 is that some undergraduate students struggle
to imagine themselves spending $100 at a restaurant!</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e461a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e468" publication-type="other">
present the increase in returns to schooling as an external shock, perhaps driven by changes in technology
or trade. Of course, one can always view this same shock as a policy that lowers taxes on high earners.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d992e478a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d992e485" publication-type="other">
Unfortunately, one of the shortcomings of the two-period model is that there is no way to model default
or other outcomes that depend on the longer run, such as a restructuring of debt payments.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d992e504a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e508" publication-type="other">
Acemoglu, Daron, and David Autor, 2011. "Skills, Tasks and Technologies: Implications for
Employment and Earnings "In Ashenfelter, Orley, and David C ard (eds. ), Handbook ofLabor Eco-
nomics, Volume 4B, 1043-1171. North-Holland Publishing Company, Amsterdam, Netherlands.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e521a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e525" publication-type="other">
Avery, Christopher, and Sarah Turner, 2012. "Student Loans: Do College Students Borrow Too
Much — Or Not Enough?" Journal of Economic Perspectives 26 (1), 165-192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e535a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e539" publication-type="other">
Becker, Gary S., and Casey B. Mulligan, 1997. "The Endogenous Determination of Time Prefer-
ence." Quarterly Journal of Economics 112 (3), 729-758.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e549a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e553" publication-type="other">
Borjas, George J., 2010. Labor Economics: Fifth Edition. McGraw-Hill Education, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e561a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e565" publication-type="other">
Ehrenberg, Ronald G., and Robert S. Smith, 2012. Modern Labor Economics: Theory and Public
Policy. Eleventh Edition. Prentice Hall, Upper Saddle River, NJ.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e575a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e579" publication-type="other">
Hyclak, Thomas, Geraint Johnes, and Robert Thornton, 2013. Fundamentals of Labor Economics,
Second Edition. Cengage Learning, Boston, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e589a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e593" publication-type="other">
Kaplow, Louis, Elisabeth Moyer, and David A. Weisbach, 2010. "The Social Evaluation of Inter-
generational Policies and its Application to Integrated Assessment Models of Climate Change."
BE. Journal of Economic Analysis and Policy 10 (2), 1-32.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e606a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e610" publication-type="other">
Laing, Derek, 2011. Labor Economics. W.W. Norton &amp; Company, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e617a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e621" publication-type="other">
McConnell, Campbell R., Stanley L. Brue, and David A. Macpherson, 2013. Contemporary
Labor Economics: Tenth Edition. McGraw-Hill, New York, NY.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e631a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e635" publication-type="other">
National Center for Education Statistics, 2015. "Postsecondary Attainment: Differences by
Socioeconomic Status." National Center for Education Statistics, Washington, DC, http://nces.
ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator_tva.asp.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e649a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e653" publication-type="other">
Nordhaus, William D, 2007. "A Review of the Stem Review on the Economics of Climate
Change." Journal of Economic Literature 45 (3), 686-702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d992e663a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d992e667" publication-type="other">
Stem, Nicholas, 2008. "The Economics of Climate Change." American Economic Review 98
(2), 1-37.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
