<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26168978</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Frequency Domain Power Distribution Strategy for Series Hybrid Electric Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kim</surname>
                  <given-names>Youngki</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Tae-Kyung</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Filipi</surname>
                  <given-names>Zoran</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ of Michigan</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>June 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26168958</issue-id>
         <fpage>208</fpage>
         <lpage>218</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2012 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26168978"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Electrification and hybridization have great potential for improving fuel economy and reducing visual signature or soot emissions in military vehicles. Specific challenges related to military applications include severe duty cycles, large and uncertain energy flows through the system and high thermal loads. A novel supervisory control strategy is proposed to simultaneously mitigate severe engine transients and to reduce high electric current in the battery without oversizing the battery. The described objectives are accomplished by splitting the propulsion power demand through filtering in the frequency domain. The engine covers only low frequency power demand profile while the battery covers high frequency components. In the proposed strategy, the separation filter is systematically designed to identify different frequency components with the consideration of fuel consumption, aggressive engine transients, and battery electric loads. The proposed strategy is implemented into the series HEV simulation framework to assess its effectiveness under various driving cycles. The results show that the proposed power distribution strategy dramatically reduces battery current peaks and aggressive engine transients while maintaining the fuel economy to a competitive level. Longer battery life under the proposed strategy compared to the baseline thermostatic SOC control is explicitly evaluated through cumulative fatigue/damage analysis. The proposed strategy provides more flexibility in HEV design/optimization and enables battery downsizing, due to the extended battery safety margin and the reduced severity of engine transients.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Erwin, S. I., Army's Next Battle: Fuel, Transportation Costs, April 2002, National Defense, Magazine http://www.nationaldefensemagazine.org/archive/2002/April/Pages/Armys_Next4086.aspx, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Carns, M. P. C., and Schlesinger, J., “Final Report of the Defense Science Board Task Force on DoD Energy Strategy,” memorandum for the Chairman, Defense Science Board, Washington, DC, January 14, pp. 3-5, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wu, B., Lin, C.-C., Filipi, Z., Peng, H., and Assanis, D., “Optimal Power Management for a Hydraulic Hybrid Delivery Truck,” J. Vehicle System Dynamics, vol. 42, no. 1-2, pp. 23-40, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Filipi, Z., Louca, L., Daran, B., Lin, C.-C., Yildir, U., Wu, B., Kokkolaras, M., Assanis, D., Peng, H., Papalambros, P., and Stein, J., “Combined optimization of design and power management of the hydraulic hybrid propulsion system for the 6 × 6 medium truck,” Int. J. Heavy Veh. Syst., vol. 11, no. 3, pp. 371-401, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hui, S., “Multi-objective optimization for hydraulic hybrid vehicle based on adaptive simulated annealing genetic algorithm,” Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence, vol. 23, no. 1, pp. 27-33, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, Y. and Filipi, Z., “Simulation Study of a Series Hydraulic Hybrid Propulsion System for a Light Truck,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-4151, 2007, doi:10.4271/2007-01-4151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ducusin, M., Gargies, S., and Mi, C., “Modeling of a series hybrid electric high-mobility multipurpose wheeled vehicle,” IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol., vol. 56, no. 2, pp. 557-565, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Velardocchia, M. and Rondinelli, E., “Design and Development of an In-Hub Motors Hybrid Vehicle for Military Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0659, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0659.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenkranz, C., “Deep cycle Batteries for Plug-in Hybrid Application,” presented at EVS-20 plug-in Hybrid Workshop, Nov 15, 2003, Monaco</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Maleki, H. and Shamsuri, A. K., “Thermal analysis and modeling of a notebook computer battery,” Journal of Power Sources, vol. 115, pp. 131-136, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sciarretta, A., and Guzzella, L., “Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicles - A Survey of Optimal Energy-Management Strategies,” in IEEE Control Systems Magazine, vol. 27, no. 2, pp. 60-70, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hochgraf, C., Ryan, M., and Wiegman, H., “Engine Control Strategy for a Series Hybrid Electric Vehicle Incorporating Load-Leveling and Computer Controlled Energy Management,” SAE Technical Paper 960230, 1996, doi: 10.4271/960230.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jalil, N., Kheir, N. A., and Salman, M., “A rule-based energy management strategy for a series hybrid vehicle,” Proceedings of the American Control Conference, pp. 689-693, 1997</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johri, R. and Filipi, Z., “Low-Cost Pathway to Ultra Efficient City Car: Series Hydraulic Hybrid System with Optimized Supervisory Control,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):505-520, 2010, doi:10.4271/2009-24-0065.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pisu, P. and Rizzoni, G., “A supervisory control strategy for series hybrid electric vehicles with two energy storage systems,” in Proc. IEEE Conf. Vehicle Power Propulsion, Chicago, IL, 2005, pp. 65-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konev, A., Lezhnev, L., and Kolmanovsky, I., “Control Strategy Optimization for a Series Hybrid Vehicle,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0663, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0663.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Di Cairano, S., Liang, W., Kolmanovsky, I.V., Kuang, M.L., and Phillips, A.M., “Engine Power Smoothing Energy Management Strategy for a Series Hybrid Electric Vehicle,” in American Control Conference, San Francisco, CA, 2011, pp. 2101-2106</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caratozzolo, P., Serra, M., Riera, J., “Energy management strategies for hybrid electric vehicles,” IEMDC'03, IEEE International Electric Machines and Drives Conference, Madison, WI, USA, vol. 1, pp. 241-248, 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Meissner, E. and Richter, G., “The challenge to the automotive battery industry: the battery has to become an increasingly integrated component within the vehicle electric power system,” J. Power Sources, vol. 144, no. 2, pp. 438-460, June 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sauer, D. U. and Wenzl, H., “Comparison of different approaches for lifetime prediction of electrochemical systems-Using lead acid batteries as example,” J. Power Sources, vol. 176, no. 2, pp. 477-483, Feb 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schaltz, E., Khaligh, A., and Rasmussen, P.O., “Influence of battery/ultracapacitor energy-storage sizing on battery lifetime in a fuel cell hybrid electric vehicle,” IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, 58 (8), pp. 3882-3891, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Argonne National Laboratory, Argonne, IL, “Powertrain systems analysis toolkit,” 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Filipi, Z., Hagena, J., Fathy, H., “Investigating the Impact of In-Vehicle Transients on Diesel Soot Emissions”, Thermal Science, Vol. 12 (2008), No. 1, pp. 53-72</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hagena, J.R., Assanis, D.N., and Filipi, Z.S., “Cycle-resolved measurements of in-cylinder constituents during diesel engine transients and insight into their impact on emissions,” Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, vol.225, pp. 1103-1117, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, T. -K., Kim, Y., Stefanopoulou, A., and Filipi, Z. S., “Hybrid electric vehicle supervisory control design reflecting estimated Lithiumion battery electrochemical dynamics,” 2011 American Control Conference, San Francisco, CA, USA, 2011</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Miner, M. A., “Cumulative Damage in Fatigue,” ASME Journal of Applied Mechanics, vol. 12, pp. 159-164, 1945.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nieslony, A., “Determination of fragments of multiaxial service loading strongly influencing the fatigue of machine components,” Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing, vol. 23(8), pp. 2712-2721, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
