<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278163</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Scuderi Split Cycle Fast Acting Valvetrain</article-title>
            <subtitle>Architecture and Development</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Meldolesi</surname>
                  <given-names>Riccardo</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bailey</surname>
                  <given-names>George</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lacy</surname>
                  <given-names>Clive</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gilbert</surname>
                  <given-names>Ian</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Pirault</surname>
                  <given-names>Jean-Pierre</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Perkins</surname>
                  <given-names>Anthony</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Southwest Research Institute</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>467</fpage>
         <lpage>481</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278163"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The Scuderi internal combustion engine is characterized by a split cycle that divides the four strokes of a conventional combustion cycle over two paired cylinders, one intake/compression cylinder and one power/exhaust cylinder, connected by a crossover port. This split cycle also has an additional high pressure “crossover” gas transfer phase versus the conventional 4-stroke cycle, during which the charge air is moved from the first to the second cylinder. The intake/compression, power/exhaust and crossover events are repeated every revolution, i.e. over two cycles, with a small phase angle between the two cylinders. The separate cylinders enable opportunities for improved combustion and the possibility for pneumatic hybridization of the engine. This paper describes the technical challenges posed by the actuation of the crossover valves in the Scuderi Split Cycle research engine. Fast actuation of these valves is a key requirement for successful combustion and for hybrid operation in the Scuderi and perhaps other pneumatic hybrid engines where the mass of air entering the cylinder is controlled by the operation of poppet valves. To successfully meet these demands design modeling, dynamic simulations of the valve opening event, and structural analysis on the components were performed concurrently. Experimental rig work was undertaken to verify the valvetrain performance and durability. The result is a valvetrain with an unusual architecture that meets the speed of actuation requirements for successful engine operation. The structural limitations in terms of mass, strength and stiffness of the major components are fully understood, as well as the dynamic behavior of the whole system. A set of verified analytical models was developed which will be used to tailor valvetrain design and performance as various Scuderi engine configurations are developed in the future.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Scuderi, C. J., “Split Four Stroke Cycle Internal Combustion Engine”, International Patent WO 03/008785 A1, January 30, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Phillips, F., Gilbert, I., Pirault, J.-P., and Megel, M., “Scuderi Split Cycle Research Engine: Overview, Architecture and Operation,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1): 464-480, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0403.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pastorelli, S., Almondo, A., and Sorli, M., “Performances of Cam follower Systems with Pneumatic Return Spring”, Proceedings of the Bath Workshop on Power Transmission and Motion Control-PTMC 2005, Bath, UK, 379-394.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pastorelli, S., Almondo, A., and Sorli, M., “Effects of mechanical and pneumatic return springs on valve train dynamics”, 8th Biennial ASME Conference on Engineering Systems Design and Analysis, 2006, Torino, Italy.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pastorelli, S., Almondo, A., and Sorli, M., “Mechanical Spring Replacement With Pneumatic Return Device in a Valve Train: Effects on Dynamics and Preload Tuning”, ASME J. Mech. Des. 132: 011008-1-9, 2010, doi: 10.1115/1.4000640.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies Inc., GT-Suite, GT-ISE, (Versions 5.2-7.0), Computer Software.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mclaughlin, S., and Haque, I., “Development of a Multi- Body Simulation Model of a Winston Cup Valvetrain to Study Valve Bounce”, Proceedings Institute of Mechanical Engineers, Part K, J. Multi-body Dynamics, 2002, 216, 237-248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sczepanski, J.G., “New Equipment and Methodology to Perform High Speed Valve Train Dynamics Testing and Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1720, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1720.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
