<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">11</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830102</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830109</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE ROLE OF NON-GOVERNMENTAL ORGANIZATIONS FOR FINANCIAL MARKETS / LE RÔLE DES ORGANISMES NON GOUVERNEMENT AUX EN FAVEUR DU DÉVELOPPEMENT DES MARCHÉS FINANCIERS</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Joachim</given-names>
                  <surname>von Stockhausen</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1987</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>201</fpage>
         <lpage>215</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830109"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Le but principal de cet article est d'analyser le rôle spécifique des organismes non gouvernementaux (O.N.G.) dans le secteur des marchés financiers pour promouvoir le développement sociale et économique des couches de la population les plus défavorisées. Contrairement aux programmes gouvernementaux de crédit fortement structurés, les organisations non gouvernementales cherchent à harmoniser l'offre et la demande des services financiers pour les groupes sociaux envisagés. Les réformes nécessaires des politiques en faveur des marchés financiers sont prévues de différentes façons par les organisations gouvernementales. Une solution habituelle consiste dans la constitution de fonds renouvelables de nature spécifique pour les prêts. Une deuxième solution cherche plutôt la voie des réformes: elle essaie de rassembler les emprunteurs potentiels et de les mettre en liaison avec les établissements bancaires béjà existants. Cela peut être effectué créant un système de garantie à deux stades: 1) les groupes sociaux envisagés forment des associations da garantie de crédit et 2) les organisations non gouvernementales pourvoyent des garanties supplémentaires. L'organisme non gouvernemental «Servienda» de la Colombie qui utilise le système mentionné montre ses effets bénéfiques pour toutes les catégories d'agents économiques envisagés. Le processus de développement socio-économique envisagé par les organismes non gouvernementaux souvent a besoin pour des raisons politiques de l'aide de organismes puissants. Pour choisir ces organismes il semble opportun de privilégier les organismes «mixtes» qui s'intéressent aux activités de la population marginale pour des raisons non seulement politiques mais encore commerciales.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d50e107a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e114" publication-type="other">
DSE-SOLIDARIOS, Fomento de los Organismos de Autoayuda con el Concurso de Corporaciones de Desar-
rollo. Bemd Breuer (Ed.). Fundacion Alemana para el Desarrollo Internacional, Centro de Seminarios de
Desarrollo Economico y Social. Berlin, 1975, p. 123.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e127a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e134" publication-type="other">
E. Liboreiro, Aspectos Teoricos de la Produccion, Commercializacibn y Financiacion de Cooperativas y otros
Formas Asociativas. In: Serie de Informes de Conferencias, Cursos y Reuniones — No. 220. IICA Instituto
Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas — OEA. Deutsche Stiftung fiir internationale Entwicklung DSE. DOC
987 A/C. Seminario Internacional sobre: Los Interrelaciones entre Produccion y Financiacion en Associa-
ciones Campesinas. Costa Rica, Noviembre, 1980, p. 13.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e153a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e160" publication-type="other">
J. Tendler, Turning Private Voluntary Organizations into Development Agencies. Questions for Evaluation.
A.I.D. Program Evaluation Discussion Paper No. 12. Washington D.C. 1982, pp. 114-115.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e170a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e177" publication-type="other">
R.I. McKinnon, Money and Capital in Economic Development. Washington D.C. 1973, p. 5.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e185a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e192" publication-type="other">
U Tun Wai, interest Rates outside the Organized Money Markets of Underdeveloped Countries*. IMF Staff
Papers, Vol. 6 (1957), pp. 80 - 83.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e202a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e209" publication-type="other">
U Tun Wai, «Role of Unorganized Financial Markets still Important in Developing Countries*. IMF Survey,
February 23, 1981, p. 56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e219a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e226" publication-type="other">
D.W. Adams, G.I. Nehman, «Borrowing Costs and the Demand for Rural Credit*. The Journal of Develop-
ment Studies, Vol. 15 (1979), No. 2, pp. 165-176.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e236a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e243" publication-type="other">
C. Gonzalez-Vega, interest Rate Restrictions and the Socially Optimun Allocation of Credit*. Savings and
Development, Vol. 4 (1980), No. 1, p. 20.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e253a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e260" publication-type="other">
P. Mottura, «Savings Mobilization in Developing African Countries*. In A Mauri ed., Mobilization of Household
Savings, Finafrica Cariplo, Milan, 1976.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e270a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e277" publication-type="other">
P.K. Quarcoo, «Strategies for Unifying Domestic Capital Markets in LDCs*. Savings and Development,
Vol. 4 (1980), No. 2, pp. 139-155.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e288a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e295" publication-type="other">
R.C. Vogel, «Barriers for Financial Reforms*. Ohio State University, Economics and Sociology Occasional
Paper No. 643, August 1979.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e305a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e312" publication-type="other">
V. Galbis, «Financial Intermediation and Economic Growth in Less-Developed Countries. A Theoretical Ap-
proach*. The Journal of Development Studies, Vol. 13 (1977), No. 2, pp. 58 - 72.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e322a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e329" publication-type="other">
Seminario Internacional: El Credito a Grupos Marginales. Quito, Ecuador. 5 al 15 de Noviembre de 1979.
Fundacion Alemana para el Desarrollo Internacional (DSE); Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas
(IICA): Fundacion Ecuatoriana de Desarrollo (Miembro de SOLIDARIOS), p. 130.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e342a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e349" publication-type="other">
Seminario Internacional op. cit., p. 135.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e356a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e363" publication-type="other">
J.U. Hoist, «The Role of Informal Financial Institutions in the Mobilization of Savings*. In D. Kessler
and P.-A.UIImo eds., Savings and Development, Economica, Paris, 1984, p. 121.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e373a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e380" publication-type="other">
Possinger, Im Vorfeld der Entwicklungsbanken: der basisnahe Revolving-Fund. Paper presented to the
Seminar «Personal and Financial Resources of the Promotion of Development Banks* organized by the
German Foundation for International Development, Berlin, July 11 - 13, 1983.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e394a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e401" publication-type="other">
J. Plata Orozco, «Alternativa para la Amortizacion de Creditos Refaccionarios
en Explotaciones Agropecuarios con Ingresos Constantes». FIRA Boletin Informativa, Vol. 16 (1984), No.
154, pp. 3-33.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e414a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e421" publication-type="other">
J. Tendler op. cit., p. 123.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e428a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e435" publication-type="other">
A. Rudra, «Non-Maximizing Behaviour of Farmers. Crop Selection*. Economic and Political Weekly, Oc-
tober 1, Vol. 18 (1983), p. 1720.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e445a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e452" publication-type="other">
M.A. Ertay, «Group Lending Experience in Turkey*. Newsletter on Rural Financial Market Research and
Policy, No. 12, p. 2.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e462a1310">
            <label>21</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e469" publication-type="other">
R.E. Soles, «Successful Rural Credit Projects in Latin America*. Development Digest, Vol. 16 (1978), No.
3, p. 19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e479a1310">
            <label>22</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e486" publication-type="other">
R.E. Soles, «Agricultural Credit in Latin America: Persistant Problems and Potential Promises*. A.I.D. Spring
Review of Small Farmer Credit, Vol. 16, Washington D.C. 1973, p. 19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e497a1310">
            <label>23</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e504" publication-type="other">
A. Bottomley, interest Rate Determination in Underdeveloped Rural Areas*. In: J.D. Von Pischke, D.W.
Adams, G. Donald (Ed.): Rural Financial Markets in Developing Countries. Their Use and Abuse. Edi Series
in Economic Development. Baltimore and London 1983, pp. 246 - 249.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e517a1310">
            <label>24</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e524" publication-type="other">
J. Von Stockhausen, La Evaluacion Critica del Funcionamiento del Credito con Fondo de Garantia en Otros
Paises aplicado a Fundaciones, Cooperativas y Bancos con y sin la Participacion del Estado. Paper
presented to the Seminar «EI Sistema de Credito con Fondo de Garantia para Financiar Proyectos de
Desarrollo* organized by Hogar y Desarrollo, Guatemala OA., November 6 - 8, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e540a1310">
            <label>25</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e547" publication-type="other">
J. Caviedes Hoyos, Experiencia de SERVIENDA en el Uso del Sistema de Creditos Rotativos. Paper
presented to the Seminar «EI Sistema de Credito con Fondo de Garantia* op. cit.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e557a1310">
            <label>26</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e564" publication-type="other">
U Tun Wai, «Criteria for Judging the Results of Policies to Promote Capital Markets*. Savings and Develop-
ment, Vol. 2 (1978), No. 2, pp. 108-143</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e574a1310">
            <label>27</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e581" publication-type="other">
A. T. Ojo, «Real Estate Financing in Nigeria*. Savings and Development, Vol. 7 (1983), No. 4, p. 340.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e588a1310">
            <label>28</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e595" publication-type="other">
O.M. Gonzalez, Modelo de Otorgamiento de «Nucleos de Credito* en Guatemala. In: ALIDE - DSE - MCA
- SOLIDARIOS: Seminario sobre «Alternativas de Credito a Grupos Marginados* del 30 de Noviembre
al 14 de Diciembre de 1981 en Berlin (Oeste), p. 204.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e609a1310">
            <label>29</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e616" publication-type="other">
J. von Stockhausen, «Peasant Organizations for Agricultural Development*. Quarterly Journal of Interna-
tional Agriculture, Vol. 23 (1984), No. 4, p. 377.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e626a1310">
            <label>30</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e633" publication-type="other">
«Modelo Experimental de Asociacidn entre Productores de Bajos Ingresos (PBI) y Otro Tipo de Productores
(OTP)*. FIRA Boletin Informativo, Vol. 16 (1984), No. 160, pp. 3-16.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d50e643a1310">
            <label>31</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d50e650" publication-type="other">
H. Sethi, «Development is not a Politically Neutral Task*. Ceres, Vol. 16 (1983), No. 3, pp. 19 - 22.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


