<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">phalanx</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50018820</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Phalanx</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Military Operations Research Society in cooperation with the Military Applications Society (MAS) of the Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01951920</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26529493</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>PROFESSIONAL FEATURES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Marine Corps Logistics Command Warehouse Optimization Model</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Coleman</surname>
                  <given-names>Amber</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>Major Amber Coleman is currently the executive officer at Combat Logistics Battalion 6 in Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, and recently transitioned from her position as an operations research analyst at Marine Corps Logistics Command (MARCORLOGCOM) in Albany, Georgia. She graduated from the United States Naval Academy in 2004 with a BS in quantitative economics. She received an MS in supply chain management from Syracuse University in 2012 and an MS in operations research from the Naval Postgraduate School in 2016. Major Coleman’s military experience includes two Operation IRAQI FREEDOM deployments, command at the platoon and company level, and multiple staff-level positions.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Aultman</surname>
                  <given-names>Amanda</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <bio>
                  <p>CWO3 Amanda Aultman is currently stationed aboard Marine Corps Logistics Base, Marine Force Storage Center, Albany, Georgia. She assists the command with planning strategic operations by transporting high-priority military equipment to Marines abroad. Her duties include load planning and loading military aircraft, vessels, rail cars, and tractor trailers. In addition to her primary duties, she supports the command’s storage initiatives by designing optimal storage solutions to maximize storage space and reduce maintenance costs.</p>
               </bio>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>September 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>51</volume>
         <issue>3</issue>
         <issue-id>e26529480</issue-id>
         <fpage>44</fpage>
         <lpage>49</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2018, Military Operations Research Society and Military Application Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26529493"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Commandant of the Marine Corps. 2018. Marine Corps Bulletin 3000, Marine Corps Readiness Reportable Ground Equipment. Retrieved from http://www.marines.mil/Portals/59/Publications/MCBUL%203000%20DTD%2021MAR17.pdf?ver=2017-03-24-080541-860.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lapsley, B. R. 2017. RODBC: ODBC Database Access. R package version 1. 3-15: https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=RODBC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naval Center for Cost Analysis. 2018. NCCA Inflation Indices and Joint Inflation Calculator. Retrieved from https://www.ncca.navy.mil/tools/inflation.cfm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R Core Team. 2017. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. Vienna, Austria. https://www.R-project.org.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
