<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="research-article"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">2353424</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/209756</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JBv71p537</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Corporate Takeovers in the Laboratory When Shareholders Own More than One Share<xref ref-type="fn" rid="FN1">*</xref>
            </article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>C. Bram</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Cadsby</surname>
               </string-name>
               <x xml:space="preserve"/>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_1">University of Guelph</aff>
            <x xml:space="preserve"/>
         </contrib-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Elizabeth</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Maynes</surname>
               </string-name>
               <x xml:space="preserve"/>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_2">York University</aff>
            <x xml:space="preserve"/>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>10</month>
            <year>1998</year>
            <string-date>October 1998</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>71</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.1998.71.issue-4</issue-id>
         <fpage>537</fpage>
         <lpage>572</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 1998 by The University of Chicago. All rights reserved.</copyright-statement>
            <copyright-year>1998</copyright-year>
            <copyright-holder>The University of Chicago</copyright-holder>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/209756"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>Tendering decisions of shareholders endowed with multiple shares are studied in the laboratory to test game‐theoretic models of the tendering process. Tendered shares cycle around the equilibrium level. Contrary to game‐theoretic predictions, bid level and bid type affect the number of shares tendered and the bid success rate. When players are given unequal endowments of shares, an equal proportion strategy organizes the data better than Holmstrom and Nalebuff's symmetric focal equilibrium in which larger shareholders tender down to a common share level. However, large shareholders often tender proportionately more shares than small shareholders.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
      <notes notes-type="footnote">
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="FN1">
               <label>*</label>
               <p>We thank Merwan Engineer for suggesting that we under take experiments on takeovers and Douglas Diamond, editor in‐chief of this journal, an anonymous referee, and Stuart Mestelman for helpful comments and suggestions. We also thank participants in the McMaster University Economics Workshop, the Bond University School of Business Seminar Series, the Spring 1996 Economic Science Association Meetings, the 1996 Northern Finance Association Conference, the 1997 Econometric Society Australian Meetings, and the 1997 Financial Management Association Conference for helpful comments. Financial support from the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada, grant 410‐93‐0331, is gratefully acknowledged. Address correspondence to C. Bram Cadsby, Department of Economics, University of Guelph, Guelph, Ontario, Canada, N1G 2W1. E‐mail: Bram@css.uoguelph.ca.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </notes>
   </front>
</article>
