<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278187</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Development of Dynamic Constraint Models for a Model Based Transient Calibration Process</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Brahma</surname>
                  <given-names>Indranil</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Bucknell Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>813</fpage>
         <lpage>827</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278187"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Model based calibration has gained popularity in recent years as a method to optimize increasingly complex engine systems. However virtually all model based techniques are applied to steady state calibration. Transient calibration is by and large an emerging technology. An important piece of any transient calibration process is the ability to constrain the optimizer to treat the problem as a dynamic one and not as a quasi-static process. The optimized air-handling parameters corresponding to any instant of time must be achievable in a transient sense; this in turn depends on the trajectory of the same parameters over previous time instances. In this work dynamic constraint models have been proposed to translate commanded to actually achieved air-handling parameters. These models enable the optimization to be realistic in a transient sense. The air handling system has been treated as a linear second order system with PD control. Parameters for this second order system have been extracted from real transient data. The model has been shown to be the best choice relative to a list of appropriate candidates such as neural networks and first order models. The selected second order model was used in conjunction with transient emission models to predict emissions over the FTP cycle. It has been shown that emission predictions based on air-handing parameters predicted by the dynamic constraint model do not differ significantly from corresponding emissions based on measured air-handling parameters.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I. and Rutland, C.J., “Optimization of Diesel Engine Operating Parameters Using Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3228, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-3228.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stuhler, H., Kruse, T., Stuber, A., Gschweitl, K. et al., “Automated Model-Based GDI Engine Calibration Adaptive Online DoE Approach,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0708, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0708.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nozaki, Y., Fukuma, T., and Tanaka, K., “Development of a Rule-based Calibration Method for Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0044, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-0044.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rask, E. and Sellnau, M., “Simulation-Based Engine Calibration: Tools, Techniques, and Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1264, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suzuki, K., Nemoto, M., and Machida, K., “Model-Based Calibration Process for Producing Optimal Spark Advance in a Gasoline Engine Equipped with a Variable Valve Train,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3235, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-3235.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montgomery, D.T. and Reitz, R.D., “Optimization of Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine Operating Parameters Using a Response Surface Method,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1962, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, S.P., Pilley, A.D., Michon, S., and Fournier, G., “The Optimisation of Common Rail FIE Equipped Engines Through the Use of Statistical Experimental Design, Mathematical Modelling and Genetic Algorithms,” SAE Technical Paper 970346, 1997, doi:10.4271/970346.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montgomery, D.T. and Reitz, R.D., “Effects of Multiple Injections and Flexible Control of Boost and EGR on Emissions and Fuel Consumption of a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0195, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0195.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burk, R., Jacquelin, F., and Wakeman, R., “A Contribution to Predictive Engine Calibration Based on Vehicle Drive Cycle Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-0225, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0225.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dimopoulos, P., Schöni, A., Eggimann, A., Sparti, C. et al., “Statistical Methods for Solving the Fuel Consumption/Emission Conflict on DI-Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1077, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kampermühler, F.T., Paulitsch, R., and Gschweitl, K., “Automatic ECU-Calibration - An Alternative to Conventional Methods,” SAE Technical Paper 930395, 1993, doi:10.4271/930395.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schmitz, G., Oligschläger, U., Eifler, G., and Lechner, H., “Automated System for Optimized Calibration of Engine Management Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 940151, 1994, doi:10.4271/940151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brooks, T., Lumsden, G., and Blaxill, H., “Improving Base Engine Calibrations for Diesel Vehicles Through the Use of DoE and Optimization Techniques,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3833, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3833.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knafl, A., Hagena, J.R., Filipi, Z.S., and Assanis, D.N., “Dual-Use Engine Calibration: Leveraging Modern Technologies to Improve Performance-Emissions Tradeoff,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1549, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-1549.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Desantes, J.M, López, J.J., Garcia, J.M., and Hernández, L., “Application of Neural Networks for Prediction and Optimization of Exhaust Emissions in a H.D. Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1144, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-1144.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, C., Allain, M., and Zhang, H., “Using Model- Based Rapid Transient Calibration to Reduce Fuel Consumption and Emissions in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-1365, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-1365.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, C. and Mott, G., “Dynamic Model-Based Calibration Optimization: An Introduction and Application to Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0026, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0026.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Westlund, A. and Ångström, H.-E., “Fast Physical Emission Predictions for Off-line Calibration of Transient Control Strategies,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1778, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1778.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., Sharp, M.C., and Frazier, T.R., “Empirical Modeling of Transient Emissions and Transient Response for Transient Optimization”, SAE International Journal of Engines, October 2009 Volume 2, pp 1433-1443.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., Sharp, M.C., and Chi, J.N., “Development of a Model Based Transient Calibration Process: for Diesel Engine ECM tables: Part 1-Data Requirements, Processing and Analysis” Manuscript in Review.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., Chi, J.N., and Sharp, M.C., “Development of a Model Based Transient Calibration Process: for Diesel Engine ECM tables: Part 2-Modeling and Optimization” Manuscript in Review.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., Chi, J.N., and Sharp, M.C., and Frazier, T.R., “Development of the Nearest Neighbor Multivariate Localized Regression Modeling Technique for Steady State Engine Calibration and Comparison With Neural Networks and Global Regression”, International Journal of Engine Research, Volume 9, Number 4, 2008, pp. 297-323(27), 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qiang, H., Fuyuan, Y., Ming, Z., and Minggao, O., “Study on Modeling Method for Common Rail Diesel Engine Calibration and Optimization,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0426, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Guerrier, M. and Cawsey, P., “The Development of Model Based Methodologies for Gasoline IC Engine Calibration,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-1466, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-1466.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bayer, J. and Foster, D.E., “Zero-Dimensional Soot Modeling,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-1070, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-1070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., Rutland, C.J., Foster, D.E., and He, Y., “A New Approach to System Level Soot Modeling,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-1122, 2005, doi: 10.4271/2005-01-1122.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mowll, D., Robinson, D.R., and Pilley, A.D., “Bayesian Experimental Design and its Application to Engine Research and Development,” SAE Technical Paper 961157, 1996, doi: 10.4271/961157.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mowll, D., Robinson, D.R., and Pilley, A.D., “Optimising Engine Performance and Emissions Using Bayesian Techniques,” SAE Technical Paper 971612, 1997, doi:10.4271/971612.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rasmussen, E., and Williams, C.K.I., ‘Gaussian Processes for Machine Learning’, MIT Press, Cambridge, MA, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schaal, S., Atkeson, C. and Vijayakumar, S., “Real time robot learning with locally weighted statistical learning”, Proc. International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA2000), San Francisco, California, vol.1, pp.288-293, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shakhranovich, G., Darrell, T. and Indyk, P., ‘Nearest Neighbor Methods in Learning and Vision’, MIT Press, Cambridge, MA, pp. 103-142, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vijayakumar, S., and Schaal, S., “LWPR : An O(n) Algorithm for Incremental Real Time Learning in High Dimensional Space” Proc. of Seventeenth International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML2000) Stanford, California, pp. 1079-1086, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schaal, S., Atkeson, C. and Vijayakumar, S., ”Scalable Locally Weighted Statistical Techniques for Real Time Robo Learning”, Applied Intelligence - Special issue on Scalable Robotic Applications of Neural Networks Vol. 17, No.1, pp. 49-60, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, Y. and Rutland, C.J., “Modeling of a Turbocharged DI Diesel Engine Using Artificial Neural Networks,” SAE Technics Paper 2002-01-2772, 2002, doi: 10.4271/2002-01-2772.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, Y., “Development of a Diesel Engine Simulation Tool using Artificial Neural Networks”, Ph.D thesis, Dept. of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, Y. and Rutland, C.J., “Application of Artificial Neural Networks in Engine Modeling,” International Journal of Engine Research, Vol. 5, No 4, Page 281-296, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brahma, I., He, Y., and Rutland, C.J., “Improvement of Neural Network Accuracy for Engine Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01-3227, 2003, doi: 10.4271/2003-01-3227.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller, R. and Schneider, B., “Approximation and Control of Engine Torque Using Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0929, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0929.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Müller, R. and Hemberger, H.-H., “Neural Adaptive Ignition Control,” SAE Technical Paper 981057, 1998, doi: 10.4271/981057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hellring, M., Munther, T., Rögnvaldsson, T., Wickström, N. et al., “Spark Advance Control Using the Ion Current and Neural Soft Sensors,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1162, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1162.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Grimaldi, C.N. and Mariani, F., “OBD Engine Fault Detection Using a Neural Approach,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0559, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0559.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Traver, M.L., Atkinson, R.J., and Atkinson, C.M., “Neural Network-Based Diesel Engine Emissions Prediction Using In-Cylinder Combustion Pressure,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1532, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atkinson, C.M., Long, T.W., and Hanzevack, E.L., “Virtual Sensing: A Neural Network-based Intelligent Performance and Emissions Prediction System for On-Board Diagnostics and Engine Control,” SAE Technical Paper 980516, 1998, doi:10.4271/980516.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ayeb, M., Lichtenthäler, D., Winsel, T., and Theuerkauf, H.J., “SI Engine Modeling Using Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 980790, 1998, doi:10.4271/980790.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lichtenthäler, D., Ayeb, M., Theuerkauf, H.J., and Winsel, T., “Improving Real-Time SI Engine Models by Integration of Neural Approximators,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1164, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1164.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hentschel, R., Cernat, R.-M., and Varchmin, J.-U., “In- Car Modelling of Emissions with Dynamic Artificial Neural Networks,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-3383, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-3383.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, L., Quek, H.C., Tee, K.H. and Zhou, N., “Optimal Size of a Feedforward Neural Network: How Much does it Matter?”, Autonomic and Autonomous Systems and International Conference on Networking and Services, 2005. ICAS-ICNS 2005. Joint International Conference on Volume, Issue, 23-28 Oct. 2005 Page(s): 69 - 69, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
