<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275461</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Light Duty Diesel Engine</article-title>
            <subtitle>Optimization of Performances, Noxious Emission and Radiated Noise</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Costa</surname>
                  <given-names>M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori – CNR – ITALY – Viale Marconi, 8 – 80125 Naples, ITALY</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Siano</surname>
                  <given-names>D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori – CNR – ITALY – Viale Marconi, 8 – 80125 Naples, ITALY</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Allocca</surname>
                  <given-names>L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori – CNR – ITALY – Viale Marconi, 8 – 80125 Naples, ITALY</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Montanaro</surname>
                  <given-names>A.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Istituto Motori – CNR – ITALY – Viale Marconi, 8 – 80125 Naples, ITALY</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Bozza</surname>
                  <given-names>F.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DIME – Università di Napoli – ITALY – Via Claudio, 21 – 80125 Naples, ITALY</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275401</issue-id>
         <fpage>740</fpage>
         <lpage>748</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2009 SAE Japan and Copyright © 2009 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275461"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The paper aims at performing an environmental and energetic optimization of a naturally aspirated, light-duty direct injection (DI) diesel engine, equipped with a Common Rail injection system.</p>
            <p>Injection modulation into up to three pulses is considered starting from an experimental campaign conducted under non-evaporative conditions in a quiescent optically-accessible cylindrical vessel containing nitrogen at different densities. The engine performances in terms of power and emitted NOx and soot are reproduced by multidimensional modelling of the in-cylinder processes. The radiated noise is evaluated by resorting to a recently developed methodology, based on the decomposition of the CFD 3D computed in-cylinder pressure signal. Once validated, both the CFD and the acoustic procedures are applied to the simulation of the prototype engine and are coupled to an external optimizer with the aim of minimizing fuel consumption, pollutant emissions and radiated noise.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siano D., Bozza F., Costa M., “Optimal Design of a Two-Stroke Diesel Engine for Aeronautical Applications Concerning both Thermofluidynamic and Acoustic Issues”, IMECE2008-68713, Proceedings of 2008 ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition, November 2008, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Stotz, J. Schommers, F. Duvinage, A. Petrs, S. Ellwanger, K. Koynagi, H. Gildein, “Potential of Common-Rail Injection System for Passenger Car Di Diesel Engines”, SAE Paper 2000-01-0944, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bression, G., Soleri, D., Savy, S., Dehoux, S. et al., "A Study of Methods to Lower HC and CO Emissions in Diesel HCCI," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):37-49, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zavala P.A.G., Pinto M.G, Pavanello R., Vaqueiro J., “Comprehensive Combustion Noise Optimization”,Sae Paper 2001-01-1509, 2001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N. Shimazaki, T. Tsurushima, T. Nishimura,”Dual Mode Combustion Concept with Premixed Diesel Combustion by Direct Injection Near Top Dead Center”, SAE 2003-01-0742, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., Hildingsson, L. and Johansson, B., “Low NOx and Low Smoke Operation of a Diesel Engine using Gasoline-like Fuels “, ASME Paper #ICES2009-76034</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., “Is Gasoline the Best Fuel for Advanced Diesel Engines? – Fuel Effects in “Premixed-Enough” compression ignition Engines”, Towards Clean Diesel Engines, TCDE2009</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Yun, M. Sellnau, N. Milovanovic, and, S. Zuelch, “Development of Premixed Low-Temperature Diesel Combustion in a HSDI Diesel Engine”, SAE Paper 2008-01-0639, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Papalambros, P.V., and Wilde, D.J., “Principles of Optimal Design Modeling and Computation”, Cambribde University Press, Cambridge, 2000</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stephenson P.W., “Multi-Objective Optimization of a Charge Air Cooler using modeFRONTIER and Computational Fluid Dynamics”, SAE Paper 2008- 01-0886, 2008</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Costa, D. Siano, G. Valentino, F. E. Corcione, F. Bozza, “Prediction and Optimization of the Performances, Noxious Emissions and Radiated Noise of a Light Duty Common-Rail Diesel Engine”, proceedings of 9th International Conference on Engines and Vehicles (ICE2009), Capri, Italy, September 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ISO 9614/1, ”Acoustics-Determination of sound power levels of noise sources using sound intensity-Part 1:Measurement at discrete points”, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W. Bosch – SAE Paper 660794</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alfuso, S., Allocca, L., Corcione, F.E., di Stasio S.: “Image Diagnostics of Common Rail Diesel Sprays Evolving in Nytrogen Ambient at Different Densities” ICE’99 Internal Combustion Engines: Experiments and Modeling, Capri 12-16 September, 1999</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">di Stasio S., Alfuso, S., Allocca, L., Corcione F.E.: “Experimental Study on the Atomization Mechanism for Fuel Sprays Evolving in Atmospheres of Different Nature and Density” - ImechE Seminar Publication 1999-17, pp.241-255</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S. Alfuso, L. Allocca, M. Auriemma, G. Caputo, F.E. Corcione, A. Montanaro, G. Valentino: “Analysis of a High Pressure Diesel Spray at High Pressure and Temperature Environment Conditions”, SAE Paper 2005-01-1239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L. Allocca, F.E. Corcione, M. Costa: “Numerical and Experimental Analysis of Multiple Injection Diesel Sprays”, SAE Paper 2004-01-1879</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. D., Siebers, D. L.: “Effect of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays”, SAE Paper 960034, 1996</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu A.B., Reitz R.D.: "Modeling the Effects of Drop Drag and Break-up on Fuel Sprays", SAE 930072, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Rourke P.J.: “Statistical Properties and Numerical Implementation of a Model for Droplet Dispersion in Turbulent Gas”, J. Comput. Physics 83, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dukowicz J.K.: "A Particle-Fluid Numerical Model for Liquid Sprays", J. Comp. Physics, 35, 229-253, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colin O., Benkenida A.: "The 3-Zones Extended Coherent Flame Model (ECFM3Z) for Computing Premixed/Diffusion Combustion", Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology, IFP, Vol. 59, N. 6, pp. 593-609, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa A.J., Broatch A., Martın J., Monelletta L., “Combustion noise level assessment in direct injection Diesel engines by means of in-cylinder pressure components”, Meas. Sci. Technol., 18 2131-2142, doi:10.1088/0957-0233/18/7/045, 2007</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F Payri, A Broatch, B Tormos and V Marant, “New methodology for in-cylinder pressure analysis in direct injection diesel engines—application to combustion noise”, Meas. Sci. Technol. 16 (2005) 540–547 doi:10.1088/0957-0233/16/2/029</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sasaki, D., 2005, “ARMOGA, An efficient Multi-Objective Genetic Algorithm”, Technical Report, January 2005</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
