<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejtransafe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019983</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Transportation Safety</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">23275626</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23275634</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26169243</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Self-Regulation Minimizes Crash Risk from Attentional Effects of Cognitive Load during Auditory-Vocal Tasks</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Young</surname>
                  <given-names>Richard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Wayne State Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>April 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26169238</issue-id>
         <fpage>67</fpage>
         <lpage>85</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26169243"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This study reanalyzes the data from a recent experimental report from the University of Utah investigating the effect on driving performance of auditory-vocal secondary tasks (such as cell phone and passenger conversations, speech-to-text, and a complex artificial cognitive task). The current objective is to estimate the relative risk of crashes associated with such auditory-vocal tasks. Contrary to the Utah study's assumption of an increase in crash risk from the attentional effects of cognitive load, a deeper analysis of the Utah data shows that driver self-regulation provides an effective countermeasure that offsets possible increases in crash risk. For example, drivers self-regulated their following distances to compensate for the slight increases in brake response time while performing auditory-vocal tasks. This new finding is supported by naturalistic driving data showing that cell phone conversation does not increase crash risk above that of normal baseline driving. The Utah data are next compared to those from a larger study that included visual-manual as well as auditory-vocal tasks. The Utah auditory-vocal tasks had negligible effects on response time compared to visual-manual tasks with socially acceptable crash risk, such as manual radio tuning. In conclusion, auditory-vocal tasks such as those in the Utah study are not expected to increase crash risk or impair real-world operation of an automobile, compared to normal baseline driving without performing such tasks.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D. L., Cooper, J. M., Turrill, J., Coleman, J., Medeiros- Ward, N., and Biondi, F., “Measuring Cognitive Distraction in the Automobile,” AAA Foundation for Traffic Safety, Washington, DC, https://www.aaafoundation.org/sites/default/files/MeasuringCognitiveDistractions.pdf, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angell, L., Auflick, J., Austria, P., Kochhar, D. et al., “Driver Workload Metrics Task 2 Final Report,” DOT HS 810 635, Crash Avoidance Metrics Partnership (CAMP), http://www.nhtsa.gov/DOT/NHTSA/NRD/Multimedia/PDFs/Crash%20Avoidance/Driver%20Distraction/Driver%20Workload%20Metrics%20 Final%20Report.pdf, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, K.L., Regan, M.A., and Lee, J.D. “Factors Moderating the Impact of Distraction on Driving Performance and Safety.” Chap. 19 in Driver Distraction: Theory, Effects and Mitigation, Lee JD Regan MA, and Young KL (Eds.), 335-351. Florida, USA: CRC Press, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A. and Schreiner, C., “Real-World Personal Conversations Using a Hands-Free Embedded Wireless Device While Driving: Effect on Airbag-Deployment Crash Rates,” Risk Analysis 29(2):187-204, 2009, doi:10.1111/j.1539-6924.2008.01146.x.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hsieh, L., Young, R.A., Bowyer, S.M., and Moran, J.E., “Conversation Effects on Driving: Neural Mechanisms Underlying Reaction Times to Visual Events,” presented at Fourth International Driving Symposium on Human Factors in Driver Assessment, Training and Vehicle Design, Stevenson, WA, http://drivingassessment.uiowa.edu/DA2007/PDF/082_HsiehYoung.pdf, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A., Seaman, S., and Hsieh, L., “Measuring Cognitive Distraction on the Road and in the Lab with the Wayne State Detection Response Task,” presented at 91st Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board, Washington, D.C., http://amonline.trb.org/211ign/1, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D.L., University of Utah, personal communication, Sept. 25, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A. “Self-Regulation Reduces Crash Risk from the Attentional Effects of Cognitive Load from Auditory-Vocal Tasks,” Poster and compendium of papers from Transportation Research Board, Washington, DC, Jan. 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Biondi, F., University of Utah, personal communication, Jan. 13, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Muttart, J.W., “Quantifying Driver Response Times Based Upon Research and Real Life Data,” Third International Driving Symposium on Human Factors in Driver Assessment, Training, and Vehicle Design, http://drivingassessment.uiowa.edu/DA2005/PDF/03_Muttartformat.pdf, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D.L., Drews, F.A., and Johnston, W.A., “Cell Phone- Induced Failures of Visual Attention During Simulated Driving,” Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied 9(1):23-32, http://distraction.tombras.com/research/PDFFiles/failures_of_visual_attention.pdf, 2003, doi:10.1037/1076-898X.9.1.23.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D.L., Cooper, J.M., and Drews, F.A., “What Do Drivers Fail to See When Conversing on a Cell Phone?”, Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting 48(19):2213-2217, http://www.psych.utah.edu/AppliedCognitionLab/HFES2004-000804-1.pdf, Sept. 1, 2004, doi:10.1177/154193120404801902.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D.L., Drews, F.A., Crouch, D.J., and Johnston, W.A., “Why Do Cell Phone Conversations Interfere with Driving?” In Cognitive Technology: Essays on the Transformation of Thought and Society, McFarland &amp; Company Inc., Jefferson, NC, pp. 51-68, http://www.bvsde.paho.org/bvsacd/cd57/whydo.pdf, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D.L., Drews, F.A., and Crouch, D.J., “A Comparison of the Cell Phone Driver and the Drunk Driver,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 48(2):381-391, http://www.distraction.gov/download/researchpdf/Comparison-of-CellPhone-Driver-Drunk-Driver.pdf, 2006, doi:10.1518/001872006777724471.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D. and Drews, F., “Profiles in Driver Distraction: Effects of Cell Phone Conversations on Younger and Older Drivers,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 46(4):640-649, www.psych.utah.edu/AppliedCognitionLab/StrayerHFES04.pdf, 2004, doi:10.1518/hfes.46.4.640.56806.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Drews, F.A., Pasupathi, M. and Strayer, D.L., “Passenger and Cell Phone Conversations in Simulated Driving,” Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied 14(4):392-400, https://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-58249134281&amp;partnerID =40&amp;md5=fcc3e4bdbd226eb2e2c1e1a8726da0b4, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D., Cooper, J. and Drews, F. “Profiles in Cell Phone- Induced Driver Distraction.” In Handbook of Driving Simulation for Engineering, Medicine, and Psychology. CRC Press, 2011, doi:10.1201/b10836-28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Strayer, D.L., Watson, J.M. and Drews, F.A. “Chapter 2 - Cognitive Distraction While Multitasking in the Automobile.” In Psychology of Learning and Motivation, edited by Brian H. Ross. 29-58. NY: Academic Press, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780123855275000024, 2011, doi:10.1016/b978-0-12-385527-5.00002-4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jamson, A.H., Westerman, S.J., Hockey, G.R.J., and Carsten, O.M.J., “Speech-Based E-Mail and Driver Behavior: Effects of an in-Vehicle Message System Interface,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 46(4):625-639, 2004, doi:10.1518/hfes.46.4.625.56814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ranney, T., Watson, G., Mazzae, E., Papelis, Y., Ahmad, O. and Wightman, J., “Examination of the Distraction Effects of Wireless Phone Interfaces Using the National Advanced Driving Simulator- Preliminary Report on a Freeway Study (DOT HS 809 737),” U.S. Department of Transportation, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), Washington, DC. 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kircher, A., Vogel, K., Törnros, J., Bolling, A. et al., “Mobile Telephone Simulator Study,” Swedish National Road and Transport Research Institute (VTI), Linköping, Sweden, http://www.vti.se/EPiBrowser/Publikationer%20-%20English/M969A.pdf, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yannis, G., Papadimitriou, E., Karekla, X. and Kontodima, E., “Mobile Phone Use by Young Drivers: Effects on Traffic Speed and Headways,” Transportation Planning and Technology 33(4):385-394, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rosenbloom, T., “Driving Performance While Using Cell Phones: An Observational Study,” Journal of Safety Research 37(2):207-212, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022437506000326, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fitch, G.M., Soccolich, S.A., Guo, F., McClafferty, J. et al., “The Impact of Hand-Held and Hands-Free Cell Phone Use on Driving Performance and Safety-Critical Event Risk Final Report,” DOT HS 811 757, NHTSA, Washington, D.C., http://www.distraction.gov/download/811757.pdf, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tobias, A. “Meta-Analysis of P-Values.” In Meta-Analysis: An Updated Collection from the Stata Journal, edited by Sterne Jonathan. 65-68. College Station, Texas: Stata Press, http://www.amazon.com/dp/1597180491/ref=rdr_ext_tmb#reader_1597180491, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evans, L. and Wasielewski, P., “Do Accident-Involved Drivers Exhibit Riskier Everyday Driving Behavior?”, Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 14(1):57-64, 1982, doi:10.1016/0001-4575(82)90007-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harbluk, J.L., Noy, Y.I., Trbovich, P.L., and Eizenman, M., “An On-Road Assessment of Cognitive Distraction: Impacts on Drivers' Visual Behavior and Braking Performance,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 39(2):372-79, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.aap.2006.08.013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gruzdaitis, L., Karola, J., Kotiranta, H., Lamble, D. et al., “Mental Load and Visual Search at Street Crossings,” proceedings of 3rd International Conference on Traffic and Transport Psychology, Nottingham, UK, http://www.psyko.helsinki.fi/psyko/Psykolog.ns f/0/7ad9629cd50c7b06c2256f9b00390ef9/$FILE/ATTVUM6D/Gruzdaitis%20Mental%20load%20and%20visual%20search_poster%20v21_040901.pdf, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, K.L. and Lenné, M.G., “Driver Engagement in Distracting Activities and the Strategies Used to Minimise Risk,” Safety Science 48(3):326-332, 2010, doi:10.1016/j.ssci.2009.10.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cooper, J.M., Vladisavljevic, I., Strayer, D.L., Martin, P.T. et al., “Drivers' Lane Changing Behavior While Conversing an a Cell Phone in a Variable Density Simulated Highway Environment,” Proceedings of the 87th Annual Meeting of Transportation Research Board, Washington, DC, http://www.psych.utah.edu/AppliedCognitionLab/LC.pdf, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, I.D., “A Comparison of Two Subsidiary Tasks Used to Measure Fatigue in Car Drivers,” Ergonomics 8(4):467-473, Oct. 01, 1965, doi:10.1080/00140136508930827.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brown, I.D., Tickner, A.H. and Simmonds, D.C., “Interference between Concurrent Tasks of Driving and Telephoning,” Journal of Applied Psychology 53(5):419-424, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/B6WY3-4NRKJBN-J/2/d62bdebd53eaf78714a7854240fac3c7, 1969.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harms, L., “Drivers' Attentional Responses to Environmental Variations: A Dual-Task Real Traffic Study,” Proceedings of Vision in Vehicles I, North Holland, Amsterdam, 1986.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fairclough, S., Ashby, M., Ross, T. and Parkes, A., “Effects of Handsfree Telephone Use on Driving Behaviour,” Proceedings of ISATAS International Symposium on Automotive Technology and Automation, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harms, L., “Variation in Drivers Cognitive Load - Effects of Driving through Village Areas and Rural Junctions,” Ergonomics 34(2):151-160, Feb 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alm, H. and Nilsson, L., “The Effects of a Mobile Telephone Task on Driver Behaviour in a Car Following Situation,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 27(5):707-715, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/B6V5S-3YF4N0S-T/2/e4404eb14a11024915d4bca6a8e0cd5e, 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Waugh, J.D., Glumm, M.M., Kilduff, P.W., Tauson, R.A. et al., “Cognitive Workload While Driving and Talking on a Cellular Phone or to a Passenger,” Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting 44(33):6-276-276-279, http://pro.sagepub.com/content/44/33/6-276.abstract, July 1, 2000, doi:10.1177/154193120004403354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haigney, D., Taylor, R. and Westerman, S., “Concurrent Mobile (Cellular) Phone Use and Driving Performance: Task Demand Characteristics and Compensatory Processes,” Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour 3(3):113-121, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishida, T. and Matsuura, T., “The Effect of Cellular Phone Use on Driving Performance,” ATSS research 25(2):6-14, http://www.iatss. or.jp/common/pdf/en/publication/iatss-research/25-2-01.pdf, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Burns, P., Parkes, A., Burton, S., Smith, R. et al., “How Dangerous Is Driving with a Mobile Phone? Benchmarking the Impairment to Alcohol,” TRL REPORT 547, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, X.S., McConkie, G.W. and Tai, Y.-C., “The Effect of Secondary Tasks on Drivers' Scanning Behavior,” Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting 47(16):1900-1903, http://pro.sagepub.com/content/47/16/1900. abstract, Oct. 1, 2003, doi:10.1177/154193120304701614.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, K., Regan, M. and Hammer, M., “Driver Distraction: A Review of the Literature,” Report Number 206, Monash University Accident Research Centre, Victoria, Australia, http://www.monash. edu.au/muarc/reports/muarc206.pdf. 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parkes, A., Burns, P., Burton, S., Smith, R. et al., “Conversations in Cars: The Relative Hazards of Mobile Phones Final Report,” http://www.mthr.org.uk/research_projects/mthr_funded_projects/documents/TRLReportFinalforweb.pdf, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jamson, A.H., Westerman, S.J., Hockey, G.R.J. and Carsten, O.M.J., “Speech-Based E-Mail and Driver Behavior: Effects of an in-Vehicle Message System Interface,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 46(4):625-639, http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15709325, 2004, doi:10.1518/hfes.46.4.625.56814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakauskas, M.E., Gugerty, L.J. and Ward, N.J., “Effects of Naturalistic Cell Phone Conversations on Driving Performance,” Journal of Safety Research 35(4):453-464, 2004, doi:10.1016/j. jsr.2004.06.003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Törnros, J.E.B. and Bolling, A.K., “Mobile Phone Use - Effects of Handheld and Handsfree Phones on Driving Performance,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 37(5):902-909, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/B6V5S-4GBWJJ9-1/2/7b617fcdd ad0ea7348cd04d777e39065, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hogema, J.H., Veltman, J.A. and Van 't Hof, A., “Effects of Motorway Lighting on Workload and Driving Behavior,” Proceedings of ICTTP 2004: Traffic &amp; Transport Psychology - Theory and Application, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jamson, A. and Merat, N., “Surrogate in-Vehicle Information Systems and Driver Behaviour: Effects of Visual and Cognitive Load in Simulated Rural Driving,” Transportation Research Part F 8:79-96, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.trf.2005.04.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Törnros, J. and Bolling, A., “Mobile Phone Use - Effects of Conversation on Mental Workload and Driving Speed in Rural and Urban Environments,” Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour 9(4):298-306, http://www.sciencedirect. com/science/article/pii/S1369847806000192, 7//2006, doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.trf.2006.01.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horberry, T., Anderson, J., Regan, M.A., Triggs, T.J. et al., “Driver Distraction: The Effects of Concurrent in-Vehicle Tasks, Road Environment Complexity and Age on Driving Performance,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 38(1):185-191, 2006, doi:10.1016/j. aap.2005.09.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.J. and Chen, H.I. “Verbal and Cognitive Distractors in Driving Performance While Using Hands-Free Phones 1, 2,” Perceptual and Motor Skills 103(3):803-810, 2006, doi:10.2466/pms.103.3.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lerner, N., Singer, J., and Huey, R., “Driver Strategies for Engaging in Distracting Tasks Using In-Vehicle Technologies,” HS DOT 810 919, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, DC, http://www.nhtsa.gov/DOT/NHTSA/NRD/Multimedia/PDFs/Crash%20Avoidance/2008/DOT%20HS%20810%20919_1.pdf, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Caird, J.K., Willness, C.R., Steel, P., and Scialfa, C., “A Meta- Analysis of the Effects of Cell Phones on Driver Performance,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 40(4):1282-1293, 2008, doi:10.1016/j.aap.2005.09.007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tan, P.H. and Lee, Y.C., “Effect of Perceptual and Cognitive Loads on Drivers' Attention and Resistance to Distractors,” Proceedings, San Antonio, TX, http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2- s2.0-77951553407&amp;partnerID=40&amp;md5=4ca32b88b7226389a6f8e df45d0c9a20, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehler, B., Reimer, B., Coughlin, J. and Dusek, J., “Impact of Incremental Increases in Cognitive Workload on Physiological Arousal and Performance in Young Adult Drivers,” Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board 2138(1):6-12, 2009, doi:10.3141/2138-02.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, K.L. and Lenné, M.G., “Driver Engagement in Distracting Activities and the Strategies Used to Minimise Risk,” Safety Science 48(3):326-332, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0925753509001891, 2010. doi:http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ssci.2009.10.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mehler, B., Reimer, B. and Coughlin, J.F., “Sensitivity of Physiological Measures for Detecting Systematic Variations in Cognitive Demand from a Working Memory Task: An on-Road Study across Three Age Groups,” Human Factors 54(3):396-412, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Landau, A., Metz, B. and Neukum, A., “Different Ways to Compensate Distraction While Using a Hands-Free Telephone in a Vehicle,” Proceedings of 3rd International Conference on Driver Distraction and Inattention, Gothenburg, Sweden, Sept. 4-6, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shinar, D., “Traffic Safety and Human Behaviour,” United Kingdom: Emerald Group Publishing, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kloeden, C.N., McLean, A.J., Moore, V.M., and Ponte, G., “Travelling Speed and the Risk of Crash Involvement. Volume 1: Findings,” CR 172, Federal Office of Road Safety, Canberra, Australia, http://www.infrastructure.gov.au/roads/safety/publications/1997/pdf/Speed_Risk_1.pdf, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kloeden, C.N., Ponte, G., and McLean, A.J., “Travelling Speed and the Risk of Crash Involvement on Rural Roads,” Australian Transport Safety Bureau, http://www.infrastructure.gov.au/roads/safety/publications/2001/pdf/Rural_Speed_1.pdf, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kloeden, C.N., McLean, A.J. and Glonek, G., “Reanalysis of Travelling Speed and the Rate of Crash Involvement in Adelaide South Australia,” CR 207, Civic Square, Australia, http://www.infrastructure.gov.au/roads/safety/publications/2002/pdf/Speed_Risk_3.pdf, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horberry, T., “Speed Choice by Drivers: The Issue of Driving Too Slowly,” Ergonomics 47(14):1561-1570, 11 2004, doi:10.1080/0014 0130412331290925.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brookhuis, K., de Vries, G. and de Waard, D., “The Effects of Mobile Telephoning on Driving Performance,” Accident Analysis and Prevention 23(4):309-316, 1991, doi:10.1016/0001-4575(91)90008-S.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Serafin, C., Wen, C., Paelke, G. and Green, P., “Car Phone Usability: A Human Factors Laboratory Test,” Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting 37(3):220-224, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Green, P., Hoekstra, E. and Williams, M., “Further on-the-Road Tests of Driver Interfaces: Examination of a Route Guidance System and a Car Phone,” University of Michigan Transportation Research Institute (Technical Report No. 93-35), 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parkes, A., Burns, P., Burton, S., Smith, R. et al., “Conversations in Cars: The Relative Hazards of Mobile Phones Final Report,” http://www.mthr.org.uk/research_projects/mthr_funded_projects/documents/TRLReportFinalforweb.pdf, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>68.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jamson, A.H., Westerman, S.J., Hockey, G.R.J. and Carsten, O.M.J., “Speech-Based E-Mail and Driver Behavior: Effects of an in-Vehicle Message System Interface,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 46(4):625-639, http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15709325, 2004, doi:10.1518/hfes.46.4.625.56814.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>69.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Östlund, J., Nilsson, L., Carsten, O., Merat, N. et al., “Deliverable 2-Hmi and Safety-Related Driver Performance. Human Machine Interface and the Safety of Traffic in Europe,” Project HASTE GRD1/2000/25361 S 12, http://www.its.leeds.ac.uk/projects/haste/Haste%20D2%20v1-3%20small.pdf, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>70.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Östlund, J., Peters, B., Thorslund, B., Engström, J. et al., “Driving Performance Assessment - Methods and Metrics, AIDE Deliverable 2.2.5,” VTI, the Swedish National Road and Transport Research Institute, Linköping, Sweden, http://www.aide-eu.org/pdf/sp2_deliv_new/aide_d2_2_5.pdf. 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <label>71.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jamson, A. and Merat, N., “Surrogate in-Vehicle Information Systems and Driver Behaviour: Effects of Visual and Cognitive Load in Simulated Rural Driving,” Transportation Research Part F 8:79-96, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.trf.2005.04.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <label>72.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merat, N. and Jamson, A.H., “Shut up I'm Driving! Is Talking to an Inconsiderate Passenger the Same as Talking on a Mobile Telephone,” Proceedings of 3rd International Driving Symposium on Human Factors in Driver Assessment, Training, and Vehicle Design, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <label>73.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merat, N., Anttila, V. and Luoma, J., “Comparing the Driving Performance of Average and Older Drivers: The Effect of Surrogate in-Vehicle Information Systems,” Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour 8(2):147-166, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1369847805000173, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.trf.2005.04.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <label>74.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zheng, X.S., McConkie, G.W. and Simons, D.J., “Effects of Verbal and Spatial-Imagery Tasks on Drivers' Situation Awareness of Traffic Information,” Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting 49(22):1999-2003, http://pro. sagepub.com/content/49/22/1999.abstract, September 1, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <label>75.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engström, J., Johansson, E., and Ostlund, J., “Effects of Visual and Cognitive Load in Real and Simulated Motorway Driving,” Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour 8(2):97-120, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.trf.2005.04.012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <label>76.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kubose, T.T., Bock, K., Dell, G.S., Garnsey, S.M. et al., “The Effects of Speech Production and Speech Comprehension on Simulated Driving Performance,” Applied Cognitive Psychology 20(1):43-64, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <label>77.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Beede, K.E. and Kass, S.J., “Engrossed in Conversation: The Impact of Cell Phones on Simulated Driving Performance,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 38(2):415-421, 2006, doi:10.1016/j. aap.2005.10.015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <label>78.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horrey, W.J. and Wickens, C.D., “Examining the Impact of Cell Phone Conversations on Driving Using Meta-Analytic Techniques,” Human Factors 48(1):196-205, http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-33646374399&amp;part nerID=40&amp;md5=5f4410fc94bd7b7004d0af42b97dbb16, 2006, doi:10.1518/001872006776412135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <label>79.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Horrey, W. and Simons, D., “Examining Cognitive Interference and Adaptive Safety Behaviours in Tactical Vehicle Control,” Ergonomics 50(8):1340-1350, http://www.tandfonline.com.proxy.lib. wayne.edu/doi/abs/10.1080/00140130701318889, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <label>80.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knappe, G., Keinath, A., Bengler, K. and Meinecke, C., “Driving Simulator as an Evaluation Tool - Assessment of the Influence of Field of View and Secondary Tasks on Lane Keeping and Steering Performance,” Innovations for Safety: Opportunities and Challenges, http://www nrd.nhtsa.dot.gov/pdf/nrd-01/esv/esv20/07-0262-O.pdf, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <label>81.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Redenbo, S.J. and Lee, Y.-C., “Effects of Cognitive and Perceptual Loads on Driver Behavior,” Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board 2138(1):20-27, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <label>82.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reimer, B., Mehler, B., Coughlin, J.F., Godfrey, K.M. et al., “An on-Road Assessment of the Impact of Cognitive Workload on Physiological Arousal in Young Adult Drivers,” Proceedings of the 1st International Conference on Automotive User Interfaces and Interactive Vehicular Applications, Essen, Germany, 2009, doi:http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1620509.1620531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref83">
            <label>83.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reimer, B., “Impact of Cognitive Task Complexity on Drivers' Visual Tunneling,” Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board 2138:13-19, 2009, doi:10.3141/2138-03.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref84">
            <label>84.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Becic, E., Dell, G., Bock, K., Garnsey, S. et al., “Driving Impairs Talking,” Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review 17(1):15-21, 2010, doi:10.3758/PBR.17.1.15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref85">
            <label>85.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, Y. and Lee, J.D., “Combining Cognitive and Visual Distraction: Less Than the Sum of Its Parts,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 42(3):881-890, http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001457509001018, 2010, doi:10.1016/j. aap.2009.05.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref86">
            <label>86.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Atchley, P. and Chan, M., “Potential Benefits and Costs of Concurrent Task Engagement to Maintain Vigilance,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 53(1):3-12, http://hfs.sagepub.com/content/53/1/3.abstract, Feb. 1, 2011, doi:10.1177/0018720810391215.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref87">
            <label>87.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">He, J., “Effects of Cognitive Distraction on Lane-Keeping: Performance Loss or Improvement?” Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting 55(1):1894-98, 2011, doi:10.1177/1071181311551394.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref88">
            <label>88.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mühlbacher, D. and Krüger, H.-P., “The Effect of Car-Following on Lateral Guidance During Cognitive Load - a Study Conducted in the Multi-Driver Simulation,” Proceedings of 2nd International Conference on Driver Distraction and Inattention, Göteborg, Sweden, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref89">
            <label>89.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reimer, B., Mehler, B., Wang, Y. and Coughlin, J.F., “A Field Study on the Impact of Variations in Short-Term Memory Demands on Drivers' Visual Attention and Driving Performance across Three Age Groups,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 54(3):454-468, http://hfs.sagepub.com/content/54/3/454.abstract, June 1, 2012, doi:10.1177/0018720812437274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref90">
            <label>90.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cooper, J.M., Medeiros-Ward, N. and Strayer, D.L., “The Impact of Eye Movements and Cognitive Workload on Lateral Position Variability in Driving,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society, online version, http://hfs. sagepub.com/content/early/2013/03/05/0018720813480177, 2013, doi:10.1177/0018720813480177.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref91">
            <label>91.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Merat, N. and Forbes, N., “Enhanced Lane Keeping and Eye Movements During Driver Distraction: The Effect of Lead Car Presence,” Proceedings of Driver Distraction and Inattention, Gothenburg, Sweden, http://document.chalmers.se/download?docid=08efdafc-599e-4893-b9a7-42cabc6b0596, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref92">
            <label>92.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Medeiros-Ward, N., Cooper, J.M. and Strayer, D.L., “Hierarchical Control and Driving,” Journal of Experimental Psychology: General, Nov. 25, 2013, doi:10.1037/a0035097.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref93">
            <label>93.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harbluk, J.L., Noy, Y.I., and Eizenman, M., “The Impact of Cognitive Distraction on Driver Visual Behaviour and Vehicle Control,” Transport Canada, http://sunburst.usd.edu/∼schieber/materials/trans-canada-13889.pdf, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref94">
            <label>94.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chiang, D.P., Brooks, A.M., and Weir, D.H., “On the Highway Measures of Driver Glance Behavior with an Example Automobile Navigation System,” Applied Ergonomics 35(3):215-223, 2004, doi:10.1016/j.apergo.2004.01.005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref95">
            <label>95.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brookhuis, K., de Vries, G., and de Waard, D., “The Effects of Mobile Telephoning on Driving Performance,” Accident Analysis &amp; Prevention 23(4):309-16, 1991, doi:10.1016/0001-4575(91)90008-S.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref96">
            <label>96.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Victor, T.W., Engström, J., and Harbluk, J.L. “Distraction Assessment Methods Based on Visual Behavior and Event Detection.” Chap. 10 in Driver Distraction: Theory, Effects, and Mitigation, Regan M. A., Lee J. D. and Young K. L. (Eds.). 135-165. Boca Raton, FL: CRC, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref97">
            <label>97.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Recarte, M.A. and Nunes, L.M., “Mental Workload While Driving: Effects on Visual Search, Discrimination, and Decision Making,” Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied 9(2):119-137, http://sunburst.usd.edu/∼schieber/psyc792/workload/RecarteNunes2003. pdf, 2003, doi:10.1037/1076-898X.9.2.119.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref98">
            <label>98.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Victor, T., Harbluk, J., and Engström, J. “Sensitivity of Eye- Movement Measures to in-Vehicle Task Difficulty.” Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour 8:167-190, 2005, doi:10.1016/j.trf.2005.04.014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref99">
            <label>99.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reimer, B., Mehler, B., Wang, Y., and Coughlin, J.F., “A Field Study on the Impact of Variations in Short-Term Memory Demands on Drivers' Visual Attention and Driving Performance across Three Age Groups,” Human Factors: The Journal of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society 54(3):454-68, June 1, 2012, doi:10.1177/0018720812437274.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref100">
            <label>100.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klauer, S.G., Dingus, T.A., Neale, V.L., Sudweeks, J.D. et al., “The Impact of Driver Inattention on near-Crash/Crash Risk: An Analysis Using the 100-Car Naturalistic Driving Study Data (Report No. DOT HS 810 594),” National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Wash., DC, 2006, http://www.nhtsa.gov/DOT/NHTSA/NRD/Multimedia/PDFs/Crash Avoidance/Driver Distraction/810594.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref101">
            <label>101.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R., “Cognitive Distraction While Driving: A Critical Review of Definitions and Prevalence in Crashes,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Electron. Electr. Syst. 5(1):326-342, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0967.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref102">
            <label>102.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A., “Seven Myths about Cognitive Distraction and Driving,” presented at 5th International Conference on Traffic and Transport Psychology, Groningen, The Netherlands, http://www.icttp2012.com/images/stories/presentations/30th/1330_Driver_attention_and_distraction_Eyes_on_the_road/Young_ICTTP2012_Seven_Myths_about_Cognitive_Di straction_and_Driving.pdf, Aug. 30 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref103">
            <label>103.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angell, L.S., “Effects of Secondary Task Demands on Drivers' Responses to Events During Driving: Surrogate Methods and Issues,” Abstract, Proceedings of the Fourth International Driving Symposium on Human Factors in Driving Assessment, Training, and Vehicle Design, Stevenson, Washington, http://drivingassessment.uiowa.edu/DA2007/PDF/005_Angell.pdf, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref104">
            <label>104.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angell, L.S., “The “Looking but Not Seeing” Phenomenon: Could It Be Happening to Us? Are We Looking and Not Seeing?”, presented at International Symposium on Naturalistic Driving, https://secure.hosting.vt.edu/www.apps.vtti.vt.edu/PDFs/NDRSpresentations/Angell.pdf, Aug. 31, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref105">
            <label>105.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A., Hsieh, L., and Seaman, S., “A New Rapid Screening Tool for Assessing the Effects of Cognition on Visual Detection in Older Drivers,” presented at The Eye and the Auto International Conference, Detroit, MI, Sept.12-14, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref106">
            <label>106.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Evans, L. “Traffic Safety,” Science Serving Society, Bloomfield Hills, MI, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref107">
            <label>107.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hakamies-Blomqvist, L., Raitanen, T., and O'Neill, D., “Driver Ageing Does Not Cause Higher Accident Rates Per Km,” Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour 5(4):271-274, 2002, doi:10.1016/S1369-8478(03)00005-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref108">
            <label>108.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klauer, S.G., Guo, F., Simons-Morton, B.G., Ouimet, M.C. et al., “Distracted Driving and Risk of Road Crashes among Novice and Experienced Drivers,” New England Journal of Medicine 370(1):54-59, http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMsa1204142, 2014, doi:10.1056/NEJMsa1204142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref109">
            <label>109.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R., “An Unbiased Estimate of the Relative Crash Risk of Cell Phone Conversation while Driving an Automobile,” SAE Int. J. Trans. Safety 2(1):in press, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0446.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref110">
            <label>110.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A., “Drowsy Driving Increases Severity of Safety- Critical Events and Is Decreased by Cell Phone Conversation,” 3rd International Conference on Driver Distraction and Inattention, Gothenburg, Sweden, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref111">
            <label>111.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R., “Event Detection: The Second Dimension of Driver Performance for Visual-Manual Tasks,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Electron. Electr. Syst. 5(1):297-316, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0964.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref112">
            <label>112.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A. and Seaman, S., “Improving Survey Methods Using a New Objective Metric for Measuring Driving Time Variability in Survey and GPS Data,” Transportation Research Board 2012 Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C., http://trid.trb.org/view. aspx?id=1130665, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref113">
            <label>113.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Posner, M.I. and Fan, J. “Attention as an Organ System.” In Topics in Integrative Neuroscience: From Cells to Cognition, edited by Pomerantz J.R.. 31-61. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref114">
            <label>114.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angell, L., Young, R., Hankey, J., and Dingus, T., “An Evaluation of Alternative Methods for Assessing Driver Workload in the Early Development of In-Vehicle Information Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-1981, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-1981.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref115">
            <label>115.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A. and Angell, L., “The Dimensions of Driver Performance During Secondary Manual Tasks,” Proceedings of Driving Assessment 2003: The Second International Driving Symposium on Human Factors in Driver Assessment, Training and Vehicle Design, Park City, Utah, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref116">
            <label>116.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ISO/WD17488. “Detection-Response Task for Assessing Selective Attention in Driving.” In Road Vehicles - Transport Information and Control Systems - Man Machine Interface ISO/TC 22/SC 13/WG 08 (preliminary work item, version 8, February), 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref117">
            <label>117.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Angell, L., Auflick, J., Austria, P., Biever, W. et al., “Driver Workload Metrics Project, Task 2 Final Report, Appendices,” National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, http://www.nhtsa.gov/DOT/NHTSA/NRD/Multimedia/PDFs/Crash%20 Avoidance/2006/Driver%20Workload%20Metric s_appendices.pdf, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref118">
            <label>118.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers Driver Focus Telematics Working Group, “Statement of Principles, Criteria and Verification Procedures on Driver-Interactions with Advanced In-Vehicle Information and Communication Systems, June 26, 2006 Version,” Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers, Washington, DC, http://www.autoalliance.org/index.cfm?objectid=D6819130-B985-11E1-9E4C000C296BA163, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref119">
            <label>119.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A., Angell, L., Sullivan, J.M., Seaman, S., and Hsieh, L., “Validation of the Static Load Test for Event Detection During Hands-Free Conversation,” Proceedings of the Fifth International Driving Symposium on Human Factors in Driver Assessment, Training and Vehicle Design 5: 268-275, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref120">
            <label>120.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A., Hsieh, L., and Seaman, S. “A New Rapid Screening Tool for Assessing the Effects of Cognition on Visual Detection in Older Drivers,” presented at The Eye and the Auto International Conference, Detroit, MI, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref121">
            <label>121.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Young, R.A., Hsieh, L., and Seaman, S., “Brain Mechanisms of Cognitive Distraction while Driving,” Paper presented at the Cognitive Neuroscience Society 2012 Annual Meeting, Chicago, Illinois, USA. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref122">
            <label>122.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seaman, S., Hsieh, L., Wu, L., and Young, R.A., “Neural Basis of Emotional Modulation while Multitasking: ERP Analysis,” poster at the Cognitive Neuroscience Society, Montreal, Quebec, Canada. April 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref123">
            <label>123.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noy, Y. and Lemoine, T., “Prospects for Using Occlusion Paradigm to Set Its Function Accessibility Limits,” Proceedings of Exploring the Occlusion Technique: Progress in Recent Research and Applications Workshop, Torino, Italy, http://www.umich. edu/∼driving/occlusionworkshop2001/papers/OW2001_Noy.zip, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref124">
            <label>124.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Noy, Y.I., Lemoine, T.L., Klachan, C. and Burns, P.C., “Task Interruptability and Duration as Measures of Visual Distraction,” Applied Ergonomics 35(3):207-213, http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j. apergo.2003.11.012, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref125">
            <label>125.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, Y., Reimer, B., Mehler, B., Zhang, J., Mehler, A., and Coughlin, J., “The Impact of Repeated Cognitive Tasks on Driving Performance and Visual Attention,” Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Applied Human Factors and Ergonomics, Miami, Florida, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref126">
            <label>126.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NHTSA, “Visual-Manual NHTSA Driver Distraction Guidelines for In-Vehicle Electronic Devices” [final], Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0053, Vol. 78, pp. 24818-24890, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, Washington, DC, http://www.regulations.gov/#!documentDetail;D=NHTSA-2010-0053-0135, Apr. 26, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref127">
            <label>127.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NHTSA, “Visual-Manual NHTSA Driver Distraction Guidelines for In-Vehicle Electronic Devices” [proposed], Docket No. NHTSA-2010-0053, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration Washington, DC, http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/FR-2012-02-24/pdf/2012-4017.pdf, Feb. 24, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref128">
            <label>128.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">NHTSA, “Overview of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration's Driver Distraction Program,” DOT HS 811 299, http://www.nhtsa.gov/staticfiles/nti/distracted_driving/pdf/811299. pdf, April 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref129">
            <label>129.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bowyer, S., Hsieh, L., Moran, J., Young, R. et al., “Conversation Effects on Neural Mechanisms Underlying Reaction Time to Visual Events While Viewing a Driving Scene Using MEG,” Brain Research 1251:151-161, http://sun3.science.wayne.edu/∼mttc/conversation_effect_MEG_Bowyer_2009.pdf, 2009, doi:10.1016/j. brainres.2008.10.001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
