<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">jfinancialedu</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007490</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Financial Education</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>


         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Financial Education Association (FEA)</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00933961</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">2332421X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26573533</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>EDUCATIONAL RESEARCH</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Flipped Classrooms and Finance—Is this a Better Way to Learn?</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Psihountas</surname>
                  <given-names>Debbie</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Webster University</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2018</year>
            <string-date>SPRING 2018</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>44</volume>
         <issue>1</issue>
         <issue-id>e26573531</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>11</lpage>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26573533"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>As expected, with the increased usage of technology in classrooms, professors have been exploring new ways of making use of classroom time, ways to encourage honesty in work, ways to bring remote classes of students together, and more. A movement started in a Colorado high school [Bergmann and Sams, 2007] has caught on at the higher education level. Flipped classrooms involve moving what would traditionally be considered lecture (normally delivered during formal class hours) into the out-of-classroom hours (typically the time that a student would have spent doing homework), and moving what used to be homework into the classroom, so that the instructor is supervising homework and group activity during what used to be the lecture period of time, and students are expected to listen to the lecture (typically pre-recorded by the instructor) outside of the class meeting time.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>Key Words:</label> 
            <kwd>Flipped Classroom</kwd> 
            <kwd>Teaching of Finance</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCE</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bishop, J.L. &amp; M.A. Verleger. “The Flipped Classroom: A Survey of the Research,” 120th American Society of Engineering Education Annual Conference and Exposition, Atlanta, Georgia, June 23-26, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bloom, B., Englehart, M., Furst, E., Hill, W., and Krathwohl, D., “Taxonomy of educational objectives: the classification of educational goals. Handbook I, Cognitive Domain.” Longmans, Green (1956.)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brame, C., (2013). Flipping the classroom. Vanderbilt University Center for Teaching. Retrieved from http://cft.vanderbilt.edu/guides-sub-pages/flippingthe- classroom/.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Butt, Adam. Student Views on the Use of a Flipped Classroom Approach: Evidence from Australia, Business Education &amp; Accreditation, 6:1, 2014, 33-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chronicle of Higher Education, “San Jose State U. Says Replacing Live Lectures with Videos Increased Test Scores,” Wired Campus article, October 17, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">DesLauriers L., Schelew E., and C. Wieman. Improved learning in a largeenrollment physics class, Science, 2011, 332: 862-864.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Findlay-Thompson, Sandi, and Peter Mombourquette. “Evaluation of a Flipped Classroom in an Undergraduate Business Course,” Business Education &amp; Accreditation, 6:1, 2014, 63-71.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flipped Learning Network. “The Four Pillars of F-L-I-P,” Flippedlearning.org, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fulton, Kathleen P. “10 Reasons to Flip,” Kappanmagazine.org, 94:2, October 2012, 20-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fulton, Kathleen. “Upside Down and Inside Out: Flip Your Classroom to Improve Student Learning,” Learning &amp; Leading with Technology, June/July 2012, 12- 17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Goodwin, Bryan, and Kirsten Miller. “Evidence on Flipped Classrooms Is Still Coming In,” Educational Leadership, March 2013, 78-81.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hamdan, Noora, Patrick McKnight, Katherine McKnight, and Kari M. Arfstrom. “A Review of Flipped Learning,” White Paper, Flipped Learning Network, Pearson Publishing, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hamdan, Noora, Patrick McKnight, Katherine McKnight, and Kari M. Arfstrom. “The Flipped Learning Model: A White Paper Based on the Literature Review Titled ‘A Review of Flipped Learning,’ “ Flipped Learning Network, Pearson Publishing, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lage, Maureen J., Glenn J. Platt, and Michael Treglia. “Inverting the Classroom: A Gateway to Creating an Inclusive Learning Environment,” Journal of Economic Education, 31:1, Winter 2000, 30-43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mason, Gregory S., Teodora Rutar Shuman, and Kathleen E. Cook. “Comparing the Effectiveness of an Inverted Classroom to a Traditional Classroom in an Upper-Division Engineering Course,” IEEE Transactions on Education, 56:4, November 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millard, Elizabeth. “5 Reasons Flipped Classrooms Work,” University Business, December 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sams, Aaron, 2/27/2014. Webinar: “Five Mistakes to Avoid when Flipping your Class,” Flipped Learning Network and Adobe Systems, co-sponsors.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schachter, Ron. “Avoiding the Pitfalls of Virtual Schooling,” www.DistrictAdministration.com, July/August 2012, 74-79.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">USA Today. “Flipped classrooms’ may not have any impact on learning,” December 5, Emily Atteberry, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
