<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278199</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Zero-Dimensional Simulation of Diesel Engine Combustion and Emissions Based on CMC Model and Skeletal Reaction Mechanism</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kwon</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaesung</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Seo</surname>
                  <given-names>Jaeyeob</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lee</surname>
                  <given-names>Dongkyu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Huh</surname>
                  <given-names>Kang Y.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Pohang Univ. of Science and Technology</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>964</fpage>
         <lpage>975</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278199"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A zero-dimensional code is developed to simulate turbulent spray combustion and NOx and soot emission in direct injection diesel engines. The code consists of two major parts; mixing calculation for the probability density function (PDF) based on the multi-zone model by Hiroyasu et al. (1983) [1] and the flame structure by the conditional moment closure (CMC) model (Klimenko &amp; Bilger, 1999) [2]. The skeletal mechanism of n-heptane is employed with the elementary reaction steps for heat release and the NOx chemistry in GRI 3.0. The spray model accounts for evaporation and mixing based on momentum balance of the spray zones, while the CMC model incorporates the conditional flame structures with one fuel group or flame structure for each injection. The spatially integrated density-weighted PDF, F(η), is defined to represent inhomogeneous mixture distribution in the cylinder. The one-equation soot model is employed for prediction of the soot emission. The program has been validated over a wide range of load and rpm with different injection schedules and EGR levels. Comparison shows reasonable agreement with measurements for the pressure trace and the NOx and soot emissions for all 16 cases with a single set of tuned constants.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., Kadota, T., and Arai, M., “Development and Use of a Spray Combustion Modeling to Predict Diesel Engine Efficiency and Pollutant Emissions (Part 1 Combustion Modeling),” Bull. JSME, Vol. 26, No. 214, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Klimenko, A.Y., and Bilger, R.W., “Conditional Moment Closure for turbulent combustion,” Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, Vol. 25:595-687, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Foster, D.E., “An Overview of Zero-Dimensional Thermodynamic Models for IC Engine Data Analysis,” SAE Technical Paper 852070, 1985, doi: 10.4271/852070.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Watson, N., Pilley, A.D. and Marzouk, M., “A Combustion Correlation for Diesel Engine Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 800029, 1980, doi: 10.4271/800029.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ning, L., “A Cycle Simulation Program for the Dynamic Operation of a Single Cylinder Direct Injection Diesel,” M.S. thesis, Mechanical Engineering Department, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 1988.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nishida, K. and Hiroyasu, H., “Simplified Three- Dimensional Modeling of Mixture Formation and Combustion in a D.I. Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 890269, 1989, doi: 10.4271/890269.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H., and Nishida, K., “Fuel Spray Trajectory and Dispersion in a D.I. Diesel Combustion Chamber,” SAE Technical Paper 890462, 1989, doi: 10.4271/890462.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshizaki, T., Yuzaki, K., Hiroyasu, H., Yamasita, H., Kaneda, K., and Suzuki, M., “Model Verification of the Evaporating Diesel Spray Distribution in the Combustion Chamber of a D.I. Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 962054, 1996, doi: 10.4271/962054.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Long, Y., Sawa, H.G., and Hiroyasu, H., “The Simulation of the Distribution of Temperature and Mass of Liquid and Vapor Fuels, and the Wall Impinging Spray Pattern in a Diesel Combustion Chamber,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-1887, 2000, doi:10.4271/2000-01-1887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, T., Miki, M., Kim, M., Watanabe, S., Hiroyasu, H., and Miao, H., “Reduction of Heavy Duty Diesel Engine Emission and Fuel Economy with Multi- Objective Genetic Algorithm and Phenomenological Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0531, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-0531.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kuo, T-W., “Evaluation of a Phenomenological Spray- Combustion Model for Two Open-Chamber Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 872057, 1987, doi: 10.4271/872057.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bazari, Z., “A DI Diesel Combustion and Emission Predictive Capability for Use in Cycle Simulation,” SAE Technical Paper 920462, 1992, doi: 10.4271/920462.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jung, D. and Assanis, D.N., “Multi-Zone DI Diesel Spray Combustion Model for Cycle Simulation Studies of Engine Performance and Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-1246, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-1246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Narayanaswamy, K. and Rutland, C.J., “Cycle Simulation Diesel HCCI Modeling Studies and Control,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-2997, 2004, doi: 10.4271/2004-01-2997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dulbecco, A., Lafossas, F.A. and Poinsot, T.J., “A 0D Phenomenological Approach to Model Diesel HCCI Combustion with Multi-Injection Strategies Using Probability Density Functions and Detailed Tabulated Chemistry,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):548-568, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-0678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inagaki, K., Ueda, M., Mizuta, J., Nakakita, K. and Nakayama, S., “Universal Diesel Engine Simulator (UniDES): 1st Report: Phenomenological Multi-Zone PDF Model for Predicting the Transient Behavior of Diesel Engine Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0843, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-0843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bhave, A., Kraft, M., Montorsi, L. and Mauss, F., “Modelling a Dual-Fuelled Multi-Cylinder HCCI Engine Using a PDF Based Engine Cycle Simulator,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0561, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0561.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hohenberg, G., “Advanced Approaches for Heat Transfer Calculations,” SAE Technical Paper 790825, 1979, doi: 10.4271/790825.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Borman, G.L. and Johnson, J.H., “Unsteady Vaporization Histories and Trajectories of Fuel Drops Injected into Swirling Air,” SAE Technical Paper 620271. 1962, doi: 10.4271/620271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Kadota, T., “Fuel Droplet Size Distribution in Diesel Combustion Chamber,” SAE Technical Paper 740715, 1974, doi: 10.4271/740715.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Seo, J., Lee, Y., Han, I., Huh, K.Y. and Kim, H., “Extended CMC Model for Turbulent Spray Combustion in a Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-2411, 2008, doi:10.4271/2008-01-2411.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O'Brien, E.E., and Jiang, T.L., “The conditional dissipation rate of an initially binary scalar in homogeneous turbulence,” Phys. Fluids A 3:3121-3123, 1991.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, S., Hewson, J.C., Chen, J.H., and Pitsch, H., “Effects of strain rate on high-pressure nonpremixed nheptane autoignition in counterflow,” Combustion and Flame 137:320-339, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
