<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Blackwell Publishing Ltd</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24440211</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>The Elasticity of Taxable Income in New Zealand</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Iris</given-names>
                  <surname>Claus</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>John</given-names>
                  <surname>Creedy</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Josh</given-names>
                  <surname>Teng</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2012</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">33</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">3</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24440209</issue-id>
         <fpage>287</fpage>
         <lpage>303</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2012 Institute for Fiscal Studies</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24440211"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper reports estimates of the elasticity of taxable income with respect to the net-of-tax rate for New Zealand taxpayers. The relative stability of the New Zealand personal income tax system, in terms of marginal rates, thresholds and the tax base, provides helpful conditions for deriving these estimates. The elasticity of taxable income was estimated to be substantially higher for the highest income groups. Changes in the timing of income flows for the higher income recipients were found to be an important response to the announcement of a new higher rate bracket. The marginal welfare costs of personal income taxation were consistent across years, being relatively small for all but the higher tax brackets. For the top marginal rate bracket of 39 per cent, the welfare cost of raising an extra dollar of tax revenue was estimated to be well in excess of a dollar. Implications of the findings are that: disincentive effects of high top marginal rates can be substantial even when labour supply responses are small; the welfare costs of increases in top marginal tax rates can be high; and announcement effects of tax policy changes can lead to considerable income shifting between time periods.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d8e202a1310">
            <label>*</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e209" publication-type="other">
Submitted February 2011.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e216a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e223" publication-type="other">
Early contributions are by Lindsey (1987) and Feldstein (1995 and 1999).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e230a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e237" publication-type="other">
For an introduction to the basic analytics, see Creedy (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e244a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e251" publication-type="other">
This is discussed further below, in Section V.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e259a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e266" publication-type="other">
Available online at http://www.ifs.org.uk/docs/fssepl2 clausetal appendix.pdf.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e273a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e280" publication-type="other">
Some studies have used regression methods involving instrumental variables and a range of
exogenous variables to deal with non-tax-related income movements. The use of such methods is
examined by Carey et al. (2012), who show that the standard instrument is not reliable. They propose an
alternative instrument based on expected tax rates.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e296a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e303" publication-type="other">
See, for example, Evans et al. (1996).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e310a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e317" publication-type="other">
The corporate tax rate was lowered from 48 per cent to 33 per cent.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e324a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e331" publication-type="other">
The average monthly exchange rate for 1994 to 2008 was US$0.60 per NZ$ 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e338a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e345" publication-type="other">
Changes to the Working for Families (WfF) package began in October 2004 and were implemented in
stages through to 1 April 2007. They included changes to in-work incentives, family entitlement and
support to meet childcare and accommodation costs. Low- to middle-income families were the key target
group for these changes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e362a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e369" publication-type="other">
For further discussion and alternative specifications, see Creedy (2010, pp. 562—4).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e376a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e383" publication-type="other">
Given information about z and r for a group of individuals, a simple regression of logz on log (1-r)
and a constant, thereby omitting the unobservable z0, cannot be expected to provide a useful estimate of t],
since the omitted variable is correlated with r.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e396a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e403" publication-type="other">
It may, in practice, modify the plans of those individuals who are just below the threshold.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e410a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e417" publication-type="other">
Estimates obtained using a difference-in-difference estimator were found to be similar, and thus are
not reported here.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e427a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e434" publication-type="other">
Fiscal drag arises from the failure to adjust thresholds in line with general increases in nominal
incomes; see Creedy and Gemmell (2006). An early study using fiscal drag to estimate the elasticity of
taxable income is Saez (2003).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e447a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e454" publication-type="other">
In addition to income tax thresholds, the real value of other tax parameters (such as allowance and
deduction limits) can fall during inflation, as examined by Onrubia and Sanz (2009). However, this is
unlikely to be an issue in New Zealand given the limited allowances and deductions over the period of
estimation.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e471a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e478" publication-type="other">
If systematic income changes occur for non-tax reasons - for example, if there is some 'regression
towards the mean' over time - the estimator may be biased. A method of allowing for such changes is
examined by Creedy (2010).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e491a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e498" publication-type="other">
The denominator of (6), as a proportionate difference in net-of-tax rates, is negative. The numerator
is expected also to be negative, since those people moving into a higher tax bracket (consisting mainly of
those who were near the top of the initial tax bracket) are likely to respond to the higher tax rate by
modifying the increase in their declared taxable income. This situation arises where all those in the tax
bracket would experience similar rates of income growth over the time period, if there were no tax
consequences.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e521a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e528" publication-type="other">
In the relatively low income ranges, significant jumps in income are known to be associated with
non-convex budget sets, but the present emphasis is on higher incomes where such non-convexities do
not arise.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e541a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e548" publication-type="other">
See also Thomas (2007, p. 18).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e555a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e562" publication-type="other">
Higher welfare costs for lower-income individuals in Australia were found by Creedy, Hérault and
Kalb (2011), using a structural labour supply model, even though labour supply changes were small. The
assumption of zero income effects, which is imposed in the present analysis, may thus affect results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e575a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e582" publication-type="other">
On these concepts, see Creedy (1998, pp. 54-9).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e590a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e597" publication-type="other">
Creedy (2010, p. 575) extends the measure to cover all tax brackets.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d8e604a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d8e611" publication-type="other">
However, Chetty (2009) suggests that, to the extent that part of the cost of evasion and avoidance
involves a transfer to other individuals, the excess burden is reduced.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d8e630a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e634" publication-type="other">
Atkinson, A. B. and Leigh, A. (2008), 'Top incomes in New Zealand 1921-2005:
understanding the effects of marginal tax rates, migration threat, and the macroeconomy',
Review of Income and Wealth, vol. 54, pp. 149-65.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e647a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e651" publication-type="other">
Carey, S., Creedy, J., Gemmell, N. and Teng, J. (2012), 'Regression estimates of the elasticity
of taxable income and the choice of instrument', NZ Treasury, unpublished paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e661a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e665" publication-type="other">
Chetty, R. (2009), 'Is the taxable income elasticity sufficient to calculate deadweight loss?
The implications of evasion and avoidance', American Economic Journal: Economic
Policy, vol. 1, pp. 31-52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e678a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e682" publication-type="other">
Creedy, J. (1998), Measuring Welfare Changes and Tax Burdens, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e690a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e694" publication-type="other">
— (2010), 'The elasticity of taxable income: an introduction', Public Finance and
Management, vol. 10, pp. 556-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e704a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e708" publication-type="other">
— and Gemmell, N. (2006), Modelling Tax Revenue Growth, Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e715a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e719" publication-type="other">
—, Hérault, N. and Kalb, G. (2011), 'Measuring welfare changes in behavioural
microsimulation modelling: accounting for the random utility component', Journal of
Applied Economics, vol. 14, pp. 5-34.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e732a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e736" publication-type="other">
Evans, L., Grimes, A., Wilkinson, B. and Teece, D. (1996), 'Economic reform in New
Zealand 1984-95: the pursuit of efficiency', Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 34, pp.
1856-902.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e749a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e753" publication-type="other">
Feldstein, M. (1995), 'The effect of marginal tax rates on taxable income: a panel study of the
1986 Tax Reform Act Journal of Political Economy, vol. 103, pp. 551-72.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e763a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e767" publication-type="other">
— (1999), 'Tax avoidance and the deadweight loss of the income tax', Review of Economics
and Statistics, vol. 81, pp. 674-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e778a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e782" publication-type="other">
Giertz, S. H. (2004), 'Recent literature on taxable-income elasticities', Tax Analysis Division
Congressional Budget Office, Technical Paper no. 2004-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e792a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e796" publication-type="other">
Lindsey, L. B. (1987), 'Individual taxpayer response to tax cuts: 1982-1984: with
implications for the revenue maximizing tax rate', Journal of Public Economics, vol. 33,
pp. 173-206.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e809a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e813" publication-type="other">
Onrubia, J. and Sanz, J. F. (2009), 'Reported taxable income and marginal tax rates: evidence
for Spain based on fiscal drag', Universidad Complutense de Madrid, unpublished paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e823a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e827" publication-type="other">
Saez, E. (2003), 'The effect of marginal tax rates on income: a panel study of "bracket
creep'", Journal of Public Economics, vol. 87, pp. 1231-58.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e837a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e841" publication-type="other">
—, Slemrod, J. B. and Giertz, S. H. (2012), 'The elasticity of taxable income with respect to
marginal tax rates: a critical review', Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 50, pp. 3-50.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d8e851a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d8e855" publication-type="other">
Thomas, A. (2007), 'Taxable income elasticities and the deadweight cost of taxation in New
Zealand', NZ Inland Revenue, unpublished paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
