<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">saetransactions</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019997</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>SAE Transactions</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Society of Automotive Engineers, Inc.</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">0096736X</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">52</volume>
         <issue-id>i40187875</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">44468122</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Aircraft-Engine INLET and EXHAUST PORTING</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>VINCENT C.</given-names>
                  <surname>YOUNG</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1944</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>202</fpage>
         <lpage>206</lpage>
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44468122"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>ONE of the many problems confronting the engine designer is that of selecting proper port dimensions. As a general rule, it appears desirable to keep the ports as small as possible. This procedure permits flexibility in obtaining proper sections to withstand thermal and hydraulic loading, gives maximum flow of coolant (whether liquid or air), makes reasonable temperatures possible, and gives the best flow characteristics of the passages in the head, which control the flow of inlet and exhaust gases. To simplify design, Mr. Young uses a port constant, which represents the slope of the line obtained by plotting the port area against a factor of speed displacement – just another but more handy way of expressing velocities. The cooling of the exhaust valve is discussed by Mr. Young as affected by heat transfer from the head section to: 1. The relatively cool new charge. 2. The heat transferred to the coolant through the seat. 3. The heat transferred to the coolant by the stem. 4. The heat transferred to the port gases during the other than exhaust portion of the cycle. Maximum flow coefficients will be obtained for intake ports, if the approach passages are of uniform section with no re-entrant curves and the actual passage shape between the seat and the valve is considered as a venturi. Cooling requirements for the inlet port are not as stringent as for the exhaust, so that guide and boss can be designed with emphasis on flow characteristics rather than on cooling effect.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d134e135a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d134e142" publication-type="other">
SAE Transactions, Vol. 51, September, 1943, pp. 334-343: "In-
take Systems for Aircraft Engines " by Carl T. Doman.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d134e152a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d134e159" publication-type="other">
SAE Transaction, Vol. 50. June. 1942, pp. 212-220, 252: "Air-
flow through Intake Valves," by G. B. Wood, Jr., D. U. Hunter. E. S.
Taylor, and C. F. Taylor.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
  </back>
</article>


