<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284868</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Spray Characterization and Ignition Delay Measurements of JP-8 and IPK in a Constant-Pressure Flow Chamber</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Tess</surname>
                  <given-names>Michael</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kurman</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthew</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kweon</surname>
                  <given-names>Chol-Bum</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>U.S. Army Research Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>June 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284847</issue-id>
         <fpage>899</fpage>
         <lpage>909</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284868"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This research compares the spray development and combustion characteristics of jet propellant 8 (JP-8) and iso-paraffinic kerosene (IPK) through a range of diesel engine in-cylinder operating conditions. Non-reacting spray experiments were performed in a constant-pressure flow chamber with 99% nitrogen gas composition at constant temperature (900 K) and densities ranging from 11-56 kg/m³. Near-simultaneous, high-speed Mie and schlieren images of the spray were acquired to measure the liquid and vapor penetration lengths of the non-reacting jet. Reacting experiments, consisting of photodiode measurements and intensified high-speed movies of OH* chemiluminescence, were performed at the same thermodynamic conditions as the non-reacting experiments, except with a 21%/79% oxygen/nitrogen ambient gas composition. Measurements of the rate of injection, issued from a single-hole axial common-rail fuel injector, showed negligible differences between the fuels. The non-reacting liquid length of IPK was approximately 20% shorter than JP-8 for the range of tested conditions, which was consistent with the average difference in volatility between the fuels. The ignition delay, determined from the photodiode record, was up to 80% longer for IPK fuel at low density conditions. Additionally, the lift-off length of IPK was measured to be approximately 50% more sensitive to ambient pressure than JP-8. These results provide fundamental information for the calibration and optimization of military diesel engines operating on conventional and alternatively sourced jet fuels.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">U.S. Department of Defense Detail Specification, “Turbine Fuel, Aviation, Kerosene Type, JP-8 (NATO F-34), NATO F-35, and JP-8+100 (NATO F-37),” MIL-DTL-83133H Amendment 2, Dec. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rollbuhler, R., “Combustion Characteristics of Gas Turbine Alternative Fuels,” NASA TM-100247, 1987.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Edwards, T., “Advancements in Gas Turbine Fuels From 1943 to 2005,” J. Eng. Gas Turb. Power 129:13-20, 2007, doi:10.1115/1.2364007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Blakey, S., Rye, L., Wilson, C.W., “Aviation gas turbine alternative fuels: A review,” P. Combust. Inst. 33:2863-2885, 2011, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2010.09.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dryer, F.L., “Chemical kinetic and combustion characteristics of transportation fuels,” P. Combust. Inst. 35:117-144, 2015, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2014.09.008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G.T., “The outlook for fuels for internal combustion engines,” Int. J. Engine Res. 15(4): 383-398, 2014, doi:10.1177/1468087414526189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R.D., “Directions in internal combustion engine research,” Combust. Flame 160(1):1-8, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.combustflame.2012.11.002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Won, S.H., Veloo, P.S., Santner, J., Ju, Y., and Dryer, F.L., “Characterization of global combustion properties with simple fuel property measurements for alternative jet fuels,” 50th AIAA/ASME/SAE/ASEE Joint Propulsion Conference, 2014, doi:10.2514/6.2014-3469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schihl, P., Hoogterp-Decker, L., and Gingrich, E., "The Ignition Behavior of a Coal to Liquid Fischer-Tropsch Jet Fuel in a Military Relevant Single Cylinder Diesel Engine," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):785-802, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1197.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G., "Auto-Ignition Quality of Practical Fuels and Implications for Fuel Requirements of Future SI and HCCI Engines," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-0239, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-0239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bosch, W., "The Fuel Rate Indicator: A New Measuring Instrument For Display of the Characteristics of Individual Injection," SAE Technical Paper 660749, 1966, doi:10.4271/660749.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Outcalt, S., Laesecke, A., and Freund, M.B., “Density and speed of sound measurements of jet A and S-8 aviation turbine fuels,” Energ. Fuel 23:1626-1633, 2009, doi:10.1021/ef800888q.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colket, M., Zeppieri, S., Dai, Z., Kim, W., et. al., “Alternative Fuels Modeling for Navy Applications,” ONR Contract N00014-12-C-0408, Final Report, Jun. 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kastengren, A.L., Tilocco, F.Z., Powell, C.F., Manin, J., et. al., “Engine combustion network (ECN): measurements of nozzle geometry and hydraulic behavior,” Atomization Spray 22(12):1011-1052, 2012, doi:10.1615/AtomizSpr.2013006309.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Manin, J., Kastengren, A., and Payri, R., “Understanding the acoustic oscillations observed in the injection rate of a common-rail direct injection diesel injector,” J. Eng. Gas Turb. Power 134(12):122801-10, 2012, doi:10.1115/1.4007276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Payri, R., Salvador, F., Gimeno, J., and de la Morena, J., “Study of cavitation phenomena based on a technique for visualizing bubbles in a liquid pressurized chamber,” Int. J. Heat Fluid Fl. 30(4):768-777, 2009, doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatfluidflow.2009.03.011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Settles, G.S., “Schlieren and shadowgraph techniques: visualizing phenomena in transparent media,” (Berlin, Springer-Verlag, 2001), doi:10.1007/978-3-642-56640-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parrish, S.E., and Zink, R.J., “Development and application of an imaging system to evaluate liquid and vapor envelopes of sprays from a multi-hole gasoline fuel injector operating under engine-like conditions,” presented at 23rd Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, USA, May 15-18, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B. and Siebers, D., "Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hall, J.M., Rickard, M.J.A., and Petersen, E.L., “Comparison of characteristic time diagnostics for ignition and oxidation of fuel/oxidizer mixtures behind reflected shock waves,” Combust. Sci. Technol. 177:455-483, 2005, doi:10.1080/00102200590909003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Arai, M., "Structures of Fuel Sprays in Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 900475, 1990, doi:10.4271/900475.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. and Siebers, D., "Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays," SAE Technical Paper 960034, 1996, doi:10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kook, S., and Pickett, L.M., “Liquid length and vapor penetration of conventional, Fischer-Tropsch, coal-derived, and surrogate fuel sprays at high-temperature and high-pressure ambient conditions,” Fuel 93:539- 548, 2012, doi:10.1016/j.fuel.2011.10.004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., "Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays," SAE Technical Paper 980809, 1998, doi:10.4271/980809.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., "Scaling Liquid-Phase Fuel Penetration in Diesel Sprays Based on Mixing-Limited Vaporization," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01- 0528, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0528.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., Mueller, C., and Siebers, D., "Measurements of Fuel Effects on Liquid-Phase Penetration in DI Sprays1," SAE Technical Paper 1999- 01-0519, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-0519.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dos Santos, F., and Le Moyne, L., “Spray atomization models in engine application, from correlations to direct numerical simulations,” Oil Gas Sci. Technol. 66(5):801-822, 2011, doi:10.2516/ogst/2011116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., and Idicheria, C., "Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets," SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhu, Y., Li, S., Davidson, D.F., and Hanson, R.K., “Ignition delay times of conventional and alternative fuels behind reflected shock waves,” Proc. Combust. Inst. (2014), doi:10.1016/j.proci.2014.05.034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L. and Hoogterp, L., "Fundamental Spray and Combustion Measurements of JP-8 at Diesel Conditions," SAE Int. J. Commer. Veh. 1(1):108-118, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rothamer, D.A., and Murphy, L., “Systematic study of ignition delay for jet fuels and diesel fuel in a heavy-duty diesel engine,” Proc. Combust. Inst. 34 (2014): 3021-3029, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2012.06.085.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kalghatgi, G.T., Hildingsson, L., Harrison, A.J., and Johansson, B., “Surrogate fuels for premixed combustion in compression ignition engines,” Int. J. Engine Res. 12(5):452-465, 2011, doi:10.1177/1468087411409307.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hildingsson, L., Johansson, B., Kalghatgi, G., and Harrison, A., "Some Effects of Fuel Autoignition Quality and Volatility in Premixed Compression Ignition Engines," SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):440-460, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0607.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D. and Higgins, B., "Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Sprays Under Quiescent Conditions," SAE Technical Paper 2001-01- 0530, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., Higgins, B., and Pickett, L., "Flame Lift-Off on Direct- Injection Diesel Fuel Jets: Oxygen Concentration Effects," SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0890, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bazyn, T., and Martin, G.C., “Spray combustion measurements in a flow-through high temperature, high pressure chamber,” presented at 23rd Annual Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, USA, May 15-18, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">ASTM D6890-13be1, “Standard test method for determination of ignition delay and derived cetane number (DCN) of diesel fuel oils by combustion in a constant volume chamber,” ASTM International, West Conshohocken, PA, 2013, doi: 10.1520/D6890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
