<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167714</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Liquid Cooled Induction Motor</article-title>
            <subtitle>Computational Design, Heat Transfer Analysis, Parametric Study, and Performance Testing</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Soparat</surname>
                  <given-names>Jenwit</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Benyajati</surname>
                  <given-names>Chi-na</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>National Metal and Materials Tech. Center</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167713</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>6</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167714"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In order to use an electric induction motor to power an automotive vehicle, heat occurred in a motor is an important issue. Generally, an induction motor could be operating at a high load for many extensive periods. The generated heat in motor could cause damage on motor parts subsequently decreasing their useful service life. The objective of this study was to develop a cooling system of the induction motor by introducing liquid coolant passages on a housing part to obtain higher cooling efficiency than that of conventional Totally Enclosed Fan Cooled system (TEFC).</p>
            <p>Principally, conventional TEFC finned housing and rear fan would be replaced by a cylindrical aluminum housing. Special heat transfer oil was chosen as a coolant mainly due to its dielectric property. The liquid cooling housing geometry was defined by series of cooling passages to guide the liquid coolant through and around the housing. The design of liquid cooling system was performed via computational simulation. In the main simulation work, the boundary conditions of heat generation in motor were obtained from previous experimental and computational work on existing TEFC motor. Using resulting temperature distribution in the motor as a design criteria, the effect of two operational variables were investigated i.e. coolant flow pattern and coolant flow rate. Simulation results in each design case were compared and discussed to determine the finalized concept of the liquid cooling system prior to a prototype fabrication and actual performance testing.</p>
         </abstract>
         <kwd-group>
            <label>KEYWORDS:</label>
            <kwd>induction motor</kwd>
            <kwd>liquid cooling</kwd>
            <kwd>heat transfer</kwd>
            <kwd>CAE</kwd>
            <kwd>Computational Fluid Dynamics</kwd>
         </kwd-group>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boldea, I. and Nasar, S.A. 2002. The Induction Machine Handbook. London: CRC Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huai, Y, Melnik, R.V.N. and Thogersen, P.B., “Computational Analysis of Temperature Rise Phenomena in Electric Induction Motors”. Applied Thermal Engineering 2003, 23, 779-795.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoon, M.K. and Kauh, S.K., “Thermal Analysis of a Small, Totally Enclosed, Fan-Cooled Induction Motor”, Heat Transfer Engineering 2005, 26(4), pp.77-86.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bellettre, J., Sartre, V., Biaist, F., and Lallemand, A., “Transient State Study of Electric Motor Heating and Phase Change Solid-Liquid Cooling”. Applied Thermal Engineering, 1997, 17 (1), 17-31</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farsane, K., Desevaux, P. and Panday, P.K., “Experiment Study of the Closed Type Electric Motor”, Applied Thermal Engineering 2000, 20, pp.1321-1334.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. 1992. “IEEE Recommended Practice for Thermal Evaluation of Insulation Systems for Alternating-Current Electric Machinery Employing Form-Wound Preinsulated Stator Coils for Machines Rated 6900 V and Below”, IEEE 275.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">International Electrotechnical Commission Standard 60085. 2004. Electrical Insulation- Thermal Evaluation and Designation. 3rd ed.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bjorklund, I.S. and Kays, W.M. 1959. “Heat Transfer between Concentric Rotating Cylinders.” Transactions of ASME, Journal of Heat Transfer. vol. 81 : 175-186.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">AIEE. 1956. “Test procedure for evaluation of systems of insulating materials for random-wound electrical machinery.” AIEE 510.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soparat J., Benyajati C., Pitaksapsin N., Wattanawongsakun P., and Phuchumnong A., “Computational Study of Totally Enclosed Fan Cooled System in an Electric Induction Motor”, 2010, 14th International Annual Symposium on Computational Science and Engineering (ANSCSE 14), March 23-26, 2010, Mae Fah Luang University, Chiang Rai, Thailand.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Soparat J., Benyajati C., Thianpong C., and Okawa S., “Development of a Liquid Cooling System for an Induction Motor”, The 7th International Conference on Automotive Engineering (ICEA-7), March 28- April 1, 2011, Challenger, Impact, Muang Thong Thani, Bangkok, Thailand.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Myers, R.H. and Montgomery, D.C. 1995. Response Surface Methodology. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
