<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">reviespafinacont</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50009991</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>

         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administarción de Empresas</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02102412</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23320753</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">26597704</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Discussion <italic>on</italic> The influence of conditional conservatism on ownership dispersion</article-title>
            <subtitle>An international analysis (by Begoña Giner, Ahmed Tahoun and Martin Walker)</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name>
                  <surname>Penalva</surname>
                  <given-names>Fernando</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IESE Business School, University of Navarra</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>7</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>July-September 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>9</month>
            <year>2013</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>42</volume>
         <issue>159</issue>
         <issue-id>e26597697</issue-id>
         <fpage>311</fpage>
         <lpage>318</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2001 Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administración de Empresas</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26597704"/>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ball, R., and Shivakumar, L. 2005. Earnings quality in U.K. private fi rms. Journal of Accounting and Economics 39: 83-128.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bona-Sánchez, C.; Pérez-Alemán, J., and Santana-Martín, D. J. 2011. Ultimate ownership and earnings conservatism. European Accounting Review 20 (1): 57-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bushman, R., and Piotroski, J. 2006. Financial reporting incentives for conservative accounting: The infl uence of legal and political institutions. Journal of Accounting and Economics 42: 107-148.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Callen, J. L.; Segal, D., and Hope, O-K. 2010. The pricing of conservative accounting and the measurement of conservatism at the fi rm-year level. Review of Accounting Studies 15: 145-178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cullinan, C.P.; Wang, F. Wang, P. and Zhang, J. 2012. Ownership structure and accounting conservatism in China. Journal of International Accounting and Taxation 21: 1-16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ettredge, M.; Huang, Y., and Zhang, W. 2012. Earnings restatements and differential timeliness of accounting conservatism. Journal of Accounting and Economics 53: 489-503.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">García Lara, J. M.; García Osma, B., and Peñalva, F. 2009. Accounting conservatism and corporate governance. Review of Accounting Studies 14 (1): 161-201.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">García Lara, J.M.; García Osma, B., and Penalva, F. 2011. Information consequences of accounting conservatism. Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">García Lara, J.M.; García Osma, B., and Penalva, F. 2012. Differential information consequences of real versus accruals earnings management. Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Giner, B.; Tahoun, A., and Walker, M. 2013. The infl uence of conditional conservatism on ownership dispersion: An international analysis. Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad, this issue.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gormley, T. A.; Kim, B. H., and Martin, X. 2012. Do fi rms adjust their timely loss recognition in response to changes in the banking industry? Journal of Accounting Research 50: 159-196.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jayaraman, S. 2012. The effect of enforcement on timely loss recognition: Evidence from insider trading laws. Journal of Accounting and Economics 53: 77-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jayaraman, S., and Shivakumar, L. 2013. Agency-based demand for conservatism: Evidence from state adoption of antitakeover laws. Review of Accounting Studies, forthcoming.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Khan, M., and Watts, R. L. 2009. Estimation and empirical properties of a fi rm-year measure of accounting conservatism. Journal of Accounting and Economics 48: 132-150.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LaFond, R. 2005. The infl uence of ownership structure on earnings conservatism and the informativeness of stock prices: An international comparison. Working paper.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LaFond, R., and Roychowdhury, S. 2008 Managerial ownership and accounting conservatism. Journal of Accounting Research 46 (1): 101-135.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">LaFond, R., and Watts, R. 2008. The information role of conservatism. The Accounting Review 83(2): 447-478.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">La Porta, R.; Lopez-De-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A., and Vishny, R. 1998. Law and fi nance. Journal of Political Economy 106: 1,113-1,155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Levine, R. 1999. Law, fi nance and economic growth. Journal of Financial Intermediation 8: 8-35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Leuz, C.; Nanda, D., and Wysocki, P. 2003. Earnings management and investor protection: An international comparison. Journal of Financial Economics 69: 505-527.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mak, C. Y.; Strong, N., and Walker, M. 2011. Conditional earnings conservatism and corporate refocusing activities. Journal of Accounting Research 49: 1,041-1,082.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morck, R.; Yeung, B., and Yu, W. 2000. The information content of stock markets: Why do emerging markets have synchronous stock price movements? Journal of Financial Economics 58: 215-260.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramalingegowda, S., and Yu, Y. 2012. Institutional ownership and conservatism. Journal of Accounting and Economics 53: 98-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
