<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejaltepowe</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019979</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Alternative Powertrains</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">21674191</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">21674205</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26167725</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Application of an Optimal Control Problem to a Trip-Based Energy Management for Electric Vehicles</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boehme</surname>
                  <given-names>Thomas Juergen</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Held</surname>
                  <given-names>Florian</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rollinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Christoph</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rabba</surname>
                  <given-names>Heiko</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Schultalbers</surname>
                  <given-names>Matthias</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>IAV Automotive Engineering</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lampe</surname>
                  <given-names>Bernhard</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>University of Rostock</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26167713</issue-id>
         <fpage>115</fpage>
         <lpage>126</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26167725"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A trip-based energy management strategy for electric vehicles (EVs) is proposed. It can use deterministic routing information obtained from, nowadays, available navigation systems and determines stochastic descriptions of process uncertainties such as stop events as unpredictable disturbances. A dynamic programming algorithm is used to calculate the optimal control trajectories required to reach the target destination safely and to suggest the driver an optimal driving style to maximize the battery range. The algorithm is implemented on a rapid prototyping platform using MATLAB/Simulink. Simulations and experimental results obtained from an EV prototype car are presented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bundesministerium für Verkehr, Bau und Stadtentwicklung, “Elektromobilität,” http://www.bmvbs.de/SharedDocs/DE/Artikel/IR/elektromobilitaet.html, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J. and Peng, H., “Control Optimization for a Power-Split Hybrid Vehicle,” Proceedings of the 2006 American Control Conference, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA, June 14-16, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kim, N., Cha, S., Peng, H., “Optimal Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicles Based on Pontryagin's Minimum Principle,” IEEE Transaction on Control System Technology, 19(5), pp. 1279-1287, 2011, doi: 10.1109/TCST.2010.2061232.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stockar, S., Marano V., Canova, M. and Rizzoni, G., “Energy-Optimal Control of Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles for Real-World Driving Cycles,” IEEE Transaction on Vehicular Technology 60(7), pp. 2949-2962, June 2011, doi: 10.1109/TVT.2011.2158565.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Powell, B. K., Bailey, K. E., Cikanek, S. R., “Dynamic Modeling and Control of Hybrid Electric Vehicle Powertrain System,” IEEE Control Systems Magazine, 18(5), pp. 17-33, 1998, doi: 10.1109/37.722250.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sharer, P. B., Rousseau, A., Karbowski, D., “Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicle Control Strategy: Comparison between EV and Charge- Depleting Options,” in SAE world congress, SAE International, Paper no. 2008-01-0460, April 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0460.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sciarretta, A. and Guzzella, L., “Rule-based and optimal control strategies for energy management in parallel hybrid vehicles,” Proc. 6th International Conference on Engines for Automobile. Capri, Italy, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schouten, N. J., Salman, M. A., Kheir, N. A., “Fuzzy Logic Control for Parallel Hybrid Vehicles,” IEEE Transaction on Control Systems Technology, 10(3), pp. 460-468, 2002, doi: 10.1109/87.998036.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colin, G., Bloch, G., Chamaillard, Y., Ivanco, A., “A real time neural energy management strategy for a hybrid pneumatic engine,” IFAC Symposium Advances in Automotive Control, AAC, Munich, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lin, C.-C. and Peng, H., “Control of a Hybrid Electric Truck Based on Driving Pattern Recognition,” Proceedings of the 2002 Advanced Vehicle Control Conference, Hiroshima, Japan, September, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gong, Q., Tulpule, P., Marano, V., Midlam-Mohler, S., Rizzoni, G., “The Role of ITS in PHEV Performance Improvement,” Proceedings of the 2011 American Control Conference, on O'Farrell Street, San Francisco, CA, USA, June 29 - July 01, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tulpule, P., Marano, V., Rizzoni, G., McGee, R. et al., “A Statistical Approach to Assess the Impact of Road Events on PHEV Performance using Real World Data,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-0875, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0875.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moura, S. J., Fathy, H. K., Callaway, D. S., Stein, J. L., “A Stochastic Optimal Control Approach for Power Management in Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” IEEE Transaction on Control Systems Technology, 19(3), pp. 545-555, 2011, doi: 10.1109/TCST.2010.2043736.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, J. and Peng, H., “Modeling and Control of a Power-Split Hybrid Vehicle,” IEEE Transaction on Control Systems Technology, 16(6), pp. 1242-1251, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bertsekas, D. P., “Dynamic Programming and Stochastic Control,” Academic Press New York, Chap. 1, 1976.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Boehme, T., Schultalbers, M., Rabba, H., Burger, A. et al., “A Framework for Simulation-Based Development and Calibration of VCU-Functions for Advanced PHEV Powertrains,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1032, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1032.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Qiuming, G., Yaoyu, L. and Zhong-Ren, P., “Computationally Efficient Optimal Power Management for Plug-in Hybrid Electric Vehicles Based on Spatial-Domain Two-Scale Dynamic Programming,” Vehicular Electronics and Safety, ICVES 2008, IEEE International Conference, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bin, Y., Li, Y., Gong, Q. and Peng, Z.-R., “Multi-Information Integrated Trip Specific Optimal Power Management for Plug-In Hybrid Electric Vehicles,” Proceddings of the 2009 Amercian Control Conference, Hyatt Regency riverfront, St. Louis, USA, June 10-12, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stengel, R. F., “Optimal Control and Estimation,” Dover Publications Inc., ISBN 0-486-68200-5, 1994.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nocedal, J. and Wright, S. J., “Numerical Optimization,” Second Edition, Springer Series in Operations Research, ISBN 13:978-0387-30303-1, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Betts, J.T., “Practical Methods for Optimal Control and Estimation using Nonlinear Programming,” SIAM, Second Edition, ISBN 978-0898716-88-7, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mitschke Henning, Wallentowitz Manfred, “Dynamik der Kraftfahrzeuge,” Springer-Verlag, 4th Edition, ISBN 3-540-42011-8, 2004</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
