<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277652</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Vehicular Emissions in Review</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Johnson</surname>
                  <given-names>Timothy</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Corning Incorporated</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>699</fpage>
         <lpage>715</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277652"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>This review paper summarizes major developments in vehicular emissions regulations and technologies (light-duty, heavy-duty, gasoline, diesel) in 2012. First, the paper covers the key regulatory developments in the field, including finalized criteria pollutant tightening in California; and in Europe, the development of real-world driving emissions (RDE) standards. The US finalized LD (light-duty) greenhouse gas (GHG) regulation for 2017-25. The paper then gives a brief, high-level overview of key developments in LD and HD engine technology, covering both gasoline and diesel. Marked improvements in engine efficiency are summarized for gasoline and diesel engines to meet both the emerging NOx and GHG regulations. HD engines are just starting to demonstrate 50% brake thermal efficiency. NOx control technologies are then summarized, including SCR (selective catalytic reduction) with ammonia, and hydrocarbon-based approaches. Emphasis is on low-temperature deNOx, durability, and cost reduction. PM (particulate matter) reduction technologies are evolving around SCR integration and the behavior of soot and ash deposits. Next, DOC (diesel oxidation catalyst) developments are summarized. They mainly involve better understanding of aging and substitution of base metals oxides for precious metal. The paper then discusses some key developments in gasoline emission controls, focusing on new coated GPF (gasoline particulate filter) understanding. Advanced three-way catalysts improve with layered coating technology, and with improved understanding on engine calibration.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Vehicular Emissions in Review,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2): 216-234, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0368.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Low-Emission Vehicles (LEV) &amp; GHG 2012, CARB website, http://www.arb.ca.gov/regact/2012/leviiighg2012/leviiighg2012.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lambert, C., “Current and Future Urea SCR Catalyst Systems for Light and Medium Duty Diesels”, 4th International CTI Conference: NOx Reduction - Current and Future Solutions for On- and Off-Road Applications, 19-10 June, 2012, Detroit, MI.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chart courtesy of Manufacturers of Emissions Control Association.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Regulation 715/2007 (LDV):Recital (15).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bonnel, P., Weiss, M., Provenza, A., “In-Use Emissions Requirements in the New and Future European Motor Vehicle Emissions Regulations”, European Commission - Joint Research Center (JRC), http://www.jrc.ec.europa.eu/. Presentation from SUN Conference, Detroit, September 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mamakos, A., Manfredi, U., “Physical Characterization of Exhaust Particle Emissions from Late Technology Gasoline Vehicles”, JRC Report 72196, ISBN 978-92-79-25312-6 (pdf), doi: 10.2788/3251.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">EPA/NHTSA Final Rulemaking to Establish 2017 and Later Model Years Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards, published October 15, 2012, www.epa.gov/OMSWWW/climate/regs-light-duty.htm</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Regulatory Impact Analysis: Final Rulemaking for 2017-2025 Light- Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards, EPA420-R-12-016, August 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Final Rulemaking to Establish Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards, Tables 1-3 through 18</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cackette, T., “Facing the Challenges of Air Pollution and Climate Change - A Vision for the Future.” SAE 2012 OBD Symposium, September 18-20, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCarthy, J., “CARB HD OBD Regulatory Update”, presentation at SAE OBD Symposium, Sept. 2012, Annaheim.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zwissler, B., “Developing HD-OBD Products for Worldwide Markets,” SAE 2012 OBD Symposium, September 18-20, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Limits and Measurement Methods for Exhaust Pollutants from Non- Road Diesel Engines”, DB11/185-2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">www.TheICCT.org</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kolwich, G., Steier, A., Kopinski, D., Nelson, B. et al., “Teardown- Based Cost Assessment for Use in Setting Greenhouse Gas Emissions Standards,” SAE Int. J. Passeng. Cars - Mech. Syst. 5(2):1059-1072, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1343.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Regulatory Impact Analysis: Final Rulemaking for 2017-2025 Light- Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emission Standards and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards, EPA420-R-12-016, August 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T., “Review of CO2 Emissions and Technologies in the Road Transportation Sector,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):1079-1098, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1276.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johnson, T. V., “Vehicle Emissions Review - 2011 (so far), US Department of Energy, Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference, October 3-6, 2011, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">King, J., Boggs, D., Heaney, M., Andersson, J., Keenan, M., Jackson, N., Owen, N., “HyBoost - An Intelligently Electrified Optimized Gasoline Engine”, Global Automotive Management Council Emissions 2012 conference, June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Winkler, M., “Particle Number Emissions of Direct Injected Gasoline Engines”, presentation at IQPC Advanced Emission Control Concepts for Gasoline Engines 2012, May 2012, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walther, J., Kampsmann, S., Busch, R., Kufferath, A., et al., “The EU6 Challenge at GDI - Assessments of Feasible Systems Solutions”, Answer to question during presentation at SAE/ATA conference on The Convergence of Systems Towards Sustainable Mobility, Turin, November 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fraidl, G., Hollerer, P., Kapus, P., Ogris, M., Vidmar, K., “Particulate Number for EU6+: Challenges and Solutions”, presentation at IQPC Advanced Emission Control Concepts for Gasoline Engines 2012, May 2012, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alger, T., “Developments in High Efficiency Engine Technologies”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“PSA to commercialize SwRI-developed Dedicated-EGR technology in high-efficiency gasoline engines by 2018”, http://www.greencarcongress.com/2013/02/psa-degr-20130204.html, February 9, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tomazic, D., Nanjundaswamy, H., “Achieving LEV III with a Light- Duty Diesel Powertrain - Impossible or Challenging?”, presentation at the 4th International CTI Conference on NOx Reduction - Current and Future Solutions for On- and Off-Road Applications, Detroit, June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">McCartney, J., Day, R., Ward, A., Rouaud, C., Newman, P., Borges- Alejo, J., Baubet, Y., Lindsey, S., “Integrated Technologies for Cost Effective CO2 Reduction”, SIA Conference, June 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ruth, M., “Cummins' Next Generation Tier 2, Bin 2 Light Truck Diesel Engine”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suresh, A., Langenderfer, D., Arnett, C., Ruth, M., “Thermodynamic Systems for Tier 2 Bin 2 Diesel Engines”, presentation at US DOE Directions in Engine-Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference, October 2012, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Balland, J., Schreurs, B., Hardam, H., Yasui, Y., “A New Clean Diesel Concept for US LEV III SULEV - Advanced Air/Fuel Control for NOx Reduction and for SCR Heat Up”, presentation at 4th IAV MinNOx Conference 12-13 June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>31.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wendler, A., “2014 Mazda 6 to Get Skyactiv Diesel [2012 L.A. Auto Show]”, http://blog.caranddriver.com/2014-mazda-6-to-get-skyactivdiesel- 2012-l-a-auto-show/</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>32.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.mazda.com/mazdaspirit/skyactiv/engine/skyactiv-d.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>33.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mazda, MTZ, Sept 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>34.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stanton, D., “Diesel Engine Technologies to Meet Future On-Road and Off-Road US EPA Regulations”, presentation at 4th CTI International Conference, NOx Reduction, Current and Future Solutions for On-Road and Off-Road Applications, Detroit, June 19-20, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>35.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Allain, M., Atherton, D., Gruden, I., Singh, S., Sisken, K., “Daimler's Super Truck Program; 50% Brake Thermal Efficiency”, presentation at US DOE Directions in Engine-Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER) Conference, October 2012, Detroit.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>36.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herold, R., Wahl, M., Regner, G., Lemke, J. et al., “Thermodynamic Benefits of Opposed-Piston Two-Stroke Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2011-01-2216, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-2216.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>37.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">“Achates Power, AVL Awarded $4.9Million TARDEC Contract”, Detroit Auto Scene, December 31, 2012, http://www.detroitautoscene.com/archive/print_edition_morgue/2012/12-31/m-2.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>38.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Regner, G., Johnson, D., Koszewnik, J., Dion, E. et al., “Modernizing the Opposed Piston, Two Stroke Engine for Clean, Efficient Transportation”, SAE Technical Paper 2013-26-0114, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>39.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rexeis, M, Hausberger, S., “NOx-Emission Trends from EU1 to EU6”, presentation at IAV MinNOx Conference, June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>40.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, A., “Current and Future Trends in Catalyst-Based Emission Control System Design”, presentation at the SAE Heavy-Duty Diesel Emission Control Symposium, September 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>41.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Prikhodko, V., Pihl, J., Lewis, S. and Parks, J., “Hydrocarbon Fouling of SCR During PCCI Combustion,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1080.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>42.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Luo, J., Yezerets, A., Henry, C., Hess, H. et al., “Hydrocarbon Poisoning of Cu-Zeolite SCR Catalysts,” SAE Technical Paper a2012-01-1096, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1096.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>43.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Schrade, F., Brammer, M., Schaeffner, J., Langeheinecke, K. et al., “Physico-Chemical Modeling of an Integrated SCR on DPF (SCR/DPF) System,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1083.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>44.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rohe, R., Marques, R., Harris, D., Jones, C., “New Acidic Zirconia Mixed Oxides for NH3-SCR Catalysts for Better Passenger Cars Integration”, presentation at the IAV MinNOx Conference, June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>45.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stiebels, S., Wendt, C., Neubauer, T., Müller-Stach, T., “Smart Catalyst Technologies for Future Automotive Emission Control”, presentation at the IAV MinNOx Conference, June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>46.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Partridge, W., Pihl, J., Auvray, X., Olsson, L., Kamasamudram, K., Yezerets, A., et al., “Local Ammonia Storage in a Monolithic SCR Catalyst”, presentation at the 9th Catalysts for Automotive Pollution Control (CAPoC) Conference, September 2012, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>47.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bartley, G., Chadwell, C., Kostek, T., and Zhan, R., “SCR Deactivation Kinetics for Model-Based Control and Accelerated Aging Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1077, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>48.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Henry, C., Gupta, A., Currier, N., Ruth, M., Hess, H., Naseri, M., Cumaranatunge, L., Chen, “Advanced Technology Light Duty Diesel Aftertreatment System”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>49.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yasui, Y., Matsunaga, H., Hashimoto, E., Satoh, N., Hardam, H., Balland, J., Yamada, M., Takahashi, T., “A New Clean Diesel Concept for US LEV-III SULEV - First Report - A New Emission Strategy and Aftertreatment Management Control, presentation at the IAV MinNOx Conference, June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>50.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yuji Yasui, Y., Matsunaga, H., Hardam, H., Balland, J., et al., “A New Clean Diesel Concept for US LEV III SULEV”, presentation at FISITA Conference, Shanghai, December 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>51.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hansen, K. F., Hägg, A., Lepage, M., Yasui, Y., et al., “Solid Ammonia Storage for 3rd Generation SCR”, presentation at the IAV MinNOx Conference, June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>52.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Laroo, C. of US EPA, Ann Arbor, personal communications, April 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>53.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moos, R, Beulertz, G., Votsmeier, M., Gieshoff, J., et al., “Overview: Status of Microwave-Based Automotive Catalyst State Diagnosis”, presentation at the 9th Catalysts for Automotive Pollution Control (CAPoC) Conference, September 2012, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>54.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Suga, K., Naito, T., Hanaki, Y., Nakamura, M. et al., “High-efficiency NOx Trap Catalyst with Highly Dispersed Precious Metal for Low Precious Metal Loading,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1246, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1246.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>55.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsukamoto, Y., Nishioka, H., Imai, D., Sobue, Y. et al., “Development of New Concept Catalyst for Low CO2 Emission Diesel Engine Using NOx Adsorption at Low Temperatures,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0370, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>56.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harold, M., Liu, Y., Luss, D., “Lean NOx Reduction With Dual Layer LNT/SCR Catalysts”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>57.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morita, T., Suzuki, N., Satoh, N., Wada, K. et al., “Study on Low NOX Emission Control Using Newly Developed Lean NOX Catalyst for Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0239, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>58.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bisaiji, Y., Yoshida, K., Inoue, M., Umemoto, K. et al., “Development of Di-Air - A New Diesel deNOx System by Adsorbed Intermediate Reductants,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):380-388, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-2089.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>59.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Inoue, M., Bisaiji, Y., Yoshida, K., Takagi, N, Fukuma, T., “DeNOx Performance and Reaction Mechanism of the Di-Air System”, presentation at the 9th Catalysts for Automotive Pollution Control (CAPoC) Conference, September 2012, Brussels.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>60.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yoshida, K., Bisaiji, Y., Takagi, N., Inoue, M., Umemoto, K., Fukuma, T., “A Study of the NOx Reduction Mechanism for Improving the Performance of Di-Air”, presentation at 4th IAV MinNOx Conference 12-13 June 2012, Berlin.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>61.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Folić, M., Johansen, K., “SCR-DPF Integrations for Diesel Exhaust Performance and Perspectives for High SCR Loadings”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref62">
            <label>62.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shiel, K., Naber, J., Johnson, J., and Hutton, C., “Catalyzed Particulate Filter Passive Oxidation Study with ULSD and Biodiesel Blended Fuel,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0837, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0837.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref63">
            <label>63.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakovec, N., Viswanathan, S., and Foster, D., “Microscale Study of DPF Permeability as a Function of PM Loading,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):913-921, 2011, doi:10.4271/2011-01-0815.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref64">
            <label>64.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Viswanathan, S., Rakovec, N., Foster, D. E., “Microscale Study of Ash Accumulation Process in the DPF Walls Using the Diesel Exhaust Filtration Analysis (DEFA) System”, proceedings of the ASME 2012 Internal Combustion Engine Division Fall Conference, paper ICEF2012-92104, September 2012, Vancouver.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref65">
            <label>65.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamp, C., Sappok, A., and Wong, V., “Soot and Ash Deposition Characteristics at the Catalyst-Substrate Interface and Intra-Layer Interactions in Aged Diesel Particulate Filters Illustrated using Focused Ion Beam (FIB) Milling,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):696-710, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0836.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref66">
            <label>66.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kamp, C. J., Sappok, A., Wong, V. W., “Uncovering Fundamental Ash- Formation Mechanisms and Potential Means to Control the Impact on DPF Performance and Engine Efficiency”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref67">
            <label>67.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sappok, A., Govani, I, Kamp, C. J., Wong, V. W., “A Revealing Look Inside Passive and Active DPF Regeneration: In-Situ Optical Analysis of Ash Formation and Transport”,”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref68">
            <label>68.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fujii, S., “DPF Design Optimization from View Point of The Lifetime Performance with Ash Loading”, presentation at GAMC Emissions 2011, Ann Arbor, June 14, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref69">
            <label>69.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bielaczyc, P., Keskinen, J., Dzida, J., Sala, R. et al., “Performance of Particle Oxidation Catalyst and Particle Formation Studies with Sulphur Containing Fuels,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(2):611-619, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0366.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref70">
            <label>70.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, J., Szailer, T., Watts, A., Currier, N., Yezerets, A., “Investigation of the Impact of Real-World Aging on Diesel Oxidation Catalysts,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1094.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref71">
            <label>71.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Millo, F. and Vezza, D., “Characterization of a New Advanced Diesel Oxidation Catalyst with Low Temperature NOx Storage Capability for LD Diesel,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0373, 2012, doi: a10.4271/2012-01-0373.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref72">
            <label>72.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ishizaki, K., Mitsuda, N., Ohya, N., Ohno, H. et al., “A Study of PGMFree Oxidation Catalyst YMnO3 for Diesel Exhaust Aftertreatment,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0365, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-0365.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref73">
            <label>73.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, W., McCool, G., Kapur, N., Yuan, G., Shan, B., Nguyen, M., Graham, U. M., Davis, B. H., Jacobs, G. Cho, K., Hao, X., “Mixed- Phase Oxide Catalyst Based on Mn-Mullite (Sm, Gd)Mn2O5 for NO Oxidation in Diesel Exhaust”, Science 337, 832 (2012), DOI: 10.1126/science.122509.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref74">
            <label>74.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cargnello, M., Delgado Jaén, J. J., Hernández Garrido, J. C., Bakhmutsky, K., et al., “Exceptional Activity for Methane Combustion over Modular Pd - CeO2 Subunits on Functionalized Al2O3, Science 337, 713 (2012), DOI: 10.1126/science.1222887.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref75">
            <label>75.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Richter, J., Klingman, R., Speiss, S., Wong, K., “Application of Catalyzed Gasoline Particulate Filters to GDI Vehicles,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(3):2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1244.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref76">
            <label>76.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chan, T., Meloche, E., Kubsh, J., Rosenblatt, D. et al., “Evaluation of a Gasoline Particulate Filter to Reduce Particle Emissions from a Gasoline Direct Injection Vehicle,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(3):1277-1290, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1727.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref77">
            <label>77.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Morgan, C., “Three Way Filters (TWFTM) for Particulate Number Control”, presentation at IQPC Advanced Emission Control Concepts for Gasoline Engines 2012, May 2012, Stuttgart.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref78">
            <label>78.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spiess, S., Wong, K. F., Richter, J. M., Klingmann, R., “Investigations of Exhaust Aftertreatment Systems for Removal of Particulate Emissions from Gasoline Injection Engines”, presentation at the 9th Catalysts for Automotive Pollution Control (CAPoC) Conference, September 2012, Brussels</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref79">
            <label>79.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Matsuzono, Y., kuroki, K., Nishi, T., Suzuki, N. et al., “Development of Advanced and Low PGM TWC System for LEV2 PZ EV and LEV3 SULEV30,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1242, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref80">
            <label>80.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ball, D. and Moser, D., “Cold Start Calibration of Current PZEV Vehicles and the Impact of LEV-III Emission Regulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1245, 2012, doi:10.4271/2012-01-1245.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref81">
            <label>81.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zammit, M., Wuttke, J., Ravindran, P., and Aaltonen, S., “The Effects of Catalytic Converter Location and Palladium Loading on Tailpipe Emissions,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-1247, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-1247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref82">
            <label>82.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toops, T. J., Parks, J. E.II, Pihl, J. A., DiGiulio, C. D., Amiridis, M. D., “Lean Gasoline Emissions Control: NH3 Generation over Commercial Three-Way Catalysts and Lean-NOx Traps”, presentation at the US Department of Energy Directions in Engine Efficiency and Emissions Research (DEER), Dearborn, MI, October 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
