<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">23026282</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>DETERMINANTS OF FARM HOUSEHOLDS' ACCESS TO INFORMAL CREDIT IN LUME DISTRICT, CENTRAL ETHIOPIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Teressa</given-names>
                  <surname>Adugna</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Franz</given-names>
                  <surname>Heidhues</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2000</year>
         </pub-date>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i23026279</issue-id>
         <fpage>27</fpage>
         <lpage>45</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23026282"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>In this article, logit models were used to identify socioeconomic factors that influence farm households' access to informal credit. The empirical results indicate that farm households' informal borrowing in kind was influenced negatively by farm size (cultivated land) and the number of oxen and positively by off-farm income and the number of small ruminants. Dependency rate and rented-out land were found to have a significant positive effect on farm households'access to informal credit in cash, while the number of oxen and off-farm income have influenced it negatively. Informal borrowing decision in kind and/or cash was affected negatively by the number of oxen and positively by dependency rate, health condition of farm household members and rented-out land. These results support the general expectation that poor farm households are more likely to involve in informal borrowings. In sum, the results of the study show that informal credit dealings are likely to be influenced by the resources farm households own (land, oxen and small ruminants), their health situation, dependency rate and land tenure arrangements. These findings have important implications for designing and delivering appropriate credit facilities to (poor) farm households. Cet article se sert de modèles Logit pour identifier les facteurs socio-économiques qui influencent l'accès des ménages agricoles au crédit informel. Les résultats empiriques indiquent d'une part que le prêt informel en nature est négativement influencé par la taille de l'exploitation (quantité de terre emblavée) et le nombre de boeufs en possession et positivement par le revenu extra-agricole et le nombre de petits ruminants. D'autre part, l'accès au crédit informel en espèce est positivement influencé par le taux de dépendance et la quantité de terre mise en location et négativement par le nombre de bceufs et le revenu extra-agricole. En outre le nombre de bœufs en possession a un impact négatif, le taux de dépendance et la situation sanitaire des membres du menage un impact positif sur le prêt en nature et/ou en espèce. Ces résultats supportent l'opinion générate selon laquelle les exploitations agricoles pauvres seraient plus impliquées dans le prêt informel. En somme, les resultats de l'étude montrent que l'accès au crédit informel est influencé par la dotation en ressources de l'exploitation (terre, bœufs et petits ruminants), sa situation sanitaire, le taux de dépendance et les arrangements fonciers. Ces résultats ont des implications importantes pour la conception et l'offre adéquates de crédit aux ménages agricoles (pauvres).</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d36e156a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e163" publication-type="other">
Greene, 1993</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e170a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e177" publication-type="other">
Maddala, 1992:330-1</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="d36e193a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e197" publication-type="other">
Abbott, J.C., "Credit for Production in Developing Countries," Food Policy, Vol. 1, No. 3, 1976, pp. 239-248.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e204a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e208" publication-type="other">
Adugna, Teressa, The Impact of Foreign Aid and Trade in Ethiopia: Macro, Sectoral and Micro Level Analysis,
Verlag Ulriche Grauer, Stuttgart, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e218a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e222" publication-type="other">
Amde, Yisgedullish, Tesfaye Teklu and Sisay Asefa, "Determinants of Participation in Rural Credit Markets in
Africa: Evidence from Botswana and Ethiopia," African Rural and Urban Studies, Vol. 1, No. 3, 1994, pp. 99-114.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e232a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e236" publication-type="other">
Binswanger, Hans P., and Shahidur R. Khandker, "The Impact of Formal Finance on the Rural Economy of
India,''The Journal of Development Studies, Vol. 32, No. 2, December 1995, pp. 234-262.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e247a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e251" publication-type="other">
The Ethiopian Herald, Vol. LIV, No. 56, Saturday 5, November 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e258a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e262" publication-type="other">
Freeman, H. A., M.A. Jabbar, S. K. Ehui and N. Gebreselassie, "The Role of Credit in the Uptake of Improved Dairy
Technologies in Ethiopia,''Ethiopian Journal of Agricultural Economics, Vol. 1, No. 1, September 1996, pp. 1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e272a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e276" publication-type="other">
Fuentes, Gabriel A., "The Use of Village Agents in Rural Credit Delivery," The Journal of Development Studies,
Vol. 33, No. 2, December 1996, pp. 188-209.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e286a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e290" publication-type="other">
Germidis, Dimitri, "Interlinking the Formal and Informal Financial Sectors in Developing Countries," Saving and
Development, Vol. XIV, No. 1, 1990, pp. 5-22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e300a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e304" publication-type="other">
Greene, William H., Econometric Analysis, 2nd ed., New York, 1993.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e311a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e315" publication-type="other">
Heidhues, Franz, "Rural Finance Markets - An Important Tool to Fight Poverty", "Quarterly Journal of International
Agriculture, Vol. 34, No. 2, 1995, pp. 105-108.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e326a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e330" publication-type="other">
Holmberg, Johan, The Credit Programme of the Chilalo Agricultural Development Unit (CADU) in Ethiopia, in
Small Farmer Credit in Ethiopia, Vol. VIII, Agency for International Development Department of State, Washington, D.C.,
February 1973.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e343a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e347" publication-type="other">
Itty, P., P. Ankers, J. Zinsstag, S. Trawally and K. Pfister, "Productivity and Profitability of Sheep Production in The
Gambia: Implications for Livestock Development in West Africa," Quarterly Journal of International Agriculture, Vol. 36,
No. 2, April-June 1997, pp. 153.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e360a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e364" publication-type="other">
Lele, Uma J., The Design of Rural Development: Lessons from Africa, Johns Hopkins University Press, Baltimore,
1975.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e374a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e378" publication-type="other">
Maddala, G.S., Introduction to Econometrics, 2nd Ed., Prentice-Hall, Inc., New Jersey, 1992.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e385a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e389" publication-type="other">
Negassa, Asfaw, Kisan Gunjal, Wilferd Mwangi and Beyene Seboka, "Factors Affecting the Adoption of Maize
Production Technologies in Bako Area, Ethiopia," Ethiopian Journal of Agricultural Economics, Vol. 1, No. 2, April 1997,
pp. 52-73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e402a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e406" publication-type="other">
World Bank, sub-Sahara Africa: From Crisis to Sustainable Growth, World Bank, Washington, D.C., 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
