<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">afrirevmonfinban</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002968</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>African Review of Money Finance and Banking</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>"Giordano dell'Amore" Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">11243163</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1/2</issue>
         <issue-id>i23027493</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23027501</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>RURAL FINANCIAL MARKETS AND THE FOOD SECURITY OF THE POOR: THE CASE OF CAMEROON</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Gertrud</given-names>
                  <surname>Schrieder</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Franz</given-names>
                  <surname>Heidhues</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1995</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>131</fpage>
         <lpage>154</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23027501"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Cameroon's overall food self—sufficiency rate equals 96 percent. Nevertheless, chronic and transitory food insecurity exists. Natural calamities and population density are generally accepted as prime causes of Cameroon's food insecurity problem. The country's North suffers from periodic droughts, and in its West and North—West provinces production falls short of needs due to insufficient access to arable land. The underlying hypothesis of this paper is that notwithstanding natural constraints and population pressure, the food security of Cameroon's rural population can be improved by developing accesible financial markets. The impact of missing rural finance schemes for the poor's food security reveals itself in two ways. Firstly, if the poor have no access to financial means to bridge temporary, often seasonal short—term food shortages, human productive capacity suffers through mal— and undernutrition. Lower productivity and income losses are the consequence. This can lead to chronic food insecurity if human productive capacity is lost in the long run. Secondly, an income shortfall and inaccessibility to external financial means can undermine the ability of rural households to invest in agriculture which may sap long—term food security. Non—investment in agriculture and alternative income creating activities reduces future income streams and consecutively endangers food security in the long run. In the framework of the IFPRI/University of Hohenheim Project 'Credit for the Rural Poor in Sub—Saharan Africa', a detailed micro—economic survey has been conducted from October 1991 to October 1992 in three Cameroonian provinces (Adamawa, North West and West). The empirical results support the above hypothesis that food security relates to financial market access and income improvements. Access to sustainable financial market services improves income, and in turn, income has a positive and significant impact on rural households' food security. Financial market services can improve food security in providing both, production and consumption credit. Le taux d'auto—suffisance alimentaire au Cameroun s'élève à 96 pour—cent. Pourtant l'insécurité alimentaire à court et à long terme y existe. Les catastrophes naturelles et la densité de la population sont généralement vues comme raisons principales de l'insécurité alimentaire au Cameroun. Le nord du pays est frappé par des sêcheresses périodiques et dans les provinces de l'Ouest et Nord—Ouest la production agricole est déficitaire à cause de l'accès insuffisant aux terres cultivables. Cet article part de l'hypothèse principale selon laquelle l'amélioration de l'accès au marché financier rural peut permettre de stabiliser et/ou d'accroître le niveau de consommation alimentaire dans les ménages ruraux. L'impact du manque des méchanisms financiers appropriés sur la sécurité alimentaire des populations pauvres se manisfeste de deux façons. Premièrement, si les populations pauvres n'ont pas accès aux moyens financiers pour couvrir l'insuffisance d'alimentation temporaire, qui se manifeste souvent pendant les saisons de pénurie, le capital de production humain souffre à cause de la sous—alimentation. Les conséquences au niveau des ménages ruraux sont la baisse de la productivité et la réduction des revenus. Cela peut produire une insuffisance alimentaire à long terme si le capital de production humain souffre en permanence. Deuxièmement, le manque de revenu et l'inexistance des services financiers externes peuvent réduire la capacité d'investissement agricole des ménages ruraux. La carence des investissements dans l'agriculture et dans des activités qui offrent des revenus alternatifs au milieu rural réduit les revenus dans l'avenir et, par conséquent, met en danger la sécurité alimentaire à long terme. Dans le cadre d'un projet conjoint de l'IFPRI en collaboration avec l'Université de Hohenheim 'Crédit pour les Populations Pauvres Rurales en Afrique Subsaharienne', une enquête micro—économique a été menée d'Octobre 1991 à Octobre 1992 dans trois provinces camerounaises (Adamaoua, Nord—Ouest et Ouest). Les résultats empiriques soutiennent l'hypothèse mentionnée ci—dessus, selon laquelle la sécurité alimentaire est étraitement liée avec l'accès aux moyens financiers et avec l'augmentation de revenu. L'accès aux services financiers viables améliore les revenus et, par conséquent, a un impact positif et significatif sur la sécurité alimentaire des ménages ruraux.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d771e174a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d771e181" publication-type="other">
A
previous version of this paper was presented at the Second International Conference on "Sécurité Alimentaire a
Court et Long Termes" Córdoba, Spain, September 14-16, 1994.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d771e194a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d771e201" publication-type="other">
von Braun et al. 1992</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d771e207" publication-type="other">
Reutlinger 1987</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d771e214a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d771e221" publication-type="other">
Feder et al. (1990)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d771e227" publication-type="other">
Zeller (1993)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d771e243a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e247" publication-type="other">
Braun, J. von, H. Bouis, S. Kumar, R. Pandya-Lorch. (1992) «Improving Food Security of the Poor: Concept Policy
and Programs». Washington, D.C.: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e257a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e261" publication-type="other">
Braun, J. von, D. Puetz, and P. Webb. (1989) «Irrigation Technology and Commercialization of Rice in The Gambia:
Effects on Income and Nutrition». IFPRI Research Report No. 75. Washington, D.C.: International Food
Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e278" publication-type="other">
Eswaran, M. and A. Kotwal. (1990) Implications of credit constraints for risk behavior in less-developed countries.
Oxford Economic Papers 42. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e292" publication-type="other">
Feder, G., Lau, L.J., Lin, J.Y., and X. Luo. (1990) «The relationship between credit and productivity in Chinese
agriculture: A microeconomic model of disequilibrium», American Journal of Agricultural Economics
Association. Vol. 72, No. 5, pp. 1151-1157.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e306a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e310" publication-type="other">
Heidhues, F. (1994a) «Die Rolle landlicher Finanzmarkte fur die Armutsbekampfung». Paper presented at the
Agrarokonomisches Kolloquium Sommer 1994. Kiel: University of Kiel.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e320a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e324" publication-type="other">
Heidhues, F. (1994b) «Consumption Credit in Rural Financial Market Development».In Financial Landscapes
Reconstructed, eds. Bouman, F.J.A. and O. Hospes,33-48. Boulder: Westview Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e334a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e338" publication-type="other">
Ikhide, S.I. (1993) «Positive Interest Rates: Financial Deepening and the Mobilization of Savings in Africa».
Development Policy Review, Vol.11 (December), pp. 367-382.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e348a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e352" publication-type="other">
Maddala, G.S. (1983) «Two-stage methods for switching regression models». In Limited–dependent and
qualitative variables in econometrics. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e362a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e366" publication-type="other">
Reutlinger, S. (1987) «Food security and poverty in developing countries». In Food policy. Integrating supply,
distribution, and consumption, eds. Gittinger, J.P., J. Leslie, and C. Hoisington, 205-214. Baltimore, Md.,
USA: Johns Hopkins University Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e379a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e383" publication-type="other">
Sab, C. (1984) «Baseline Survey of Protein-Energy Malnutrition in Donga/Mantung Division». Bamenda/North
West Province, Cameroon: Ministry of Agriculture, Preventive Medicine and Rural Health Services, Nutrition
Service.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e397a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e401" publication-type="other">
Schrieder, G. and F. Heidhues. (1993) «.Credit for the rural poor: Cameroon country case». Part 3 of Final Report
to GTZ. Washington, D.C.: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e411a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e415" publication-type="other">
World Bank. (1991) «Report 9048–CM: Staff Appraisal Report – Republic of Cameroon –Food Security Project».
Washington, D.C.: Agricultural Operations, Occidental and Central African Department. May.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e425a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e429" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M. (1993) «Credit policies for food security for the poor: country case Madagascar». Part 2 of Final Report
to GTZ. Washington, D.C.: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d771e439a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d771e443" publication-type="other">
Zeller, M. etal. (1993) "Credit for food security of the rural poor: Conceptual issues." Summary of an IFPRI project
workshop. Washington, D.C.: International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI).</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


