<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278343</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>A Study of Newly Developed HCCI Engine With Wide Operating Range Equipped With Blowdown Supercharging System</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kuboyama</surname>
                  <given-names>Tatsuya</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Moriyoshi</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuo</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Chiba Univ.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hatamura</surname>
                  <given-names>Koichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Hatamura Engine Research Office</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Takanashi</surname>
                  <given-names>Junichi</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>HONDA R&amp;D</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Urata</surname>
                  <given-names>Yasuhiro</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>HONDA R&amp;D</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yamada</surname>
                  <given-names>Toshio</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>CD-adapco</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2012</year>
            <string-date>May 2012</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">5</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278342</issue-id>
         <fpage>51</fpage>
         <lpage>66</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright 2011 Society of Automotive Engineers of Japan, Inc. and SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278343"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>To extend the operating range of a gasoline HCCI engine, the blowdown supercharging (BDSC) system and the EGR guide were developed and experimentally examined. The concepts of these techniques are to obtain a large amount of dilution gas and to generate a strong in-cylinder thermal stratification without an external supercharger for extending the upper load limit of HCCI operation whilst keeping dP/dθ<sub>max</sub>and NOₓ emissions low. Also, to attain stable HCCI operation using the BDSC system with wide operating conditions, the valve actuation strategy in which the amount of dilution gas is smaller at lower load and larger at higher load was proposed. Additionally to achieve multi-cylinder HCCI operation with wide operating range, the secondary air injection system was developed to reduce cylinder-to-cylinder variation in ignition timing. As a result, the acceptable HCCI operation could be achieved with wide operating range, from IMEP of 135 kPa to 580 kPa. Compared to conventional SI operation, BSFC was improved by 14 % ∼ 35 % with more than 99 % reduction in NOₓ emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Willand, J., Nieberding, R., Vent, G., and Enderle, C., “The Knocking yndrome- Its Cure and Its Ptential”, SAE technical paper No. 982483, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urata, Y., Awasaka, M, Takanashi, J., Kakinuma, T., Hakozaki, T. and memoto, A., “A Study of Gasoline-Fuelled HCCI Engine Equipped ith an Electromagnetic Valve Train”, SAE technical paper No. 2004-01-1898, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiraya, K., Hasegawa, K., Urushihara, T., Iiyama, A. and Itoh, T., “A tudy on Gasoline Fueled Compression Ignition Engine ∼ A Trial of peration Region Expansion ∼”, SAE technical paper No. 2002-01-0416, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuerhapter, A., Piock, W. F., and Fraidl, G. K., “CSI - Controlled Auto gnition - the Best Solution for the Fuel Consumption - Versus Emission rade-Off?”, SAE technical paper No. 2003-10-0754, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hyvönen, J., Haraldsson, G. and Johansson, B., “Supercharging HCCI o Extend the Operating Range in a Multi-Cylinder VCR-HCCI ngine”, SAE technical paper No. 2003-01-3214, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Johansson, T., Johansson, B., Tunestal, P. and Aulin, H, “HCCI perating Range in a Turbo-charged Multi Cylinder Engine with VVT nd Spray-Guided DI”, SAE technical paper No. 2009-01-0494, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. and Yang, Y., “Boosted HCCI for High Power without Engine nock and with Ultra-Low NOx Emissions - using Conventional asoline,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):750-767, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1086.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Takanashi, J., Awasaka, M., Kakinuma, T., Takazawa, M. and Urata, Y., “A STUDY OF GASOLINE HCCI ENGINE EQUIPPED WITH AN LECTROMAGNETIC VVT MECHANISM - INCREASING THE IGHER LOAD OPERATIONAL RANGE WITH THE INTERCYLINDER GR BOOST SYSTEM -”, F2006P360, FISITA2006, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Comparing Enhanced Natural Thermal tratification Against Retarded Combustion Phasing for Smoothing of CCI Heat-Release Rates”, SAE technical paper No. 2004-01-2994, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Potential of Thermal Stratification and ombustion Retard for Reducing Pressure-Rise Rates in HCCI Engines, ased on Multi-Zone Modeling and Experiments”, SAE technical paper o. 2005-01-0113, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M. and Dec, J. E., “Effects of Engine Speed, Fueling Rate, and ombustion Phasing on the Thermal Stratification Required to Limit CCI Knocking Intensity”, SAE technical paper No. 2005-01-2125, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E., Hwang, W. and Sjöberg, M., “An Investigation of Thermal tratification in HCCI Engine Using Chemiluminescence Imaging”, AE technical paper No. 2006-01-1518, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Krasselt, J., Foster, D., Ghandhi, J., Herold, R., Reuss, D. and Naji, P., “Investigation into the Effects of Thermal and Compositional tratification on HCCI Combustion - Part I: Metal Engine Results”, AE technical paper No. 2009-01-1105, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Herold, R., Krasselt, J., Foster, D., Ghandhi, J. et al., “Investigations nto the Effects of Thermal and Compositional Stratification on HCCI ombustion - Part II: Optical Engine Results,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1): 1034-1053, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1106.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Assanis, D. N. and Fiveland, S., “An Approach for odeling the Effects of Gas Exchange processes on HCCI Combustion nd its Application in Evaluating Variable Valve Timing Control trategies”, SAE technical paper No. 2002-01-2829, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Babajimopoulos, A., Lavoie, G. A. and Assanis, D., “Modeling HCCI ombustion With High Levels of Residual Gas Fraction - A omparison of Two VVA Strategies”, SAE technical paper NO. 2003-01-3220, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Urushihara, T., Hiraya, K., Kakuhou, A. and Itoh, T., “Expansion of CCI Operating Region by the Combination of Direct Fuel Injection, egative Valve Overlap and Internal Fuel Reformation”, SAE technical aper No. 2003-01-0749, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mariott, C. D. and Reitz, R. D., “Experimental Investigation of Direct njection-Gasoline for Premixed Compression Ignition Combustion hasing Control”, SAE technical paper No. 2002-01-0418, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mariott, C. D., Kong, S. and Reitz, R. D. Investigation of Hydrocarbon mission from a Direct Injection-Gasoline Premixed Charge ompression Ignited Engine. SAE Technical paper No. 2002-01-0419</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sjöberg, M., Edling, L., Eliassen, T., Magnusson, L. and Ångström, H., “GDI HCCI: Effects of Injection Timing and Air Swirl on Fuel tratification, Combustion and Emissions Formation”, SAE technical aper No. 2002-01-0106</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J. E. and Sjöberg, M., “A Parametric Study of HCCI Combustion - he Sources of Emissions at Low Loads and the Effects of GDI Fuel njection”, SAE technical paper No. 2003-01-0752</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Flowers, D., Aceves, S. M., Martinez-Frias, J., Smith, J. R., Au, M., irard, J. and Dibble, R., “Operation of a Four-Cylinder 1.9L Propane ueled Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition Engine: Basic perating Characteristics and Cylinder-to-Cylinder Effects”, SAE echnical paper No. 2001-01-1895, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yun, H., Kang, J., Chang, M., and Najt, P., “Improvement on Cylinderto- ylinder Variation Using a Cylinder Balancing Control Strategy in asoline HCCI Engines”, SAE technical paper No. 2010-01-0848, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hatamura, K., “A Study on HCCI (Homogeneous Charge Compression gnition) Gasoline Engine Supercharged by Exhaust Blow Down ressure”, SAE technical paper No. 2007-01-1873, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.cd-adapco.com/products/star_cd/index.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.gtisoft.com/products/p_GT_SUITE.php</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.diganars.com/index.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Golovichev, V., Mechanism for ic8h18 (+EGR), Chalmers University, othenburg, Sweden, 2004. www-cms.llnl.gov/combustion/ombusiton2.html</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Eng, J. A., “Characterization of Pressure Waves in HCCI Combustion”, AE technical paper No. 2002-01-2859, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>30.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Milovanovic, N., Blundell, D., Pearson, R., Turner, J and Chen, R., “Enlarging the Operational Range of a Gasoline HCCI Engine By ontrolling the Coolant Temperature”, SAE technical paper No. 2005-01-0157, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
