<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Giodano Dell'Amore Foundation</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">18</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">4</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830391</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830398</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>THE BID-ASK SPREADS IN THE BLACK MARKETS FOR DOLLARS OF EL SALVADOR AND GUATEMALA / L'ECART ENTRE PRIX D'ACHAT ET DE VENTE EN DOLLAR SUR LES MARCHES PARALLELES DU GUATEMALA E DU SALVADOR</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Luis René</given-names>
                  <surname>Cáceres</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Oscar</given-names>
                  <surname>Núñez-Sandoval</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>517</fpage>
         <lpage>524</lpage>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830398"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>This paper analyses the spread between selling and buying prices of the US dollars in the black markets of Guatemala and El Salvador. This is a topic that has received relatively little attention in the Economies Literature but it can be a source of insights on the role palyed by uncertainty, volume and seasonal factors on the price of foreign exchange. After a review of the literature on this theme, a model was formulated with monthly date expressing the spread as a function of the money supply, the mont variation of the exchange rate and the standard variation of the exchange rate in the past five months. The equation was estimated with mixed results: the money supply has a sign contrary to the expected in El Salvador: the initiation on the exchange rate is significant in both equations but shows a contrary sign in El Salvador. The variability of the exchange rate was primitive and significative in Es Salvador but insignificative in Guatemala. The results permit to conclude that money supply is not an appropriate proxy for the volume of transactions in the foreign exchange market and that volatility of the exchange market has incidence on the spread, thus stable markets contribute to reducing the costs of requiring currency in the exchange markets. Ce document analyse l'écart entre les prix d'achat et de vente en dolar. E.U sur les marchés parallèles du Guatemala et du El Salvador. C'est un sujet important qui a reçu relativement peu d'attention sur le plan économique, mais il peut êntre la source d'analyse du rôle à jouer par l'incertitude, le volume et les facteurs saisoniers sur les prix des opérations en devises. Après avoir réexaminé ce sujet, un modèle a été formulé à l'aide de données mensuelles exprimant l'écart comme une fonction de l'offre de monnaie, les variations mensuelles du taux de change et les variations standard du taux de change dans les cinq mois antérieurs. L'équations a été estimée avec des résultats différénts: l'offre de monnaie a un signe contraire à ce qu'on attendait au El Salvador; et les variations du taux de change sont significatives dans les deux cas, mais elles montrent un signe contraire au El Salvador. Les variations du taux de change étaient positives et significatives au El Salvador, mais insignificatives dans le cas du Guatemala. Les résultats permettent de conclure que l'offre de monnaie n'est pas une donnée appropriée pour les volumes des transactions sur le marché de changes extérieur, et que la volatilité du marché de changes a une incidence sur l'écart, et que des marchés stables ont contribué à réduire les coûts de la monnaie acquise sur les marchés des changes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d15e129a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e136" publication-type="other">
Dornbusch et el (1983)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e142" publication-type="other">
Caceres and Nunez-Sandoval (1991</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e148" publication-type="other">
1992a</mixed-citation>
            </p>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e155" publication-type="other">
1992b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
        <fn id="d15e162a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d15e169" publication-type="other">
Caceres and Nunez-Sandoval (1992b)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d15e185a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e189" publication-type="other">
Agmon, T. and A. Barnea, "Transaction Costs and Marketability Services in the Eurocurrency Money Market",
Journal of Monetary Economics, Vol. 3, 1977, pp. 359-366.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e199a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e203" publication-type="other">
Caceres, L.R. and O. Nunez-Sandoval, "La Determinacion del Tipo de Cambio en el Mercado Negro de El Salvador",
El Trimestre Econdmico, Vol. LVIII (2), No. 230, April-June, 1991, pp. 249-262.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e213a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e217" publication-type="other">
Caceres, L.R. and O. Nunez-Sandoval,"Influencias Domesticas y Externas en la Determinacion de las Tasas de
Cambio en los Mercados Negros de Guatemala y El Salvador", El Trimestre Econdmico, April-June, 1992,
pp. 297-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e230a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e234" publication-type="other">
Caceres, L.R. and O. Nunez-Sandoval, "La Relacion de Equilibrio de Largo Plazo entre las Tasas de Cambio en
los Mercados Negros de Guatemala y El Salvador", El Trimestre Econdmico, July-September, 1992, pp.
297-310;</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e248a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e252" publication-type="other">
Dornbusch, R. et al, "The Black Market for Dollars in Brazil".The Quaterly Journal of Economics, Vo. 98, February
1983, pp. 25-40.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e262a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e266" publication-type="other">
Fieleke, N.S. "Exchange-Rate Flexibility and the Efficiency of the Foreign-Exchange Markets", Journal of Financial
Quantitative Analysis, Vol. 10, September, 1975, pp. 406-428.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e276a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e280" publication-type="other">
Glassman, D., "Exchange Rate Risk and Transaction Costs: Evidence from Bid-Ask Spreads". Journal of
International Money and Finance, Vol, 6, 1987, pp. 479-490.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e290a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e294" publication-type="other">
Overturf, S.F., "Risk Transaction Charges and the Market for Foreign Exchange Services", Economic Inquiry, Vol,
XX, No. 2, April 1982, pp. 291-301.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d15e304a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d15e308" publication-type="other">
Wei, Shang-Jin, "Anticipations of Foreign Exchange Volatility and Bid-Ask Spreads", Board of Governors of the
Federal Reserve System, International Finance Discussion Papers, No. 409, August, 1991.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


