<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26275514</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effects of Rail Pressure, Pilot Scheduling and EGR Rate on Combustion and Emissions in Conventional and PCCI Diesel Engines</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Catania</surname>
                  <given-names>Andrea Emilio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>d'Ambrosio</surname>
                  <given-names>Stefano</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Finesso</surname>
                  <given-names>Roberto</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Spessa</surname>
                  <given-names>Ezio</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Politecnico di Torino</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2010</year>
            <string-date>2010</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26275465</issue-id>
         <fpage>773</fpage>
         <lpage>787</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2010 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26275514"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In Diesel engines the optimization of engine-out emissions, combustion noise and fuel consumption requires the experimental investigation of the effects of different injection strategies as well as of a large number of engine operating variables, such as scheduling of pilot and after pulses, rail pressure, EGR rate and swirl level. Due to the high number of testing conditions involved full factorial approaches are not viable, whereas Design of Experiment techniques have demonstrated to be a valid methodology. However, the results obtained with such techniques require a subsequent critical analysis, so as to investigate the cause and effect relationships between the set of engine operating variables and the combustion process characteristics that affect pollutant formation, noise of combustion and engine efficiency.</p>
            <p>To this purpose, the zero-dimensional multizone diagnostic combustion model developed at ICEAL was applied for the combustion and emission formation analysis in two different diesel engines, for various sets of injection strategies and engine operating parameters. The experimental data were acquired at the highly dynamic test rig of ICEAL, both in a EURO V low compression ratio diesel engine with a twin-stage turbocharger, equipped with piezoelectric injectors, and in a PCCI low compression ratio diesel engine equipped with solenoid injectors. The model results were discussed and reported in the well known ϕ-T diagrams, which give a synthetic representation of the local thermodynamic charge conditions during the mixture formation and premixed-diffusion combustion processes. The rail pressure increase was found to be an effective means to improve fuel-charge premixing and to lower the average local equivalence ratio of the charge during premixed combustion, so leading to a decrease in soot formation. As regards the effects of cooled high-pressure EGR on combustion, it was shown that an increase of its rate does not significantly affect the average equivalence ratio during premixed combustion, which is associated to the soot formation rate. Finally, a proper calibration of the dwell-time between pilot and main injection, so as to have the main injection pulse center-of-gravity phased in correspondence to the start of pilot burning, resulted to produce a reduction of CO and soot emissions higher than 50% with respect to baseline case, without any deterioration of NOₓ emissions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E., d'Ambrosio, S., Ferrari, A., Finesso R. et al., “Experimental Analysis of Combustion Processes and Emissions in a 2.0L Multi-Cylinder Diesel Engine Featuring a New Generation Piezo-Driven Injector,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-24-0040, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Baratta, M., Catania, A.E., Ferrari, A., Finesso, R., and Spessa, E., 2008, “Innovative Multizone Premixed-Diffusion Combustion Model for Performance and Emission Analysis in Conventional and PCCI Diesel Engines,” presented at COMODIA 2008, July 28-31, Sapporo, Japan, Paper No. HC4-3, JSME No. 08-202: 351-362.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E., d'Ambrosio, S., Finesso, R., Spessa, E. et al., “Combustion System Optimization of a Low Compression-Ratio PCCI Diesel Engine for Light-Duty Application,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(1):1314-1326, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cipolla, G., Vassallo, A., Catania, A.E., Spessa, E. et al., “Combined Application of CFD Modeling and Pressurebased Combustion Diagnostics for the Development of a Low Compression Ratio High-Performance Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-24-0034. SAE Transactions, 2007 Journal of Engines: 1521-1539, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Catania, A.E., Ferrari A., Spessa E., “Numerical- Experimental Study and Solutions to Reduce the Dwell Time Threshold for Fusion-Free Consecutive Injections in a Multijet Solenoid-Type C.R. System”, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power 131(1): 022804-1-022804-14, 2009, doi:10.1115/1.2938394.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dec, J.E., “A Conceptual Model of Diesel Combustion Based on Laser-Sheet Imaging,” SAE Techical Paper 970873, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chmela, F.G. and Orthaber, G.C., “Rate of Heat Release Prediction for Direct Injection Diesel Engines Based on Purely Mixing Controlled Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-0186, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Egnell, R., “A Simple Approach to Studying the Relation between Fuel Rate, Heat Release Rate and NO Formation in Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3548, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ericson, C., Westerberg, B., Andersson, M., and Egnell, R., “Modelling Diesel Engine Combustion and NOx Formation for Model Based Control and Simulation of Engine and Exhaust Aftertreatment Systems,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0687, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., Higgins, B., and Pickett, L., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Fuel Jets: Oxygen Concentration Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0890, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Torregrosa A.J., Broatch A., Martín J., Monelletta L., “Combustion noise level assessment in direct injection Diesel engines by means of in-cylinder pressure components”, Meas. Sci. Technol. 18: 2131-2142, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Idicheria Cherian A., Pickett Lyle M., “Effect of EGR on diesel premixed-burn equivalence ratio”, Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 31: 2931-2938, 2007, doi:10.1016/j.proci.2006.08.022.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
