<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">natitaxjour</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50005631</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>National Tax Journal</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>National Tax Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00280283</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19447477</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26349717</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>MEANS TESTING SOCIAL SECURITY: INCOME VERSUS WEALTH</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Alan L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Gustman</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Thomas L.</given-names>
                  <surname>Steinmeier</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>Nahid</given-names>
                  <surname>Tabatabai</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2017</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">70</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i26349711</issue-id>
         <fpage>111</fpage>
         <lpage>131</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2017 National Tax Association-Tax Institute of America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26349717"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>A Social Security means test targeting benefit recipients in the top quarter of the income distribution will have substantially different distributional effects from a means test targeting the top quarter of wealth holders. Only 14.5 percent of individuals fall in the top quarters of both the income and wealth distributions. A means test based on income will reduce benefits for 10.5 percent of individuals who fall outside the top quarter of wealth holders, while a means test based on wealth will have similar consequences for those who fall outside the top quarter of the income distribution.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d957e195a1310">
            <label>1</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e202" publication-type="other">
For an introduction to means testing Social Security and some of its consequences, and a list of plans
that would base means tests on current income, see American Academy of Actuaries (2012). These plans
include proposals by the Concord Coalition, which would reduce benefits beginning with family income
of $40,000 up through an 85 percent reduction in benefits for a family income of $120,000, and by the
Heritage Foundation, which would begin reducing benefits at $55,000 of non-Social Security income for
single tax payers and $ 110,000 for tax payers who file jointly, eliminating benefits when income exceeds
these thresholds by $55,000 or more. Some of the presidential candidates in 2016 focused on means testing
benefits. Although these candidates were unsuccessful in 2016, their views on means testing are represen-
tative of an important class of policy prescriptions. For example, in April 2015, NJ Gov. Chris Christie
proposed an income cap on Social Security benefits that would begin to reduce benefits of individuals
with an income of $80,000 and phase benefits out entirely if income exceeded $200,000. Some plans for
means testing, like Gov. Christie's, are specific; others are more general. OH Gov. John Kasich also took
a position in favor of means testing as did FL Sen. Marco Rubio and FL Gov. Jeb Bush.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e247a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e254" publication-type="other">
Thus, a number of transfer programs include a means test based on wealth (Moffitt, 2016). Wealth data
are also collected for determining student loans. Defined contribution plan balances from work in jobs not
covered by Social Security are relevant for computing the Social Security benefits accrued by individuals
who held other jobs that were covered. Their Social Security benefits are adjusted under Social Security's
Windfall Elimination Provision (WEP) and Government Pension Offset (GPO) provisions. For further
discussion of the importance of including wealth when measuring poverty, see Wimer and Manfield (2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e277a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e286" publication-type="other">
Current earnings are a major part of the current incomes of those in the population in their early to late
sixties (Social Security Administration, 2014). Thus, if we apply a means test based on income to those
in their early to mid-sixties, one could expect a major labor supply response. The resulting disincentives
for work would be inconsistent with decades of policy initiatives designed to encourage older persons
to delay their age of retirement. Facing a wave of baby boomer retirements, Congress abolished the
Social Security earnings test for those between the full retirement age and age 70, raised the full retirement
ages from 65 to 67, and increased to 8 percent the delayed retirement credit, the actuarial adjustment for
delayed claiming of benefits. Other legislation and/or court decisions also encouraged delayed retirement
by abolishing various forms of age discrimination. Thus, together with the courts, Congress abolished
mandatory retirement, required defined benefit pensions to adopt actuarially fair adjustments in benefits
for those who delay retiring until after age 65, and similarly required employers to continue to contribute
to the defined contribution pension plans of those workers who are beyond the full retirement age speci-
fied by their plan.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e331a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e338" publication-type="other">
We realize that by focusing on the top quarter group we are introducing a notch. The adjustment we intro-
duce below, basing the means test on the amount of current income, reduces the size of the notch.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e349a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e356" publication-type="other">
One caveat should be mentioned. We do not consider the potential of modifying the income tax in order
to further means test Social Security benefits. Under current law, Social Security is subject to income tax
if AGI is over $25,000. For married couples filing jointly, the threshold is $44,000. Income taxes are paid
on up to 85 percent of Social Security benefits. More specifically, for couples filing jointly with incomes
exceeding $44,000, the amount of benefits counted in income is the lesser of 85 percent of Social Security
or the sum of $6,000 plus 85 percent of income over $44,000. For singles, the amount of benefits counted
in income is the lesser of 85 percent of Social Security or the sum of $4,500 plus 85 percent of income
over $34,000 (Social Security Administration, 2013). The vast majority of Social Security benefits of
high-income individuals are already subject to the income tax. This leaves very little room for using the
income tax per se as a basis for means testing Social Security benefits. For further analysis of the taxation
of Social Security benefits under the income tax, see Purcell (2015).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e394a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e401" publication-type="other">
"Rand HRS Data Files, Supported by NIAand SSA," RAND Labor and Population, http://www.rand.org/
labor/aging/dataprod/hrs-data.html.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e411a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e418" publication-type="other">
Note that when measuring the current income of retirees some income originating from defined contribution
(DC) pensions is attributed to other sources. For example, the HRS does not identify as pension income
some irregular withdrawals from DC accounts that continue to be held throughout retirement. However,
additional questions are included in the HRS pension and income sequences inquiring about other pen-
sion income and other income not reported. These questions are designed to capture income from live
DC accounts that is not directly reported. In addition, at the time of retirement, pensions are sometimes
transformed into other forms of assets. Income from these assets may not be attributed to pensions. Finally,
note that while the income sequence in the HRS is designed to report realized income, such as withdrawals
from IX accounts and regular payments from defined benefit (DB) plans, unrealized capital gains in IX
accounts are not included in reported income. For comparisons of pension values measured before and
after retirement and related discussions, see Gustman, Steinmeier, and Tabatabai (2014b).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e456a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e463" publication-type="other">
Total wealth includes the present value of Social Security benefits, the present value of DB pensions, current
assets in DC pension accounts, real estate, business, finance, vehicles, and IRA accounts. For respondents
who have not yet retired, we calculate future Social Security benefits from working on a covered job by
applying the Social Security Administration's ANYPIA software program to the covered earning records
for the respondent ("Social Security Benefit Calculator Download," https://www.ssa.gov/oact/anypia/
download.html). When earnings or benefit records are not available from the Social Security Administra-
tion, we impute them based on individual and job characteristics, including self-reported earnings.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e489a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e496" publication-type="other">
In discounting pension and Social Security flows, we use a real interest rate of 2 .8 percent and a nominal rate
of 5.8 percent. These correspond to the long run rates in the Report of the Board of Trustees (2015). We use
a life table from the Social Security Administration that is not adjusted for place in the income distribution.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e509a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e516" publication-type="other">
An alternative table that excludes individuals falling in the top and bottom 1 percent of the wealth distribu-
tion differs very slightly from Table 1.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e527a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e534" publication-type="other">
One might consider asking about the effects of a means test based on an average of income or wealth
calculated over a longer period. Averaging would reduce transitory fluctuations in these measures and
therefore increase the correlation between them. For example, a high-wealth individual is likely to have
lower income in years with few realized capital gains and higher income in years with large capital gains
realizations. Averaging over a few years would, however, complicate reporting, thereby increasing the
costs of a means test.
Ironically, a measure of average earnings is readily available over a very long period. Average Indexed
Monthly Earnings (AIME) measures covered earnings over the individual's working life. The Social
Security Administration already calculates this measure because it is the basis for calculating Social
Security benefits. Calculating AIME thus does not create an additional administrative burden. Because
Social Security benefits are already based on AIME and are redistributive, one must calculate the additional
redistribution fostered by an AIME based means test to understand the effects of a means test based on
AIME. We have made the required calculations and have compared the additional redistribution from an
AIME-based means test with the redistribution under a means test that uses wealth as a measure of means.
The means tests based on each criterion are then evaluated according to the relevant criterion. For further
details, see Gustman, Steinmeier, andTabatabai (2014c).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e588a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e595" publication-type="other">
Not all of the data required for means testing at the household level are readily available to the Social
Security Administration. Social Security does not aggregate individuals into households until after retire-
ment and, even then, does not do so for all households. For further discussion, see Compson (2011).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e608a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e615" publication-type="other">
See Samwick (2012) and Samwick and Zhou (2014) for related discussions in the context of means testing
health benefits and financial aid for college education.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d957e625a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d957e632" publication-type="other">
According to the SSI, "SSI does not treat assets in defined benefit and defined contribution retirement
plans in the same manner. Beneficiaries of a defined benefit plan must apply for pension benefits when
qualifications are met, and those benefits offset the SSI payment, but SSI applicants and recipients are
allowed to retain the asset until it can be annuitized. By contrast, holdings in a defined contribution plan
must be reduced or eliminated, depending on the amount of the holdings, for the SSI applicant or recipient
to be eligible for SSI" (Parent, 2006).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d957e664a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e668" publication-type="other">
American Academy of Actuaries, 2012. "Means Testing for Social Security." Issue Brief. American
Academy of Actuaries, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e678a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e682" publication-type="other">
Board of Trustees, Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance and Federal Disability Insurance
Trust Funds, 2015. "The 2015 Annual Report of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age
and Survivors Insurance and Federal Disability Insurance Trust Funds." OASI and DI Trust
Funds, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e698a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e702" publication-type="other">
Compson, Michael, 2011. "The 2006 Earnings Public-Use Microdata File: An Introduction."
Social Security Bulletin 71 (4), 33-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e712a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e716" publication-type="other">
Goss, Steven C., 2010. "The Future Financial Status of the Social Security Program." Social
Security Bulletin 70 (3), 111-125.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e727a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e731" publication-type="other">
Gustman, Alan L., and F. Thomas Juster, 1996. "Income and Wealth of Older American
Households: Modeling Issues for Public Policy Analysis." In Hanushek, Eric Α., and Nancy L.
Maritato (eds), Assessing Knowledge of Retirement Behavior, 11-60. National Academy Press,
Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e747a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e751" publication-type="other">
Gustman, Alan L., Thomas L. Steinmeier, and Nahid Tabatabai, 2014a. "The Social Security
Windfall Elimination and Government Pension Offset Provisions for Public Employees in the
Health and Retirement Study." Social Security Bulletin 74 (3), 55-69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e764a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e768" publication-type="other">
Gustman, Alan L., Thomas L. Steinmeier, and Nahid Tabatabai, 2014b. "Mismeasurement of Pen-
sions Before and After Retirement: The Mystery of the Disappearing Pensions with Implications
for the Importance of Social Security as a Source of Retirement Support." Journal of Pension
Economics and Finance 13 (1), 1-26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e784a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e788" publication-type="other">
Gustman, Alan L., Thomas L. Steinmeier, and Nahid Tabatabai, 2014c. "Distributional Effects
of Means Testing Social Security: An Exploratory Analysis." NBER Working Paper No. 20546,
National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e801a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e805" publication-type="other">
Moffitt, Robert A. (ed ), 2016. Means-Tested Transfer Programs in the United States. University
of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e815a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e819" publication-type="other">
Parent, Rene, 2006. "Defined Contribution Pension Plans and the Supplemental Social Security
Program." Policy Brief No. 2006-01. Social Security Administration, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e830a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e834" publication-type="other">
Purcell, Patrick J., 2015. "Income Taxes on Social Security Benefits." Issue Paper No. 2015-02.
Social Security Administration, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e844a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e848" publication-type="other">
Samwick, Andrew Α., 2012. "Means-Testing Federal Health Entitlement Benefits." Manuscript.
Department of Economics, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e858a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e862" publication-type="other">
Samwick, Andrew Α., and William L. Zhou, 2014. "The Insurance Value of Financial Aid."
Manuscript. Department of Economics, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e872a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e876" publication-type="other">
Social Security Administration, 2013. Annual Statistical Supplement to the Social Security Bul-
letin, 2012. SSA Publication No. 13-11700. Social Security Administration, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e886a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e890" publication-type="other">
Social Security Administration, 2014. Income of the Population 55 or Older, 2012. SSA Publica-
tion No. 13-11871. Social Security Administration, Washington, DC.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d957e900a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d957e904" publication-type="other">
Wimer, Christopher, and Lucas Manfield, 2015. "Elderly Poverty in the United States in the 21"
Century: Exploring the Role of Assets in the Supplemental Poverty Measure." CRR WP 2015-29.
Center for Retirement Research, Boston College, Boston, MA.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
