<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">reviespafinacont</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50009991</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Revista Española de Financiación y Contabilidad</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administarción de Empresas</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">02102412</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">38</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">141</issue>
         <issue-id>i24717601</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">24718073</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>La estructura financiera de la empresa familiar y el cambio generacional / The financial structure of the family firm: generation does matter</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Virginia Blanco</given-names>
                  <surname>Mazagatos</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Esther</given-names>
                  <surname>de Quevedo Puente</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Juan Bautista Delgado</given-names>
                  <surname>García</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>3</month>
            <year>2009</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>57</fpage>
         <lpage>73</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2001 Asociación Española de Contabilidad y Administración de Empresas</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24718073"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>Este trabajo analiza una muestra de 672 empresas no financieras pertenecientes a la Comunidad Autónoma de Castilla y León para evidenciar el efecto que ejerce el deseo de perpetuar el control familiar sobre la estructura financiera de las empresas familiares y realiza dos grandes contribuciones. En primer lugar, se comprueba que esta premisa de trascendencia genera en la empresa familiar un orden de preferencias de financiación acorde con la establecida por la Teoría del Pecking Order. En segundo lugar, aunque con los cambios generacionales se mantiene el deseo de control familiar, el debilitamiento de los lazos reduce la capacidad de sacrificio de los miembros familiares y, por tanto, varía la ponderación de las fuentes de financiación. This paper analyzes the effect of the desire to perpetuate family control on the financial structure of family firms across generations. We test this effect in a sample where both family and nonfamily firms have the same level of ownership concentration. We verify that the desire for family control gives rise to financing preferences in line with the pecking order theory. Since the desire for family control persists across generations, these financing preferences remain the same. However, we find that generational transitions weaken family bonds and thus reduce the family members' capacity for sacrifice, leading to variations in their weighting of the sources of financing.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>spa</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>BIBLIOGRAFÍA</title>
        <ref id="d1786e189a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e193" publication-type="other">
Anderson, R. C.; Mansi, S. A., y Reeb, D. M. 2003. Founding family ownership and the agency cost of
debt. Journal of Financial Economics 68 (2): 263-285.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e203a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e207" publication-type="other">
Anderson, R. C, y Reeb, D. M. 2003a. Founding-family ownership, corporate diversification, and firm
leverage. Journal of Law and Economics 46 (2): 653-680.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e217a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e221" publication-type="other">
Anderson, R. C., y Reeb, D. M. 2003b. Founding family ownership and firm performance: Evidence from
the S&amp;P 500. Journal of Finance 58 (3): 1301-1328.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e231a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e235" publication-type="other">
Acrawal, A., y Nagarajan, N. J. 1990. Corporate capital structure, agency costs, and ownership control:
The case of all-equity firms. Journal of Finance 45 (4): 1325-1331.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e246a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e250" publication-type="other">
Aronoff, C. E., y Ward, J. L. 1995. Family-owned businesses: A thing of the past or a model for the
future? Family Business Review 8 (2): 121-130.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e260a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e264" publication-type="other">
Barton, S. L., y Gordon, P. J. 1987. Corporate strategy: Useful perspective for the study of capital struc-
ture? Academy of Management Review 12 (1): 67-75.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e274a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e278" publication-type="other">
Barton, S. L„ y Matthews, C. H. 1989. Small firm financing: Implications from a strategic management
perspective. Journal of Small Business Management 27 (1): 1-7.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e288a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e292" publication-type="other">
Cabrera-SuArez, K., y Santana-Martín, D. J. 2004. Governance in Spanish family business. International
Journal of Entrepreneurial Behaviour &amp; Research 10 (2): 141-163.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e302a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e306" publication-type="other">
Carney, M. 2005. Corporate governance and competitive advantage in family-controlled firms. Entre-
preneurship Theory and Practice 29 (3): 249-265.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e316a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e320" publication-type="other">
Chaganti, R., y Damanpour, F. 1991. Institutional ownership, capital structure and firm performance.
Strategic Management Journal 12 (7): 479-491.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e331a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e335" publication-type="other">
Churchill, N., y Hatten, K. 1987. Non-market based transfers of wealth and power: A research fra-
mework for family business. American Journal of Small Business Management 11 (3): 51-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e345a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e349" publication-type="other">
Coleman, S., y Carsky, M. 1999. Sources of capital for small family-owned businesses: Evidence from the
national survey of small business finances. Family Business Review 12 (1): 73-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e359a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e363" publication-type="other">
Corbetta, G. 1995. Patterns of development of family businesses in Italy, Family Business Review, 8
(4), 255-265.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e373a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e377" publication-type="other">
Dalton, D. R., y Daily, C. M. 1992. Financial performance of founder-managed versus professionally
managed corporations. Journal of Small Business Economics 30 (2): 25-34.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e387a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e391" publication-type="other">
De Jong, A., y Veld, C. 2001. An empirical analysis of incremental capital structure decisions under
managerial entrenchment. Journal of Banking and Finance 25 (10): 1857-1895.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e401a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e405" publication-type="other">
Demaris, A. 1992. Logit modeling: Practical applications. Newbury Park, CA: Sage.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e413a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e417" publication-type="other">
Demsetz, H., y Lehn, K. 1985. The structure of corporate ownership: Causes and consequences. Journal
of Political Economy 93 (6): 1155-1177.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e427a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e431" publication-type="other">
Donaldson, G. 1961. Corporate debt capacity: A study of corporate debt policy and the determination of
corporate debt capacity. Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Division of Research.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e441a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e445" publication-type="other">
Fernández, Z., y Nieto, M. J. 2005. La estrategia de internacionalización de la pequeña empresa fami-
liar. Cuadernos de Economía y Direction de la Empresa 22 (1): 107-125.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e455a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e459" publication-type="other">
Galve, C., y Salas, V. 2003. La empresa familiar en España. Fundamentos Económicos y Resultados.
Bilbao: Fundación BBVA.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e469a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e473" publication-type="other">
— 2005. Family ownership and performance: The net effect of productive efficiency and growth cons-
traints. European Corporate Governance Institute-Finance Working Paper: 66.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e483a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e487" publication-type="other">
Gallo, M. A., y GarcIa Pont, C. 1989. La empresa familiar en la economía española. Papeles de Econo-
mía Española 39: 67-85.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e498a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e502" publication-type="other">
Gallo, M. A.; Tápies, J., y Cappuyns, K. 2004. Comparison of family and nonfamily business: Financial
logic and personal preferences. Family Business Review 17 (4): 303-318.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e512a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e516" publication-type="other">
Gkrsick, K. E.; Davis, J. A., McCollom, M., y Lansberg, 1.1997. Generation to generation: Life cycles of the
family business. Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e526a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e530" publication-type="other">
Grier, P., y Zychowicz, E. 1994. Institutional Investors, corporate discipline and the role of debt. Journal
of Economics and Business 46 (1): 1-11.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e540a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e544" publication-type="other">
Habbershon, T. G., y Williams, M. L. 1999. A resource-based framework for assessing the strategic ad-
vantages of family firms. Family Business Review 12 (1): 1-25.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e554a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e558" publication-type="other">
Hair, J. F.; Anderson, R. E.; Tatham, R. L., y Black, W. C. 1995. Multivariate data analysis: With readings.
Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e568a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e572" publication-type="other">
Hamilton, R. T., y Fox, M. A. 1998. The financing preferences of small firm owners, International Jour-
nal of Entrepreneurial Behaviour &amp; Research 4 (3): 239-248.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e583a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e587" publication-type="other">
Harris, M., y Raviv, A. 1990. Capital structure and the informational role of debt. Journal of Finance
45 (2): 321-349.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e597a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e601" publication-type="other">
Holtz-Eakin, D.; Joulfaian, D., y Rosen, H. S. 1993. The Carnegie conjecture: Some empirical evidence.
The Quarterly Journal of Economics 108 (2): 413-435.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e611a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e615" publication-type="other">
Hoskisson, R. E.; Hnr, M. A., y Ireland, R. D. 2004. Competing for advantage. Cincinnati, OH: South-
western College Publishing.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e625a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e629" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. C. 1986. Agency costs of free cash flow, corporate finance, and takeovers. American Econo-
mic Review 76 (2): 323-329.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e639a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e643" publication-type="other">
Jensen, M. C., y Meckung, W. 1976. Theory of the firm: Managerial behaviour, agency cost and owners-
hip structure. Journal of Financial Economics 3 (2): 4-19.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e653a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e657" publication-type="other">
Karra, N.; Tracey, P., y Phillips, N. 2006. Altruism and agency in the family firm: Exploring the role of
family, kinship and ethnicity. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice 30 (6): 861-877.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e668a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e672" publication-type="other">
Kleiman, R.; Lange, J.; Leleux, B.; Petty, W., y Shulman, J. 1996. An index of family controlled publicly
traded companies. Boston, MA: Frontiers of Entrepreneurial Research. Badson College.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e682a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e686" publication-type="other">
La Porta, R.; Lopez-de-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A., y Visiiny, R. W. 1998. Law and finance. Journal of Political
Economy 106 (6): 1113-1155.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e696a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e700" publication-type="other">
Litz, R. A. 1995. The family business: Toward definitional clarity. Family Business Review 8 (2):
71-82.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e710a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e714" publication-type="other">
López-Gracia, J., y Aybar-Arias, C. 2000. An empirical approach to the financial behaviour of small and
medium sized companies. Small Business Economics 14(1): 55-63.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e724a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e728" publication-type="other">
Lubatkin, M.; Schulze, W; Ling, Y., y Diño, R. 2005. The effects of parental altruism on the governance of
family-managed firms. Journal of Organizational Behavior 26 (3): 313-330.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e738a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e742" publication-type="other">
Lyagoubi, M. 2006. Family firms and financial behavior: How family shareholder preferences influence
firms" financing, en Poutziouris, P. Z.; Smyrnios, K. X., y Klein, S. B. (Eds.): Handbook of research on
family business: 537-551. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e756a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e760" publication-type="other">
Mahérault, L. 2000. The influence of going public an investment policy: An empirical study of French
family-owned businesses. Family Business Review 13 (1): 71-79.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e770a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e774" publication-type="other">
Matthews, C. H.; Vasudevan, D. P.; Barton, S. L., y Apaña, R. 1994. Capital structure decision making in
privately held firms: Beyond the finance paradigm. Family Business Review 7 (4): 349-367.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e784a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e788" publication-type="other">
McConaughy, D.; Matthews, C. H., y Fialko, A. 2001. Founding family controlled firms: Performance, risk
and value. Journal of Small Business Management 39 (1): 31-49.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e798a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e802" publication-type="other">
MgMahon, R. G. P., y Stanger, A. M. J. 1995. Understanding the small enterprise financial objective
function. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice 19 (4): 21-39.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e812a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e816" publication-type="other">
Miller, D., y Le Breton-Miller, I. 2005. Managing for the long run: Lessons in competitive advantage
from great family businesses. Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e826a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e830" publication-type="other">
Mishra, C. S., y McConaughy, D. L. 1999. Founding family control and capital structure: The risk of loss
of control and the aversion to debt. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice 23 (4): 53-64.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e841a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e845" publication-type="other">
Myers, S. C. 1984. The capital structure puzzle. Journal of Finance 39 (3): 575-592.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e852a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e856" publication-type="other">
Myers, S. C., y Majluf, N. S. 1984. Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have infor-
mation that investors do not have. Journal of Financial Economics 13 (2): 187-221.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e866a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e870" publication-type="other">
Neubauer, F., y Lank, A. G. 1998. The family business-Its governance for sustainability. Londres: Mac-
millan Press.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e880a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e884" publication-type="other">
Norton, E. 1991. Factors affecting capital structure decisions. The Financial Review 26 (3): 431-446.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e891a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e895" publication-type="other">
Pedersen, T., y Thomsen, S. 2003. Ownership structure and value of the largest European firms: The
importance of owner identity. Journal of Management and Governance 7 (1): 27-55.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e905a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e909" publication-type="other">
Pérez-González, F. 2006. Inherited control and firm performance. American Economic Review 96 (5):
1559-1588.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e920a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e924" publication-type="other">
Poutziouris, P. 2001. The views of family companies on venture capital: Empirical evidence from the UK
small to medium-size enterprising economy. Family Business Review 14 (3): 277-291.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e934a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e938" publication-type="other">
Romano, C. A.; Tanewski, G. A., y Smyrnios, K. X. 2000. Capital structure decision making: A model for
family business. Journal of Business Venturing 16 (3): 285-310.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e948a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e952" publication-type="other">
Schulze, W.; Lubatkin, M., y Diño, R. 2002. Altruism, agency, and the competitiveness of family firms.
Managerial and Decision Economics 23 (4/5): 247-259.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e962a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e966" publication-type="other">
Schulze, W; Lubatkin, M., y Diño, R. 2003. Exploring the agency consequences of ownership dispersion
among the directors of private family firms. Academy of Management Journal 46 (2): 179-195.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e976a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e980" publication-type="other">
Scott, W. R. 1981. Organizations: Rational, natural, and open systems. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice
Hall.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e990a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e994" publication-type="other">
Shleifer, A., y Visnhy, R. W. 1997. A survey of corporate governance. The Journal of Finance 52 (2):
737-783.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e1005a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e1009" publication-type="other">
Shyam-Sunder, L., y Myers, S. C. 1999. Testing static tradeoff against pecking order models of capital
structure. Journal of Financial Economics 51 (2): 219-244.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e1019a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e1023" publication-type="other">
Sirmon, D. G., y Hitt, M. A. 2003. Managing resources: Linking unique resources, management, and
wealth creation in family firms. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice 27 (4): 339-358.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e1033a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e1037" publication-type="other">
Smith, B. F., y Amoako-Adu, B. 1999. Management succession and financial performance of family con-
trolled firms. Journal of Corporate Finance 5: 341-368.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e1047a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e1051" publication-type="other">
Villalonga, B., y Amit, R. 2006. How do family ownership, control and management affect firm value?
Journal of Financial Economics 80 (2): 385-417.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e1061a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e1065" publication-type="other">
Ward, J. L. 1987. Keeping the family business healthy: How to plan for continuing growth, profitability,
and family leadership. San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d1786e1075a1310">
          
            <mixed-citation id="d1786e1079" publication-type="other">
Westhead, P., y Cowling, M. 1998. Family firm research: The need for a methodological rethink. Entre-
preneurship Theory and Practice 23 (1): 31-56.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


