<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">savideve</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50002264</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Savings and Development</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Finafrica</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">03934551</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">13</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">1</issue>
         <issue-id>i25830170</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">25830176</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>FEDERAL GOVERNMENT'S RECENT BUDGETARY ALLOCATIONS: IMPLICATIONS FOR AGRICULTURAL DEVELOPMENT IN NIGERIA / LES RÉCENTES ALLOCATIONS DU BUDGET DU GOUVERNEMENT FÉDÉRAL: LES CONSÉQUENCES POUR LE DÉVELOPPEMENT AGRICOLE AU NIGÉRIA</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Aja</given-names>
                  <surname>Okorie</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>1989</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>87</fpage>
         <lpage>100</lpage>
      
      
      
      
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/25830176"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The paper analyzes the Nigerian Federal Government's budgetary allocation to agriculture between 1981 and 1985. Allocations to agriculture were found to be grossly inadequate when compared with allocations to other sectors. Within the agricultural sector itself, lopsided allocations to irrigation development and crop subsector resulted in considerable and consistent neglect of livestock, fishery and forestry subsectors. This allocation pattern coupled with low level of actual expenditure was identified as a major contributory factor to the stagnation of agricultural development in Nigeria. Suggested measures that could ameliorate the situation include: higher budgetary allocation to agriculture; more equitable intra-sectoral allocation within the sector based on identified nation-felt needs; and a more effective supervision and monitoring of budget implementation. Cet article analyse les allocations du budget du gouvernement fédéral du Nigéria au secteur agricole entre 1981 et 1985. Le montant des ressources financières dédié à l'agriculture a été considéré par plusieurs auteurs remarquablement inadéquat par rapport aux autres secteurs. Même à l'intérieur du secteur agricole on a du remarquer que les sommes consacrées à l'irrigation et aux cultures ont été absolument insuffisantes: les sous-secteurs de l'élevage, des forêts et de la pêche ont été donc negligés d'une façon importante. La stagnation du développement agricole au Nigéria peut être attribuée en majeure partie à deux facteurs: la distribution inégale entre les différents secteurs des allocations et le faible montant des dépenses effectivement réalisées. On suggère des mesures qui peuvent améliorer la situation actuelle: par example des allocations budgétaires plus élevées pour le secteur agricole; une distribution des sommes plus équitables à l'intérieur du secteur agricole sur la base des priorités nationales et enfin des systèmes de supervision et de contrôle des mesures budgétaires plus efficaces.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        <title>[Footnotes]</title>
        <fn id="d36e153a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e160" publication-type="other">
J.C. Wells. Agricultural Policy and Economic Growth in Nigeria, 1962-68 (pp. 93-96)</mixed-citation>
            </p>
        </fn>
      </fn-group>
    
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>REFERENCES</title>
        <ref id="d36e176a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e183" publication-type="other">
Caiden, N. and Wildavsky A. Planning and Budgeting in Poor Countries, John Wiley and Sons, New York,
1974.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e193a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e200" publication-type="other">
Federal Republic of Nigeria Third National Development Plan 1975-80, Vol. II, The Central Planning Office.
Federal Ministry of Economic Development, 1975.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e210a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e217" publication-type="other">
Federal Republic of Nigeria Fourth National Development Plan 1981-85, Vol. I, The National Planning Of-
fice, Federal Ministry of National Planning, Lagos, January 1981.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e227a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e234" publication-type="other">
Ojukwu, C. «1984 Federal Budget: Implications for Agriculture and Rural Developments Memograph. Federal
Agricultural Coordinating Unit, Ibadan, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e245a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e252" publication-type="other">
Wells, J.C. Agricultural Policy and Economic Growth in Nigeria, 1962-1963. The Nigerian Institute of Social
and Research (NISER), Ibadan, 1974.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d36e262a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d36e269" publication-type="other">
Wildavsky A. The Politics of the Budgetary Process. Little Brown and Co. Boston, 1984.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


