<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">fiscalstudies</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50017170</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Fiscal Studies</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>Institute for Fiscal Studies</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">01435671</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">14755890</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">24437321</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Financial Constraints and Company Investment</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>STEPHEN</given-names>
                  <surname>BOND</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <given-names>COSTAS</given-names>
                  <surname>MEGHIR</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>1994</year>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">15</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">i24437318</issue-id>
         <fpage>1</fpage>
         <lpage>18</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© Institute for Fiscal Studies 1994</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/24437321"/>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <fn-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <title>[Footnotes]</title>
         <fn id="d36e147a1310">
            <label>2</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e154" publication-type="other">
In the UK these include the Macmillan Committee on Finance and Industry (1931), the Radcliffe Committee on
the Working of the Monetary System (1959) and the Wilson Committee to Review the Functioning of Financial
Institutions (1980).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e167a1310">
            <label>3</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e174" publication-type="other">
This concern was highlighted in the recent report. Saving for Sustained Economic Growth, produced by the CBI
(1993).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e184a1310">
            <label>4</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e191" publication-type="other">
Though as we discuss further below, the finding that financial constraints matter is not by itself a rationale for
intervention. First, these constraints may reflect unavoidable asymmetries in the information available to firms
and investors which the Government is in no position to reduce. Second, intervention in the allocation of investment
finance would bring with it the danger that government policy produces a worse allocation of resources than would
otherwise have occurred.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e210a1310">
            <label>5</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e217" publication-type="other">
Although it is worth noting that Coen (1971) allowed the speed with which investment responds to changes in
desired capital to depend on cash flow, and found a significantly faster response when cash flow was high.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e228a1310">
            <label>6</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e235" publication-type="other">
Note that investment spending may be constrained by cash flow even though the firm has access to finance from
debt or new share issues. All that is required is a significant cost differential between external and internal finance.
Thus evidence of financial constraints on investment spending does not necessarily indicate the presence of credit
rationing or of 'gaps' in the capital market.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e251a1310">
            <label>7</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e258" publication-type="other">
CBI (1993) reports that on average between April 1991 and January 1993 about 24 per cent of firms surveyed
reported that investment was limited by a shortage of internal finance. This fraction tends to rise in periods when
profits are low and fall in periods when profits are high. See Devereux and Schiantarelli ( 1990) for more discussion
of this survey evidence.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e274a1310">
            <label>8</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e281" publication-type="other">
Pension funds pay no income tax on dividend income, but can reclaim credits on company dividend payments
subject to advance corporation tax.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e291a1310">
            <label>9</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e298" publication-type="other">
See Mayer (1988), for example.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e305a1310">
            <label>10</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e312" publication-type="other">
See Myers and Majluf (1984) for a model where new equity is more expensive than retained profits as a result
of asymmetric information, and Stiglitz and Weiss (1981) for a model where credit rationing may occur.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e322a1310">
            <label>11</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e329" publication-type="other">
In only 7 per cent of the observations in our sample do we find companies paying zero dividends. See Edwards
(1984a) for a good discussion of company dividend policies.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e340a1310">
            <label>12</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e347" publication-type="other">
Clearly a similar result would hold if these firms had no access to external finance, and in this case there would
be no firms in Regime 3. In the context of Figure 1, this corresponds to the case where the cost of new equity
finance (rN) is infinitely high.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e360a1310">
            <label>13</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e367" publication-type="other">
Debt may of course be cheaper than finance from retained earnings at low levels of borrowing, as a result of the
tax advantage associated with interest deductibility against corporation tax. Firms in Regime 1 may use a
combination of retentions and debt, with the optimal borrowing policy reflecting a trade-off between the tax
advantage and the dead-weight costs of bankruptcy.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e383a1310">
            <label>14</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e390" publication-type="other">
The situation illustrated in Figure 2 assumes that these firms do not encounter credit rationing, although this is
not crucial.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e400a1310">
            <label>15</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e407" publication-type="other">
The concept of the user cost of capital was developed by Jorgenson (1963). This can be thought of as the minimum
rate of return an investment project must earn before the firm considers it to be attractive. This depends on rates
of interest, inflation and depreciation, as well as on taxes. See Bond, Denny and Devereux (1993) for a recent
non-technical discussion.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e423a1310">
            <label>16</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e430" publication-type="other">
See Jorgenson (1971) and Nickell (1978, Ch. 12) for surveys of this econometric literature.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e437a1310">
            <label>17</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e444" publication-type="other">
See Blundell, Bond and Meghir (1992) and Chirinko (1993) for surveys of this recent literature.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e452a1310">
            <label>18</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e459" publication-type="other">
These requirements include perfect competition, constant returns to scale and, crucially, that the stock-market
value correctly measures the 'fundamental' expected present value of the firm's future net cash flows. The formal
development of the model was due to Hayashi (1982).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e472a1310">
            <label>19</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e479" publication-type="other">
See Shiller (1981), for example.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e486a1310">
            <label>20</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e493" publication-type="other">
See Bond and Meghir(1994) for details. The restrictive assumptions of perfect competition and constant returns
to scale can be relaxed. This approach to modelling investment was developed by Abel ( 1980) and is closely related
to the 'random walk' consumption model developed by Hall (1978).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e506a1310">
            <label>21</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e513" publication-type="other">
The presence of the squared investment term reflects the assumed quadratic form of the adjustment cost function,
which is common to this and to the Q model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e523a1310">
            <label>22</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e530" publication-type="other">
In particular, this will result when there are important financial constraints on investment in period t+1, given
the high correlation between cash flow in period (+1 and cash flow in period t.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e540a1310">
            <label>23</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e547" publication-type="other">
This approach parallels that used in the microeconometric literature testing for liquidity constraints on
consumption, where samples are divided into high-wealth and low-wealth households. See Hayashi (1985b) and
Zeldes (1989). Fazzari et al. (1988) also estimate some traditional investment models on their sub-samples, with
similar findings to those from the Q model.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e564a1310">
            <label>24</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e571" publication-type="other">
More precisely, we consider current dividends to be low when the ratio of dividends to capital stock falls below
three-quarters of the mean value of this ratio for the firm over the whole period. Alternative criteria for 'low'
dividends gave similar results.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e584a1310">
            <label>25</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e591" publication-type="other">
i.e. the share of profits paid to the Government in the form of corporate taxes.</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
         <fn id="d36e598a1310">
            <label>26</label>
            <p>
               <mixed-citation id="d36e605" publication-type="other">
See Edwards (1984b) and Devereux (1987).</mixed-citation>
            </p>
         </fn>
      </fn-group>
      <ref-list>
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="d36e621a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e625" publication-type="other">
Abel, A. B. (1980), 'Empirical investment equations: an integrative framework', Carnegie-Rochester
Conference Series on Public Policy, vol. 12, pp. 39-91.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e635a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e639" publication-type="other">
Blundell, R. W., Bond, S. R., Devereux, M. R and Schiantarelli, F. (1992), 'Investment and Tobin's
Q: evidence from company panel data', Journal of Econometrics, vol. 51, pp. 233-57.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e649a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e653" publication-type="other">
—, — and Meghir, C. (1992), 'Econometric models of company investment', in L. Matyas and P.
Sevestre (eds), The Econometrics of Panel Data, Dordrecht: Kluwer Academic Publishers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e663a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e667" publication-type="other">
Bond, S. R., Denny, K. and Devereux, M. P. (1993), 'Capital allowances and the impact of corporation
tax on investment in the UK', Fiscal Studies, vol. 14, no. 2, pp. 1-15.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e678a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e682" publication-type="other">
— and Meghir, C. (1994), 'Dynamic investment models and the firm's financial policy', Review of
Economic Studies, vol. 61, pp. 197-222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e692a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e696" publication-type="other">
CBI (1993), Saving for Sustained Economic Growth, Report of the CBI's Economic Affairs
Committee Savings Group, December.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e706a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e710" publication-type="other">
Chirinko, R. S. (1993), 'Business fixed investment spending: modeling strategies, empirical results,
and policy implications', Journal of Economic Literature, vol. 31, pp. 1875-911.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e720a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e724" publication-type="other">
Coen, R. M. (1971), 'The effect of cash flow on the speed of adjustment', in G. Fromm (ed.), Tax
Incentives and Capital Spending, Washington DC: Brookings Institution.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e734a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e738" publication-type="other">
Devereux, M. P. (1987), 'On the growth of corporation tax revenues', Fiscal Studies, vol. 8, no. 2,
pp. 77-85.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e748a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e752" publication-type="other">
— and Schiantarelli, F. (1990), 'Investment, financial factors, and cash flow', in R. G. Hubbard (ed.),
Asymmetric Information, Corporate Finance and Investment, Chicago: University of Chicago
Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e766a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e770" publication-type="other">
Edwards, J. S. S. (1984a), 'Does dividend policy matter?', Fiscal Studies, vol. 5, no. 1, pp. 1-17.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e777a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e781" publication-type="other">
— (1984b), 'The 1984 corporation tax reform', Fiscal Studies, vol. 5, no. 2, pp. 30-40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e788a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e792" publication-type="other">
Fazzari, S. M., Hubbard, R. G. and Petersen, B. C. (1988), 'Financing constraints and corporate
investment', Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, no. 1988:1, pp. 141-95.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e802a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e806" publication-type="other">
Hall, R. E. (1978), 'Stochastic implications of the life cycle permanent income hypothesis: theory and
evidence', Journal of Political Economy, vol. 86, pp. 971-87.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e816a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e820" publication-type="other">
Hayashi, F. (1982), 'Tobin's marginal q and average q: a neoclassical interpretation', Econometrica,
vol. 50, pp. 213-24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e830a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e834" publication-type="other">
— (1985a), 'Corporate finance side of the Q theory of investment', Journal of Public Economics,
vol. 27, pp. 261-80.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e845a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e849" publication-type="other">
— (1985b), 'Tests of liquidity constraints: a critical survey', in T. Bewley (ed.), Advances in
Econometrics, vol. II, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e859a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e863" publication-type="other">
— and Inoue, T. ( 1991 ), 'The relation between firm growth and Q with multiple capital goods: theory
and evidence from panel data on Japanese firms', Econometrica, vol. 59, pp. 731-53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e873a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e877" publication-type="other">
Hoshi, T.. Kashyap, A. K. and Scharfstein, D. (1991), 'Corporate structure, liquidity and investment:
evidence from Japanese industrial groups', Quarterly Journal of Economics, vol. 106, pp. 33-60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e887a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e891" publication-type="other">
Jorgenson, D. W. (1963), 'Capital theory and investment behaviour', American Economic Review,
vol. 53, pp. 247-59.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e901a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e905" publication-type="other">
— (1971), 'Econometric studies of investment behaviour: a survey', Journal of Economic Literature,
vol. 9, pp. 1111-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e915a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e919" publication-type="other">
Macmillan Committee (1931), Committee on Finance and Industry, Report, Cmd 3897, London:
HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e930a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e934" publication-type="other">
Mayer, C. P. (1988), 'New issues in corporate finance', European Economic Review, vol. 32, pp.
1167-89.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e944a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e948" publication-type="other">
Modigliani, F. and Miller, M. H. (1958), 'The cost of capital, corporation finance and the theory of
investment', American Economic Review, vol. 48, pp. 261-97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e958a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e962" publication-type="other">
Myers, S. C. and Majluf, N. S. (1984), 'Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms
have information that investors do not have', Journal of Financial Economics, vol. 13, pp.
187-221.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e975a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e979" publication-type="other">
Nickell, S. J. (1978), The Investment Decisions of Firms, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e986a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e990" publication-type="other">
Radcliffe Committee (1959), Committee on the Working of the Monetary System, Report, Cmnd 827,
London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1000a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1004" publication-type="other">
Shiller, R. J. (1981), 'Do stock prices move too much to be justified by subsequent changes in
dividends?', American Economic Review, vol. 71, pp. 421-36.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1015a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1019" publication-type="other">
Stiglitz, J. E. and Weiss, A. ( 1981), 'Credit rationing in markets with imperfect information', American
Economic Review, vol. 71, pp. 393-410.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1029a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1033" publication-type="other">
Wilson Committee (1980), Committee to Review the Functioning of Financial Institutions, Report,
Cmnd 7937, London: HMSO.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="d36e1043a1310">
            <mixed-citation id="d36e1047" publication-type="other">
Zeldes, S. P. (1989), 'Consumption and liquidity constraints: an empirical investigation', Journal of
Political Economy, vol. 97, pp. 305^16.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
