<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277906</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Numerical Modelling and Experimental Characterization of a Pressure-Assisted Multi-Stream Injector for SCR Exhaust Gas After-Treatment</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Varna</surname>
                  <given-names>Achinta</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Swiss Federal Institute of Tech.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Boulouchos</surname>
                  <given-names>Konstantinos</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Swiss Federal Institute of Tech.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Spiteri</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>EMPA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Eggenschwiler</surname>
                  <given-names>Panayotis Dimopoulos</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>EMPA</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Wright</surname>
                  <given-names>Yuri M.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>ETH Zurich/Combustion+FlowSolutions GmbH</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2014</year>
            <string-date>October 2014</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">7</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277873</issue-id>
         <fpage>2012</fpage>
         <lpage>2021</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2014 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277906"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Simulations for a pressure-assisted multi-stream injector designed for urea-dosing in a selective catalytic reduction (SCR) exhaust gas system have been carried out and compared to measurements taken in an optically accessible high-fidelity flow test rig. The experimental data comprises four different combinations of mass flow rate and temperature for the gas stream with unchanged injection parameters for the spray. First, a parametric study is carried out to determine the importance of various spray sub-models, including atomization, spray-wall interaction, buoyancy as well as droplet coalescence. Optimal parameters are determined using experimental data for one reference operating condition. The model is subsequently applied to all operating conditions with unaltered parameters and validated by means of the measured droplet velocity fields, droplet diameter distributions and spray-tip propagations which have been characterized by means of Particle Image Velocimetry (PIV), Phase Doppler Anemometry (PDA) and shadow imaging. Finally, the model is used to investigate in detail phenomena characteristic of inclined sprays in cross-flows. Effects such as formation of vortices behind the spray core for low cross flow velocities, greater entrainment of droplets at high flow rates as well as wall film dynamics and the interaction of droplets also with the side walls are discussed in detail, highlighting the importance of the respective phenomena at the different operating conditions.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Birkhold, F., Meingast, U., Wassermann, P., and Deutschmann, O., “Analysis of the Injection of Urea-Water-Solution for Automotive SCR DeNOx-Systems: Modeling of Two-Phase Flow and Spray/Wall-Interaction,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-0643, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0643.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Birkhold, F., et al., Modeling and simulation of the injection of urea-water-solution for automotive SCR DeNOx-systems. Applied Catalysis B: Environmental 70, 2007: p. 119-127.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jeong, S.J., Lee S.-J., and Kim W.-S., Numerical Study on the Optimum Injection of Urea-Water Solution for SCR DeNOx System of a Heavy-Duty Diesel Engine to Improve DeNOx Performance and Reduce NH3 Slip. Environmental Engineering Science, 2008. 25(7): p. 1017-1035.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ström, H., Lundström A., and Andersson B., Choice of urea-spray models in CFD simulations of urea-SCR systems. Chemical Engineering Journal 150, 2009: p. 69-82.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">van Helden, R., Verbeek, R., Willems, F., and van der Welle, R., “Optimization of Urea SCR deNOx Systems for HD Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2004-01-0154, 2004, doi:10.4271/2004-01-0154.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Spiteri, A.C. and Eggenschwiler P. Dimopoulos, Experimental Fluid Dynamic Investigation of Urea-Water Sprays for Diesel SCR-DeNOx Applications. Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research, 2014. 53(8): p. 3047-3055.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Montenegro, G. and Onorati A., 1D thermo-fluid dynamic modelling of de-NOx SCR systems for diesel engine exhaust gas after-treatment. International Journal of Vehicle Design, 2006. 41: p. 285-306.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Costa, M., Melo M.J., and Sousa J.M.M., Spray Characteristics of Angled Liquid Injection into Subsonic Crossflows. AIAA, 2006. 44(3): p. 646-653.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, S.S., Kim W.H., and Yoon W.S., Spray formation by a swirl spray jet in low speed cross-flow. Journal of Mechanical Science and Technology, 2010. 24(2): p. 559-568.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Choi, S.M., et al., Spray in Crossflow of a Rotary Atomizer. Atomization and Sprays, 2012. 22(2): p. 143-161.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Panao, M.R. and Moreira A.L.N., Spray Impingement on a Flat Plate Under Cross Flow Conditions, in ILASS-Europe 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Panao, M.R. and Moreira A.L.N., Experimental Characterization of an Intermittent Gasoline Spray Impinging under Crossflow Conditions. Atomization and Sprays, 2005. 15: p. 201-222.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Panao, M.R., Moreira A.L.N., and Durao D.F.G., Effect of a crossflow on spray impingement with port fuel injection systems for HCCI engines. Fuel 106, 2013: p. 249-257.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ghosh, S. and Hunt J.C.R., Spray jets in a cross-flow. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 1998. 365: p. 109-136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dekeyser, D., et al., Assessment of orchard sprayers using laboratory experiments and computational fluid dynamics modelling. Biosystems Engineering 114, 2013: p. 157-169.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Endalew, A.M., et al., A new integrated CFD modelling approach towards air-assisted orchard spraying. Part I. Model development and effect of wind speed and direction on sprayer airflow. Computers and Electronics in Agriculture 71, 2010: p. 128-136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Endalew, A.M., et al., A new integrated CFD modelling approach towards air-assisted orchard spraying-Part II: Validation for different sprayer types. Computers and Electronics in Agriculture 71, 2010: p. 137-147.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bade, K.M., Kalata W., and Schick R.J., Experimental and Computational Study of a Spray at Multiple Injection Angles, in ILASS Americas 2010: Cincinnati, Ohio.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arcoumanis, C. and Cutter, P., “Flow and Heat Transfer Characteristics of Impinging Diesel Sprays Under Cross- Flow Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 950448, 1995, doi:10.4271/950448.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kihm, K.D., Lyn G.M., and Son S.Y., Atomization of Cross- Injecting Sprays into Convective Airstream Atomization and Sprays, 1995. 5: p. 417-433.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arienti, M., et al., Modeling Wall Film Formation and Breakup Using an Integrated Interface-Tracking/Discrete-Phase Approach. Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 031501, 2011. 133(3).</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Özdemir, I.B. and Whitelaw J.H., Impingement of an unsteady two-phase jet on unheated and heated flat plates. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 1993. 252: p. 499-523.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CD-adapco, Methodology Star-CD Version 4.16. 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pizza, G., et al., Evaporating and non-evaporating diesel spray simulation: comparison between the ETAB and wave breakup model. Int. J. Vehicle Design, 2007. 45: p. 80-99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. and Diwakar, R., “Effect of Drop Breakup on Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 860469, 1986, doi:10.4271/860469.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reitz, R. and Diwakar, R., “Structure of High-Pressure Fuel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 870598, 1987, doi:10.4271/870598.p</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reynolds, W.C., et al., Bifurcating and blooming jets. Annual Review of Fluid Mechanics, 2003. 35: p. 295-315.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fric, T.F. and Roshko A., Vortical structure in the wake of a transverse jet. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 1994. 279: p. 1-47.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kelso, R.M., Lim T.T., and Perry A.E., An experimental study of round jets in cross-flow. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 1996. 306: p. 111-144.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
