<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308284</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis of Different Gasoline Combustion Concepts with Focus on Gas Exchange</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Sauer</surname>
                  <given-names>Christina</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Kulzer</surname>
                  <given-names>André</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Rauscher</surname>
                  <given-names>Martin</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hettinger</surname>
                  <given-names>Alexander</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Robert Bosch GmbH, Stuttgart</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>336</fpage>
         <lpage>345</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308284"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Novel combustion technologies, which de-throttle the gasoline spark ignition (SI) engine, show high potential in reducing the fuel consumption. Technologies like variable valve actuation and/or gasoline direct injection, allow new strategies to run the SI engine unthrottled with early inlet valve closing (SI-VVA), charge stratification (SI-STRAT) and controlled auto ignition (CAI), also known as gasoline homogeneous charge compression ignition (HCCI). These diverse combustion concepts show thermodynamic gains that stem from several, often different, sources.</p>
            <p>A multitude of definitions of thermodynamic gas exchange potentials arise when looking at the various publications concerning de-throttled combustion concepts. This paper shows a summary and comparison of these definitions and points out which one can be applied in general to evaluate various combustion concepts under the same basis of evaluation.</p>
            <p>Additionally, a comparison between de-throttled gasoline combustion concepts at two representative engine operating points and a load sweep for the SI-VVA combustion concept is shown to illustrate the different interpretations of thermodynamic analysis of the gas exchange process. Advantages of the different combustion concepts are analyzed using thermodynamic split of losses method, which starts its potential analysis with the ideal constant volume cycle. A combustion concept comparison regarding these thermodynamic potentials, especially concerning gas exchange losses, is also performed.</p>
            <p>The purpose of this paper is to propose a clear definition of thermodynamic benefits of de-throttled gasoline combustion concepts.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kulzer, A.; Christ, A.; Rauscher, M.; Sauer, C.; ürfel, G., Blank, T.: "Thermodynamic Analyses and enchmark of Various Gasoline Combustion oncepts“, SAE Paper 2006-01-0231</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ortmann, R.; Arndt, S.; Raimann, J.; Würfel, G., rzeszik, R.: "Methods and Analysis of Fuel njection, Mixture Preparation and Charge tratification in Different Direct-Injected SI Engines“, AE Paper 2001-01-0970</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mischker, K.; Denger, D.: "Anforderungen an einem ollvariablen Ventiltrieb und Realisierung durch die lektrohydraulische Ventilsteuerung EHVS“ 24. International Viena Engine Symposium 2003</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Weberbauer, F.; Rauscher, M.; Kulzer, A.; Knopf, .; Bargende, M.: "Generally applicable split of osses for new combustion concepts“, otortechnische Zeitschrift MTZ 2/2005, Jahrgang 66</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pierik, R. J.; Burkhard, J. F.; “Design and evelopment of a Mechanical Variable Valve ctuation System“, SAE Paper 2000-01-1221</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Shelby, M. H.; Stein, R. A.; Warren, C. C.; “A New nalysis Method for Accurate Accounting of IC ngine Pumping Work and Indicated Work“, SAE aper 2004-01-1262</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wurms, R.; Löbbert, P.; Dengler, S.; Budack, R.; iser, A.; “How Much Valve Train Variability Really akes Sense?“, Haus der Technik, Variable entilsteuerung, 13.-14. Februar 2007, Essen</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Löbbert, P.; “Möglichkeiten und Grenzen der eillaststeuerung von Ottomotoren mit vollvariablem entilhub“, Ph.D, TU Dresden, 2006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Witt, A.; “Analyse der thermodynamischen Verluste ines Ottomotors unter den Randbedingungen ariabler Steuerzeiten “, Ph.D, TU Graz, 1999</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heil B.; Weining H.K.; Karl G.; Panten D.; underlich K.: “Verbrauch und Emissionen – eduzierungskonzepte beim Ottomotor (Teil 2)“, TZ (12/2001)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
