<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308304</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Analysis of Premix Flame and Lift-Off in Diesel Spray Combustion using Multi-Dimensional CFD</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Campbell</surname>
                  <given-names>J. W.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Imperial College, London, UK</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Gosman</surname>
                  <given-names>A. D.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Imperial College, London, UK</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hardy</surname>
                  <given-names>G.</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Iveco Motorenforschung AG, Switzerland</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>571</fpage>
         <lpage>590</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2008 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308304"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A detailed analysis is performed upon the results of CFD combustion simulations of several diesel fuel spray flame experiments. Simulations are validated against measurements from a constant volume combustion chamber testcase [9]. Particular emphasis is made in the analyses to identify mechanisms associated with the ’lift-off’ phenomena characteristic of contemporary high injection pressure diesel engine combustion. A recently developed industry state of the art RANS hybrid combustion model (Extended Coherent Flame Model - 3 Zones) [41] is used which takes account of both a propagating (premixed) flame combustion mode as well as the conventionally assumed diffusion flame mode used in most diesel combustion models. The location of and development of a propagating reaction front, obtained from analysis of the progress variable within the model, is studied in relation to the lift-off behaviour. The entrainment of air upstream of the lift-off is quantified from the CFD simulated field results and compared with values estimated from an empirical model [38] considered in recent experimental studies [34]. The fuel vapour field is also examined and compared with recent field data experiments of fuel concentration [22].</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>[1]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">STAR-CD v3.2 Methodology. CD-Adapco, London, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>[2]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">STAR-CD v3.26 Supplementary notes. CDAdapco, ondon, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>[3]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Barths. Three-dimensional simulation of pollutant ormation in a di diesel engine using multi- le interactive flamelets. SAE Technical paper, (982459), 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>[4]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Chomiak and A. Karlsson. Flame lift-off in iesel sprays. Proc. Combust. Inst., 26:2557-2504, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>[5]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. J. Curran, P. Gaffuri, W. J. Pitz, and C. K. estbrook. A comprehensive modeling study f n-heptane oxidation. Combustion and Flame, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>[6]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D.C.Wilcox. Turbulence Modeling for CFD. DCW ndustries, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>[7]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Diwaker. Assessment of the ability of a multidimensional omputer code to model combustion n a homogenous charge engine. SAE technical aper, (840230), 1984.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>[8]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">K. M. Lyons; K. A. Watson; C. D. Carter; J. M. onbar. Upstream islands of flame in lifted-jet artially premixed combustion. Combustion Science nd Technology, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>[9]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D.Siebers and B.Higgins. Flame lift-off on directinjection iesel sprays under quiescent condition. AE Technical Paper, (2001-01-0530), 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>[10]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">D.Siebers and B.Higgins. Measurements of the lame lift-off location on di diesel sprays using h chemiluminescence. SAE Technical Paper, (2001-01-0918), 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>[11]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.K. Dukowicz. A particle-fluid numerical model or liquid sprays. Journal of Computational hysics, 1980.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>[12]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christoph Espey and John E. Dec. Planar laser ayleigh scattering for quantitative vapour-fuel magiing in a diesel jet. Combustion and Flame, 109:65–86, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>[13]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">F.A.Tap and D.Veynante. Simulation of flame liftoff n a diesel jet using a generalized flame surface ensity modeling approach. Proceedings of he Combustion Institute, 30:912–926, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>[14]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Demoulin F.X. and Borghi R. Modeling of turbulent pray combustion with application to diesel ike experiment. Combustion and Flame, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>[15]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">A.D. Gosman and D.Clerides. Diesel spray modelling: review. In ILASS Europe Annual Meeting, 1997.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>[16]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G.Subramanian, A.Pires da Crus, O. Colin, and . Vervisch. Modeling engine turbulent autoignition sing tabulated detailed chamistry. SAE echnical paper, (2007-01-0150), 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>[17]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C. Hasse, G. Bikas, and N. Peters. Modeling i diesel combustion using the eulerian particle lamelet model. SAE Technical paper, (2000-01- 2934), 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>[18]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H.Hiroyasu, T.Kadota, and M.Arai. Bull JSME, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>[19]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B.S. Higgins, D.L. Siebers, and A. Aradi. Diesel pray ignition and premixed burn behaviour. SAE echnical paper, (2000-01-0940), 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>[20]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Hiroyasu and K. Nishida. Simplified threedimensional odeling of mixture formation and ombustion in a d.i. diesel engine. SAE Technical aper, 1989.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>[21]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cherian A. Idicheria and Lyle Pickett. Quantitative ixing measurements in a vaporizing diesel pray by rayleigh imaging. SAE Technical paper, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>[22]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cherian A. Idicheria and Lyle M. Pickett. Effect f egr on diesel premixed-burn equivalence ratio. roc. Combust. Inst., 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>[23]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">IMAGINE/AMESim. ttp://www.amesim.com/software/tools/ifpc3d. spx.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>[24]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">I.Magnussen, M.Balthasar, and T. Hellstroem. imulation of soot formation for diesel engine like onditions and comparison with experimental ata. In THIESEL 2006 Conference on Thermoand luid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>[25]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Venkatraman Iyer and John Abraham. An evaluation f a two-fluid eulerian-liquid eulerian-gas odel for diesel sprays. Journal of Fluids Engineering, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>[26]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.E.Dec. A conceptual model of di diesel combustion ased on laser-sheet imaging. SAE echnical Paper Series, (970873), 1997. Society f Automobile Engineers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>[27]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">W.P. Jones and J.H. Whitelaw. Calculation methods or reacting turbulent flows: A review. Combustion nd Flame, 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>[28]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">C Krueger. Validierung eines 1D-Spraymodells ur Simulation der Gemischebildung in direkteinspritzenden ieselmotoren. PhD thesis, RWTH achen, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>[29]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Vanquickenborne L. and A. Van Tiggelen. The tabilization mechanism of lifted diffusion flames. ombustion and Flame, 10:59–69, 1966.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref30">
            <label>[30]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sandia National Laboratories. ttp://public.ca.sandia.gov/ecn/cvdata/ignitiondelay.php. ssociated with the TNF site.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref31">
            <label>[31]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sandia National Laboratories. ttp://public.ca.sandia.gov/ecn/cvdata/liftoff.php. ssociated with the TNF site.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref32">
            <label>[32]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harry Lehtiniemi, Fabian Mauss, Michael althasar, and Ingemar Magnusson. Modeling iesel engine combustion with detailed chemistry sing a progress variable approach. SAE echnical paper, (2005-01-3855), 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref33">
            <label>[33]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Harry Lehtiniemi, Fabian Mauss, Michael althasar, and Ingemar Magnusson. Modeling iesel spray ignition using detailed chemistry ith a progress variable approach. Combustion cience and Technology, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref34">
            <label>[34]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L.Pickett and D. Siebers. Soot in diesel fuel jets: ffects of ambinet temperature, ambient density, nd injection pressure. Combustion and Flame, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref35">
            <label>[35]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zolver M., Klahr D., Bohbot J., Laget O., and Torres . Reactive cfd in engines woith a new unstructured arallel solver. Oil Gas and Science eview, 58:33–46, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref36">
            <label>[36]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jean-Marc Duclos Marc Zellat, Stefano Duranti. owards a universal combustion model in starcd or ic engines: from gdi to hcci and application o di diesel combustion optimization. ulti-dimensional Engine Modelling Users conference, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref37">
            <label>[37]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M. Metghalchi and J.C Keck. Burning velocities f mixtures of air with methanol, iso-octane nd indolene at high pressure and temperature. ombust. Flame., (48, 191-210), 1982.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref38">
            <label>[38]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J.D. Naber and D.L. Siebers. Effects of gas ensity and vaporization on penetration and dispersion f diesel sprays. SAE Technical paper, (960034), 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref39">
            <label>[39]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">J. Nagle and R..F. Strickland-Constable. Oxidation f carbon between 1000-2000 c. In Proc. of he Fifth Carbon Conference, page 154. Pegamamon ress, 1962.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref40">
            <label>[40]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Colin. O., Pires da Cruz A., and Jay S. Detailed hemistry based auto-ignition model including ow temperature phenomena applied to 3d engine calculations. In Proceedings of the ombustion Institute, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref41">
            <label>[41]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">O.Colin and A.Benkenida. The 3-zones extended oherent flame model (ECFM3Z) for omputing premixed/diffusion combustion. Oil nd Gas Science and Technology - Review IFP, 59(6):593–609, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref42">
            <label>[42]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">M.A. Patterson, S.G. Kong, G.J. Hampson, and .D Reitz. Modeling the effects of fuel injection haracteristics on diesel engine soot and ox emissions. SAE Technical Paper Series, (940523), 1994. Society of Automobile Engineers.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref43">
            <label>[43]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Christoph Pauls, Stefan Vogel, Gerd Gruenefeld, nd Norbert Peters. Combined simulations nd oh-chemiluminescence measurements f the combustion process using different fuels nder diesel-engine like conditions. SAE Technical aper, (2007-01-0020), 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref44">
            <label>[44]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N Peters. The effects of spray formation on mixing, uto-ignition and combustion in diesel engines. n THIESEL 2006 Conference on Thermoand luid Dynamic Processes in Diesel Engines, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref45">
            <label>[45]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">N Peters and F.A. Williams. Liftoff characteristics f turbulent jet diffusion flames. AIAA Journal, 21, 1983.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref46">
            <label>[46]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Norbert Peters. Turbulent Combustion. Cambridge niversity Press, 2000. Chap.4.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref47">
            <label>[47]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">L.M. Pickett and C.A. Idicheria. Effects of ambient emeprature and density on soot formation nder high egr conditions. In Thiesel Conference roceedings 2006, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref48">
            <label>[48]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">H. Pitsch, Y.P. Wan, and N. Peters. Numerical nvestigation of soot formation and oxidation under iesel engine condition. SAE technical paper, (952357), 1995.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref49">
            <label>[49]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">S.B. Pope. A explanation of the turbulent roundjet/ lane-jet anomaly. AIAA, 16, 1978.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref50">
            <label>[50]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">B. Reveille, A.Kleeman, and S.Jay. Towards ven cleaner diesel engines: Contribution of 3d fd tools. Oil &amp; Gas Scienec and Technology - ev.IFP, 61(1), 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref51">
            <label>[51]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R.Steiner, C.Bauer, C.Krueger, F.Otto, and .Maas. 3d-simulation of a di-diesel combustion pplying a progress variable approach accounting or complex chemistry. SAE, (2004-01-0106), 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref52">
            <label>[52]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R.Tatschl, P.Preisching, and J.Ruetz. Recent advances n di-diesel combustion modeling in avl ire - a validation study. International Multidiemnsional ngine Modeling User’s Group Meeting, pril 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref53">
            <label>[53]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R.Venugopal and J.Abraham. A numerical investigation f flame lift-off in diesel jets. Combustion cience and Technology, 179:2599–2618, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref54">
            <label>[54]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">P.K. Senecal, E.Pomraning, K.J. Richards, T.E riggs, C.Y. Choi, R.M. McDavid, and M.A. Patterson. ulti-dimensional modeling of directinjection iesel sp[ray liquid length and flame liftoff ength using cfd and parallel detailed chemistry. AE technical series, (2003-01-1043), 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref55">
            <label>[55]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dennis L. Siebers. Liquid-phase fuel penetration n diesel sprays. SAE technical paper, (980809), 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref56">
            <label>[56]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Subramanian, O. Colin, A. Pires da cruz, . Vervisch, and G. Bruneaux. Modeling turbulent ixing of an evaporating spray. In 20th International olloquium on the Dynamics of Explosions nd Reactive Systems - ICDERS, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref57">
            <label>[57]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">G. Subramanian, L. Vervisch, and F. Ravet. New evelopments in turbulent combustion modeling or engine design: The ecfm-cleh combustion ubmodel. SAE Technical paper, (2007-01- 0154), 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref58">
            <label>[58]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">R. Venugopal and J. Abraham. A review of undamental studies relevant to flame lift-off in iesel jets. SAE Technical paper, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref59">
            <label>[59]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">V.Magi, V.Iyer, and J.Abraham. The k-epsilon odel and computed spreading rates in round nd plane jets. Numerical Heat Transfer,Part A, (40):317–334, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref60">
            <label>[60]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">E. von Berg, A. Alajbegovic, R. Tatschl, . Krueger, and U. Michels. Multiphase modeling f diesel sprays with the eulerian/eulerian pproach. ILASS, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref61">
            <label>[61]</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Engine Combustion Network Website. ttp://public.ca.sandia.gov/ecn/cvdata/dsearch.php. andia National Laboratories,.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
