<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26278243</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Comparison of Experimental PIV Data and CFD Simulations for Flow in a Diesel Particulate Filter Inlet Diffuser</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Turner</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Queen’s Univ., Belfast</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Thornhill</surname>
                  <given-names>David</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Queen’s Univ., Belfast</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>McCullough</surname>
                  <given-names>Geoffrey</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Queen’s Univ., Belfast</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Patel</surname>
                  <given-names>Samir</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Ansys Europe</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2011</year>
            <string-date>2011</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26278130</issue-id>
         <fpage>1556</fpage>
         <lpage>1570</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2011 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26278243"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>Flow maldistribution of the exhaust gas entering a Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) can cause uneven soot distribution during loading and excessive temperature gradients during the regeneration phase. Minimising the magnitude of this maldistribution is therefore an important consideration in the design of the inlet pipe and diffuser, particularly in situations where packaging constraints dictate bends in the inlet pipe close to the filter, or a sharp diffuser angle. This paper describes the use of Particle Image Velocimetry (PIV) to validate a Computational Fluid Dynamic (CFD) model of the flow within the inlet diffuser of a DPF so that CFD can be used with confidence as a tool to minimise this flow maldistribution.</p>
            <p>PIV is used to study the flow of gas into a DPF over a range of steady state flow conditions. The distribution of flow approaching the front face of the substrate was of particular interest to this study. Optically clear diffusing cones were designed and placed between pipe and substrate to allow PIV analysis to take place. Stereoscopic PIV was used to eliminate any error produced by the optical aberrations caused by looking through the curved wall of the inlet cone.</p>
            <p>In parallel to the experiments, numerical analysis was carried out using a CFD program with an incorporated DPF model. Boundary conditions for the CFD simulations were taken from the experimental data, allowing an experimental validation of the numerical results. The CFD model incorporated a DPF model, the cement layers seen in segmented filters and the intumescent matting that is commonly used to pack the filter into a metal casing. The mesh contained approximately 580,000 cells and used the realizable κ-ε turbulence model. The CFD simulation predicted both pressure drop across the DPF and the velocity field within the cone and at the DPF face with reasonable accuracy, providing confidence in the use the CFD in future work to design new, more efficient cones.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zhang, X., Romzek, M., Keck, M., and Kurz, F., “Numerical Optimization of Flow Uniformity inside Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3702, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3702.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Konstandopoulos, A.G. and Johnson, J.H., “Wall-Flow Diesel Particulate Filters - Their Pressure Drop and Collection Efficiency,” SAE Technical Paper 890405, 1989, doi:10.4271/890405.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Masoudi, M., Konstandopoulos, A., Nikitidis, M.S., Skaperdas, E. et al., “Validation of a Model and Development of a Simulator for Predicting the Pressure Drop of Diesel Particulate Filters,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0911, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0911.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Koltsakis, G.C., Samaras, Z.C., Echtle, H., Chatterjee, D. et al., “Flow Maldistribution Effects on DPF Performance,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1280, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1280.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bensaid, S.; Marchisio, D.L.; Fino, D.; Saracco, G.; Specchia, V., “Modelling of diesel particulate in wall-flow traps” Chem. Eng. J. (2009) DOI 10.1016/j.cej.2009.03.043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Charbonnel, S. and Opris, C.N., “Fundamental Diesel Particulate Filter (DPF) Pressure Drop Model,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1271, 2009, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-1271.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opris, C.N. and Johnson, J.H., “A 2-D Computational Model Describing the Flow and Filtration Characteristics of a Ceramic Diesel Particulate Trap,” SAE Technical Paper 980545, 1998, doi:10.4271/980545.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Stratakis, G. A. and Stamatelos, A. M., “Flow maldistribution measurements in wall-flow diesel filters” Proc. Instn Mech Engrs 218 Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering, 995-1009, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hwang, K., Lee, K., Mueller, J., Stuecken, T. et al., “Dynamic Flow Study in a Catalytic Converter Using Laser Doppler Velocimetry and High Speed Flow Visualization,” SAE Technical Paper 950786, 1995, doi:10.4271/950786.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Benjamin, S. F.; Roberts, C. A.; Wollin, J., “A study of Pulsating Flow in Automotive Catalyst Systems” Experiments in Fluids 33: 629-639, 2002, DOI 10.1007/s00348-002-0481-0.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Raffell, M.; Willert, C.; Kompenhans, J., “Particle Image Velocimetry-A Practical Guide”, Springer, ISBN 3-540-63683-8:1-59, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Breuer, M., Schernus, C., Böwing, R., Kuphal, A. et al., “Experimental Approach to Optimize Catalyst Flow Uniformity,” SAE Technical Paper 2000-01-0865, 2000, doi: 10.4271/2000-01-0865.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Persoons, T.; Vanierschot, M.; Van den Buck, E., “Stereoscopic PIV Measurements of Swirling Flow Entering a Catalyst Substrate” Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 32:1590-1596, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thornhill, D.; Currie, T.; Fleck, r.; Chatfield, G., “Particle Image Velocimetry Investigation of a Finite Amplitude Pressure Wave,” Experiments in Fluids 40:400-404, 2006, DOI 10.1007/s00348-005-0077-6.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bissett, E.J., Mathematical Model of the Thermal Regeneration of a Wall-Flow Monolith Diesel Particulate Filter, Chemical Engineering Science, Vol. 39, Nos. 7/8, pp. 1233-1244, 1984</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Hinti, I., “Investigation and Modelling of Diesel Particulate Filters”, Doctoral Thesis, Queen's University Belfast, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Al-Hinti, I., McCullough, G., Douglas, R. “Current Considerations for the Application of Diesel Particulate Filters”. The 4th Jordanian International Mechanical Engineering Conference, JIMEC 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
