<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26308346</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Mobile Source Air Toxics (MSATs) from High Efficiency Clean Combustion</article-title>
            <subtitle>Catalytic Exhaust Treatment Effects</subtitle>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Storey</surname>
                  <given-names>John M. E.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lewis</surname>
                  <given-names>Samuel A.</given-names>
                  <suffix>Sr.</suffix>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Parks</surname>
                  <given-names>James E.</given-names>
                  <suffix>II</suffix>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Szybist</surname>
                  <given-names>James P.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Barone</surname>
                  <given-names>Teresa L.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Prikhodko</surname>
                  <given-names>Vitaly Y.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>1</month>
            <year>2009</year>
            <string-date>2009</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26308254</issue-id>
         <fpage>1157</fpage>
         <lpage>1166</lpage>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26308346"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>High Efficiency Clean Combustion (HECC) strategies such as homogenous charge compression ignition (HCCI) and pre-mixed charge compression ignition (PCCI) offer much promise for the reduction of NOx and PM from diesel engines. While delivering low PM and low NOx, these combustion modes often produce much higher levels of CO and HC than conventional diesel combustion modes. In addition, partially oxygenated species such as formaldehyde (an MSAT) and other aldehydes increase with HECC modes. The higher levels of CO and HCs have the potential to compromise the performance of the catalytic aftertreatment, specifically at low load operating points. As HECC strategies become incorporated into vehicle calibrations, manufacturers need to avoid producing MSATs in higher quantities than found in conventional combustion modes. This paper describes research on two different HECC strategies, HCCI and PCCI. Engine-out data for several MSAT species (formaldehyde, acetaldehyde, benzene, toluene, ethylbenzene, xylenes, naphthalene, PAHs, diesel PM) as well as other HC species are presented and compared when possible with conventional operation. In addition, catalyst-out values were measured to assess the destruction of individual MSATs over the catalyst. At low engine loads, MSATs were higher and catalyst performance was poorer. Particle sizing results identify large differences between PM from conventional and HECC operation.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S., nd Dean, A., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich iesel Combustion By Reducing Temperature,” AE Paper Number 2001-01-0655. Society of utomotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hasegawa, R., Yanagiahara, H., “HCCI Combustion n DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Paper Number 2003-01- 0745. Society of Automotive Engineers, arrendale, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walter, B., Gatellier, B., “Near Zero NOX Emissions nd High Fuel Efficiency Diesel Engine: The ADI™ Concept Using Dual Mode Combustion,” Oil &amp; Gas Science and Technology, Vol. 58, No. 1, pp. 101-114, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Okude, K., Mori, K., Shiino, S., and Moriya, T., “Premixed Compression Ignition (PCI) Combustion or Simultaneous Reduction of NOX and Soot In iesel Engine,” SAE Paper Number 2004-01-1907. ociety of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jacobs, T., Bohac, S., Assanis, D., and zymkowicz, P., “Lean and Rich Premixed ompression Ignition Combustion in a Light-Duty iesel Engine,” SAE Paper Number 2005-01-0166. ociety of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C. S., Wagner, R. M., Lewis S. A., and torey, J. M. E., “Exhaust Chemistry of Low-NOX, ow-PM Diesel Combustion,” SAE Paper Number 2004-01-0114. Society of Automotive Engineers, arrendale, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, R. M., Sluder, C. S., Storey, J. M., and ewis, S. A., “Chemical Composition of the Exhaust rom Low-NOX, Low-PM Diesel Combustion,” Paper umber 254. Proceedings of the International ouncil on Combustion Engines Congress, Kyoto, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wagner, R. M., Green, J. B. Jr., Lewis, S. A., and torey, J. M., “Simultaneous low engine-out NOX nd particulate matter with highly diluted diesel ombustion,” SAE Paper Number 2003-01-0262. ociety of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2003.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., “Non-sooting, low flame emperature mixing-controlled DI diesel ombustion,” SAE Paper Number 2004-01-1399. ociety of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kawamoto, K., Araki, T., Shinzawa, M., Kimura, S., oide, S., and Shibuya, M., “Combination of ombustion Concept and Fuel Property for Ultra- lean DI Diesel,” SAE Paper Number 2004-01- 1868. Society of Automotive Engineers, arrendale, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C. S., Wagner, R. M., Lewis, S. A., Storey, J. ., “Fuel Property Effects on Emissions From High fficiency Clean Combustion in a Diesel Engine,” AE Paper Number 2006-01-0080. Society of utomotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewis, S. A., Storey, J. M., Bunting, B., Szybist, J. ., “Partial Oxidation Products and Other ydrocarbon Species in Diesel HCCI Exhaust,” AE Paper Number 2005-01-3737. Society of utomotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2005.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Swartz, M., Huff, S. P., Parks. J. E., and West, B. H., “Intra-Catalyst Reductant Chemistry and NOx onversion of Diesel Lean NOx Traps at Various tages of Sulfur Loading,” SAE Paper Number 2006-01-3423. Society of Automotive Engineers, arrendale, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Huff, S. P., West, B. H., Parks, J. E., Swartz, M., reen, J. B., and Graves, R. L., “In-Cylinder egeneration of Lean NOx Trap Catalysts Using ow Temperature Combustion,” SAE Paper umber 2006-01-1416. Society of Automotive ngineers, Warrendale, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">West, B. H., Huff, S. P., Parks, J. E., Lewis, S. A., hoi, J. S., Partridge, W. P., and Storey, J. M., “Assessing Reductant Chemistry During In-Cylinder egeneration of Diesel Lean NOx Traps,” SAE aper Number 2004-01-3023. Society of Automotive ngineers, Warrendale, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parks, J. E., West, B. H., and Huff, S. P., “Characterization of Lean NOx Trap Catalysts with n-Cylinder Regeneration Strategies,” SAE Paper umber 2008-01-0448. Society of Automotive ngineers, Warrendale, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Parks, J. E., Prikhodko, V., Kass, M. D., and Huff, S. ., “Synergies of PCCI-Type Combustion and Lean Ox Trap Catalysis for Diesel Engines,” SAE Paper umber 08FFL-0074. Society of Automotive ngineers, Warrendale, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Szymkowicz, P., French, D., and Crellin, C., “Effects f Advanced Fuels on the Particulate and NOX missions from an Optimized Light-Duty CIDI ngine,” SAE Paper Number 2001-01-0148. ociety of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kenney, T., Gardner, T., Low, S., Eckstrom, J., Wolf, ., Korn, S., and Szymkowicz, P., “Overall Results: hase 1 Ad Hoc Diesel Fuel Test Program,” SAE aper Number 2001-01-0151. Society of utomotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gonzalez, M., Clark, W., Wolf., L., Garbak, J., right, K., Natarajan, M., Yost., D., Frame, E., enney, T., Ball, J., Wallace, J., Hilden, D., and Eng, ., “Impact of Engine Operating Conditions on Low- OX Emissions in a Light-Duty CIDI Engine Using dvanced Fuels,” SAE Paper Number 2002-01- 2884. Society of Automotive Engineers, arrendale, 2002.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abdul-Khalek, I. S., Kittelson, D. B., Graskow, B. R., ei, Q., and Brear, F., “Diesel Exhaust Particle ize: Measurement Issues and Trends,” SAE Paper umber 980525. Society of Automotive Engineers, arrendale, 1998.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Storey, J. M., Domingo, N., Lewis, S. A., and Irick, . K., “Analysis of Semivolatile Organic Compounds n Diesel Exhaust Using a Novel Sorption and xtraction Method,” SAE Paper Number 1999-01- 3534. Society of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewis, S. A., Storey, J. M., Strzelec, A., and chuette, E. “Accelerated Extraction of Diesel articulate Matter SOF.” 13th Annual Diesel Engine missions Reduction (DEER) Conference, available n line at http://www1.eere.energy.gov /vehiclesandfuels/pdfs/deer_2007/poster3/deer07_le is.pdf</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Park, K., Kittelson, D. B., and McMurry, P. H., ”Structural Properties of Diesel Exhaust Particles easured by Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM): Relationships to Particle Mass and Mobility,” erosol Science and Technology, Vol. 38, No. 9, pp. 881-889, 2004.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brasil, A. M., Farias, T. L., and Carvalho, M. G., “A ecipe for Image Characterization of Fractal-Like ggregates,” Journal of Aerosol Science, Vol. 30, o. 10, pp. 1379-1389, 1999.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C. S., West, B. H., “Performance of a NOx dsorber and Catalyzed Particle Filter System on a ight-Duty Diesel Vehicle,” SAE Paper Number 2001-01-1933. Society of Automotive Engineers, arrendale, 2001.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">West, B. H., López, A. J., Theiss, T. J., Graves, R. ., Storey, J. M., and Lewis, S. A., “Fuel Economy nd Emissions of the Ethanol-Optimized Saab 9-5 iopower,” SAE Paper Number 2007-01-3994. ociety of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref28">
            <label>28.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Duffin, R., Tran, L., Brown, D., Stone, V., and onaldson, K., “Proinflammogenic Effects of Low- oxicity and Metal Nanoparticles In Vivo and In itro: Highlighting the Role of Particle Surface Area nd Surface Reactivity,“ Inhalation Toxicology, Vol. 19, No. 10, pp. 849-856, 2007.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref29">
            <label>29.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kittelson, D. B., Brear, F., Khalek, I., “ Nanoparticle rowth During Dilution and Cooling of Diesel xhaust: Experimental Investigation and Theoretical ssessment,” SAE Paper Number 2000-01-0515. ociety of Automotive Engineers, Warrendale, 2000.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
