<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">mathcomp</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100273</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Mathematics of Computation</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>American Mathematical Society</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">00255718</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">10886842</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">79</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">272</issue>
         <issue-id>i20779128</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">20779136</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ANALYSIS OF A FINITE PML APPROXIMATION TO THE THREE DIMENSIONAL ELASTIC WAVE SCATTERING PROBLEM</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>JAMES H.</given-names>
                  <surname>BRAMBLE</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>JOSEPH E.</given-names>
                  <surname>PASCIAK</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>DIMITAR</given-names>
                  <surname>TRENEV</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2010</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>2079</fpage>
         <lpage>2101</lpage>
      
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2010 American Mathematical Society</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/20779136"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>We consider the application of a perfectly matched layer (PML) technique to approximate solutions to the elastic wave scattering problem in the frequency domain. The PML is viewed as a complex coordinate shift in spherical coordinates which leads to a variable complex coefficient equation for the displacement vector posed on an infinite domain (the complement of the scatterer). The rapid decay of the PML solution suggests truncation to a bounded domain with a convenient outer boundary condition and subsequent finite element approximation (for the truncated problem). We prove existence and uniqueness of the solutions to the infinite domain and truncated domain PML equations (provided that the truncated domain is sufficiently large). We also show exponential convergence of the solution of the truncated PML problem to the solution of the original scattering problem in the region of interest. We then analyze a Galerkin numerical approximation to the truncated PML problem and prove that it is well posed provided that the PML damping parameter and mesh size are small enough. Finally, computational results illustrating the efficiency of the finite element PML approximation are presented.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
  <back>
    
      <ref-list>
        <title>References</title>
        <ref id="d2742571e167a1310">
            <label>1</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e174" publication-type="other">
J.-P. Bérenger. A perfectly matched layer for the absorption of electromagnetic waves.
J. Comput Phys., 114(2): 185-200, 1994. MR1294924 (95e:78002)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e184a1310">
            <label>2</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e191" publication-type="other">
J. H. Bramble and J. E. Pasciak. Analysis of a finite PML approximation for the three dimen-
sional time-harmonic Maxwell and acoustic scattering problems. Math. Comp., 76(258) :597-
614 (electronic), 2007. MR2291829 (2008b:65130)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e204a1310">
            <label>3</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e211" publication-type="other">
J. H. Bramble and J. E. Pasciak. A note on the existence and uniqueness of solutions of

              frequency domain elastic wave problems: A priori estimates in H
              
              . J. Math. Anal. Appl.,
            
345:396-404, 2008. MR2422659 (2009j:74053)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e227a1310">
            <label>4</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e234" publication-type="other">
W. Chew and Q. H. Liu. Perfectly matched layers for elastodynamics: A new absorbing
boundary condition. J. Comput. Acoust., 4(4):341-359, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e245a1310">
            <label>5</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e252" publication-type="other">
W. Chew and W. Weedon. A 3d perfectly matched medium for modified Maxwell's equations
with streched coordinates. Microwave Opt. Techno. Lett., 13(7):599-604, 1994.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e262a1310">
            <label>6</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e269" publication-type="other">
F. Collino and P. Monk. The perfectly matched layer in curvilinear coordinates. SIAM J. Sci.
Comp., 19(6):2061-2090, 1998. MR1638033 (99e:78029)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e279a1310">
            <label>7</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e286" publication-type="other">
F. Collino and C. Tsogka. Application of the perfectly matched absorbing layer model to the
linear elastodynamic problem in anisotropie heterogeneous media. Geophysics, 66(l):294-307,
2001.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e299a1310">
            <label>8</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e306" publication-type="other">
D. Colton and R. Kress. Inverse acoustic and electromagnetic scattering theory, volume 93
of Applied Mathematical Sciences. Springer-Ver lag, Berlin, second edition, 1998. MR1635980
(99c:35181)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e319a1310">
            <label>9</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e326" publication-type="other">
F. D. Hastings, J. B. Schneider, and S. L. Broschat. Application of the perfectly matched
layer (pml) absorbing boundary condition to elastic wave propagation. The Journal of the
Acoustical Society of America, 100(5):3061-3069, 1996.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e339a1310">
            <label>10</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e346" publication-type="other">
M. Lassas and E. Somersalo. On the existence and convergence of the solution of PML
equations. Computing, 60(3):229-241, 1998. MR1621305 (99a:65133)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e357a1310">
            <label>11</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e364" publication-type="other">
P. Monk. Finite element methods for Maxwell 's equations. Numerical Mathematics and Sci-
entific Computation. Oxford University Press, New York, 2003. MR2059447 (2005d:65003)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e374a1310">
            <label>12</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e381" publication-type="other">
J.-C. Nédélec. Acoustic and electromagnetic equations, volume 144 of Applied Mathematical
Sciences. Springer-Verlag, New York, 2001. Integral representations for harmonic problems.
MR1822275 (2002c:35003)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e394a1310">
            <label>13</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e401" publication-type="other">
S. Nicaise. About the Lamé system in a polygonal or a polyhedral domain and a coupled
problem between the Lamé system and the plate equation. I. Regularity of the solutions.
Ann. Scuola Norm. Sup. Pisa CI. Sci. (4), 19(3):327-361, 1992. MR1205404 (94b:35069)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e414a1310">
            <label>14</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e421" publication-type="other">
J. Nitsche. Ein Kriterium für die Quasi-Optimalität des Ritzschen Verfahrens. Numer. Math.,
11:346-348, 1968. MR0233502 (38:1823)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e431a1310">
            <label>15</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e438" publication-type="other">
J. Peetre. Espaces d'interpolation et théorèm de Soboleff. Ann. Inst. Fourier, 16:279-317,
1966. MR0221282 (36:4334)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e448a1310">
            <label>16</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e455" publication-type="other">
C. J. Randall. Absorbing boundary condition for the elastic wave equation: Velocity-stress
formulation. Geophysics, 54(9):1141-1152, 1989.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e466a1310">
            <label>17</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e473" publication-type="other">
M. Renardy and R. C. Rogers. An introduction to partial differential equations, volume 13 of
Texts in Applied Mathematics. Springer-Verlag, New York, second edition, 2004. MR2028503
(2004j:35001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e486a1310">
            <label>18</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e493" publication-type="other">
A. Schatz. An observation concerning Ritz-Galerkin methods with indefinite bilinear forms.
Math. Comp., 28:959-962, 1974. MR0373326 (51:9526)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e503a1310">
            <label>19</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e510" publication-type="other">
L. Tartar. Topics in Nonlinear Analysis. Math. d'Orsay, Univ. Paris-Sud, 1978. MR532371
(81b:35001)</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="d2742571e520a1310">
            <label>20</label>
          
            <mixed-citation id="d2742571e527" publication-type="other">
Y. Zheng and X. Huang. Anisotropie perfectly matched layers for elastic waves in cartesian
and curvilinear coordinates. Research report, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2002.</mixed-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    
  </back>
</article>


