<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277693</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Simulation and Analysis of In-Cylinder Soot Formation in a Low Temperature Combustion Diesel Engine Using a Detailed Reaction Mechanism</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Naik</surname>
                  <given-names>Chitralkumar V.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Puduppakkam</surname>
                  <given-names>Karthik</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Meeks</surname>
                  <given-names>Ellen</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Reaction Design Inc.</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>June 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">2</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277648</issue-id>
         <fpage>1190</fpage>
         <lpage>1201</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277693"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>3-D Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) simulations have been performed using a detailed reaction mechanism to capture the combustion and emissions behavior of an IFP Energies Nouvelles optical diesel engine. Simulation results for in-cylinder soot volume fraction (SVF) have been compared to experimental data reported by Pires da Cruz et al. [1] for the engine operating in low-temperature combustion (LTC) mode with high EGR, and for varied operating conditions. For the simulations, a 4-component surrogate blend containing n-hexadecane, heptamethylnonane, 1-methylnaphthalene, and decalin was used to represents the chemical and physical properties of the standard European diesel used in the engine tests. A validated detailed surrogate mechanism containing 392 species and 2579 reactions was employed to model the chemistry of fuel combustion and emissions. In addition, a new pseudo-gas soot model was developed and coupled with the fuel chemistry to simulate in-cylinder soot nucleation, growth, and oxidation processes. A 60° sector mesh containing 53500 cells was used for the engine simulations using the FORTÉ CFD simulation software. Comparisons of calculated in-cylinder soot volume fractions to those measured show good agreement for crank-angle-resolved SVF. Soot production nominally begins as soon as the combustion starts around 6 crank angle degrees (CAD) after TDC, and peaks approximately 12 CAD after TDC when soot oxidation begin to dominate. Simulations captured the location of soot in the center of the bowl just above the wall, and trends in SVF with variation in operating parameters, including fuel loading, EGR, injection timing, and intake temperature. Advancing injection timing and increasing fuel loading increases peak soot levels, whereas lower EGR and lower intake temperatures lower peak soot levels. Simulations also capture the trends in other emissions for varied operating conditions. Further analyses have been performed to understand the combustion and emissions processes.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pires da Cruz, A., Dumas, J., and Bruneaux, G., “Two-Dimensional In- Cylinder Soot Volume Fractions in Diesel Low Temperature Combustion Mode,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):2023-2047, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-1390.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liang, L., Naik, C., Puduppakkam, K., Wang, C. et al., “Efficient Simulation of Diesel Engine Combustion Using Realistic Chemical Kinetics in CFD,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0178, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H. and Kadota, T., “Models for Combustion and Formation of Nitric Oxide and Soot in Direct Injection Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 760129, 1976, doi: 10.4271/760129.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tao, F., Srinivas S., Reitz R.D., et al., “Comparison of Three Soot Models Applied to Multi-Dimensional Diesel Combustion Simulations”, JSME International Journal, 2005. 48(4): p. 671-678.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">FORTÉ CFD Simulation Package, 2012, Reaction Design.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C., Puduppakkam, K., Wang, C., Kottalam, J. et al., “Applying Detailed Kinetics to Realistic Engine Simulation: the Surrogate Blend Optimizer and Mechanism Reduction Strategies,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):241-259, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0541.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Reaction Workbench with CHEMKIN-PRO, 2011, Reaction Design.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">The Model Fuels Consortium II. 2012; Available from: www.reactiondesign.com/support/open/mfcII.html.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Puduppakkam, K., Naik, C., Wang, C., and Meeks, E., “Validation Studies of a Detailed Kinetics Mechanism for Diesel and Gasoline Surrogate Fuels,” SAE Technical Paper 2010-01-0545, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-0545.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C.V., Puduppakkam K.V., and Meeks E., “An Improved Core Reaction Mechanism for Saturated C0-C4 Fuels”, J. Eng. Gas Turbines Power, 2012. 134(2): p. doi: 10.1115/1.4004388.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C., Puduppakkam, K., Meeks, E., and Liang, L., “Ignition Quality Tester Guided Improvements to Reaction Mechanisms for n-Alkanes: n- Heptane to n-Hexadecane,” SAE Technical Paper 2012-01-0149, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0149.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C.V., Detailed Chemical Kinetic Modeling of Decalin Combustion, in 7th US National Technical Meeting of the Combustion Institute 2011: Atlanta, GA. p. RK76.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naik, C., Puduppakkam, K., and Meeks, E., “Modeling the Detailed Chemical Kinetics of NOx Sensitization for the Oxidation of a Model fuel for Gasoline,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 3(1):556-566, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2010-01-1084.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang, H. and Camacho J., Private Communication for Model Fuels Consortium, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abid, A.D., Heinz N., Tolmachoff E.D., et al., “On evolution of particle size distribution functions of incipient soot in premixed ethyleneoxygen- argon flames”, Comb. Flame, 2008. 154: p. 775-788.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abid, A.D., Camacho J., Sheen D.A., et al., “Towards Quantitative Measurement of Soot Particle Size Distribution in Premixed Flames - The Burner-Stabilized Stagnation Flame Approach”, Comb. Flame, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">CHEMKIN-PRO 15112, 2011, Reaction Design: San Diego.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ramirez, H.P., Hadj-Ali K., Dievart P., et al., “Kinetics of Oxidation of Commercial and Surrogate Diesel Fuels in a Jet-Stirred Reactor: Experimental and Modeling Studies”, Energy &amp; Fuels, 2010. 24: p. 1668-1676.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Haylett, D.R., Cook R.D., Davidson D.F., et al., “OH and C2H4 species time-histories during hexadecane and diesel ignition behind reflected shock waves”, Proc. Comb. Inst., 2011. 33: p. 167-173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oehlschlaeger, M.A., Shen H.-P.S., Frassoldati A., et al., “Experimental and Kinetic Modeling Study of the Pyrolysis and Oxidation of Decalin”, Energy &amp; Fuels, 2009. 23: p. 1464-1472.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Oehlschlaeger, M.A., Steinberg J., Westbrook C.K., et al., “The autoignition of iso-cetane at high to moderate temperatures and elevated pressures: Shock tube experiments and kinetic modeling”, Comb. Flame, 2009. 156(11): p. 2165-2172.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Abani, N., Kokjohn, S., Park, S., Bergin, M. et al., “An Improved Spray Model for Reducing Numerical Parameter Dependencies in Diesel Engine CFD Simulations,” SAE Technical Paper 2008-01-0970, 2008, doi: 10.4271/2008-01-0970.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
