<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50007470</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jcode">jinsuissu</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>Journal of Insurance Issues</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">15316076</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">23324244</issn>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name specific-use="jstor-licensing-publisher">Western Risk and Insurance Association</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26608367</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>ARTICLES</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Reinsurance and Insurers’ Risk-Return Profile</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Lei</surname>
                  <given-names>Yu</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>

         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                   xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2019</year>
            <string-date>Spring 2019</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">42</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26608363</issue-id>
         <fpage>37</fpage>
         <lpage>65</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2019 by the Western Risk and Insurance Association</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26608367"/>
         <abstract xml:lang="eng">
            <p>Reinsurance has long been known to reduce the ceding company’s underwriting risk and provide capital relief. While the benefits of reinsurance to insurers are abundant, they do not come without a cost. The net value of reinsurance hinges on the trade-off between the costs and benefits of reinsurance. This study examines the effect of reinsurance on firm performance by utilizing a model of total return to stakeholders and a measure of reinsurance that encompasses both ceded premiums and reinsurance recoverables. Our empirical analyses show that reinsurance as measured by the ratio of reinsurance recoverables to ceded premiums negatively affects risk-adjusted return on equity. This result, however, does not necessarily mean that insurers should reduce the use of reinsurance. Every firm is different in its risk tolerance and overall objective. For firms that focus more on the risk reduction effect of reinsurance, reinsurance does provide a meaningful channel to hold down the cost of risk.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="r1">
            <mixed-citation id="c1">AMF (2013) “Reinsurance, Risk Management Guidelines,” accessed on February 23, 2019 from https://lautorite.qc.ca/fileadmin/lautorite/reglementation/lignesdirectrices- assurance/g_reinsurance_2013_p.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r2">
            <mixed-citation id="c2">Bingham, R. E. (2000) “Risk and Return: Underwriting, Investment and Leverage,” accessed on February 23, 2019 from https://www.casact.org/library/00pcas/ bingham.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r3">
            <mixed-citation id="c3">Borch, K. (1961) “Some Elements of a Theory of Reinsurance,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 28(3): 35−43.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r4">
            <mixed-citation id="c4">Browne, M. J., J. M. Carson, and R. E. Hoyt (2001) “Dynamic Financial Models of Life Insurers,” North American Actuarial Journal 5(2): 11–26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r5">
            <mixed-citation id="c5">Campa, J. M., and S. Kedia (2002) “Explaining the Diversification Discount,” Journal of Finance 57(4): 1731–1762.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r6">
            <mixed-citation id="c6">Che, X., A. P. Liebenberg, I. A. Liebenberg, and L. S. Powell (2017) “Decomposing Diversification Effect: Evidence from the U.S. Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” Insurance Markets and Companies 8(1): 16–28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r7">
            <mixed-citation id="c7">Chen, C. F. and R. Rothschild (2010) “An Application of Hedonic Pricing Analysis to the Case of Hotel Rooms in Taipei,” Tourism Economics 16(3): 685–694.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r8">
            <mixed-citation id="c8">Chen H., J. D. Cummins, T. Sun, and M. A. Weiss (2016), “Reinsurance Network and the Performance of U.S. Property-Liability Insurers,” working paper available accessed on February 23, 2019 from http://aria.org/Annual_Meeting/2016/ 2016AcceptedPapers.htm.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r9">
            <mixed-citation id="c9">Choi, B. P. and M. A. Weiss (2005) “An Empirical Investigation of Market Structure, Efficiency, and Performance in Property-Liability Insurance,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 72(4): 635–673.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r10">
            <mixed-citation id="c10">Cole, C. R., and K. A. McCullough (2006) “A Reexamination of the Corporate Demand For Reinsurance,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 73 (1): 169–192.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r11">
            <mixed-citation id="c11">Cole, C. R. and K. A. McCullough (2008) “A Comparative Analysis of U.S. Property and Casualty Reinsurers and Insurers,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 11(1): 179–207.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r12">
            <mixed-citation id="c12">Cummins, J. D. and G. Nini (2002) “Optimal Capital Utilization by Financial Firms: Evidence from the Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” Journal of Financial Services Research 21(1–2): 15–53.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r13">
            <mixed-citation id="c13">Cummins, J. D. and D. W. Sommer (1996) “Capital and Risk in Property-Liability Insurance Markets,” Journal of Banking and Finance 20(6): 1069–1092.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r14">
            <mixed-citation id="c14">Cummins, J. D., Z. Feng, and M. A. Weiss (2012) “Reinsurance Counterparty Relationships and Firm Performance in the U.S. Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” accessed on February 23, 2019 from https://ssrn.com/abstract=1997444.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r15">
            <mixed-citation id="c15">Cummins, J. D., M. A. Weiss, and H. Zi (1999) “Organizational Form and Efficiency: The Coexistence of Stock and Mutual Property-Liability Insurers,” Management Science 45: 1254–1269.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r16">
            <mixed-citation id="c16">Cummins, J. D., G. Dionne, R. Gagné, and A. Nouira (2008) “The Costs and Benefits of Reinsurance,” accessed on February 23, 2019 from https://ssrn.com/ abstract=1142954.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r17">
            <mixed-citation id="c17">Dohoo, I., C. Ducrot, C. Fourichon, A. Donald, and D. Hurnik (1997) “An Overview of Techniques for Dealing with Large Numbers of Independent Variables in Epidemiologic Studies,” Preventive Veterinary Medicine, 29(3): 221–239.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r18">
            <mixed-citation id="c18">Elango B., Y. Ma, and N. Pope (2008) “An Investigation into the Diversification-Performance Relationship in the U.S. Property-Liability Insurance Industry,”Journal of Risk and Insurance 75(3): 567–591.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r19">
            <mixed-citation id="c19">Fama, E. F. and M. C. Jensen (1983a) “Separation of Ownership and Control,” Journal of Law and Economics 26(2): 301–325.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r20">
            <mixed-citation id="c20">Fama, E. F. and M. C. Jensen (1983b) “Agency Problems and Residual Claims,” Journal of Law and Economics 26(2): 327–349.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r21">
            <mixed-citation id="c21">Froot, K. (2001) “The Market for Catastrophe Risk: A Clinical Examination,” Journal of Financial Economics, 60(2–3), 529–571.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r22">
            <mixed-citation id="c22">Grace, E. (1990) “Property-Liability Insurer Reserve Errors: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 57(1): 28–46.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r23">
            <mixed-citation id="c23">Greene, W. H. (1997) Econometric Analysis, Prentice Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r24">
            <mixed-citation id="c24">Greene, W. H. and D. Segal (2004) “Profitability and Efficiency in the U.S. Life Insurance Industry,” Journal of Productivity Analysis 21(3): 229–247.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r25">
            <mixed-citation id="c25">Hoyt, R. E. and J. S. Trieschmann (1991) “Risk/Return Relationships for Life-Health, Property-Liability, and Diversified Insurers,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 58(2): 322–330.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r26">
            <mixed-citation id="c26">Lai, G. C. and P. Limpaphayom (2003) “Organizational Structure and Performance: Evidence from the Nonlife Insurance Industry in Japan,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 70(4): 735–757.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r27">
            <mixed-citation id="c27">Lee, H. and C. Lee (2012) “An Analysis of Reinsurance and Firm Performance: Evidence from the Taiwan Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” The Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance—Issues and Practice 37(3): 467–484.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r28">
            <mixed-citation id="c28">Lei, Y. and J. T. Schmit (2010) “Factors Influencing the Demand for Reinsurance in the Medical Malpractice Insurance Market: A Focus on Organizational Form,” Journal of Insurance Regulation 29(1): 1–28.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r29">
            <mixed-citation id="c29">Liebenberg, A. P. and D. W. Sommer (2008) “Effects of Corporate Diversification: Evidence from the Property-Liability Insurance Industry,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 75(4): 893–919.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r30">
            <mixed-citation id="c30">Lin, F. J. (2008) “Solving Multicollinearity in the Process of Fitting Regression Model Using the Nested Estimate Procedure,” Quality and Quantity 42(3): 417–426.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r31">
            <mixed-citation id="c31">Lin, Y, J. Yu, and M. O. Peterson (2015) “Reinsurance Networks and Their Impact on Reinsurance Decisions: Theory and Empirical Evidence,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 82(3): 531–569.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r32">
            <mixed-citation id="c32">Ma, Y. and B. Elango (2008) “When Do International Operations Lead to Improved Performance? An Analysis of Property-liability Insurer,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 11(1): 141–155.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r33">
            <mixed-citation id="c33">Mankaï, S. and A. Belgacem (2016) “Interactions between Risk Taking, Capital, and Reinsurance for Property-Liability Insurance Firms,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 83(4): 1007–1043.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r34">
            <mixed-citation id="c34">Mao, H., J. M. Carson, and K. M. Ostaszewski (2017) “Optimal Insurance Pricing, Reinsurance, and Investment for a Jump Diffusion Risk Process under a Competitive Market,” Journal of Insurance Issues 40(1): 90–124.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r35">
            <mixed-citation id="c35">Mayers, D. and C. W. Smith (1981) “Contractual Provisions, Organizational Structure, and Conflict Control in Insurance Markets,” Journal of Business 54(3): 407– 434.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r36">
            <mixed-citation id="c36">Mayers, D. and C. W. Smith (1987) “Corporate Insurance and the Underinvestment Problem,” Journal of Risk and Insurance, 54(1): 45–54.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r37">
            <mixed-citation id="c37">Mayers, D. and C. W. Smith (1988) “Ownership Structure Across Lines of Property-Casualty Insurance,” Journal of Law and Economics 31(2): 351–378.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r38">
            <mixed-citation id="c38">Mayers, D. and C. W. Smith (1990) “On the Corporate Demand for Reinsurance: Evidence from the Reinsurance Market,” Journal of Business 63(1): 19–40.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r39">
            <mixed-citation id="c39">Mayers, D. and C. W. Smith, Jr. (1994) “Managerial Discretion and Stock Insurance Company Ownership Structure,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 61(4): 638–655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r40">
            <mixed-citation id="c40">Meier, U. B. and J. Outreville (2006) “Business Cycle in Insurance and Reinsurance: The Case of France, Germany and Switzerland,” The Journal of Risk and Finance 7(2): 160–173.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r41">
            <mixed-citation id="c41">Petersen, M. A. (2009) “Estimating Standard Errors in Finance Panel Data Sets: Comparing Approaches,” Review of Financial Studies 22(1): 435–480.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r42">
            <mixed-citation id="c42">Pottier, S. W. and D. W. Sommer (1999) “Property-Liability Insurer Financial Strength Ratings: Differences across Rating Agencies,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 66(4): 621–642.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r43">
            <mixed-citation id="c43">Powell, L. S. and D. W. Sommer (2007) “Internal Versus External Capital Markets in the Insurance Industry: The Role of Reinsurance,” Journal of Financial Service Research 31(2–3): 173–188.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r44">
            <mixed-citation id="c44">Scordis, N. A. and S. Petra Steinorth (2012) “Value from Hedging Risk with Reinsurance,” Journal of Insurance Issues 35(2): 210–231.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r45">
            <mixed-citation id="c45">Sommer, D. W. (1996) “The Impact of Firm Risk on Property-Liability Insurance Prices,” Journal of Risk and Insurance 63(3): 501–514.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r46">
            <mixed-citation id="c46">Venter, G. (2006) “Measuring Value in Reinsurance,” accessed on February 23, 2019 from https://www.casact.org/pubs/forum/01sforum/01sf179.pdf.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r47">
            <mixed-citation id="c47">Weber, J. (2006) “Discussion of the Effects of Corporate Governance on Firms Credit Ratings,” Journal of Accounting and Economics 42(1–2): 245–254.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r48">
            <mixed-citation id="c48">Wen, J., K. C. Chen, and L. Wu (2015) “Empirical Study of Adverse Selection and Moral Hazard in the Property and Liability Reinsurance Market,” Journal of Finance and Accountancy 19: 1–22.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="r49">
            <mixed-citation id="c49">Yu, T., B. Lin, H. R. Oppenheimer, and X. Chen (2008) “Intangible Assets and Firm Asset Risk Taking: An Analysis of Property and Liability Insurance Firms,” Risk Management and Insurance Review 11(1): 157–178.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
   <floats-group>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 1.</label>
         <caption id="ca-1">
            <p>Variable Definitions</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 2.</label>
         <caption id="ca-2">
            <p>Correlation Coefficients</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 3.</label>
         <caption id="ca-3">
            <p>Summary Statistics and Variance Inflation Factor (VIF)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 4.</label>
         <caption id="ca-4">
            <p>Two-Way Fixed-Effects Regression (Y = ADJ3_ROE)</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 5.</label>
         <caption id="ca-5">
            <p>Two-Way Fixed-Effects Regression Using Alternative Variable Measures</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
      <fig>
         <label>Table 6.</label>
         <caption id="ca-6">
            <p>Two-Way Fixed-Effects Regression Using Difference-in-Difference of Variables</p>
         </caption>
      </fig>
   </floats-group>
</article>
