<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         article-type="research-article"
         dtd-version="1.0"
         xml:lang="en">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jbusiness</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>The Journal of Business</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>The University of Chicago Press</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn pub-type="ppub">00219398</issn>
         <issn pub-type="epub">15375374</issn>
         <custom-meta-group/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor-stable">3663803</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/422633</article-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="msid">JB770415</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Channel Contract Behavior: The Role of Risk Attitudes, Risk Perceptions, And Channel Members' Market Structures</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Joost M. E.</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Pennings</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_1">University of Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign</aff>
            <aff id="aff_2">Wageningen University, The Netherlands</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Brian</given-names>
                  <x xml:space="preserve"> </x>
                  <surname>Wansink</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff id="aff_3">University of Illinois at Urbana‐Champaign</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <month>10</month>
            <year>2004</year>
            <string-date>October 2004</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume>77</volume>
         <issue>4</issue>
         <issue-id>jb.2004.77.issue-4</issue-id>
         <fpage>697</fpage>
         <lpage>724</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2004 by The University of Chicago. All rights reserved.</copyright-statement>
            <copyright-year>2004</copyright-year>
            <copyright-holder>The University of Chicago</copyright-holder>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.1086/422633"/>
         <abstract>
            <p>By integrating elements of both marketing and finance, we show how risk influences channel contract behavior. We model risk behavior as the interaction between risk attitude and risk perception (IRAP). An analysis of the joint channel decisions of 208 producers, wholesalers, and processors provides three results. First, risk attitudes significantly vary across different levels of channel members. Second, IRAP – in combination with the channel member's market structure on the buying and selling side – is a strong predictor of contract behavior. Third, increases in channel power strengthen the impact of IRAP on channel contract behavior.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>en</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <body>
      <sec id="sc1">
         <label>I.</label>
         <title>Introduction</title>
         <p>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf8"/>
            <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf48"/>Risk and uncertainty influence many channel decisions, especially those in turbulent channels with uncertain pay‐offs. Managing or reducing such risk involves managing the vulnerability and volatility of cash flows to help create shareholder value (Srivastava, Shervani, and Fahey<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf54">1998</xref>). Such an effort requires the integration of finance and marketing (Rappaport<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf49">1986</xref>). A key question is how risk reduction behaviors are influenced by risk perceptions, risk attitudes, and the market structure across the buying side and the selling side of the channel. Understanding and anticipating the resulting changes is especially important in commodity and in technology industries where risk continually fluctuates (Anderson<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf3">1982</xref>). It is also critical in industries where unpredicted events—such as product recalls or food safety concerns—dramatically influence channel supply and demand of products with prescribed characteristics (Pennings, Wansink, and Meulenberg<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf46">2002</xref>).</p>
         <p>Research on risk management in channel situations often assumes risk aversion and focuses on either risk perceptions or on risk attitudes. Seldom, however, have these two constructs—risk perceptions and risk attitudes—been investigated simultaneously. Yet, channel members are not homogeneous and differences in risk attitudes and their risk perceptions may vary quite dramatically up and down the channel. These differences in risk attitudes and risk perceptions may be played out in different channel contract strategies. In addition, channel contract behavior may be also influenced by the market structure in which channel members operate and by their relative channel power.</p>
         <p>Consistent with the notable work of Pratt (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf47">1964</xref>) and Arrow (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf5">1971</xref>), we investigate how the interaction between risk attitude and risk perception (IRAP) influences channel members' contract decisions. Understanding this interaction provides us with a tool to better understand how risk management behaviors (such as using fixed‐price contracts) vary across different market structures and different levels of channel power. This is tested by examining the probability with which a channel member (such as a producer, wholesaler, or processor) employs various channel contract strategies to manage their risks. In this paper, we specifically examine the use of three common strategies: 1) establishing spot contract relationships on both the buying and selling side, 2) establishing fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side, and 3) establishing asymmetric contract relationships. Asymmetric contract relationships are characterized by the use of spot contracts on the buying side and fixed‐price contract contracts on the selling side, or vice versa.</p>
         <p>This paper begins with an overview of how risk attitudes and risk perceptions, combined with channel market structure, influence the behavior of channel members. Following this, hypotheses are derived that relate the interaction of risk attitudes and risk perceptions to contracting behavior.</p>
         <p>The empirical findings, based on personal computer‐guided interviews with 208 channel members, show that risk attitudes and risk perceptions differ widely across the three channel levels. Furthermore, the interaction between risk attitude and risk perception (IRAP), in combination with the channel member's market structure, is shown to be a useful predictor of a channel member's contract behavior. This influence of IRAP on channel contract decision behavior is strengthened as channel power increases.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc2">
         <label>II.</label>
         <title>The Interaction between Risk Attitude and Risk Perception</title>
         <p>Risk may be perceived differently across channel members, and how channel members cope with perceived risk will depend on their risk attitude. Before a channel member can respond to risk, risk must first be perceived or identified (Trimpop<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf58">1994</xref>). Stone, Yates, and Parker (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf56">1994</xref>) modeled the identification of risks as a cognitive process of identification, storage, and retrieval. While a market might be considered turbulent by economic standards, the level of risk it presents to a channel member depends on his or her risk perception. A channel member who believes that he or she can predict the market price will perceive the market as less risky than a channel member who believes he or she is unable to predict the market price.</p>
         <p>
            <italic>Risk perception</italic>reflects the channel member's interpretation of the likelihood of exposure to the content of the risk (e.g., price fluctuations) and is defined as a channel member's assessment of the risk inherent in a particular situation. On the other hand,<italic>risk attitude</italic>reflects the channel member's general or consistent predisposition toward risk. It is important to emphasize that risk attitude and risk perceptions are two different concepts. Whereas risk attitude deals with the decision‐maker's interpretation of the content of the risk, and how much he or she dislikes risk, risk perception deals with the decision‐maker's interpretation of the likelihood of being exposed to the content of a particular risk.</p>
         <p>We do not expect risk attitude and risk perception to individually have a direct impact on the contract strategies employed by channel members. Instead, as shown in<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">Figure 1</xref>, we believe it is the<italic>combination</italic>of risk attitude and risk perception that influences behavior. After all, regardless of one's individual risk attitudes a channel member will not change his or her behavior if no risk is perceived in a given situation.<fig-group content-type="figgrp" id="fg1" position="float">
               <label>Fig. 1.<x xml:space="preserve">—</x>
               </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>How the interaction between risk attitude and risk perception influences behavior.</p>
               </caption>
               <fig position="float" fig-type="figure">
                  <graphic xlink:href="fg1"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </fig>
            </fig-group>
         </p>
         <p>When risk‐averse channel members perceive risk, they will exhibit risk management behavior (i.e., behavior to decrease their risk exposure). Risk‐seeking channel members, on the other hand, will exhibit risky behavior when they perceive risk, or they may even seek out ways to increase their risk (because of the corresponding expected pay‐off). The interaction between risk attitude and risk perception (IRAP) represents how the channel member intends to cope with risks in the channel, along with the risks his or her own actions generate. As such, the concept is related to risk behavior intention.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">1</xref>
         </p>
         <p>This basic hypothesis that the interaction between risk attitudes and risk perceptions is related to behavior is consistent with the notable research that<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf47">Pratt (1964)</xref>and<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf5">Arrow (1971)</xref>conducted on the analysis of risk management behavior (See<xref ref-type="app" rid="apa">Appendix A</xref>). Both risk attitude and risk perception are continuous variables. Risk attitudes range from extremely risk‐averse (i.e., refusing any risk under any condition) to extremely risk‐seeking (i.e., always preferring a risk‐carrying outcome). Risk perceptions, on the other hand, range from perceiving no risk to perceiving high risk.</p>
         <p>In this study, we define IRAP as positive when channel members perceive risk<italic>and</italic>are risk averse. We define it as negative when channel members perceive risk<italic>and</italic>are risk seeking. We define it as zero when channel members either do not perceive any risk or when they are risk neutral (see<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg1">Figure 1</xref>). A channel member's IRAP profile should reveal how he or she is going to react to future situations. It should also reflect channel members' predispositions to dealing with the risks inherent to the stimuli they receive and the risks their actions generate.</p>
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn1">
               <label>1.</label>
               <p>An analogue can be made with the multi‐attribute attitude theory introduced by Fishbein and Azjen (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf20">1975</xref>). In this theory, the attitude towards an object (e.g., a risk management strategy) leads to the intention to choose that object, and, ultimately, to choice. IRAP is on the intention level (as opposed to the attitude level) and reflects a latent behavior to deal with risk.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc3">
         <label>III.</label>
         <title>Channel Member's Contract Behavior on Both the Selling and Buying Side</title>
         <p>While there are many motivations to manage risk, a notable one involves the creation of shareholder value. Srivastava, Shervani, and Fahey (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf54">1998</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf55">1999</xref>) argue that lower volatility and vulnerability reduce the risk associated with cash flows. This may result in a lower cost of capital and a lower discount rate, thereby potentially contributing to the creation of shareholder value. A channel member's objective is to reduce<italic>profit</italic>volatility, which does not necessarily mean reducing<italic>price</italic>volatility, because profit is a composite of all cash flow streams (prices of inputs and outputs). That is, the channel member is interested in the risk that remains after parts of the cash flow risks from buying and selling products and services have been cancelled out. (Anderson and Danthine<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf1">1980</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf2">1981</xref>; Zilcha and Broll<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf62">1992</xref>). This remaining risk, which equals profit risk, is often referred to as residual risk. Hence, risk management behavior must take an integrative perspective, and must include both the buying and selling markets of channel members. Each market may generate different levels of risk, due to structural differences.</p>
         <p>Channel members can manage their risk by buying from several suppliers and by using a risk‐reducing channel‐contract strategy within the channel. In this paper, we elaborate on how channel members use contracts on both the buying and selling side to reduce profit risk. By doing so, they reduce the fluctuations in their net cash flow stream.</p>
         <p>The research framework shown in<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg2">Figure 2</xref>consists of the buying and selling side of four types of channel members: 1) the producer, 2) the wholesaler, 3) the processor, and 4) the retailer. The solid arrows represent the cash flow streams between channel members generated by channel contracts (e.g., spot transactions versus fixed‐price contracts). The dashed arrows represent cash flow streams that are generated by the channel member's cost structure (variable versus fixed costs) and reflect the channel member's production process. The relationship between the cash flows on the buying and selling side is influenced by the market structures in which channel members operate and the production processes employed. In this paper we focus on how the channel member's IRAP profile and the channel member's market structures on the buying and selling side drive channel contract behavior.<fig-group content-type="figgrp" id="fg2" position="float">
               <label>Fig. 2.<x xml:space="preserve">—</x>
               </label>
               <caption>
                  <p>Research framework</p>
               </caption>
               <fig position="float" fig-type="figure">
                  <graphic xlink:href="fg2"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </fig>
            </fig-group>
         </p>
         <sec id="sc3.1">
            <label>A.</label>
            <title>Spot Contracts versus Fixed‐price Contracts</title>
            <p>Different channel contract strategies carry different levels of risk (e.g., Lusch and Brown<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf36">1996</xref>). A channel member can influence the level of price risk exposure by carefully selecting his or her channel contract strategy when selling and when buying. In this paper, we focus on two broad classes of price‐related channel contracts: 1) spot contracts (also referred to as spot transactions), and 2) fixed‐price contracts. Spot contracts define the price at the moment of the transaction (at time<italic>t</italic> + <italic>1</italic>), based on the spot market. Cash flows resulting from such contracts are uncertain at time<italic>t</italic>. Fixed‐price contracts, on the other hand, fix the price at the moment that the contract is initiated (at time<italic>t</italic>). Hence, the cash flow generated at the time of actual delivery (time<italic>t</italic> + <italic>1</italic>) is certain. Thus, a fixed‐price contract reduces the volatility of cash flows between channel members (e.g., Crocker and Masten<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf16">1991</xref>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn2">2</xref>The role of fixed‐price contracts in industrial marketing channels is significant, as many channel relations are characterized by a chain of fixed‐price contracts between two or more channel members.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn2">
                  <label>2.</label>
                  <p>In the work of Lusch and Brown (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf36">1996</xref>), fixed‐price contracts can be described as<italic>explicit, hard</italic>and<italic>discrete</italic>contracts (e.g., Dwyer, Schurr, and Oh<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf17">1987</xref>).</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc3.2">
            <label>B.</label>
            <title>Channel Members' Market Structures on the Buying and Selling Side: Cash Flow Relationships</title>
            <p>It has been argued that the motivation for risk reduction is not to reduce the<italic>price risk</italic>of a single asset or commodity but to reduce the<italic>residual risk</italic>of all aggregate contracts (Anderson and Danthine<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf1">1980</xref>; Rolfo<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf50">1980</xref>; Anderson and Danthine<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf2">1981</xref>; Zilcha and Broll<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf62">1992</xref>; and Pennings and Leuthold<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf44">2001</xref>). Channel members are interested in the<italic>profit</italic>resulting from all contract relationships, not just a single contract relationship. The profit is the result of the channel member's entire production process; all the goods and services he or she purchases and sells. The volatility of this profit is determined by the cash flow relationships between inputs and outputs, and this volatility increases when there is a negative correlation between the cash flow of inputs and outputs. In such a case, the volatility in the cash flow streams is increased because the combined profit volatility is higher than the cash flow volatility of the separate inputs or outputs. In contrast, when there is a positive correlation between the cash flow of inputs and outputs, profit volatility decreases, because the cash flow fluctuations (partly) neutralize each other. This is a situation often referred to as a natural hedge (Pennings and Leuthold<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf44">2001</xref>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn3">3</xref>
            </p>
            <p>The correlation (ρ) between the cash flow streams reflects the channel member's cash flow relationships and is an important factor when understanding channel behavior.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn4">4</xref>The correlation between the cash flows is determined by the market structures on the buying and selling side. Besides being influenced by competition (pure competition vs. oligopoly), the correlation between the cash flows is influenced by the firm's cost‐structure (ratio between variable and fixed costs), which is closely related to the production system employed by the channel member. Figures 2 visualizes how the market structure influences the cash flows (i.e., the solid arrows) and how the production process (i.e., the firm's cost structure) influences the cash flows (i.e., the dashed arrows). Variations in the correlation (ρ) between the cash flow streams for the same category of channel members are attributed to variations across dissimilar production systems. Channel members with similar production systems, such as wholesalers of commodities (whose “production system” is rather simple, as it entails trading the commodity), will show a relatively low variation in the correlation (ρ) between the cash flow streams, whereas channel members with heterogeneous production systems show a relatively higher variation in (ρ).</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn3">
                  <label>3.</label>
                  <p>A natural hedge expresses a condition in which an exposure to a risk factor is offset or partly offset by an opposite exposure to that risk factor.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn4">
                  <label>4.</label>
                  <p>Cash flow relationships are not only important when understanding firm's channel contract behavior but also to understand the value of the firm (Brick, Frierman and Kim<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf10">1998</xref>).</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc3.3">
            <label>C.</label>
            <title>Channel Members' Market Structures &amp; Channel Members' IRAP Profiles</title>
            <p>A channel member's market structure profile is reflected by the relationships between the cash flows generated on the selling and the buying side. It is the interaction between a channel member's market structure profile and his or her IRAP profile that ultimately determines the final contract behavior (i.e., whether spot contracts or fixed‐price contracts are used to manage risk).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn5">5</xref>While a channel member's market structure profile reflects the net cash flow volatility, the IRAP profile reflects the channel member's propensity towards this net cash flow (profit) volatility. Hence, the IRAP profile and the correlation (ρ) between the cash flows on the buying and selling side play a crucial role in understanding channel contract behavior. Let us consider each individually:<list>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>1.</label>
                     <p>
                        <italic>The channel member's IRAP profile</italic>. When IRAP &gt; 0, the channel member perceives risk, while being risk averse. We expect this channel member to be inclined to decrease his or her profit volatility. When IRAP &lt; 0, the channel member perceives risk, while being risk seeking. We expect this channel member to be inclined to increase his or her profit volatility.</p>
                  </list-item>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>2.</label>
                     <p>
                        <italic>The correlation</italic>ρ<italic>between the cash flows from the buying and selling side</italic>. When ρ &lt; 0, there is reinforcement of the cash flow volatilities from the buying and selling side. When ρ &gt; 0, the cash flow volatilities from the buying and selling side are (partly) neutralized, resulting in a natural hedge.</p>
                  </list-item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>In this paper, a channel member is assumed to decide on contract relationships for purchases and sales simultaneously, based on the economic principle of the coordination of channel contract relationships on the buying and selling side in order to maximize profit, discounted by risk (i.e., maximizing shareholder value).<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>illustrates three channel contract strategies: 1) establishing spot contract relationships on both the buying and selling side, 2) establishing fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side, and 3) establishing asymmetric contract relationships. The latter contract strategy includes spot contracting relationships on the buying side and fixed‐price contract relationships on the selling side or vice versa. In the empirical part of this study, we classify channel members' contract strategies along the dimensions of their IRAP and market structure.<table-wrap id="tb1" position="float">
                  <label>Table 1</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Hypothesized Contract Relationships Across Various Market Structures and Channel Members' IRAP Profiles</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb1"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="3" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="10pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="10pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="10pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Channel Manager's IRAP Profile</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Channel Member's Market Structure (Correlation between inputand output cash flows—ρ)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">IRAP &gt; 0 (<italic>The motivation is to decrease the volatility in the net cash flow stream</italic>)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">IRAP &lt; 0 (<italic>The motivation is to increase the volatility in the net cash flow stream</italic>)</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">ρ &gt; 0 (Natural hedge situation)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Buying side → Spot contracts Selling side → Spot contracts</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Buying side → Fixed‐price contracts Selling side → Spot contracts<italic>or</italic>Buying side → Spot contracts Selling side → Fixed‐price contracts</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">ρ &lt; 0 (No natural hedge)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Buying side → Fixed‐price contracts Selling side → Fixed‐price contracts</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Buying side → Spot contracts Selling side → Spot contracts</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <p>
               <xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>shows how the different combinations of these key variables are hypothesized to influence channel contract relationship behavior. It shows that spot contracting occurs on the buying and selling side, when there is a positive correlation between the cash flows on the buying and selling side and when the manager has a positive IRAP. The reason for this is that a spot contract strategy decreases risk exposure by using the “natural‐hedge” effect (whereby cash flow fluctuations on the selling side (partly) neutralize the cash flow volatility on the buying side). Under these conditions, the use of fixed‐price contracting on both the buying and selling side would also reduce risk exposure. Yet, whether a channel member uses spot contracts or fixed‐price contracts in this situation depends on the size of the natural hedge. If the natural hedge is large enough to reduce the net cash flow volatility sufficiently, the channel member will prefer to use the less complex natural hedge. In case of a negative IRAP, the channel member is motivated to increase or even maximize the volatility of the net cash flow stream. This can be accomplished by using asymmetric contract relationships on the buying and selling side.</p>
            <p>
               <xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>also addresses the situation when ρ &lt; 0; that is, when the cash flow volatility of the buying side and selling side reinforce each other (leading to increased profit volatility). In this situation, a manager with a positive IRAP will hypothetically use fixed‐price contracts on the buying and selling side. In general, we hypothesize the following:<list>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>H<sub>1</sub>:</label>
                     <p>The interaction between a channel member's IRAP profile and market structure is related to the probability of using a particular channel contract strategy.</p>
                  </list-item>
               </list>Based on<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>, we can refine H<sub>1</sub>as follows:<list>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>H<sub>2A</sub>:</label>
                     <p>If a channel member's IRAP is positive and natural hedge market structures exist (ρ &gt; 0), spot contracts on both the selling and buying side will be the dominant channel contract strategy (upper left cell of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>).</p>
                  </list-item>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>H<sub>2B</sub>:</label>
                     <p>If a channel member's IRAP is negative and natural hedge market structures exist (ρ &gt; 0), asymmetric channel contract relationships will be the dominant channel contract strategy (upper right cell of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>).</p>
                  </list-item>
               </list>and<list>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>H<sub>3A</sub>:</label>
                     <p>If a channel member's IRAP is positive and<italic>no</italic>natural hedge market structures exist (ρ &lt; 0), fixed‐price contracts on both the selling and buying side will be the dominant channel contract strategy (lower left cell of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>).</p>
                  </list-item>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>H<sub>3B</sub>:</label>
                     <p>If a channel member's IRAP is negative and<italic>no</italic>natural hedge market structures exist (ρ &lt; 0), spot contracts on both the selling and buying side will be the dominant channel contract strategy (lower right cell of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>).</p>
                  </list-item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn5">
                  <label>5.</label>
                  <p>We are grateful to an anonymous reviewer who pointed out the important role of the channel member's market structure to understand channel contract behavior.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc3.4">
            <label>D.</label>
            <title>Channel Power</title>
            <p>The type of trading strategy used by channel members may also depend on their channel power. Consistent with El‐Ansary and Stern (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf18">1972</xref>) and Frazier (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf21">1983</xref>), power is defined as the ability of one channel member to influence another's marketing strategy. In the context of this study, power can be used to influence the price term in a contract on two dimensions—the price level and the price variability (Gaski and Nevin<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf23">1985</xref>; Kale<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf31">1986</xref>; Anderson, Lodish, and Weitz<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf4">1987</xref>; Frazier, Gill, and Kale<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf22">1989</xref>; and Buchanan<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf12">1992</xref>). In this study, power refers to a channel member's ability to influence the price discovery process in the channel. If a channel member can influence the price formation process, he or she is said to have power.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn6">6</xref>
            </p>
            <p>Channel members who exert power over the price formation process can do so on two dimensions. First, they can influence prices, by trying to realize the highest (lowest) price level possible when selling (purchasing). Second, risk‐averse channel members with a market structure of ρ &lt; 0 who perceive risk (i.e., with positive IRAP) can try to reduce net cash flow variability by shifting the price risk to other channel members by using fixed‐price contracts. In contrast, channel members with a negative IRAP will instead use risk‐shifting power to accumulate risk in this situation. Hence, we expect the influence of IRAP on channel contract strategy to increase as channel power increases:<list>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>H<sub>4</sub>:</label>
                     <p>The more (less) power the channel member has, the larger (smaller) the effect of IRAP on the probability of using a particular channel contracting strategy.</p>
                  </list-item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn6">
                  <label>6.</label>
                  <p>The channel member's power to influence the price term of a contract may come from the fact that the channel member is able to manipulate other contract terms, such as place or time of delivery, and quality (e.g., Betancourt and Gautschi<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf7">1998</xref>).</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc4">
         <label>IV.</label>
         <title>Research Method</title>
         <sec id="sc4.1">
            <label>A.</label>
            <title>Empirical Domain</title>
            <p>To test the proposed hypotheses effectively, we needed a channel context with minimal channel coordination, minimal channel integration, and multiple channel members at multiple channel levels. Also we needed a competitive environment with a wide range of heterogeneity among the channel members. The Dutch pork industry was found to meet all these requirements. It consists of three types of channel members: producers (hog farms, where piglets are raised to slaughter‐ready hogs), wholesalers (wholesalers of live hogs), and processors (slaughterhouses, which are usually also meat packers), who sell their meat products to the retailers.</p>
            <p>Producers face an oligopolistic market structure on the buying side (there are relatively few suppliers of mixed feed) and a competitive market structure on the selling side (there are relatively many wholesalers). Wholesalers face a competitive market on the buying side and a oligopolistic market structure on the selling side (there are relatively few processors). Processors also face a competitive market on the buying side (there are relative many wholesalers), and an oligopolistic market structure on the selling side (there are only five large retail organizations that buy meat products from processors in the Netherlands).</p>
            <p>The producers are heterogeneous as to their production methods, and they use either an “open production system” (OPS) or a “closed production system” (CPS). In the OPS, both piglets and feed is purchased, and piglets are then raised to slaughter hogs in three months. The CPS is similar to the OPS, except that in CPS the producer breeds the piglets instead of buying them. The “production” process of wholesalers is rather simple and homogeneous: they trade the hogs and serve as intermediaries between producers and processors. Processors have rather homogeneous production processes, although innovations in slaughtering techniques may cause some small differences in labor productivity (computer‐guided cutting equipment versus manual labor). Since we study behavior on the level of the individual channel member, we can test the relationship between market structure and members’ channel contracting behaviors empirically.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc4.2">
            <label>B.</label>
            <title>Sample and Data Collection Procedure</title>
            <p>The Dutch pork industry consists of 20,000 hog farmers, 150 hog wholesalers and 65 slaughterhouses. A sample was randomly drawn from directories kept by the Dutch Agricultural Association for hog farms, the Dutch Union of Livestock Wholesalers, and the Dutch Pork Association, for the processors. Before sending a written request to participate in the computer‐guided interview, preliminary phone calls were made to assure up‐to‐date contact information and to obtain pre‐commitment for completing the study (Sudman and Wansink<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf57">2002</xref>). Response rates were 80% among producers (<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $n=128$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>), 60% among wholesalers (<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $n=50$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>), and 60% among processors (<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $n=30$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>). The personal computer‐guided interview was developed and 30 test interviews were conducted to ensure that the questions were interpreted correctly. All interviewers had prior experience and were trained in the assessment procedures. The interviews took place at the channel member’s enterprise and were conducted during the first half of 1998. The interviews lasted about 35 minutes, during which the channel members worked through several assignments and questions.</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc4.3">
            <label>C.</label>
            <title>Measures</title>
            <sec id="sc4.3.1">
               <label>1.<x xml:space="preserve"/>
               </label>
               <title>Spot Contracts versus Fixed‐price Contracts</title>
               <p>It was coded whether channel members used fixed‐price contracts or spot transactions with their main contract parties, for both the selling and the buying side.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn7">7</xref>Fixed‐price contracts, in this context, refer to agreements in which prices are determined before delivery or reception of the commodity. Spot contracts refer to sales or purchases in the spot market, where transaction and price determination take place at the same moment.</p>
               <fn-group>
                  <fn id="fn7">
                     <label>7.</label>
                     <p>In the Dutch hog industry, managers usually purchase or sell all their products through either fixed‐price contracts or the spot market. Mixed strategies are scarce.</p>
                  </fn>
               </fn-group>
            </sec>
            <sec id="sc4.3.2">
               <label>2.<x xml:space="preserve"/>
               </label>
               <title>Channel Members’ Market Structures</title>
               <p>Channel members were asked to indicate whether the cash flow streams of the buying and selling side generated by their main contract party were moving together (e.g., positive correlation), had no relation (e.g., correlation of zero), or were moving in opposite directions (e.g., negative correlation). We divided the market structure into two classes: 1) a structure with a natural hedge present (e.g. positive correlation) and 2) a structure without a natural hedge (e.g., no correlation or negative correlation).</p>
            </sec>
            <sec id="sc4.3.3">
               <label>3.<x xml:space="preserve"/>
               </label>
               <title>Channel Power</title>
               <p>Following the work of Butaney and Wortzel (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf13">1988</xref>), we focused on the perceived market power of the channel members in determining the allocation of power between the channel members. Brown, Johnson, and Koening (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf11">1995</xref>) found that the direct approach of measuring channel power resulted in measurements with good construct validity. Therefore, the power perceived by a channel member was measured by asking him or her to indicate the perceived extent to which he or she has power over the price discovery process (relative to the other channel member). To obtain an accurate measurement, each respondent was asked to distribute 100 points among his or her own enterprise and the other channel member, where more points indicated more power.</p>
            </sec>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc5">
         <label>V.</label>
         <title>Assessing Risk Attitude, Risk Perception, and IRAP</title>
         <p>The IRAP cannot be measured directly because of its composite structure (i.e., the combination of risk perception and risk attitude). In the context of our study, risk perception refers to the risk that managers perceive with respect to their profits (net cash flow stream). Risk attitude is a domain‐specific concept (MacCrimmon and Wehrung<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf37">1986</xref>; March and Shapira<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf38">1992</xref>). Since our domain constitutes both purchasing and sales transactions, we elicited risk attitude in the domain of financial (market) risk. While the two concepts, risk attitude and risk perception can easily be discerned in a theoretical perspective, operationalization of the two concepts is a challenge. Following Pennings and Smidts (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf43">2000</xref>), we used a revealed behavior method to elicit risk attitude. In this method the channel member's utility function is elicited and the curvature of the utility function is used as a measure for risk attitude. This elicitation procedure is conceptually consistent with the Pratt and Arrow framework outlined in Section II, yet it uses a scaling procedure to measure risk perception.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn8">8</xref>We will now first describe the risk perception and risk attitude measures, followed by the IRAP measure.</p>
         <sec>
            <title/>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn8">
                  <label>8.</label>
                  <p>Some researchers have measured risk perception by assessing the probability function of respondents, using the interval technique (see for an application Smidts (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf53">1997</xref>), and for a detailed description of these techniques Farquhar (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf19">1984</xref>), and Hershey and Schoemaker (1985)). A drawback of this measurement is that it requires a great deal of effort and time from the respondents, and it is extremely costly when conducted on a large scale.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc5.1">
            <label>A.</label>
            <title>Risk Perception</title>
            <p>We measured risk perception through a scale that we developed according to the iterative procedure recommended by Churchill (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf15">1979</xref>). First, based on the literature, we generated a large pool of items, taking care to tap the domain of the risk perception construct as closely as possible. Next, we tested the items for clarity and appropriateness in personally administered pretests with 30 channel managers. The respondents were asked to complete a questionnaire, to provide general feedback, and to indicate any ambiguities or other difficulties in responding to the items. Based on their feedback, we eliminated some items, modified others, and developed additional items. The resulting scale measures the extent to which channel members perceive their own financial performance (which is reflected in their net cash flow stream) as risky. The composite reliability (α) is 0.82, indicating a reliable construct measurement (e.g., Hair et al.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf24">1998</xref>). (See<xref ref-type="app" rid="apb">Appendix B</xref>for a detailed description of the scale).</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc5.2">
            <label>B.</label>
            <title>Risk Attitude</title>
            <p>In this study, we have used the recent findings of Pennings and Smidts (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf43">2000</xref>) and Pennings and Garcia (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf45">2001</xref>) to measure risk attitude, as related to the expected utility model (von Neumann and Morgenstern<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf40">1947</xref>). In the expected utility model, the curvature of the utility function<italic>u</italic>(<italic>x</italic>) reflects risk attitude (Keeney and Raiffa<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf33">1998</xref>). Fundamental to this approach is that the utility function, and hence, risk attitude, is assessed through the certainty equivalence method by means of lotteries.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn9">9</xref>
            </p>
            <p>Several authors have provided conditions and useful generalizations to minimize response bias, often caused by experiments that do not match the real decision situations of the subjects under consideration (Hershey, Kunreuther, and Schoemaker<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf27">1982</xref>; Tversky, Sattath, and Slovic<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf60">1988</xref>; and Pennings and Smidts<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf43">2000</xref>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn10">10</xref>Following Pennings and Smidts (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf43">2000</xref>), we constructed choice sets that closely match the choices that these channel members make on a daily basis. The dimensions of the “lottery” constitute an important design issue. Specifically, what probability and outcome levels should be used to elicit risk preferences? Consistent with the financial literature perspective that prices follow a random walk path (prices can go up or down with equal probability), we used a probability of 0.5 to express this random walk (Working<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf61">1934</xref>; Kendall<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf34">1953</xref>; and Cargill and Rausser<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf14">1975</xref>). Since Dutch hog prices have fluctuated between 2.34 and 4.29 Dutch Guilders during the period 1990–1998, this range is used in our experimental design. The certainty equivalence technique was computerized. Channel members could select between a lottery, a fixed price, or they could state their indifference. Alternative A consisted of a 50/50 lottery. Alternative B consisted of a fixed price, whereby the initial fixed price was randomly generated by the computer within the initial upper and lower bounds. Alternative C consisted of the statement that they were indifferent to alternative A or B. For each lottery, the channel member was asked to assess the fixed price (i.e. the certainty equivalent) by choosing between A or B, until the channel member chose C, after which a new lottery would start. As such, the assessment of the certainty equivalent was an iterative process.</p>
            <p>The measurement procedure took approximately 20 minutes. Nine points of the utility curve were assessed. Based on the assessed utility curve, the Pratt‐Arrow coefficient of absolute risk aversion was derived as a measure of risk attitude. The widely‐used negative exponential function was fit to each subject's outcomes (Tsiang<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf59">1972</xref>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn11">11</xref>After scaling the boundaries of this function, estimation of just one parameter is sufficient to characterize a respondent's risk attitude.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn12">12</xref>After having measured the risk attitude and the risk perception for each channel member, we were able to compose each channel member's IRAP. The IRAP of channel member<italic>i</italic>is calculated by:<disp-formula id="df1">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df1"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<italic>RA</italic>is the channel member's risk attitude (positive if the channel member is risk averse, zero if risk neutral, and negative if risk seeking), and RP the channel member's risk perception. Because risk attitude and risk perception were measured on two different scales, we standardized the risk attitude and risk perception of each channel member prior to calculating the IRAP (Nunnally and Bernstein<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf41">1994</xref>).</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn9">
                  <label>9.</label>
                  <p>In the certainty equivalence method (cf. Keeney and Raiffa<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf33">1998</xref>), the respondent compares the lottery (x<sub>l</sub>,p;x<sub>h</sub>) with a certain outcome, where (x<sub>l</sub>,p;x<sub>h</sub>) is the two‐outcome lottery that assigns probability p to outcome x<sub>l</sub>and probability 1–p to outcome x<sub>h</sub>, with x<sub>l</sub> &lt; x<sub>h</sub>. The certain outcome is varied until the respondent reveals indifference (this certain outcome is denoted by CE(p)). By application of the von Neumann‐Morgenstern utility<italic>u</italic>(x) we obtain:<italic>u</italic>(CE(p)) = p<italic>u</italic>(x<sub>l</sub>) + (1–p)<italic>u</italic>(x<sub>h</sub>). When eliciting utilities, two outcomes are fixed first, such that the range of outcomes between them includes all outcomes of interest. Second, one may set<italic>u</italic>(x<sub>L</sub>) = 0 and<italic>u</italic>(x<sub>H</sub>) = 1 where x<sub>L</sub>and x<sub>H</sub>denote the upper and lower bound respectively of the outcome range. The certainty equivalence method used in this study concerns a bisection framework by only using probability 0.5. First, the certainty equivalent CE(0.5) with utility 0.5 is found as above. Then the outcome CE(0.25) is obtained with utility 0.25 through an indifference CE(0.25) ∼ (x<sub>L</sub>, 0.5; CE(0.5)). The indifference CE(0.75) ∼ (CE(0.5), 0.5; x<sub>H</sub>) yields certainty equivalence CE(0.75), with utility 0.75, etc. Former responses to lotteries are used in the assessment of subsequent responses. A large number of CEs can be found after a sufficient number of questions, in which each question involves a bisection of a particular interval.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn10">
                  <label>10.</label>
                  <p>In the economics literature, Binswanger (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf9">1982</xref>) argued that biases in the elicitation procedure may come from, negative preferences toward gambling, absence of realism in the game setting, and compounding of errors in the elicitation process. Binswanger (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf9">1982</xref>) stresses the importance of choice set construction when obtaining the decision‐maker's utility function. We designed the elicitation procedure such that the choice sets corresponded to the channel members' daily decisions.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn11">
                  <label>11.</label>
                  <p>Tsiang (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf59">1972</xref>) refers to Arrow (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf5">1971</xref>), who provides four conditions for an acceptable utility function: 1) the marginal utility of wealth is positive, 2) the marginal utility of wealth decreases with increasing wealth, 3) absolute risk aversion is constant or decreasing with increasing wealth, and 4) proportional risk aversion is constant or increasing with increasing wealth. The negative exponential function meets all four conditions.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn12">
                  <label>12.</label>
                  <p>See Smidts (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf53">1997</xref>) for a detailed procedure regarding the estimation of the risk parameters using the negative exponential function.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc6">
         <label>VI.</label>
         <title>Analysis and Results</title>
         <sec id="sc6.1">
            <label>A.</label>
            <title>Measurement Results of Risk Attitude and Risk Perception</title>
            <p>The parameters presented in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">Table 2</xref>display the curvature of the channel member's utility curve obtained through the certainty equivalence task and reflect the channel member's preference for risk. For the producers, wholesalers, and processors, the mean squared errors (MSE) of their utility curves were 0.028, 0.032, and 0.012, respectively, and their mean R‐square values were 0.87, 0.87, and 0.91. This indicates a good fit with channel members' responses to the certainty equivalence tasks. Risk attitude varied widely among producers, indicating that it is not valid to assume risk aversion or risk neutrality across all producers. The same pattern was found for the wholesalers and processors. The mean risk attitude parameter (mean α = −0.462) implies that the average producer exhibits risk‐seeking behavior.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn13">13</xref>In contrast to the producers, we find that, on average, the wholesalers and processors are risk averse (with means of<italic>b</italic> = 0.118 and<italic>c</italic> = 0.316, respectively).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn14">14</xref>
               <table-wrap id="tb2" position="float">
                  <label>Table 2</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Risk Attitude Estimates for each Channel Member</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb2"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="4" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="7pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="7pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="7pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="7pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Producers</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Wholesalers</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">Processors</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>a</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>b</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>c</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Parameter</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Mean</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">−0.462</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.118</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.316</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Median</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">−0.217</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.093</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.289</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">st.dev.</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">1.232</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.669</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.796</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Fit indices</italic>
                                 <xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fn1">a</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Mean MSE</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.028</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.032</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.012</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Mean R<sup>2</sup>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.872</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.874</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0.913</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Classification of respondents</italic>
                                 <xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fn2">b</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">on the basis of the t‐value<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb2fn3">c</xref>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Risk Averse</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">39%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">63%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">78%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Risk Neutral</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">4%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">3%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">4%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Risk Seeking</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">57%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">34%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">18%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
                  <table-wrap-foot>
                     <fn id="tb2fn1">
                        <label>a</label>
                        <p>MSE = Mean Squared Error; R<sup>2</sup>is calculated by squaring the Pearson correlation between actual values and the values predicted from the model.</p>
                     </fn>
                     <fn id="tb2fn2">
                        <label>b</label>
                        <p>If<italic>a, b</italic>or<italic>c</italic> &gt; 0, the respondent is said to be risk averse and if<italic>a, b</italic>or<italic>c</italic> &lt; 0, risk seeking.</p>
                     </fn>
                     <fn id="tb2fn3">
                        <label>c</label>
                        <p>A respondent is classified as risk neutral when the parameter is not significantly different from zero at the<italic>p</italic> = 0.05 level.</p>
                     </fn>
                  </table-wrap-foot>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <p>Two consistency checks were built into the elicitation procedure to assess whether the channel members were consistent in their choices. Two measurements at<italic>u</italic>(<italic>x</italic>) = 0.5 and two measurements at<italic>u</italic>(<italic>x</italic>) = 0.625 were obtained in order to test the internal consistency of the assessments. If channel members responded in accordance with expected utility theory, similar certainty equivalents should result. As expected, the assessed certainty equivalents for the same utility levels were similar (pairwise test =<italic>p</italic> &gt; 0.99) for both consistency measurements.</p>
            <p>These findings support the notion that the channel members were consistent in their choices. The findings further substantiate that the research design closely resembles the real business context of the channel members, thereby minimizing response mode effects (Payne<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf42">1997</xref>; Shapira<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf51">1997</xref>).</p>
            <p>The parameter estimates from<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb2">Table 2</xref>are illustrated in<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fg3">Figure 3</xref>, which shows the average utility curves for producers, wholesalers, and processors. In this figure, a convex curve (a negative parameter in the negative exponential function) indicates risk‐seeking behavior, whereas a concave curve (a positive parameter in the negative exponential function) indicates risk‐averse behavior.<fig-group content-type="figgrp" id="fg3" position="float">
                  <label>Fig. 3.<x xml:space="preserve">—</x>
                  </label>
                  <caption>
                     <p>The average utility function for producers, wholesalers and processors</p>
                  </caption>
                  <fig position="float" fig-type="figure">
                     <graphic xlink:href="fg3"
                              mimetype="image"
                              position="float"
                              xlink:type="simple"/>
                  </fig>
               </fig-group>
            </p>
            <p>The risk perception scores were 8.0 for producers, 7.8 for wholesalers, and 6.9 for processors. This suggests that the channel members agree that the markets in which they sell are risky (see<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb3">Table 3</xref>). Implicitly, these empirical findings show that risk attitudes and risk perceptions differ across different levels in the channel. Furthermore our data indicate that channel members' risk perceptions and risk attitudes are not significantly correlated (ρ = 0.16,<italic>p</italic> = 0.12), confirming the conceptual notion that risk attitude and risk perception are different concepts.<table-wrap id="tb3" position="float">
                  <label>Table 3</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Results of Risk Perception Scale<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tb3fn1">1</xref>
                     </title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb3"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="top"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="4" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="9pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="7pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="7pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="7pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Producers</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Wholesalers</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Processors</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Mean</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">8.05</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">7.77</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">6.89</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Median</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">5.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">7.00</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">6.00</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Standard Deviation</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">1.67</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">2.13</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">2.23</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
                  <table-wrap-foot>
                     <fn id="tb3fn1">
                        <label>1</label>
                        <p>The average sum score of the risk perception scale is presented (some items were re‐coded, so that a relatively high score indicates the perception of relatively high levels of risk). See appendix B for a detailed description of the scale.</p>
                     </fn>
                  </table-wrap-foot>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn13">
                  <label>13.</label>
                  <p>These results are in line with previous results from Miller, Kets de Vries, and Toulouse (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf39">1982</xref>), who found that CEOs from small firms were more inclined towards risk taking. Several explanations of risk‐taking behavior have been advanced depending on the specific domain. For example, Jaworski and Kohli (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf28">1993</xref>) found that responding to market developments entails some degree of risk taking. Han, Kim, and Srivastava (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf25">1998</xref>) found that greater market orientation leads to higher degrees of risky, innovative behavior.</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn14">
                  <label>14.</label>
                  <p>The hypothesis that the means of the risk attitude measures of manufactures, wholesalers and processors are equal was rejected at the 5% level, using an ANOVA analysis, thereby further substantiating that different channel members have different levels of risk attitude.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc6.2">
            <label>B.</label>
            <title>Descriptive Findings: Actual Channel Member Behavior</title>
            <p>In line with previous findings (Pennings and Smidts<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf43">2000</xref>),<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb4">Table 4</xref>shows that the majority of processors are risk averse and perceive risk (IRAP &gt; 0). This is in contrast to the producers, who are willing to take risks (53.9% of the producers show a negative IRAP).<table-wrap id="tb4" position="float">
                  <label>Table 4</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Characteristics of Sample &amp; Channel Members' Contract Relationships</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb4"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="4" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="12pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="6pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="6pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="6pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Producers(<italic>n</italic> = 128)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Wholesalers(<italic>n</italic> = 50)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">Processors(<italic>n</italic> = 30)</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">IRAP</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•IRAP &gt; 0 (<italic>n</italic>=103)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">46.1%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">50.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">63.3%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•IRAP &lt; 0 (<italic>n</italic>= 105)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">53.9%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">50.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">36.7%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Market Structure</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•Natural hedge situation</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">42.2%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">80.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">53.3%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•No natural hedge situation</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">57.8%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">20.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">46.7%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Channel Power (self‐perceived)</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•Low channel power</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">51.6%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">52.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">36.7%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•High channel power</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">48.4%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">48.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">63.3%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="1"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Channel Contract Relationship</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•Spot contracting on both buying and selling side</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">28.9%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">24.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">16.7%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•Fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">39.1%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">34.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">50.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">•Asymmetric contract relationships</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">32.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">42.0%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">33.3%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
            <p>The market structure differs for the three types of channel members. Wholesalers are operating in a market structure dominated by a natural hedge situation. This might be explained by the fact that wholesalers only move the product through the chain, without minimal modification. Producers and processors face both natural and non‐natural hedge situations. Market channel members at the same level in the channel (producers, wholesalers or processors) show greater homogeneity in the correlation between input and output cash flows (ρ) than across the three channel categories. The extent of homogeneity of ρ within a channel category varies with the variation in cost structures (reflected in the production systems employed) of these channel members. The homogeneity in the correlation between input and output cash flows (ρ) for wholesalers is explained by the fact that they face a similar market structure and have similar cost structures. Producers and processors show less homogeneity in ρ because of more dissimilarities in the cost structures.</p>
            <p>The majority of producers perceive their channel power as low, whereas a majority of the processors believe that they have power in the marketing channel.</p>
            <p>The differences in market structures and IRAP profiles among the three types of channel members are played out in different channel contract relationship strategies. Interestingly, all types of channel contract strategies are employed by the three types of channel members, showing that the heterogeneity in channel contract relationship strategies is not solely driven by the type of channel member, but also by risk behavior (IRAP profile) and environment (market structure).</p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc6.3">
            <label>C.</label>
            <title>Procedure for Testing the Hypotheses</title>
            <p>To test the hypotheses reflected in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>, we classified the respondents according to their channel contract strategy, IRAP, market structure, and channel power. Respondents were classified as having relatively low power, if they had allocated less than 50 points to themselves (and hence more than 50 points to their trading partner), and as having relatively high power, if they had allocated more than 50 points to themselves.<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>shows the observed frequencies of channel members using spot contracting on both the buying and selling side, fixed‐price contracting on both the buying and selling side, or asymmetric contract relationships. This study was designed so that the hypotheses, as reflected in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb1">Table 1</xref>, could be related to the empirical results in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>. The market structure of the majority of the channel members was characterized by the presence of a natural hedge; that is, there was a positive correlation between the cash flow streams generated by selling and buying activities. This phenomenon occurs often in commodity channels in which products are “moved” through the channel with little modification. Indeed, we have found that natural hedges are more common among wholesalers than for producers and processors.<table-wrap id="tb5" position="float">
                  <label>Table 5</label>
                  <caption>
                     <title>Classification of Channel Members' Channel Contract Relationships by IRAP, Market Structure and Channel Power</title>
                  </caption>
                  <graphic xlink:href="tb5"
                           position="float"
                           mimetype="image"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
                  <oasis_0:table xmlns:oasis="//OASIS//DTD XML Exchange Table Model 19990315//EN"
                                 xmlns:oasis_0="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table"
                                 frame="topbot"
                                 colsep="0"
                                 rowsep="1"
                                 pgwide="1"
                                 orient="port">
                     <oasis_0:tgroup cols="7" align="left">
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="6pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="4pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="4pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="4pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="4pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="6" colname="6" colwidth="4pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:colspec colnum="7" colname="7" colwidth="4pi"/>
                        <oasis_0:tbody valign="top">
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="bottom">
                                 <italic>Market Structure</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">
                                 <italic>IRAP</italic> &gt; 0 (<italic>n</italic> = 103)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="5"
                                             nameend="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="bottom">
                                 <italic>IRAP</italic> &lt; 0 (<italic>n</italic> = 105)</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">ρ&gt;0 (Natural hedge exists)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="5"
                                             nameend="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Incidence of Channel Contract Relationships:</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">All channel members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">Low‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">High‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">All channel members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">Low‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">High‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Spot contracting on both buying and selling side</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">27*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">12*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">15*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">5</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">5</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">2</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">2</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">12</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">12</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Asymmetric contract relationships</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">2</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">1</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">1</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">62*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">43*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">19*</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Correctly classified channel members</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">87%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">86%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">94%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">78%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">72%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">100%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">ρ≤0 (No natural hedge exists)</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="2"
                                             nameend="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle"/>
                              <oasis_0:entry namest="5"
                                             nameend="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle"/>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">Incidence of Channel Contract Relationships:</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">All Channel members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">Low‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">High‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">All channel members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">Low‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="center"
                                             valign="middle">High‐power members</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Spot contracting on both buying and selling side</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">3</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">2</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">1</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">18*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">12*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">6*</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">66*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">12*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">54*</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">3</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">3</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="0"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Asymmetric contract relationships</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">3</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">2</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">1</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">5</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">0</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                           <oasis_0:row>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="1"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="left"
                                             valign="middle">
                                 <italic>Correctly classified channel members</italic>
                              </oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="2"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">92%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="3"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">75%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="4"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">96%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="5"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">72%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="6"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">86%</oasis_0:entry>
                              <oasis_0:entry colname="7"
                                             colsep="0"
                                             rowsep="1"
                                             align="char"
                                             char="."
                                             valign="middle">100%</oasis_0:entry>
                           </oasis_0:row>
                        </oasis_0:tbody>
                     </oasis_0:tgroup>
                  </oasis_0:table>
                  <table-wrap-foot>
                     <p>* Indicates that the percentage of correctly classified channel members, based on the observed contract relationship, is significant at<italic>p</italic> &lt; 0.05, employing a one‐sample multinomial test (e.g. Bain and Engelhardt<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf6">1987</xref>).</p>
                  </table-wrap-foot>
               </table-wrap>
            </p>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc6.4">
            <label>D.</label>
            <title>IRAP, Market Structure and Their Influence on Contract Behavior</title>
            <p>Consistent with H<sub>2A</sub>,<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>clearly shows that the majority of channel members with IRAP &gt; 0 engage in spot contracting relationships on both the selling and the buying side (87%) if a natural hedge is present. Using a one‐sample multinomial test (Bain and Engelhardt<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf6">1987</xref>), the correctly‐classified hypothesized contract relationships were found to be significant.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn15">15</xref>Consistent with H<sub>2B</sub>, the majority (78%) of the channel members with IRAP &lt; 0 choose asymmetric contracting relationships in a natural hedge situation. Again, the correctly‐classified channel contract relationships were found to be significant. The results confirm the general hypothesis (H<sub>1</sub>) that the interaction between IRAP profile and market structure drives channel contract relationships on both the buying and selling side.</p>
            <p>Consistent with H<sub>3A</sub>, if no natural hedge is present in the market structure (lower part of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>), the majority of channel members (92%) with IRAP &lt; 0 choose fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side. In contrast, the majority of channel members (72%) with IRAP &gt; 0 chose spot contracting on both the buying and selling side (H<sub>3B</sub>). Here too, the correctly‐classified channel contract relationships were found to be significant.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn16">16</xref>Interestingly, channel members with a negative IRAP profile show risk‐increasing channel contract behavior. A comment from one of the channel members who operates in a market structure without natural hedges and who uses spot contracting relationships on both the buying and selling side illustrates their motivation: “In our business, input prices and output prices do not have a positive relationship, in fact they often move in opposite directions. We use spot contract relationships on both sides, so that we may take advantage if the gap between input and output prices widens”.</p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn15">
                  <label>15.</label>
                  <p>There are<italic>c</italic>possible types of channel relationships,<italic>A</italic>
                     <sub>1</sub>,<italic>A</italic>
                     <sub>2</sub>,…,<italic>A</italic>
                     <sub>c</sub>. In our case<italic>c</italic> = 3 and<italic>A</italic>
                     <sub>1</sub> = spot contract relationships on both the selling and buying side;<italic>A</italic>
                     <sub>2</sub> = fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side;<italic>A</italic>
                     <sub>3</sub> = Asymmetric contract relationships in a sample of size<italic>n</italic>(the sum of a column in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>). Let<italic>o</italic>
                     <sub>1</sub>,…,<italic>o</italic>
                     <sub>
                        <italic>c</italic>
                     </sub>denote the number of observed outcomes of each channel member. We assume probabilities<italic>P</italic>(<italic>A</italic>
                     <sub>
                        <italic>j</italic>
                     </sub>) = <italic>p</italic>
                     <sub>
                        <italic>j</italic>
                     </sub>,<italic>j</italic> = 1,…<italic>c</italic>, where<inline-formula>
                        <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\sum_{j=1}^{c}p_{j}=1$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                     </inline-formula>, and we wish to test the completely specified hypothesis<italic>H</italic>
                     <sub>0</sub>:<italic>p</italic>
                     <sub>
                        <italic>j</italic>
                     </sub> = <italic>p</italic>
                     <sub>
                        <italic>jo</italic>
                     </sub>,<italic>j</italic> = 1,…<italic>c</italic>. Under<italic>H</italic>
                     <sub>0</sub>the expected values for each type are given by<italic>e</italic>
                     <sub>
                        <italic>j</italic>
                     </sub> = <italic>np</italic>
                     <sub>
                        <italic>jo</italic>
                     </sub>. The chi‐square statistic can then be written as:<inline-formula>
                        <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $x^{2}=\sum_{j=1}^{c}( o_{j}-e_{j}) ^{2}/ e_{j}$ \end{document}</tex-math>
                     </inline-formula>. The limiting distribution of this statistic is chi‐squared with<italic>c</italic> = 1 degrees of freedom, so an approximate size α test is to reject<italic>H</italic>
                     <sub>0</sub>if<italic>x</italic>
                     <sup>2</sup> &gt; x<sup>2</sup>
                     <sub>1 − α</sub>(c − 1).</p>
               </fn>
               <fn id="fn16">
                  <label>16.</label>
                  <p>The number of observations in the cells corresponding to a market structure with no natural hedge and negative IRAP is lower than for the market structure characterized by a natural hedge situation, thereby weakening the Chi‐square test.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </sec>
         <sec id="sc6.5">
            <label>E.</label>
            <title>Does Channel Power Strengthen the Influence of IRAP?</title>
            <p>Recall that H<sub>4</sub>claims that channel power strengthens the influence of IRAP. To test this, we distributed the channel members' contract relationships along the dimensions of low and high channel power, as shown in<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>.<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>shows that if IRAP &gt; 0 and a natural hedge situation exists, the percentage of correctly‐classified channel contract relationships increases from 87% to 94% (compare column 2 with column 4 in upper right part of<xref ref-type="table" rid="tb5">Table 5</xref>). Similar results are found for the other cases: IRAP &lt; 0 and natural hedge situation (78% vs. 100%), IRAP &gt; 0 and no natural hedge situation (92% vs. 96%), and IRAP &lt; 0 and no natural hedge situation (72% vs. 100%). This confirms H<sub>4</sub>. These empirical results suggest that channel members use channel power to shift risk when IRAP &gt; 0, or they use channel power to accumulate risk when IRAP &lt; 0.</p>
         </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sc7">
         <label>VII.</label>
         <title>Discussion and Conclusions</title>
         <p>Marketing has a long tradition of studying the (optimal) structure of marketing channel relationships. Concepts such as trust and channel power play an important role in this context. In contrast, finance has focused on raising and allocating financial funds. The financial performance of a firm, often expressed in terms of its capacity to generate shareholder value, has often been the dependent variable in finance research. As a result, concepts such as cash flow volatility and risk play an important role in financial literature. In this paper, we begin to integrate the principles of marketing and finance in the context of contract relationship management between suppliers and buyers. The results show that the marketing and finance approach can be tied to the channel member's IRAP profile and market structure on the buying and selling side.</p>
         <p>Although previously neglected in the channel literature, IRAP is an important variable in trying to understand channel behavior, particularly in turbulent markets. When market researchers suspect the domain to entail some level of risk, it is recommended that they take IRAP into account when analyzing channel behavior. The impact of IRAP appears to become even more important when there is power asymmetry in the channel.</p>
         <p>When channel members perceive risk, they use their power to either shift it away from them, when they are risk averse, or to accumulate it, when they are risk seeking. They do so through various channel contract strategies. Based on the cash flow consequences of channel contracts, we make a distinction between three types of channel contract strategies: 1) establishing spot contract relationships on both the buying and selling side, 2) establishing fixed‐price contract relationships on both the buying and selling side, 3) establishing asymmetric contract relationships.</p>
         <p>Our empirical study reveals that risk attitudes and risk perceptions differ across channel members, and that this results in different types of risk management behavior for upstream and downstream channel members. Channel contracting behavior is driven by the interaction between IRAP and the channel member's market structure on the buying and selling side.</p>
         <p>Channel members have a wide range of risk reduction instruments and risk reduction strategies available. Knowing and recognizing the IRAP profile of other members within the channel seems valuable, since IRAP, in combination with the marketing channel member's market structure, reflects a channel member's contract preference structure. Conducting business with other channel members depends heavily on the way one expects the other channel member to behave. To gain insight into the behavioral pattern of channel members, it is necessary to understand the IRAP profile and the market structure of other channel members. In the empirical study, the IRAP profiles and the channel market structures of producers differ from that of wholesalers and processors. This results in substantially different channel contracting behavior between them.</p>
         <p>In this study, risk perception was measured with a self‐report scale, thereby lacking the advantages of the revealed‐preference methods which were used to elicit risk attitude. Using a revealed‐preference method for risk perception, such that the respondent's cumulative probability distribution function were elicited (e.g., Farquhar<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf19">1984</xref>; Jia, Dyer, and Butler<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf29">1999</xref>), would further enhance our measurements of IRAP and would reinforce our conclusion that IRAP is a critical variable in understanding channel behavior. An elicitation technique measuring the respondent's cumulative probability which can be conveniently applied in a channel setting is the interval technique.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn17">17</xref>This technique can be used for encoding the channel member's subjective probability function, and is, as such, closely related to Pratt and Arrow's conceptualization of risk perception. Having elicited some points of the cumulative probability function for the channel member, one might fit a distribution function (e.g., lognormal or Weibull) to the points and use the parameters or the moments of the distribution for further analysis. Combining these results of the interval technique with the certainty equivalence technique will result in a strong predictor (i.e., IRAP) of channel contract behavior.</p>
         <p>An important strain of channel research literature uses the transaction cost model. Usually, a channel member has the opportunity to sell or buy his or her goods through different marketing channels, such as traders, wholesalers, retailers, or even to sell directly to the final customer. This choice of distribution channel, therefore, determines the extent of price risk exposure. When selling or buying, we expect channel members to choose marketing channels that fit their IRAP profiles. Klein, Frazier, and Roth (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf35">1990</xref>) found the transaction cost model to have low predictive power in classifying export firms in terms of their channel choices. This suggests that such a model might be incomplete (cf. Heide and John<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf26">1988</xref>). Given this flaw in the transaction cost model, IRAP could be a valuable complement that may increase its predictive accuracy. Moreover, this integration of IRAP into the transaction cost model is supported by the literature on market entry, which suggests that factors related to political and economic risks influence channel integration and channel choice (Keegan<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf32">1984</xref>).<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn18">18</xref>
         </p>
         <fn-group>
            <fn id="fn17">
               <label>17.</label>
               <p>See Smidts (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf52">1990</xref>) for a detailed discussion and application of the interval technique.</p>
            </fn>
            <fn id="fn18">
               <label>18.</label>
               <p>Financial support from Euronext, the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, the Foundation for Research in Agricultural Derivatives, Iowa Pork Association, the Marketing Science Institute, Unilever, AST (Algemene Stichting Termijnmarkten), the Niels Stensen Foundation, and the Office for Futures and Options Research made it possible to conduct the large‐scale interview. The authors appreciate the insightful comments of two anonymous referees, Pradeep K. Chintagunta (editor), Abbie Griffin, James Hess, Erno Kuiper, Matthew Meulenberg, Rudy Nayga, William Qualls, Jose Antoine Rosa, Ale Smidts, and Michael Ward on prior drafts of this paper. The authors also express their thanks to the participants of the 1999 Marketing Science conference in Syracuse, the 7th Behavioral Decision Research in Management Conference (2000), and the participants of the marketing seminar at the London Business School.</p>
            </fn>
         </fn-group>
      </sec>
   </body>
   <back>
      <app-group>
         <app id="apa">
            <label>Appendix A</label>
            <title>The Role of the Interaction between Risk Attitude and Risk Perception in Risk Management</title>
            <p>In Pratt and Arrow's work, risk management, reflected in the risk premium π, is a function of risk attitude (risk aversion<italic>r</italic>), the situation (base wealth<italic>W</italic>) and perceived risk (with a mean of<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\overline{\varepsilon }$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>and variance σ<sup>2</sup>of source of additional wealth ε). In their analysis, risk management is determined by the statement that the risk premium leaves the decision‐maker indifferent between holding the perceived risky asset or holding its mean value minus the risk premium. That is,<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $EU( W+\varepsilon ) =EU( W+\varepsilon -\pi ) $ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>, where<italic>EU</italic>is the expected utility. In the expected utility model this translates into:<disp-formula id="df2">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df2"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<italic>U</italic>(.) is the von Neumann‐Morgenstern utility function and<italic>f</italic>(.) the probability density function of additional wealth ε. By taking Taylor series approximation around<italic>W</italic>, the behavioral equation is approximately equivalent to<disp-formula id="df3">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df3"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>For simplicity, assume that<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\overline{\varepsilon }=0$ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>, then, solving for the behavioral risk premium, we obtain<disp-formula id="df4">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df4"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>which can be written as:<disp-formula id="df5">
                  <graphic xlink:href="df5"
                           mimetype="image"
                           position="float"
                           xlink:type="simple"/>
               </disp-formula>where<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $r( W) =-U^{\prime \prime }( W) / U^{\prime }( W) $ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>, the Pratt‐Arrow coefficient of absolute risk aversion. From<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df2">(1)</xref>
               <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df3"/>
               <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df4"/>–<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df5">(4)</xref>, it follows that risk management behavior depends on the interaction of perceived risk and risk aversion. The right hand side of expression<xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="df5">(4)</xref>for the behavioral risk premium equals IRAP, that is<inline-formula>
                  <tex-math notation="LaTeX">\documentclass{aastex} \usepackage{amsbsy} \usepackage{amsfonts} \usepackage{amssymb} \usepackage{bm} \usepackage{mathrsfs} \usepackage{pifont} \usepackage{stmaryrd} \usepackage{textcomp} \usepackage{portland,xspace} \usepackage{amsmath,amsxtra} \usepackage[OT2,OT1]{fontenc} \newcommand\cyr{ \renewcommand\rmdefault{wncyr} \renewcommand\sfdefault{wncyss} \renewcommand\encodingdefault{OT2} \normalfont \selectfont} \DeclareTextFontCommand{\textcyr}{\cyr} \pagestyle{empty} \DeclareMathSizes{10}{9}{7}{6} \begin{document} \landscape $\mathrm{IRAP}\,\equiv \sigma ^{2}r( W) $ \end{document}</tex-math>
               </inline-formula>.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn19">19</xref>
            </p>
            <fn-group>
               <fn id="fn19">
                  <label>19.</label>
                  <p>We thank James Hess for his discussion.</p>
               </fn>
            </fn-group>
         </app>
         <app id="apb">
            <label>Appendix B</label>
            <title>Description of Risk Perception Scale</title>
            <p>Confirmatory factor analysis was used (using LISREL 8) to examine the measurement quality (Jöreskog and Sörbom<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="rf30">1993</xref>). In this study, channel members were asked to indicate their agreement with the following items through a nine‐point scale ranging from “strongly disagree” to “strongly agree”:<list>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>1)</label>
                     <p>I am able to predict hog prices</p>
                  </list-item>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>2)</label>
                     <p>The hog market is not risky at all</p>
                  </list-item>
                  <list-item>
                     <label>3)</label>
                     <p>I am exposed to a large amount of risk when I am buying/selling hogs</p>
                  </list-item>
               </list>Construct Reliability: 0.82</p>
         </app>
      </app-group>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed">
         <title>References</title>
         <ref id="rf1">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Anderson, R. W., and Danthine, J‐P. 1980. Hedging and joint production, theory and illustrations.<italic>Journal of Finance</italic>35 (May): 487–489.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf2">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Anderson, R. W., and Danthine, J‐P. 1981. Cross hedging. Journal of Political Economy 89 (December): 1182–1196.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf3">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Anderson, P. 1982. Marketing planning and the theory of the firm.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>46 (Spring): 15–26.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf4">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Anderson, E., Lodish, L. M., and Weitz, B. A. 1987. Resource allocation in conventional channels.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>24 (February): 85–97.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf5">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Arrow, K. J. 1971.<italic>Essays in the Theory of Risk Bearing</italic>. Chicago: Markham Publishing Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf6">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Bain, L. J., Engelhardt, M. 1987.<italic>Introduction to Probability and Mathematical Statistics</italic>. Boston: Duxbury Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf7">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Betancourt, R. R., and Gautschi, D. A. 1998. Distribution services and economic power in a channel.<italic>Journal of Retailing</italic>74 (Spring): 37–60.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf8">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Bettman, J. R. 1973. Perceived risk and its components, a model and empirical test.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>10 (May): 184–190.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf9">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Binswanger, H. P. 1982. Empirical estimation and use of risk preferences: Discussion.<italic>American Journal of Agricultural Economics</italic>64(May): 391–393.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf10">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Brick, I. E., Frierman, M., and Kim, Y. K. 1998. Asymmetric information concerning the variance of cash flows: The capital structure choice.<italic>International Economic Review</italic>39 (August): 745–761.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf11">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Brown, J. R., Johnson, J. L., and Koenig, H. F. 1995. Measuring the sources of marketing channel power: A comparison of alternative approaches.<italic>International Journal of Research in Marketing</italic>12 (November): 333–354.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf12">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Buchanan, L. 1992. Vertical trade relationships: the role of dependence and symmetry in attaining organizational goals.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>29 (February): 65–75.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf13">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Butaney, G., and Wortzel, L. H. 1988. Distributor power versus manufacturer power: the customer role.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>52 (January): 52–63.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf14">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Cargill, Th. F., and Rausser, G. C. 1975. Temporal price behavior in commodity futures markets.<italic>Journal of Finance</italic>30 (September): 1043–1053.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf15">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Churchill, G. A. 1979. A paradigm for developing better measures of marketing constructs.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>16 (February): 64–73.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf16">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Crocker, K. J., and Masten, S. E. 1991. Pretia ex machina? Prices and process in long‐term contracts.<italic>Journal of Law and Economics</italic>34 (April): 69–99.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf17">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Dwyer, F. R., Schurr, P. H., and Oh, S. 1987. Developing buyer‐seller relationships.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>51 (April): 11–27.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf18">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">El‐Ansary, A. I., and Stern, L. W. 1972. Power measurement in the distribution channel.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>9 (February): 47–52.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf19">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Farquhar, P. H. 1984. Utility assessment methods.<italic>Management Science</italic>30 (November): 1283–1300.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf20">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Fishbein, M., and Azjen, I. 1975.<italic>Belief, Attitude, Intention and Behavior: An Introduction to Theory and Research</italic>. Reading, MA: Addison‐Wesley.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf21">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Frazier, G. L. 1983. On the measurement of interfirm power in channels of distribution.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>20 (May): 158–166.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf22">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Frazier, G. L., Gill, J. D., and Kale, S. H. 1989. Dealer dependence levels and reciprocal actions in a channel of distribution in a developing country.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>53 (January): 50–69.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf23">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Gaski, J. F., and Nevin, J. R. 1985. The differential effects of exercised and unexercised power sources in a marketing channel.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>22 (May): 130–142.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf24">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Hair, J. F., Anderson, R. E., Tathem, R. L., and Black, W. C. 1998.<italic>Multivariate Data Analysis</italic>. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice‐Hall.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf25">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Han, J. K., Kim, N., and Srivastava, R. K. 1998. Market orientation and organizational performance: is innovation the missing link?<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>62 (October): 30–45.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf26">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Heide, J. B., and John, G. 1988. The role of dependence balancing in safeguarding transaction‐specific assets in conventional channels.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>52 (January): 20–35.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf27">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Hershey, J. C., Kunreuther, H. C., and Schoemaker, P. J. H. 1982. Sources of bias in assessment procedures for utility functions.<italic>Management Science</italic>28 (August): 936–954.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf28">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Jaworski, B. J., and Kohli, A. K. 1993. Market orientation: Antecedents and consequences.<italic>Journal Marketing</italic>57 (July): 53–70.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf29">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Jia, J., Dyer, J. S., and Butler, J. C. 1999. Measures of perceived risk.<italic>Management Science</italic>45 (April): 519–532.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf30">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Jöreskog, K. G., and Sörbom, D. 1993.<italic>LISREL 8: Structural Equation Modeling with the SIMPLIS Command Language</italic>. Chicago: Scientific Software International, Inc.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf31">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Kale, S. H. 1986. Manufacturer's power and influence strategies within distribution channels in a developing country.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>23 (August): 387–393.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf32">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Keegan, W. J. 1984. International competition: the Japanese challenge.<italic>Journal of International Business Studies</italic>15 (Winter): 189–193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf33">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Keeney, R. L., and Raiffa, H. 1998.<italic>Decisions With Multiple Objectives: Preferences and Value Tradeoffs</italic>. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf34">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Kendall, M. G. 1953. The analysis of economic time series prices, Part I.<italic>Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. Series A</italic>96:11–25.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf35">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Klein, S., Frazier, G. L., and Roth, V. J. 1990. A transaction cost analysis model of channel integration in international markets.<italic>Journal of Marketing Research</italic>27 (May): 196–208.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf36">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Lusch, R. F., and Brown, J. R. 1996. Interdependency, contracting, and relational behavior in marketing channels.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>60 (October): 19–38.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf37">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">MacCrimmon, K. R., and Wehrung, D. A. 1986.<italic>Taking Risks: The Management of Uncertainty</italic>New York: The Free Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf38">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">March, J. G., and Shapira, Z. 1992. Variable risk preferences and the focus of attention.<italic>Psychological Review</italic>99 (1):172–183.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf39">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Miller, D., Kets de Vries, M. F. R., and Toulouse, J‐M. 1982. Top executive locus of control and its relationship to strategy‐making, structure, and environment.<italic>Academy of Management Journal</italic>25 (June): 237–253.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf40">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">von Neumann, J., and Morgenstern, O. 1947.<italic>Theory of Games and Economic Behavior</italic>. 2d ed. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf41">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Nunnally, J. C., and Bernstein, I. H. 1994.<italic>Psychometric Theory</italic>. Third Edition. New York: McGraw‐Hill.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf42">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Payne, J. W. 1997. The Scarecrow's search: a cognitive psychologist's perspective on organizational decision making. In Z. Shapira (ed.),<italic>Organizational Decision Making</italic>. pp. 353–374. New York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf43">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Pennings, J. M. E., and Smidts, A. 2000. Assessing the construct validity of risk attitude.<italic>Management Science</italic>46 (October): 1337–1348.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf44">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Pennings, J. M. E., and Leuthold, R. M. 2001. Introducing new futures contracts: reinforcement versus cannibalism.<italic>Journal of International Money &amp; Finance</italic>20 (October): 659–675.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf45">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Pennings, J. M. E., and Garcia, P. 2001. Measuring producers' risk preferences: A global risk attitude construct.<italic>American Journal of Agricultural Economics</italic>83 (November): 993–1009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf46">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Pennings, J. M. E., Wansink, B., and Meulenberg, M.T.G. 2002. A note on modeling consumers' reactions to a crisis: The case of the madcow disease.<italic>International Journal of Research in Marketing</italic>19 (February): 91–100.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf47">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Pratt, John W. 1964. Risk aversion in the small and in the large.<italic>Econometrica</italic>32:122–136.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf48">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Rao, S., and Farley, J. U. 1987. Effects of environmental perceptions and cognitive complexity on search and information processing.<italic>Psychology and Marketing</italic>4 (Winter): 287–302.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf49">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Rappaport, A. 1986.<italic>Creating Shareholder Value</italic>. New York: The Free Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf50">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Rolfo, J. 1980. Optimal hedging under price and quantity uncertainty: the case of a cocoa producer.<italic>Journal of Political Economy</italic>88 (February): 100–116.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf51">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Shapira, Z. 1997.<italic>Organizational Decision Making</italic>. New York: Cambridge University Press.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf52">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Smidts, A. 1990.<italic>Decision Making Under Risk</italic>. Wageningen, the Netherlands: Wageningse Economische Studies.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf53">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Smidts, A. 1997. The relationship between risk attitude and strength of preference: a test of intrinsic risk attitude.<italic>Management Science</italic>43 (March): 357–370.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf54">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Srivastava, R. K., Shervani, T. A., and Fahey, L. 1998. Market‐based assets and shareholder value: a framework for analysis.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>62 (January): 2–18.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf55">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Srivastava, R. K., Shervani, T. A., and Fahey, .L. 1999. Marketing, business processes, and shareholder value: an organizationally embedded view of marketing activities and the discipline of marketing.<italic>Journal of Marketing</italic>63 (October. Special Issue): 168–179.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf56">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Stone, E. R., Yates, J. F., and Parker, A. M. 1994. Risk communication: absolute versus relative expressions of low‐probability risks.<italic>Organizational Behavior &amp; Human Decision Processes</italic>60 (December): 387–408.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf57">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Sudman, S., and Wansink, B. 2002.<italic>Consumer Panels</italic>, Second Edition. Chicago: American Marketing Association.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf58">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Trimpop, R. M. 1994.<italic>The Psychology of Risk Taking Behavior</italic>. New York: North‐Holland Publishers &amp; Co.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf59">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Tsiang, S. C. 1972. The rationale of the mean‐standard deviation analysis, skewness preference and demand for money.<italic>American Economic Review</italic>64 (June): 354–371.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf60">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Tversky, A., Sattath, S., and Slovic, P. 1988. Contingent weighting in judgement and choice.<italic>Psychological Review</italic>95 (July): 371–384.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf61">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Working, H. 1934. A random differences series for use in the analysis of time series. Journal of the American Statistical Association 29: 11–24.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="rf62">
            <mixed-citation xlink:type="simple">Zilcha, I., and Broll, U. 1992. Optimal hedging by firms with multiple sources of risky revenues.<italic>Economic Letters</italic>39 (August): 473–477.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
