<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<article dtd-version="1.0" article-type="research-article">
  <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">jcompgrapstat</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j100879</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <journal-title>Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
      
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>JCGS Management Committee of the American Statistical Association, Institute of Mathematical Statistics, and Interface Foundation of North America</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">10618600</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
         <volume xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                 xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">20</volume>
         <issue xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
                xmlns:oasis="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/oasis-exchange/table">2</issue>
         <issue-id>i23110435</issue-id>
         <article-id pub-id-type="jstor">23110483</article-id>
         <article-categories>
            <subj-group>
               <subject>20th Anniversary Feature: 2009 ASA Data Expo</subject>
            </subj-group>
         </article-categories>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>ASA 2009 Data Expo</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib>
               <string-name>
                  <given-names>Hadley</given-names>
                  <surname>Wickham</surname>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>6</month>
            <year>2011</year>
         </pub-date>
         <fpage>281</fpage>
         <lpage>283</lpage>
      
      
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>© 2011 American Statistical Association, the Institute of Mathematical Statistics, and the Interface Foundation of North America</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
      
         <self-uri xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/23110483"/>
      
      
         <abstract>
            <p>The ASA Statistical Computing and Graphics Data Expo is a biannual data exploration challenge. Participants are challenged to provide a graphical summary of important features of the data. The task is intentionally vague to allow different entries to focus on different aspects of the data, giving the participants maximum freedom to apply their skills. The 2009 data expo consisted of flight arrival and departure details for all commercial flights on major carriers within the USA, from October 1987 to April 2008. This is a large dataset: there are nearly 120 million records in total, and takes up 1.6 gigabytes of space compressed and 12 gigabytes when uncompressed. The complete dataset and challenge are available on the competition website http://stat-computing.org/dataexpo/2009/. Because the dataset is so large, we also provided participants introductions to useful tools for dealing with this scale of data: Linux command line tools, including sort, awk, and cut, and sqlite, a simple SQL database. Additionally, we provided pointers to supplemental data on airport locations, airline carrier codes, individual plane information, and weather.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group>
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
  </front>
</article>


