<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284797</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Backward Flow of Hot Burned Gas Surrounding High-Pressure Diesel Spray Flame from Multi-hole Nozzle</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Fuyuto</surname>
                  <given-names>Takayuki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs., Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Hattori</surname>
                  <given-names>Yoshiaki</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Toyota Central R&amp;D Labs., Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Yamashita</surname>
                  <given-names>Hayato</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>Nippon Soken Inc.</aff>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mashida</surname>
                  <given-names>Makoto</given-names>
               </string-name>
               <aff>DENSO Corp.</aff>
            </contrib>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>71</fpage>
         <lpage>83</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2015 SAE Japan and Copyright © SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284797"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>The backward flow of the hot burned gas surrounding a diesel flame was found to be one of the factors dominating the set-off length (also called the lift-off length), that is, the distance from a nozzle exit into which a diffusion flame cannot intrude. In the combustion chamber of an actual diesel engine, the entrainment of the surrounding gas into a spray jet from a multi-hole nozzle is restricted by the walls and adjacent spray jets, which induces the backward flow of the surrounding gas. A new momentum theory to calculate the backward flow velocity was established by extending Wakuri's momentum theory. Shadowgraph imaging in an optical engine successfully visualized the backward flow of the hot burned gas.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yanagihara, H., Satou, Y., and Mizuta, J., “A simultaneous reduction of NOx and soot in diesel engines under a new combustion system (Uniform Bulky Combustion System - UNIBUS),” 17th. Int. Vienna Motor Symposium, 1996.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kimura, S., Aoki, O., Ogawa, H., Muranaka, S. et al., “New Combustion Concept for Ultra-Clean and High-Efficiency Small DI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-3681, SAE Transactions, 108, No. 3, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-3681.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Aoyagi, Y., Osada, H., Misawa, M., Goto, Y., and Ishii, H., “Advanced Diesel Combustion Using of Wide Range, High Boosted and Cooled EGR System by Single Cylinder Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2006- 01-0077, 2006, doi:10.4271/2006-01-0077.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakisaka, Y., Hotta, Y., Inayoshi, M., Nakakita, K. et al., “Emissions Reduction Potential of Extremely High Boost and High EGR Rate for an HSDI Diesel Engine and the Reduction Mechanisms of Exhaust Emissions,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):611-623, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008-01-1189.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Thirouard, M., Mendez, S., Pacaud, P., Chmielarczyk, D., Ambrazas, I., Garsi, C., Lavoisier, F., and Barbeau, B., “Potential to Improve Specific Power Using Very High Injection Pressure In HSDI Diesel Engines,” SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-1524, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-1524.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wloka, J., Pflaum, S., and Wachtmeister, G., “Potential and Challenges of a 3000 Bar Common-Rail Injection System Considering Engine Behavior and Emission Level,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):801-813, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-1131.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Akihama, K., Takatori, Y., Inagaki, K., Sasaki, S., and Dean, A., “Mechanism of the Smokeless Rich Diesel Combustion by Reducing Temperature,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0655, SAE Transactions, 110, No. 3, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0655.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., and Higgins, B., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct-Injection Diesel Sprays Under Quiescent Conditions,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01- 0530, SAE Transactions, 110, No. 3, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0530.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins, B., and Siebers, D., “Measurement of the Flame Lift-Off Location on DI Diesel Sprays Using OH Chemiluminescence,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0918, SAE Transactions, 110, No. 3, 2001, doi:10.4271/2001-01-0918.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Siebers, D., Higgins, B., and Pickett, L., “Flame Lift-Off on Direct- Injection Diesel Fuel Jets: Oxygen Concentration Effects,” SAE Technical Paper 2002-01-0890, SAE Transactions, 111, No. 3, 2002, doi:10.4271/2002-01-0890.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lewis, B., and von Elbe, G., “Combustion Flames and Explosions of Gases”, Academic Press Inc, 2nd Edition, pp. 228-261, 1961.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Arai, M., “Diesel Spray and Its Combustion”, Atomization (journal of the ILASS Japan), Vol. 22, No. 77, pp. 189-202, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsuda, S., Kosaka, H., and Aizawa, T., “A Study on Effect of Heterogeneity of Oxygen Concentration and Temperature Distributions in a Combustion Chamber on Combustion and Emissions of Diesel Engine”, Proceedings of COMODIA 2008, No. DE3-2, pp. 189-196, 2008.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Siebers, D., and Idicheria, C., “Relationship Between Ignition Processes and the Lift-Off Length of Diesel Fuel Jets,” SAE Technical Paper 2005-01-3843, SAE Transactions, 114, No. 3, 2005, doi:10.4271/2005-01-3843.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bruneaux, G., Defransure, F., Garsi, C., Gastaldi, P., Griffaton, B., Kashdan, J., Le Ru, J., Lombard, B., Malbec, L., Nicolas, B., and Topenot, E., “DICO: a new step towards emission free diffusive combustion”, Proceedings of THIESEL 2012, Conference on Thermoand Fluid Dynamic Processes in Direct Injection Engines, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Polonowski, C., Mueller, C., Gehrke, C., Bazyn, T. et al., “An Experimental Investigation of Low-Soot and Soot-Free Combustion Strategies in a Heavy-Duty, Single-Cylinder, Direct-Injection, Optical Diesel Engine,” SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 5(1):51-77, 2012, doi:10.4271/2011-01-1812.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Chartier, C., Aronsson, U., Andersson, Ö., Egnell, R., and Johansson, B., “Influence of jet-jet interactions on the lift-off length in an optical heavy-duty DI diesel engine”, Fuel, Vol. 112, pp. 311-318, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pawlowski, A., Kneer, R., Vogel, S., and Peters, N., “Investigation of the Flow Field between Diesel Sprays to Characterize Spray-Spray Interaction”, Proceedings of the ICLASS 2006, No. ICLASS06-138, 2006.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Malbec, L. and Bruneaux, G., “Study of Air Entrainment of Multi-hole Diesel Injection by Particle Image Velocimetry - Effect of Neighboring Jets Interaction and Transient Behavior After End of Injection.,” SAE Int. J. Engines 3(1):107-123, 2010, doi:10.4271/2010-01-0342.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Toda, N., Yamashita, H., and Mashida, M., “PTV analysis of the entrained air into the diesel spray at high-pressure injection”, Proceedings of International Conference on Optical Particle Characterization, 2014.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wakuri, Y., Fujii, M., Amitani, T., and Tsuneya, R., “Studies on the Penetration of Fuel Spray of Diesel Engine”, Transactions of the JSME, Vol. 25, No. 156, pp. 820-826, 1959.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Naber, J. and Siebers, D., “Effects of Gas Density and Vaporization on Penetration and Dispersion of Diesel Sprays,” SAE Technical Paper 960034, SAE Transactions, 105, No. 3, 1996, doi:10.4271/960034.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Fuyuto, T., Akihama, K., Fujikawa, T., and Nakakita, K., “Diesel In- Cylinder Measurement Technique Using a Multi-Direction Optically Accessible Engine”, Journal of Environment and Engineering, Vol. 5, No. 1, pp. 72-83, 2010.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">http://www.sandia.gov/ecn/tutorials/tutorial/orifice.php</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Donkerbroek, A., Boot, M., Luijten, C., Dam, N., and ter Meulen, J., “Flame lift-off length and soot production of oxygenated fuels in relation with ignition delay in a DI heavy-duty diesel engine”, Combustion and Flame, Vol. 158, pp. 525-538, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref26">
            <label>26.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Musculus, M., “Effects of the In-Cylinder Environment on Diffusion Flame Lift-Off in a DI Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2003-01- 0074, SAE Transactions, 112, No. 3, 2003, doi:10.4271/2003-01-0074.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref27">
            <label>27.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Pickett, L., Kook, S., Persson, H., Andersson, Ö., “Diesel fuel jet lift-off stabilization in the presence of laser-induced plasma ignition,” Proc. Combust. Inst., vol. 32, Issue 2, pp. 2793-800, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
