<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26277600</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>Effect of Piston Bowl Geometry on Dual Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) in a Light-Duty Engine Operated with Gasoline/Diesel and Methanol/Diesel</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Dempsey</surname>
                  <given-names>Adam B.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Walker</surname>
                  <given-names>N. Ryan</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Reitz</surname>
                  <given-names>Rolf</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>Univ. of Wisconsin</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>5</month>
            <year>2013</year>
            <string-date>May 2013</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">6</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26277593</issue-id>
         <fpage>78</fpage>
         <lpage>100</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2013 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26277600"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>A single-cylinder light-duty diesel engine was used to investigate dual fuel reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI) operated with two different fuel combinations: gasoline/diesel fuel and methanol/diesel fuel. The engine was operated over a range of conditions, from 1500 to 2300 rpm and 3.5 to 17 bar gross IMEP. Using the stock re-entrant piston bowl geometry, both fuel combinations were able to achieve low NOx and PM emissions with a peak gross indicated efficiency of 48%. However, at light load conditions both gasoline and methanol yielded poorer combustion efficiencies. Previous studies have shown that the high-levels of piston induced mixing that are created by the stock piston are not required, and in fact are detrimental due to increased heat transfer losses, for premixed combustion. Thus a modified piston featuring a shallow, flat piston bowl with nearly no squish land was also investigated. Using the modified piston, the gross indicated efficiency of RCCI combustion was significantly improved at light loads due to increases in combustion efficiency and decreases in heat transfer losses. At higher loads the modified piston also performed better than the stock piston, but the improvements were not as significant. Over the entire load and speed range, the modified piston yielded low NOx and PM emissions with a peak gross indicated efficiency of nearly 51%.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Najt, P. and Foster, D., “Compression-Ignited Homogeneous Charge Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 830264, 1983, doi: 10.4271/830264.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Bessonette, P., Schleyer, C., Duffy, K., Hardy, W. et al., “Effects of Fuel Property Changes on Heavy-Duty HCCI Combustion,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0191, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0191.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L., Hanson, R. M., Splitter, D. A., and Reitz, R. D., Fuel reactivity controlled compression ignition (RCCI): a pathway to controlled high-efficiency clean combustion, International Journal of Engine Research, 2011.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. and Reitz, R., “Computational Optimization of Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition in a Heavy-Duty Engine with Ultra Low Compression Ratio,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(2):2222-2239, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-24-0015.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Splitter, D. A., Wissink, M. L., Hendricks, T. L., Ghandhi, J. B., and Reitz, R. D., Comparison of RCCI, HCCI, and CDC Operation from Low to Full Load, THIESEL 2012 Conference on Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Direct Injection Engines, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. B., Adhikary, B. D., Viswanathan, S., and Reitz, R. D., Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition Using Premixed Hydrated Ethanol and Direct Injection Diesel, Journal of Engineering for Gas Turbines and Power, 2012, Vol. 134.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dempsey, A. B., Walker, N. R., Splitter, D. A., Wissink, M. L., and Reitz, R. D. Characterization of Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Using Premixed Hydrated Ethanol and Direct Injection Diesel in Heavy-Duty and Light-Duty Engines, THIESEL 2012 Conference on Thermo- and Fluid Dynamic Processes in Direct Injection Engines, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Nichols, R. J., The Methanol Story: A Sustainable Fuel for the Future, Journal of Scientific &amp; Industrial Research, 2003, Vol. 62, pp. 97-105.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hanson, R., Curran, S., Wagner, R., Kokjohn, S. et al., “Piston Bowl Optimization for RCCI Combustion in a Light-Duty Multi-Cylinder Engine,” SAE Int. J. Engines 5(2):286-299, 2012, doi: 10.4271/2012-01-0380.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., and Reitz, R., “Experiments and Modeling of Dual-Fuel HCCI and PCCI Combustion Using In-Cylinder Fuel Blending,” SAE Int. J. Engines 2(2):24-39, 2010, doi: 10.4271/2009-01-2647.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S., Hanson, R., Splitter, D., Kaddatz, J. et al., “Fuel Reactivity Controlled Compression Ignition (RCCI) Combustion in Light- and Heavy-Duty Engines,” SAE Int. J. Engines 4(1):360-374, 2011, doi: 10.4271/2011-01-0357.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, J. B., Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals, 1988, McGraw-Hill Book Company.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gamma Technologies. GT Suite v7.0, 2009.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kenney, T., Gardner, T., Low, S., Eckstrom, J. et al., “Overall Results: Phase I Ad Hoc Diesel Fuel Test Program,” SAE Technical Paper 2001-01-0151, 2001, doi: 10.4271/2001-01-0151.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sluder, C. and Wagner, R., “An Estimate of Diesel High-Efficiency Clean Combustion Impacts on FTP-75 Aftertreatment Requirements,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-3311, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-3311.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kokjohn, S. L. and Reitz, R. D., RCCI and Conventional Diesel Combustion: A Comparison of Methods to Meet Light-Duty NOx and Fuel Economy Targets, International Journal of Engine Research, 2013.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Walker, N. R., Dempsey, A. B., Andrie, M. J., and Reitz, R. D., Experimental Study of Low-Pressure Fueling Under RCCI Engine Operation, 24th International Conference on Liquid Atomization and Spray Systems, San Antonio, Texas, 2012.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Cooper, B., Penny, I., Beasley, M., Greaney, A. et al., “Advanced Diesel Technology to Achieve Tier 2 Bin 5 Emissions Compliance in US Light-Duty Diesel Applications,” SAE Technical Paper 2006-01-1145, 2006, doi: 10.4271/2006-01-1145.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Opat, R., Ra, Y., Gonzalez D., M., Krieger, R. et al., “Investigation of Mixing and Temperature Effects on HC/CO Emissions for Highly Dilute Low Temperature Combustion in a Light Duty Diesel Engine,” SAE Technical Paper 2007-01-0193, 2007, doi: 10.4271/2007-01-0193.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
