<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.0" xml:lang="eng">
   <front>
      <journal-meta>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="publisher-id">saeintejengi</journal-id>
         <journal-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" journal-id-type="jstor">j50019980</journal-id>
         <journal-title-group>
            <journal-title>SAE International Journal of Engines</journal-title>
         </journal-title-group>
         <publisher>
            <publisher-name>SAE International</publisher-name>
         </publisher>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">19463936</issn>
         <issn xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="epub">19463944</issn>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
      </journal-meta>
      <article-meta>
         <article-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-id-type="jstor">26284837</article-id>
         <title-group>
            <article-title>First and Second Law Heat Release Analysis in a Single Cylinder Engine</article-title>
         </title-group>
         <contrib-group>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Mattson</surname>
                  <given-names>Jonathan M. S.</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <contrib contrib-type="author">
               <string-name xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
                  <surname>Depcik</surname>
                  <given-names>Christopher</given-names>
               </string-name>
            </contrib>
            <aff>University of Kansas</aff>
         </contrib-group>
         <pub-date xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" pub-type="ppub">
            <day>1</day>
            <month>4</month>
            <year>2016</year>
            <string-date>April 2016</string-date>
         </pub-date>
         <volume xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">9</volume>
         <issue xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">1</issue>
         <issue-id xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">e26284791</issue-id>
         <fpage>536</fpage>
         <lpage>545</lpage>
         <permissions>
            <copyright-statement>Copyright © 2016 SAE International</copyright-statement>
         </permissions>
         <self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
                   xlink:href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26284837"/>
         <abstract>
            <label>ABSTRACT</label>
            <p>In-cylinder engine modeling is a necessary aspect of combustion research. In particular, simulating heat release connects variable combustion behavior to fuel properties through the 1<sup>st</sup>Law of Thermodynamics. One extension of such models is to evaluate changes to in-cylinder behavior using the Second Law of Thermodynamics in order to identify the peak period of availability for work extraction. Thus, Second Law models are a useful tool to augment research into alternative fuel usage and optimization. These models also help identify internal irreversibilities that are separate from heat transfer and exhaust gas losses.</p>
            <p>This study utilizes a multi-zone 1<sup>st</sup>and 2<sup>nd</sup>Law Heat Release model to characterize the changes in combustion behavior of a number of neat fuels used in a single-cylinder compression ignition (CI) engine. This includes standard Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel (ULSD), biodiesels derived from jatropha and tallow feedstocks, Jet A aviation fuel, and a synthetic aviation fuel derived from renewable sources. In all cases, fuel injection timing was adjusted to align the peak pressure timing of each fuel with that of ULSD.</p>
            <p>Overall, variations in fuel properties were found to bring about considerable changes in engine operation when investigating the 2<sup>nd</sup>Law. Most prominently, fuel density, energy content, cetane number, and viscosity serve as the primary fuel characteristics that drive combustion timing, duration, and intensity. In particular, it is shown that large viscosities (a characteristic of biodiesels) lead to delayed and prolonged combustion, which serves to add availability to the working fluid later in the expansion stroke, subsequently making it more difficult to extract that availability as useful work. In addition, the strengths of incorporating the 2<sup>nd</sup>Law analysis are expressed, both alone and in tandem with the traditional 1<sup>st</sup>Law analysis.</p>
         </abstract>
         <custom-meta-group xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
            <custom-meta>
               <meta-name>lang</meta-name>
               <meta-value>eng</meta-value>
            </custom-meta>
         </custom-meta-group>
      </article-meta>
   </front>
   <back>
      <ref-list content-type="unparsed-citations">
         <title>REFERENCES</title>
         <ref id="ref1">
            <label>1.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Heywood, JB, "Internal Combustion Engine Fundamentals"1988: McGraw-Hill, Inc. 930.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref2">
            <label>2.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Gatowski, J., Balles, E., Chun, K., Nelson, F. et al., "Heat Release Analysis of Engine Pressure Data," SAE Technical Paper 841359, 1984, doi:10.4271/841359.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref3">
            <label>3.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, CD and Giakoumis, EG, "Second-law analyses applied to internal combustion engines operation". Progress in Energy and Combustion Science, 2006. 32(1): p. 2-47. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.pecs.2005.10.001</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref4">
            <label>4.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moran, MJ, Shapiro, HN, Boettner, DD, and Bailey, MB, "Fundamentals of engineering thermodynamics"2010: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref5">
            <label>5.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Rakopoulos, CD and Kyritsis, DC, "Comparative second-law analysis of internal combustion engine operation for methane, methanol, and dodecane fuels". Energy, 2001. 26(7): p. 705-722. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0360-5442(01)00027-5</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref6">
            <label>6.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Alkidas, A., "The Use of Availability and Energy Balances in Diesel Engines," SAE Technical Paper 890822, 1989, doi:10.4271/890822.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref7">
            <label>7.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tat, ME, "Cetane number effect on the energetic and exergetic efficiency of a diesel engine fuelled with biodiesel". Fuel Processing Technology, 2011. 92(7): p. 1311-1321. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fuproc.2011.02.006</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref8">
            <label>8.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kotas, TJ, "The exergy method of thermal plant analysis"2013: Elsevier.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref9">
            <label>9.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Brzustowski, T and Brena, A, "Second-law analysis of energy processes. IV- The exergy of hydrocarbon fuels". Canadian Society for Mechanical Engineering, Transactions, 1986. 10(3): p. 121-128</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref10">
            <label>10.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Moran, MJ, "Availability analysis: a guide to efficient energy use". 1982</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref11">
            <label>11.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mattson, JMS and Depcik, C, "Emissions-calibrated equilibrium heat release model for direct injection compression ignition engines". Fuel, 2014. 117, Part B(0): p. 1096-1110. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2013.10.026</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref12">
            <label>12.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mangus, M, Kiani, F, Mattson, J, Tabakh, D, et al., "Investigating the Compression Ignition Combustion of Multiple Biodiesel/ULSD Blends via Common-Rail Injection". Energy, 2015(in press)</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref13">
            <label>13.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hiroyasu, H and Nishida, K, "Simplified Three-Dimensional Modeling of Mixture Formation and Combustion in a DI Diesel Engine". 1989</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref14">
            <label>14.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Kee, RJ, Rupley, FM, Meeks, E and Miller, JA, "CHEMKINIII: A FORTRAN chemical kinetics package for the analysis of gas-phase chemical and plasma kinetics".</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref15">
            <label>15.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ra, Y., Reitz, R., McFarlane, J. and Daw, C., "Effects of Fuel Physical Properties on Diesel Engine Combustion using Diesel and Bio-diesel Fuels," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 1(1):703-718, 2009, doi:10.4271/2008- 01-1379.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref16">
            <label>16.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mattson, J., Mangus, M. and Depcik, C., "Efficiency and Emissions Mapping for a Single-Cylinder, Direct Injected Compression Ignition Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01-1242, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014- 01-1242.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref17">
            <label>17.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Churkunti, PR, "Combustion Performance of Waste-Derived Fuels with respect to Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel in a Compression Ignition Engine", in Mechanical Engineering 2015, University of Kansas: Lawrence, KS.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref18">
            <label>18.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Groendyk, M. and Rothamer, D., "Effects of Fuel Physical Properties on Auto-Ignition Characteristics in a Heavy Duty Compression Ignition Engine," SAE Int. J. Fuels Lubr. 8(1):200-213, 2015, doi:10.4271/2015- 01-0952.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref19">
            <label>19.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Agarwal, A. and Dhar, A., "Performance, Emission and Combustion Characteristics of Jatropha Oil Blends in a Direct Injection CI Engine," SAE Technical Paper 2009-01-0947, 2009, doi:10.4271/2009-01-0947.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref20">
            <label>20.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Knothe, G, Van Gerpen, JH and Krahl, J, "The biodiesel handbook". Vol. 1. 2005: AOCS press Champaign, IL.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref21">
            <label>21.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Lee, CS, Park, SW, and Kwon, SI, "An experimental study on the atomization and combustion characteristics of biodieselblended fuels". Energy &amp; Fuels, 2005. 19(5): p. 2201-2208</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref22">
            <label>22.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Langness, C., Mangus, M., and Depcik, C., "Construction, Instrumentation, and Implementation of a Low Cost, Single-Cylinder Compression Ignition Engine Test Cell," SAE Technical Paper 2014-01- 0817, 2014, doi:10.4271/2014-01-0817.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref23">
            <label>23.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mangus, M, Mattson, J, and Depcik, C, "Performance and Emissions Characteristics of Hydroprocessed Renewable Jet Fuel Blends in a Single-Cylinder Compression Ignition Engine with Electronically Controlled Fuel Injection". Combustion Science and Technology, 2015. 187(6): p. 857-873</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref24">
            <label>24.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tazerout, M., Le Corre, O., and Rousseau, S., "TDC Determination in IC Engines Based on the Thermodynamic Analysis of the Temperature- Entropy Diagram," SAE Technical Paper 1999-01-1489, 1999, doi:10.4271/1999-01-1489.</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
         <ref id="ref25">
            <label>25.</label>
            <mixed-citation publication-type="other">Mangus, M, Kiani, F, Mattson, J, Depcik, C, et al., "Comparison of Neat Biodiesels and ULSD in an Optimized Single-Cylinder Diesel Engine with Electronically-Controlled Fuel Injection". Energy &amp; Fuels, 2014. 28(6): p. 3849-3862. 10.1021/ef500417b</mixed-citation>
         </ref>
      </ref-list>
   </back>
</article>
